(suspenseful music) (footsteps)
(filmstrip running)
(ominous music)
♪ Star-spangled banner yet wave
♪ O'er the land of the free
♪ And the home
♪ Of the brave
(applause)
- Thank you, Pearl, for that fine rendition.
Now, a few words from the sheriff.
- A quick community note for you.
The Browns are having an auction this Sunday
with the proceeds going to help--
- That's us, that's our auction.
- They got chocolate cream pies at this thing.
- Jack, take human bites.
- Ready?
- Always, Cap'n.
- I look stupid.
- You're beautiful.
- I'd rather be sailing.
- Now, if you would let me talk to you a little bit
about firework safety.
Now, everyone be careful with them fireworks, okay?
And now our Independent State Youth Speech,
Molly-- (microphone feedback)
Molly Brown.
- Our ancestors fought many battles.
From the beginning of our country,
they have believed in faith.
Since my dad's always telling me that I'm stubborn,
I mean, independent, (audience laughter)
I guess our forefathers and mothers were independent, too.
They had faith in something they really couldn't see.
(striking match drowns out words)
to the crackle of a gun fire.
(firecrackers)
That's it, you're dead Cory.
Jack, take it back way.
Let's go, Jillian!
- Settle down, everybody, just settle down.
Just another prankster.
Pearl, can we get another one
of your beautiful renditions?
- [Voiceover] This is you, Dr. Turner?
- Yes, ma'am, a long time ago, when I was --
- And that story about the lost treasure.
Do you still believe it?
- Uh, as I wa saying--
- You never found it, did you, Dr. Turner?
- No, ma'am, just a couple of coins, an old letter,
and an awful lot of mud.
- Well, there's no sense beating a dead horse, Dr. Turner.
(laughter)
- He has not aged well, at all.
- Not aged well, huh?
Well, I still got the old Turner charm.
Plus the IQ of the combined population of this town.
Just one more piece of the puzzle,
and that treasure will be mine.
- You kids better be more careful, geez!
This is a new shirt.
- [Voiceover] I'd rather Jimmy (engine drowns out words)
house on the hill.
- Molly, could you run this right over to your grandfather?
It's a get-well card.
- But...
Yes, Mrs. Stephenson.
- Poor girl, being raised without a mother.
Practically lives on that river.
And she talks to herself.
A lot.
- She reminds me a lot of her grandfather.
Sometimes too much.
So, how are you doing, Paul?
You found anything, yet?
- No, not a lot of work for historians right now.
- There never is, I should know.
I wish I could get you on here.
- Thanks, when they cut back at the college,
I didn't really think I'd--
- Yes, yes, things are tight all over.
Listen, Paul, I've inventoried all of the--
(car honking)
Things you gave us from Sara's research,
but I can't seem to find the old diary.
- I suppose it could be stored some place else.
After she died, I didn't really have the heart to--
- Well, without the diary, we might not be as interested.
Would your father-in-law know something?
- I don't think so, he's not doing so well.
- Well, how about I stop by when you have more time?
- Okay, sure.
(strong, whimsical music)
- [Voiceover] Uh oh, kid, bad hair day.
- Alex, I'm Nurse Rancette.
Welcome to White River Foster Care.
Hands out of your pockets and look at me, please.
You've been placed in three foster homes
and run away from all three.
Each time you stole from the good people who took you in.
That adds up to ...
- Trouble.
- And now you've been sent here.
If you steal, or run from me,
the next stop is Juvenile Detention Center,
and that would be bad now, wouldn't it?
Simonton?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Correct.
Rule number one, you do not leave the property grounds
unless otherwise authorized.
Do you understand?
What?
- Yeah.
- Yes what?
- Yes ma'am.
- Yes ma'am what?
- Yes ma'am, yes ma'am, three bags full.
(laughter)
- Enough, follow me.
- Don't you got some kid stuff to do?
- Yeah, honey, he's probably going to sleep all afternoon.
- Now look the main sail.
Taking the helm.
Pull in the slack, the spanker.
- Spank her?
I hardly know her.
- He's a master sailor.
You should give him more respect.
- R-E-S-P-E-C-T.
Spank it to me, baby.
(laughter)
- Molly. (coughing)
Get me some water, will you, babe?
Oh, thank you, dear, oh.
How's the river, huh?
- Water's up a little with all the rain.
- How's my house?
- Dad and I have been going through old boxes of stuff.
We have to auction off, Cappy,
because we don't have enough money to--
- Money, money, money.
You do believe in the treasure, don't you, Molly?
Your mother knew.
She knew it was there.
- She never found it, nobody has.
- Maybe it's time now for you to finish what she started.
It's your journey now.
- But Cappy.
- The river is, at night,
it mirrors clear sight.
Your story told,
of the soldier's gold.
- [Molly] Cappy.
- Time for your nap, Cappy.
- Faith, truth,
and courage.
(nostalgic piano music)
(whimsical music)
- [Jack] Hey, Molly, I mean Cap'n.
- [Molly] Is our science officer ready?
- In position, up the river.
- Or home watching Star Trek.
- [Molly] Helmets?
- Jack.
Helmets, check.
- Check.
- Thanks.
(whistling)
(banjo music)
- All head full.
- Next time, I'll look out and Jillian's pedaling.
(banjo music)
- Keep sharp lookout!
- Can't keep this up.
I need fuel.
Wow, Mom was wrong, these are good for you.
I'm Superman now.
- Jack, check the rope!
- Uh, Captain, the rope's off, again.
Over.
- We're slowing down!
(suspenseful music)
- I could use a drink.
Thanks.
- I can't believe it, every time!
Go fill up some water balloons.
- Fire!
(yelling muffled)
- [Voiceover] You need to cool off!
- I'm out of there in less than one hour.
Ha, beating my own record, with travel money.
- My ammo's gone!
- Engine room, we're running in for lunch.
- Twinkies?
- I'm hit, I'm hit!
- Yes!
- Matty coming.
- My ammo's gone!
- Jillian, raise the white flag!
- Looks like they're out of ammo!
- Hurry, before they--
Never mind.
(triumphant music)
- [Voiceover] Jack, do something!
- [Voiceover] Hal, I thought you had a plan.
They're killing us.
- Roger, Blue Leader, I copy.
- This battle stops, my cover's blown.
- Hey, the white flag's up!
Don't you know the kid's code of the river?
(laughter)
- Uh oh.
- [Voiceover] We like to sing, we like to dance,
we see Molly's underpants.
(laughter)
- [Voiceover] Hal, if you're gonna do something,
now would be a good time.
- Roger, Blue Leader, dropping on your 20, over.
- On my what? Over?
- If I were you, I'd duck.
(engines buzzing)
- What are you doing here, kid?
- Uh, I'm just trying to hide?
(engines buzzing)
- What's that?
- I would hide.
(engines buzzing) - Run!
- Couldn't have said it better, myself.
(engines buzzing)
- Here comes somebody's mom.
Boy, does she look mad!
- That's no mother, that's Evil's evil twin.
You gotta hide me.
Kids' code of the river?
- There's no kids' code of the river for you.
You threw a water balloon at me when the white flag was up.
- Well, if they catch me, I'm downriver to Juvenile Hall.
In there?
- If you don't wanna get caught.
- But I can't swim.
- Better hurry.
- I hope there's no snakes.
This water's cold.
Oh my gosh.
- Simonton!
All right, children, where is he?
- Where is who?
- Our recent arrival.
I know he's here, I heard voices.
- I think you heard our voices, ma'am.
- It's not safe out here for a young boy.
You can't trust that boy, you know.
He steals from everyone.
- He's a thief?
(yelling)
- You're only making this harder on yourself.
- Hey, don't hurt him.
- It's for his own good, dear.
- Everything checks out.
(dialing)
Except, where's Unit Seven?
- Come on.
- Not cold.
Not cold?
That water was freezing!
(engines buzzing)
- Ah, kids, come on!
- [Voiceover] Bad hair day!
- Bad remote helicopter.
Bad, bad, bad.
- Oh the humanity!
And to think they pick on poor, helpless Twinkies.
Come to Papa.
- You're too old to be cute anymore.
10 years old, no parents, and a juvie to boot.
There are no more foster homes for you, mister.
You're an orphan with no prospects of ever having a family.
Get that into that thick little head of yours.
And if you ever run away again, I'll chain you to your bed.
Forever.
(mellow banjo music)
- [Molly] Hey, Dad.
Dr. Turner.
- Hello, Molly.
- What happened to you?
- You should see the other guys.
- We were just talking about your grandpa.
- The museum would like to purchase some things
before the auction.
- What things?
- Oh, any of your grandfather's Civil War relics.
Any of Sara's, your mother's research regarding the--
- The lost treasure?
- Did you ever see her diary, honey?
- We're willing to pay a nice price.
- Even if I did know where it was, it's not for sale.
- Molly, that's not polite.
- Dad, that belongs to us.
- Paul, maybe you and I should talk about this later.
- Okay, thanks, Louis.
- What was that all about?
- We can take the journey, Grandpa said.
- Where?
(inspirational music)
Your grandpa's not doing well.
He says some crazy things.
- I believe him.
We can take the boat, Dad.
- You're not going after any treasure, it's dangerous.
And besides, it's all just a story.
It's not true.
- Mom thought it was.
(melancholy music)
- Listen, young lady, no treasure hunt.
- If we found that treasure, we'd solve all our problems.
- Money doesn't solve problems.
Besides, I've already worked things out with the museum.
Dr. Turner will pay for those Civil War relics
of your grandfather's.
- Turner's a snake.
- You might as well know that snake
thinks he's found a buyer for this house.
- Dad, this is Grandpa's house.
- Even then, we still can't cover his medical costs.
He's been sick a long time.
- I won't leave the river.
- Molly!
(brushing teeth) (toilet flushing)
(loud radio blasting)
- Simonton, turn down the music!
(phone ringing)
- Where is she?
She's gotta be there.
Faulty wiring at the foster home.
Try again.
(phone ringing)
- White River Foster Care, Beatrice Rancette speaking.
Oh, hello Director.
Oh, yes sir.
- I'll be there in two days.
And I'm bringing Mr. Farr of White River paper.
- Oh, of course, yes sir.
Um, why the head of a paper company, sir?
- [Director] You just be sure everything is in good order.
No trouble, especially with the children.
- Oh, of course sir, absolutely.
Everything will be spit-spot.
(rock music)
Simonton!
- Yes, Nurse Rancid?
- Rancette, idiot.
More than I need to know, Simonton.
- Yes, Rancette.
- Look, the director is com--
Would you cover up, please?
The director is coming.
I want you to make sure there's no trouble,
especially, Alex, come with me!
- Yes Nurse Rancette.
- Oh sheets.
- Find him!
If there is anything, anything amiss here
when the director arrives--
- You'll probably lose your job.
- Yes, and if I lose my job, then what happens to you?
- Um, I get a raise?
- Oh shut up, you lose yours, too.
Now find that child!
- [Dad] Hey, you sure you don't want any dinner?
- Yeah.
Dad, we can't leave the river.
- A lot of kids move.
At least you'll have some great memories.
- Like you have memories of Mom?
- Of course.
- It's not the same, is it?
I miss her.
- Me too, honey.
Hard to believe we were married, we were so different.
- Treasure hunter and the teacher.
- Just the facts for me,
but she loved the wild tales of the river.
She devoted herself to searching for that treasure.
- Lost Treasure of White River?
- But when you were born, she stopped.
Seemed you were the only treasure she really needed.
- Dad!
We could do it, you and me.
We could finish what she started.
- Molly, stop, there's no documentation
that the Army ever shipped gold on the river.
- Mom believed it, and Grandpa says
you have to have faith and stuff.
- You can't eat the things he's always spouting about.
Faith, truth, courage.
And it won't put a roof over your head.
Anyway, I need to get to bed.
I've got a job interview in the city tomorrow.
It'll be okay.
Better get to sleep.
By the way, I loved your speech.
Blaze of glory.
- [Cappy] In every journey, you've got to have three things,
faith, truth, courage.
Oh, and a little bit of luck.
- [Molly] That's four, faith, truth, courage, and luck.
- [Cappy] Well, you can't count on luck.
Believe in yourself, believe in the river.
And oh. (laughter)
Yessir.
- [Molly] Wow.
- When you start your journey, remember the legend.
- The legend?
- Indians used to tell a story about a spirit bear
that watched over the river.
It was a great big, old, mean bear.
Three toes.
- Is he mad about something?
- I don't know, it was a legend.
But they say that he was the guardian
of the river's treasures.
- I'd be too scared to go against that big bear.
There's no way, right, Cappy?
- Now, just remember, faith, truth, and courage.
(electronic screeches)
(rattling cans)
- [Voiceover] So let it be.
(electronic screeches) (rattling cans)
- Who's there?
(electronic screeches)
Hal?
- Greetings, Captain.
- [Molly] Are you okay?
- Neuromuscular 63%.
Vision, system failure.
- [Molly] What were you wearing?
- Night vision goggles.
This was the test run.
You can see in the dark.
(electronic screeches)
Sorta.
- Wait, say that again.
- Sorta?
- No, the part about seeing in the dark.
- Well, technically, they reflect
off the charged-coupled device.
- That's it, seeing in the dark.
River at night, mirrors clear as sight.
Your story told, the soldier's gold.
- That's really not the technical description.
- It's a riddle!
It's a clue to finding the treasure.
We have to find it, Hal, we have to.
It's the only way I can stay on the river
and save Grandpa's house.
(clunking)
Sh.
(dog barking) (electronic screeching)
(yelling)
- [Molly] You, what are you doing here?
- [Hal] Hey, navigational charts of the river.
- [Molly] My mom's research!
What are you doing in here?
- I just want to talk about your boat.
- [Molly] What about my boat?
- I just want to go downriver, a few miles,
and then I'd--
- [Molly] Steal my boat.
That's what you're trying to do.
- Nah, borrow it, come on.
- And just how were you planning to return it?
- Well, I'd...
- That's it, out, and stay off my boat.
- Sure, whatever.
- Hold it, what's that?
- Here.
Not bad reading once you get past the buried treasure parts.
- What is it?
- It's my mom's diary.
(nostalgic piano music)
They were clobbering us when Jillian raised the white flag.
It turned out to be a big pair of ladies' underwear.
- [Cappy] Oh, how'd those get in there?
- Then, my life, as I knew it, was over.
- Oh, I said the same thing when your grandmother
bought them drawers.
- And then they all started singing.
- Big underwear can have that effect on people.
Help you sir?
- Yes, I've come to visit Jacob Bradshaw.
Is this his room?
- Yeah, his granddaughter's in there with him.
- I found Mom's diary.
She was closer to finding the treasure than anybody knew.
And there's a map.
Mom's diary says there's someone named Bert
that can help us.
We can make it in a day, you and me, Cappy.
- I'm afraid not, Molly.
I'm just so tired.
- I can't go without you.
- The river at night. - [Molly] Cappy.
- Soldier's gold. - [Molly] Cappy.
- I'm just so tired, Sara.
- Cappy, Cappy?
♪ There is a voice in all of us
♪ It never will divide
(beeping)
♪ It speaks to everyone of us
♪ A message from the heart
♪ When fears are strong
♪ Take faith in hand
♪ And the truth will be your guide
♪ Find courage true
♪ Just listen to
♪ The voice that speaks inside
- Beautiful.
That old eyesore of a foster home gone.
The old Jacob Bradshaw house gone.
Hello, White River Papers.
Now, if I could just get my hands on that diary.
- Now what would they want with some old motor,
silly children.
You'd think they were going on some kind of cruise.
- [Molly] Come on, Jack, try it again.
(motor starting and sputtering out)
- Hal, can't you program something to make this work?
- If only it had an EEPROM.
Without the additional power,
our journey will be severely curtailed.
- What'd he say?
- We can't go.
- I'll never get downriver to find Bert.
- [Voiceover] Hello, Mr. Brown.
This is White River Nursing Home.
I'm calling about your father-in-law,
and we wanted to make sure Molly was all right.
Well, call us as soon as you get this message, please.
- Uh, uh, uh, Molly.
There's somebody in there.
- Hi.
- You again, don't you ever give up?
- [Jillian] It's that delinquent kid.
- Alex, name's Alex.
Well, I just want a ride out of here.
I can help, you know.
- [Molly] I suppose you know something about motors?
- Well, one of the loving foster homes I was in
was with this mechanic, a real prince.
I had to work in his garage or else no bed, no food.
You pick up stuff.
(light piano music)
- [Jillian] Okay, sleeping bags, check.
Food?
- Affirmative.
Highly adequate, proteinaceous sustenance.
- What did he say?
- He's got the food.
- Oh.
- Parental consent, accounted for?
- Check, all of your parents think you're at my house.
And my dad's away at a job interview.
- Except for...
- No worries, I don't have any parents.
- No worries, you're not going.
We can't risk that woman coming after us.
Thanks for the help.
But sorry, Alex.
- I'm gonna be grounded for life if my mom finds out
we're not sleeping at your house, Molly.
- GPS navigation system, Hal 9000 patent pending?
- [Voiceover] Hello, how are you?
- Check.
- [Jillian] Gas can?
- Check, and, uh, negative.
- What?
Great, this wrecks everything.
- [Alex] I know where some is.
- Where?
- There.
- Great, do we knock first, or ring the bell?
- Neither.
They'd never think I'm stupid enough to break back in.
- Isn't that stealing?
- I gave them the best 59 minutes and 20 seconds of my life.
Think of it as a trade.
- I'll go, you stay here.
- You know, technically, if we get caught, we're done.
Need these, Molly?
- [Jillian and Molly] No.
- [Hal] Just made a few minor adjustments.
(electronic pulses)
- Oh brother.
(dog barking) (suspenseful music)
- Stay here.
- Yes, Nurse Rancette.
Who's a good doggie.
You're a good doggie, yes you are.
(snoring)
(thudding)
This dream, oh, we were married this time.
Rancette babies.
Terminal bad hair, oh.
(suspenseful music) (barking)
- Let me have it.
- You don't take me with you, no gas.
- Fine, promise no more stealing.
- I promise.
- What?
- I promise!
- Sh.
- What is it now?
- Who's there?
- What's going on out there?
- I thought I heard someone, Nurse Rancid.
- Rancette, Simonton.
- I'm sorry, Nurse Rancette.
- Bed check, immediately.
What's that smell?
- What's the smell, let's see, it's you, Nurse Rancid.
- That smell was gas!
The kids, the motor, oh Simonton!
- [Jillian] They got caught, I just know it.
- [Jack] We're in big trouble.
- They've been gone approximately...
- [Voiceover] 13 minutes, seven seconds.
- Too long.
(mellow piano music)
- Honey, I'm home.
Slip me some skin.
- All right.
- Okay, let's shove off.
- It's all clear now, he's been hiding on that boat.
- Why would he do that?
- Because he's going downriver
with the rest of the children.
They must all be running away.
- Enemy approaching, and boy, does she look mad.
Or not. (electronic screeches)
Hal, I thought you fixed these.
(mystical music)
- Yes, this is Louis Turner.
Paul, I was in the area and I thought we could talk.
I'll try back later.
(mystical music)
- Nothing, the boat's gone.
- Jack, the motor will make noise.
- By my calculations, sound travels at 620 feet per second.
- Oh, the director's gonna have my head for this.
- Yes, Nurse Rancid, your head.
- Rancette.
Oh, shut up.
Call the sheriff, call the sheriff.
If my home isn't good enough for that boy,
maybe the big house will be.
- Stop it!
- [Molly] Okay, Jack, start the motor.
- Okay, got it.
(motor running and sputtering out)
Not good.
- Looks like we risked a criminal record for nothing.
- Try it now.
(motor running)
Don't panic.
- Great job.
Now we just need to figure out our coordinates.
- [Voiceover] Hello, I'm Hal 9000.
Nice to meet you.
We are now docking into Earth orbit nine,
(Spanish speaking)
- Perfect, we're headed in the right direction.
- Everything okay, Nurse Rancette?
- Oh, hello, Dr. Turner.
Just one small problem, one of our boys has run away.
- Yeah, and he stole my wallet.
- We believe he's headed downriver as we speak
with that awful bunch of river rats on their homemade boat.
- You mean Molly?
They're on Molly's boat?
- Yes, we saw them making ready for some kind of journey.
- Did they, do you know where they were going?
- No, but clearly they planned all along
to spirit away the boy. - [Simonton] Thief.
- We were just about the call the sheriff.
- Nurse Rancette.
- Beatrice, call me Beatrice.
- Beatrice, and you must call me Louis.
Why don't I help you run downriver?
I'm sure that we could intercept them at the first bridge.
Molly's father is a friend of mine,
and I'd hate to see them get into any trouble.
- And if we found them first,
we wouldn't have to tell the director about it.
- Oh, uh, well, I wouldn't want poor Mr. Brown
to experience any difficulties.
Perhaps you're right, Louis. (giggles)
Get in, Simonton.
(running motor)
- I'm looking for it, I'm looking for it, all right?
- Look at your fly! (giggling)
- It's on my fly, it's on my fly.
It's like, it's like you put a big spotlight on me.
- Wait, I don't remember a big brown spot on my underwear.
(laughter)
Spikes, wings, really weird things biting me.
- Molly, I'm trying to verify coordinates.
What's that rhyme?
- The river at night, mirrors clear as sight.
Your story told, the soldier's gold.
- Gold?
What gold?
- Never mind.
Get to sleep, I'll take first watch.
We have to stay in the middle of the river.
(suspenseful music)
- Night, honey.
(whimsical music)
- GPS, what direction are we headed?
- [Voiceover] 24 (Spanish language)
- That's not right, is it?
- [Voiceover] Five seven five latitude.
- I must have mixed programs in the download.
Spanish translator with global positioning.
- [Voiceover] Your direction is 2 (Spanish language)
- What does that mean?
- Your fly's open.
- it is not.
- Made you look.
(upbeat music)
(snoring)
- Oh, oh, Louis, I'm so sorry, oh how rude of me.
- It's quite all right, Beatrice.
Now, where's Simonton?
(whimsical music) (snoring)
- Simonton!
(yelling) (crashing)
- Did they pass here, yet?
- Not that I noticed.
- Oh you idiot, they're probably far ahead by now.
- I have an idea.
(phone dialing)
Mr. Farr, yes, this is Louis Turner.
Yes, hello.
We're very close, but I wanna make sure
that a certain little girl and her friends
don't find something that could
prove fortunate for them and unfortunate
for the White River Papers.
In a word sir, I need a boat.
Excellent, you'll be signing the papers by the weekend.
- That's a coincidence, Louis.
The president of the White River Papers
is to be a the foster home in two days.
- Yes, life is strange, isn't it, Beatrice?
- Simonton, come on.
♪ There is a voice in all of us
♪ It never will depart
♪ It speaks to everyone of us
♪ A message from the heart
♪ When fears are strong
♪ Take faith in hand
♪ And the truth will be your guide
♪ Find courage true
♪ Just listen to
♪ The voice that speaks inside
- Look, a fork in the river.
- Where?
- There.
- Very funny, Jillian.
- I'm King of the World!
- I'm Queen of the World!
- I'm King of the,
I'm President of Microsoft!
- Can you hear me now?
Can you hear me now?
♪ And I know you will decide
♪ What's right for you
♪ Just listen to
♪ The voice that speaks inside
(phone ringing)
- Hello?
Yes, it's Paul Brown.
Oh God, no.
Yes, I see.
Molly?
She was there when he--
Oh, yes, thank you.
Molly!
Liz, hi, it's Paul Brown.
Listen, is Molly there?
They what?
No, not here.
I got home late.
I just found out that Cappy passed away yesterday.
I'll check and I'll call you back.
Thanks.
Ah, Molly.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, Simonton!
Well, I can't say that I've ridden in anything
quite so open before.
Oh!
- Sorry, Beatrice.
- Quite all right.
(motor revving)
- [Jack] I'm starving, how about lunch?
- Yes, protein would be nice.
What's that?
- Hey, what's going on?
Jillian, the ropes!
Cut the motor, we're breaking up!
- We're about to get boarded.
What do you want?
- I think they're human.
- I think they're teenagers.
- Great, that's all we need, teenagers.
- Whaddya got?
- [Molly] Nothin' really.
- Then I guess we're just gonna have to take your boat.
- I don't like this.
- Hey, look.
- Hey, give those back.
- Just give them the stupid Twinkies, Jack.
- Look, beans.
- By my calculations, there are five of us,
and 20 of them.
- [Jillian] Jack.
- You don't know how painful this is.
- [Voiceover] You're not going anywhere.
- Hands off, creep.
(roaring)
- That sounded like a bear.
Can bears climb ropes?
- So, I don't think is just some fun on the water.
For Molly to take off like this after Cappy's--
(phone ringing)
- You might be right.
Sheriff Donnelly.
Right.
So, neither the groundskeeper nor the head nurse are there?
I see.
All right, thanks.
Seems we got a kid missing, too.
Alex, new arrival.
- Maybe they're all in this together somehow.
Molly's got this idea about a treasure.
- Yeah, I've heard that story since I was a kid.
That's what Cappy said,
"You have to have faith to find your truth,
"and the courage to follow it,"
is that it?
- Yeah, but she really believes it,
and I think she may be desperate enough
to do something dangerous.
- [Voiceover] A witch! (yelling)
- Would you quit that noise, please?
- She's very polite, for a witch.
- Ridiculous child.
- That it, no evil spells?
No fire coming out your nose?
- Was that you that made that bear noise?
- It's bear country.
I could tell you stories.
Best be on your way.
- [Molly] Bert?
- Yeah, how do you know me?
- You're Bert?
- Hm, short for Roberta.
And now you kids better get,
before those bad boys come back.
- But Bert, I'm Sara's daughter, Molly.
- Sara?
- Yes, I need to know the story of the treasure.
Cappy's been sick and we had to sell everything.
And move from the weather, and Cappy--
- Hey Molly, what's wrong?
- Molly?
- I see.
You come ashore.
The rest of you stay put, there's bears.
- How do you know?
- Same way I know lots of stuff, I'm old, you brat.
(guitar music)
(motorboat engine)
- Keep your eyes peeled, Paul.
We'll get there in time.
- [Paul] Can't you go any faster?
(guitar music)
- You look like your mother.
- [Molly] I do?
- Yeah, scruffy and earnest,
and pretty, too.
- Thanks.
- So, her father, your grandpa, huh?
- Gone.
- Oh well, that's too bad, huh.
Huh?
- What?
- All right, you wanna hear the story I told your mother?
- Yes, please.
- Did you know that your great-great grandma
had the treasure in her hand in 1864?
- No, really?
- Sure, strong women run in your family.
I'll tell ya, it wasn't long ago
that the terrible war between the states
was just about over.
It was a time of great desperation for the troops
as they prepared for one last battle.
Your great-great grandma was a doctor there.
Pretty rare in those days.
- Wow, she was cool.
- Yeah, a lot like you, kiddo.
As night fell, a guard brought up
a wounded prisoner for treatment.
The gold was the last hope for the wounded.
It could buy badly needed food and medicine.
As the prisoner approached, he saw the gold,
and he got some high hopes of his own.
With a battle upon him, the prisoner decided
to make his move for that gold.
There was a struggle.
The prisoner got the gun.
Shots rang out.
He left with the gun and the gold.
And now, your great-great grandma was wounded,
along with the others in the tent.
- So, what happened?
- Well, the trooper made his way down river
and was hiding the gold.
They say greed's always afraid to show its true face.
Many men suffered because he stole that gold,
but there's a legend about the spirit bear
that guards the river,
and sees to it that justice is done.
And that night, that prisoner met justice.
- [Molly] The three-toed bear?
- That's right, missy.
You afraid, girl?
Can't be afraid.
Who knows what happened to that trooper?
He didn't have the courage to face that bear
after what he'd done.
The prisoner and the gold were never seen again.
- [Molly] Is there a map?
- Well, I don't know, child.
I never had a map, myself. (creaking wood)
It's how come I never went after the treasure myself.
- Uh, hi.
- [Bert] What you doing here, sneaky boy?
- Molly, we were just worried about you.
- [Molly] I'm fine.
- There's nothin' for you to pinch here, kid.
- [Molly] How did you know?
Alex promised he wouldn't steal anymore.
- I, uh, I was in your shed, Molly.
I wanted to return it.
It was tucked in your mom's diary.
It's some kind of map.
- You stole it?
- Indeed it is, lookit.
This little island called Little Sue's is marked.
- Can you tell us how to get there?
- Sure, but,
I tell you who else is probably there.
- Three-toed bear.
I'm scared.
- You're in big trouble.
- It can be dangerous in there at night.
- [Jillian] Molly, do you think you can find this island?
- [Molly] Yeah, but it means we can't get back today.
- [Hal] Provisions, anyone?
- What?
- He means anybody hungry?
- Beans, is that it?
That's lunch?
That's all you brought?
- The bean, pound for pound, contains the most protein
in the smallest package, and can be eaten safely
at any temperature.
- Great, now we're all gonna be gas-powered.
- And me without my Twinkies.
- Even I could go for a Twinkie right now.
- Oh well, it's food.
- I think they must have taken the left fork back there.
- Now can you explain how the paper company
comes into all of this?
- Patience, my dear.
You might receive a very nice payoff with a little patience.
(farting)
- Made some more space.
- [Hal] Is that confirmed,
that there are bears in this area?
- Um, bears?
- Lions and tigers and bears!
- So funny, I forgot to laugh.
- But you didn't forget to pee your pants.
Made you look.
- Would you quit doing that?
- Hal, didn't you think that with all these beans--
(farting) Whoops.
- I never thought girls-- (farting)
- The average person, male or female,
breaks wind 16 times a day.
- [Alex] You mean (farting) per minute.
- [Voiceover] A common by-product of bean consumption
by humans. (farting)
- [Hal] Anything is possible.
- [Alex] In the land of (farting) Fartzilla!
- [Hal] Now that's going to leave a mark.
- Right.
They think they saw the hulk of a homemade boat
a couple of hours ago.
- How much further can we go by boat?
- Well, quite a ways till the dam.
Indians used to call it Wapahoni.
- Wapahoni?
- Yeah, it's the Indian word for mini falls.
- There's no chance they'll get that close to the dam,
right?
- Well, let's find them before they find it.
(motor starting)
(gentle music)
- [Alex] What's up with you?
- [Molly] Nothin'.
Really, nothing.
Cappy died.
- [Alex] Oh, I'm sorry.
- [Molly] So, that'll just leave me and my dad.
And if we have to move and leave the river,
I won't have a home or
my friends, and eveything will change.
- [Alex] I guess that leaves me and you in the same boat.
I'm sorry I stole that map.
- That's all right, you gave it back.
And besides, I still don't even know where we're going.
And once we get there,
I don't know how to find the treasure.
And, there's a legend about a three-toed bear
that'll eat you alive if you're afraid.
- Well, that leaves you out.
I've never met anybody as brave as you.
- Really?
- Mhmm.
So, I'm with you to the island,
to the treasure, up against the bear.
Proud to serve, Captain.
- Thanks, Alex.
- But right now, I gotta go.
- You goin' someplace.
- I gotta go!
- Just go over the side.
- No, I gotta go.
(ominous music)
(roaring)
- You're short.
- Oh, that hurts.
- What? - [Jillian] That really hurts.
(growling)
- Bravest person in the world, ha.
Hey Alex, watch out for poison ivy!
- What was that, two or three leaves?
(growling)
Hello?
(roaring)
Okay, bye.
- [Cappy] Faith, truth, courage.
- [Alex] Bear!
- [Voiceover] Alert, big trouble.
- [Alex] Bear, bear! (roaring)
- Come on!
- Come on you guys, quick! - [Jack] Come on, come on!
- [Jack] Get on the boat, quick, there's a bear out there!
(growling)
- Do you need to stop, Simonton?
- Shouldn't be too hard to catch up with them.
- I hope not.
- [Jack] Okay, first the gas, then the beans,
then the gas, which came from the beans.
Then a witch named Bert.
- Molly, that diary won't help us find the treasure.
- And not to mention, the bad kids.
I just wanna go home.
- But Cappy said, you have to have faith,
truth, and courage.
- [Jack] Did Cappy ever say anything about Twinkies?
- [Molly] Jack!
- Oh my God.
- What do you have there?
- Uh, nothing.
But I think we're hot on their trail, come on.
- It can be dangerous out here at night.
- I've got a bad feeling about this.
(peaceful orchestral music)
- Can I see that?
- Sure.
I'm gonna do things when I grow up.
I'm not gonna have a boring job.
I'm gonna, travel the Sierra,
sail all the Seven Seas, and go to Mars.
- [Jack] Don't you think you're already on Mars, Molly?
- Look what he's looking at.
(jeering)
- [Molly] Jack, I know you like them, but just stop.
- There they are, finally.
Louis, did you see that sign?
- What sign?
- The sign about the (rushing water).
- River at night, mirrors clear sight.
- What's that sound?
- Here our story told.
- [Voiceover] The medallion is highly protein.
And the medallion is the map.
- Wait!
That's it, the medallion!
- I hear a roar.
- [Voiceover] You are moving in a--
- Dam!
Turn to shore!
No, to shore!
Over side, now!
- [Voiceover] Wow, I guess (words drowned out by crashing)
- Oh my goodness.
Why don't we go pick them up?
- Too late.
- But Louis, did they all make it to shore?
- That's what I'm worried about.
- Where's Molly and Jillian?
- I, I don't think they made it.
- Come on.
(suspenseful music)
- I'm going to go into that cove over there.
- [Molly] Are you okay?
- [Jillian] Yeah.
(new age music)
- Molly!
Molly?
Molly!
Oh, sorry.
- Come on.
I'm sorry I got you in this.
We lost the map, the boat.
We're cold, and it's dark.
- And don't forget, we lost all of our beans over the dam.
- Is your whole life food?
- Wait a minute, wait a minute.
We could have been killed.
We're alive, and--
- Well, we're waiting.
- We're alive, did I say that already?
- You're lucky you don't have parents,
'cause mine are gonna kill me.
- I'm real lucky, Jack, real lucky.
- I just, I mean, sorry.
- Wait a minute!
The map, it's still around your neck!
- It's not a map of the river, it's--
- Of this island.
And the markings indicate the location of the treasure.
I'd say that we go right up this hill.
- Let's go.
- Think there's any wild animals out here?
- Of course not, Simonton.
Are there, Louis?
- I'm gonna try to move quietly toward the young folks.
I don't wanna scare them.
- And I just wanna get my wallet back.
And a slice of whatever it is you're into, Louis.
- I don't know what you mean.
- Sure you do.
And if I don't get it, I blow the whistle on the whole deal.
The fact that the paper mill's trying to buy up
the Bradshaw property and the foster home
so they can put a paper mill on the river.
And the fact that you're trying to steal the treasure
away from these kids.
The whole deal.
- What?
Will somebody tell me what's going on?
- Done.
All right, everybody walk like a woodsman.
I think they're up there.
So, you know about the paper mill?
- Everybody knows the paper company's
wanted that stretch of land forever.
And with Jacob Bradshaw in the nursing home,
I could just see the vultures circling in.
- Well, they'll have to sell now.
Paul Brown's already agreed,
and the foster home is next on the chopping block.
- What?
(growling)
(coughing)
- There should be a rock somewhere.
- Uh, guys, look.
A skull.
- We need a light.
- It's also a 60-decibel audible alarm.
- Just the light, Hal.
- Wow.
Gold, just like in the museum.
(growling)
- Look, cloth from the Civil War.
- The treasure must be here.
- [Jack] Let's keep digging.
- [Alex] Hold it.
- [Molly] It's Dr. Turner.
- Miss Rancette, come back for me.
(roarling) (yelling)
- That's Molly, come on.
- [Voiceover] Molly, come on!
- [Alex] Molly, he's guarding the treasure,
it's not worth it.
- Don't you see, courage is the only way.
I can do this.
Faith.
Truth.
Courage.
(growling)
(ominous music)
- [Molly] Help!
(roaring)
(spooky music)
- [Alex] Molly! Molly?
Molly. Molly.
- Here, in here.
Bear gone?
- [Alex] I hope so, my butt's sticking out.
(laughing)
Is that what I think it is?
- Yup, faith, truth, and,
help me drag it out.
- Okay, now for the piece of resistance.
- What?
- It's French for open the sucker.
- It's locked.
- Get a big rock, and hit it.
- Very scientific, Hal.
- One more, there.
(wondrous music)
- We'll take over from here, kids.
- Oh yeah? - [Simonton] Yeah.
That's for taking my wallet.
And now we'll be taking this,
and there's nothing you can do about it.
- [Jack] Finders keepers.
- Yes, but we're the keepers and you're the weepers.
Sadly, kids have no rights in this world, now do they?
- Yeah, you...
losers.
- [Alex] Where's Nurse Rancette?
- On the beach, a-scared of bears.
- We'll tell everyone what happened.
They'll believe us.
- No they won't.
Nobody believes this treasure ever existed.
- What about the paper mill?
It'll destroy the river.
- Survival of the fittest.
And I'll just take this and live quietly in,
say, Las Vegas.
- [Sheriff] Maybe Sing Sing.
- [Paul] Molly!
- Last time I checked, Louis,
stealing from anybody was against the law.
- [Jack] Got that right.
- You kids all right?
- Oh dear me, this is terrible.
I'm gonna be out of a home and a job, too.
- Now you know what it feels like, Nurse Ran--
Rancette.
- It's Ran--
I'm sorry, Alex.
Simonton!
How could you?
And Louis?
Stealing from children.
- Both of you better stay right where you're at.
- I can't believe you left, I've been so worried about you.
- Paul, you bring the kids and the nurse on down.
Let's go, you two.
- But I didn't do anything.
I have a Ph.D., I'll have you know.
- Fud, isn't that contagious?
- Not where he's going.
Come on.
- By my calculations, there's 3000 coins in there.
At $20 each,
that's $60,000.
- [Jillian] Won't the government take it back?
- I don't think so, river salvage laws.
Something lost in the river's fair game.
- I think we need to buy a foster home, too.
To keep the paper mill from destroying the river.
- Will we have enough?
- These coins are pure gold
and their historical value makes them worth
at least $500-1000 apiece, I'd say.
- That's three million dollars!
- Oh wow. - [Molly] Whoa.
- [Jack] We're all rich!
- So, can Alex stay with us?
- We'll see, honey, let's just get home.
- That sounds good enough.
- I'm getting too old for this.
All I ever wanted was to have my own restaurant.
I know a special way to cook tamales.
- [Alex] Maybe I could make you, Beatrice.
- Oh, please call me Bea--
Thanks, Alex.
- Wait.
Where's my medallion?
Guess I don't need it anymore.
Thanks, Cappy.
- [Jack] Do you think we could stop on the way home
and get a snack?
- [Jillian] Snack?
We could buy the whole 7-11.
- Thanks.
- You just gotta have a little--
Faith.
- Truth.
- Courage.
- Oh, and a little bit of luck.
(roaring)
(happy music)
♪ Well it took a lot of faith
♪ To get us here today
♪ Along the way I'm glad that I found you
♪ As we walk on down the road
♪ In our hearts we'll know
♪ That nothing is forever
♪ But we are here together
♪ 'Cause we still have faith
♪ To help each other through
♪ We still have faith
♪ It's all that we can do
♪ To lift each other up
♪ So when others drink the cup
♪ And still have faith
♪ Life can have its ups and downs
♪ A spinning wheel of chance
♪ But through it all
♪ We do it all
♪ With more than circumstance
♪ 'Cause we still have faith
♪ To help each other through
♪ We still have faith
♪ It's all that we can do
♪ To lift each other up
♪ So that others drink the cup
♪ And still have faith
♪ River equals you
♪ You equal life
♪ This bear protects treasure
♪ Inviting me
♪ Through faith we overcome
♪ Faith, truth, and courage
♪ At this journey's end
♪ We shall remain friends
♪ An experience such as this
♪ Finds us now
♪ Our friendship shall persist
♪ Through faith, truth, and courage
♪ Faith, truth, and courage
♪ An experience
♪ Such as this
♪ Certainly cannot miss
♪ An experience such as this
♪ Certainly begins with this
♪ Faith, truth, and courage
♪ River equals you
♪ You equal life
♪ This bear protects treasure
♪ Inviting me
♪ Through faith we overcome
♪ Faith, truth, and courage
♪ Don't you know the way
♪ That I feel about you baby
♪ Don't you understand