To my parents,
who left everything.
Attachment
Chapter 1. Julia
Mom, now that Dad sgoing to be here all day,
have you thought about doing something
Your Dad, here all day!
It could be fun.
You ve been wanting to remodel the back,
and Dad likes working with wood.
It could be a nice project.
Hurry up, honey.
Mom, we re talking here!
Whisky!
That one was good.
Let me see how it came out.
Let s take a look, wehave to approve first.
If I look bad I say no.
Allow me, boss.
Here it is.
See guys!
Excellent!
Pretty!
We can send it to the relatives in Chile.
Who is that?
I don t know.
Look closely,
your grandpa!
When he was younger.
He was doing a military training in Cuba.
So he was a soldier?
Something like that.
And were you a solider too?
No!
No, honey, I hate war,because the only thing it does
is separate families.
Could you help me write a letter?
Yes.
To who?
To my dad.
Bye!
You re gonna get it now!
The underwear is crazy!
Kids, we re leaving.
No!
What are you doing?
Nothing.
What a mess!
None.
Get going, they re waiting for you.
No, mom!
Get going.
They re waiting for you.
Don t run, help Cami please.
Claudia has me worried.
She seems really sad.
I m talking to you.
Yes, yes.
Hello?
Good morning, honey, how are you?
Your daughter openeda Facebook page for me
and I don t know what to do with it.
Well you re supposed to post pictures,
write something for people to read.
What for?
What people? There s no one here.
This is too darn complicated.
If you don t like itclose it and that s that.
How nice of you!
Is it that hard for youto help me understand it?
Go to the search bar.
What search bar?
The little magnifying glass at the top.
At the top of the page
Ok, got it, the little one.
Yes.
OK
You write the name of the personyou want to look for there,
press enter, and it shows up.
I m going to put yours.
No, Mom, not mine. Why?
We see each other every day, youre going to spy on me there too?
I don t know why I wastemy time with you Ana,
now I understand your husband.
Mom, hey!
Mom!
Hello?
OK, I m coming.
We ve just been hired todevelop a beach hotel in Mexico
in Los Cabos.
So you and Fernández, are eachgoing to present a project
and the one the client likes best goes.
This is a big deal that can helpus on an international level.
Of course.
I m counting on you and Iwant something extraordinary.
Nothing less,
OK
Understood?
High five!
Where should we send the plane?
Let s see
Oh God, that can t be.
Why do I look so old?
Why so close up!
How awful!
Let s try it without glasses,maybe it will come out better.
Don t be so cruel, find a good angle.
I took it with affection!
How about a smile?
Look at my cheeks, I look like Kiko.
This one is pretty.
Let me see... I like it
Yes, I like it! It s not that bad.
It s pretty!
This one?
Are you going to put it up now?
Yes.
Does it take a long time?
No, it s really fast,even Claudia can do it.
She showed me, she made the page.
She s so smart.
Kids these days, it s incredible.
They learn really fast.
Speaking of,
have you noticed that Claudia s been sad?
Sad, why?
I don t know.
She seems sad lately.
I think she should see her father more.
Enough already.
Your daughters need tobe with their dad more.
They need a dad.
What s the password?
What password?
For Facebook.
Concepción 68.
Ana, I m being serious,
they need a father figure.
Aren t you going to say anything?
No, Mom.
Only one!
Simon says throw Camila in the fountain.
Let s go!
To the fountain!
I found a bunch of childhood friends.
I ve been chatting with an oldcollege friend all week, Ernesto.
What does he do?
Pass me the bread.
He owns hotels in La Serena.
In La Serena? Hotels?
He must be one of your snobfriends, probably pro-Pinochet.
Adri and me want to go toChile, we want to take the kids.
Yes. Yesterday we were watchinga report about Torres del Paine
You know what the problem isthings aren t like they used to be,
Chile is full of snobsnow, living the high life.
All that sacrifice for nothing.
Right, all that sacrifice for nothing.
What do you mean for nothing?
What s wrong with living well.
There s nothing wrong with living well.
What s wrong is living well atthe expense of everyone else.
All your friends got rich atthe expense of everyone else.
And in those cases, youbring the housekeeper
to live here and pay her better.
So how is your friend?
Ernesto is very well.
He invited me to go there for a few days.
That s a good idea, we were talking about
going together, all of us.
We can take our vacation days,
take the kids and all go together.
Claudia is dying to go.
Fabio has never been on aplane, it would be so nice.
I m going alone
The Atacama Desert is the best.
I m going alone!
What do you mean, alone?
You ve always said you dont like to travel alone.
Now I do.
Isn t it a little weird to go alone
to see a guy you don t even know?
The Opus Dei has spoken.
What s that supposed to mean?
She wants to go alone.
But we re family, we canmake the decision together.
It s not our decision, it s hers.
I think it s somethingthat affects us all.
We have to make a plan together.
This one looks great on you.
You like it?
It s not too wide?
It looks great.
It doesn t make my hips look big?
Look at your face, youlook fresh, younger.
That s so sweet, honey.
I m going to get it.
Yes, get it.
So, they offered to send me toMexico to develop a project.
It s a competition, it s not for sure yet.
Are you listening to me?
Yes.
And what would you do with the girls?
You re going to take themaway from their family,
take them out of schoolin the middle of the year,
with all of the support they have?
I don t know, mom.
I haven t thought about that yet.
I gave up everything foryou guys and your father.
Everything.
You came here because you wanted to,
nobody forced you to.
Is that really what you think?
That I wanted to leave my country,
my family, my friends,
my job,
my life?
Is that really what you think, Ana?
I brought you some more in your size.
Thank you.
You re welcome.
I ll take them to the dressing room.
What this shows is knowledge,a way of doing things,
the skills of our trade.
I understand, César.
I understand your proposal completely.
What I m worried about isthe economic side of it,
because our image is at stake
Dad: Your mom has a lover
and I don t want it toend up being too simple.
Ana, are you OK?
Well that won t be the case, less is more.
And your investment is going tobe reflected in these decisions.
Dad, are you crazy?
That s impossible.
We ll talk later, I m inthe middle of a meeting.
OK.
Bye.
In this previous project,
with the same base of these littleislands, autonomous elements,
we re going to create a seriesof communications that are
more fluid for the user andthat gives us the framework
for this current project.
César, I m clear on theidea, but we re going to
need a more down-to-earth advance.
Of course.
My two collaborators havebeen working out ideas
and they will share thosepreliminary results with us.
Ana?
Yes, one second,
I just have to find the document.
While Ana is getting ready
I wanted to tell you about my proposal
which is based on the rawmaterials we re going to use,
which are of the highest quality.
It is cold. But just thinkingabout you I get warm.
When I have your sweet penis
Are you OK?
No, I don t feel so well.
You look pale.
Very pale
My blood pressure is just low.
Want something?
No, don t worry.
It ll pass soon.
Are you sure?
Don t worry, it happens sometimes.
One, two, three, four, and five.
Very good, we re going toopen our legs, flex that knee,
not forcing it.
And back.
Now the other one.
Auch!!!
Alicia help her please, slowly.
Come here!
Be careful
it s just a cramp.
He s not that ugly.
He s awful!
He has the face of a pervert,
but these things happen,it s not his fault.
Gross!
It s not that bad
Besides, it s not exactlylike you ve dated models.
No, he looks awful.
This seriously doesn t bother you?
This is the guy Mom isgoing to go away with.
That s one thing, but Dad hasnt exactly been the best guy,
it s not like we can hold it against Mom.
What s wrong is...
Why would Dad send me this?
He s not going to send it to me,
I don t want to see that picture.
He can barely remember my birthday.
Poor thing, no one remembers thebaby of the family s birthday.
Have you ever thoughtwhat it would be like
if we d been born there, in Chile?
Our grandparents...
a mom... I don t know...
We d be the same, butit would have been nice
to have more family, it s just us here.
Have cousins, not only us.
Mom would be less hysterical.
Mom isn t hysterical, she s complicated.
Chapter 2. Ana.
Hi
I m close by and I thought wecould get some coffee or something.
I can t, I m still at the office.
Can I call you in a bit?
I m in a meeting.
Hi, honey.
- How are you? - Good.
Mommy, look, we have a dog.
His name is Chocolito.
Chocolito!
He wants to go in the bedroom.
Are you crazy?
You bought them a dog?
Hi, Anita.
That dog is going to stay here?
We talked about this last year.
Last year, not now.
We agreed that the girls needto learn about responsibility.
Besides, when was the lasttime you saw them this happy?
Does he have his vaccines?
Yeah, he has one left butI can take him next week.
And the food?
Cami has a little food in her backpack,
and I can help you out with some more,
it s cheap.
He s really cute.
You should have told me.
I m sorry.
I need you to pay the girls tuition,
they ve been calling me all the time.
For two weeks straight now.
I can deposit some moneyin your account tomorrow,
the rest I ll have to pay you back causeI don t get paid until the other week.
That s not an option,
they ve been expecting thepayment for too long now.
Call the school yourself,explain your situation
and that way they don t thinkthat I don t want to pay.
Call who?
I don t know, the principal, thebilling department, call, ask.
OK.
Girls, I m leaving.
Bye, Daddy.
I love you.
Bye cutie!
Bye, Chocolito.
Bye, Anita.
Thanks!
Anita!
What?
Do you remember the deal with the firm?
The meeting is Saturday.
No, no way!
This is too much!
We talked about me havingSaturday for forever.
I need to work.
It s a one-time thing.
I just need to trade you for Wednesday,
I ll take the girls Wednesday and Thursday
and you take them Saturday.
I can t! I have too much work that day.
I can t say no.
So you ll take them on Wednesday.
Until Thursday.
Ok, fine, get out of here.
Thank you.
Bye.
That looks fun, honey.Where did you get those?
Aunt Nicole gave them to me
Who?
Aunt Nicole, Daddy s girlfriend.
That s pretty for playing dress up, right?
But not for wearing in real life.
I m going to be a model.
You could also be an artist,
a singer,
an astronaut...
I m going to be theprettiest model in the world.
One, two, three!
Hi!
Hi Mom!
How are you, doña Ana?
Fine.
I m so sorry, I m soembarrassed, traffic was awful.
Don t worry.
I wanted to talk to you about something.
Do you have a few minutes?
Yes.
Girls stay here a minute,we ll be right back,
don t move.
Let s seat there.
Is something wrong?
Nothing serious, really.
This morning Claudia bit a classmate,
that s never happened before
and I ve noticed she sbeen really rebellious,
she s been different lately.
She is changing.
Claudia s dad and I separated recently.
And it s been hard to schedule the visits
and Claudia is really close with him.
It could be that it s affecting her.
Maybe without realizingit you re transmitting
a little bit of anxiety to her.
Maybe, I hadn t thought of it that way.
Just saying...
In any case, don t worry,here at school we have
a really good psychologist.
If you want I can scheduleher an appointment.
What s going to happen tothese little guys today?
I want you to read us Sleeping Beauty.
No, that s so boring.
No. The story of Chocolito.
OK. Once upon a time
there was a dog named Chocolito
and he liked to go to the park.
I wanna go to the park!
And then Chocolito realizedthat they closed the park.
But Chocolito wasn t alone...
Hello?
Daniel!
But you promised, you re kidding me.
Claudia is going to a psychologist
and you think that s normal.
Moron.
What s wrong Mom?
Nothing, honey.
I have to take you to Grandma s,
do you want to go?
Let s go.
Ducks in the water!
Mommy,
Yes?
Why hasn t Dad come to see us?
Why doesn t Dad love us?
Of course he loves you, hes just been really busy,
so he hasn t had timeto come see you guys,
but he will soon,
you can go out and do something.
It s your fault because youre always bothering him.
It s not my fault, I don t bother him.
The only thing I ask of himis that he does the things
that he s supposed to.
It s very convenient that I m the only one
who worries about you guys.
He worries about us, he gave us Chocolito,
and you re always asking for more money
and a lot more money.
Claudia, you re dad doesn t have the money
because he spends it on his girlfriend.
Hello!
Hi honey!
Hi.
What happened?
Why do you have that look on your face?
Girls, please, unbuckle your seatbelts.
I don t know why you insiston working at a company
that doesn t appreciate you.
It s not that they don tvalue me, that s how it is,
you have to go to work sothat they pay you more.
Why don t you change jobs?
Your brother can get you one.
Have you thought about gettingback together with Daniel,
he s such an honorable guy, so loving.
Mom, enough, I don t havetime for this right now.
Where are my beautiful girls?
Give your grandma a hug.
Where s my baby?
Come here baby,
come to grandma.
Go on in, I want to talk to your mother.
You re okay with it because I m the one
who takes care of the girls,
but I m not trying to rub it in your face,
it just worries me thatyou re at a job where
you can t even pay for a nanny.
It s not that I don t makeenough, it s that Daniel
doesn t help me at all.
I had to pay two monthsof the girls school,
he doesn t give memoney, it s not my fault.
Chocolito!
Who s Chocolito?
You mean you re goingto leave that dog here?
Mom, I can t take him to work.
And your dad s allergies?No, absolutely not.
Chocolito, come here!
Go get him.
So, who wants dessert, wehave pancakes with honey,
pancakes with dulce de leche,we can make a cheese tart,
the one I made last time.Or... what do you want?
Come say hi to your grandpa princesses
Hi Pop Pop!
Here s a little present foryou, and for you, and this one
is for you to share.
Thank you!
I m gonna get you! Here I come!
Hi!
Hi Dad.
Aren t you going to do something?
You re just going to letMom go away with a stranger?
He s not a stranger to your mother.
Look, at this stage in the game
it s very hard to fall in love again,
even for you, it s not easy.
I can t take the dog to themeeting, absolutely not.
Me neither, they won t let metake the dog to my work either.
My job is important too.
This is an office.
And you know what else,you bought that dog,
it should be your responsibility.
Just like going to see thegirls every once in a while.
I m dying to spend moretime with my girls,
but as long as this deallasts, I have less time
they know that.
I could care less, becausewhen you are with them
it s a problem too, you letthem do whatever they want
and then when I set anyrules they think I m crazy.
That s not true.
Give this back to your girlfriend
What s this?
And I don t want her buying anymore sexist toys for Claudia.
Claudia asked for that.
It doesn t matter, doesn tyour girlfriend have a brain
to say no?
She should, she s a political scientist
I m sorry.
You re an idiot,
I m nervous!
You don t even deserve Chocolito.
Anita, I m sorry.
You have a lot of talent,
I was sure that you were goingto really dive into this,
that you were going to make it your own,
and I don t see a lot.
I ve just been really busyand I m a little stuck
on the whole parking lot thing.
I promise that next week I mgoing to show you something
that you ll like a lot, Ijust need a little more time.
OK, but there isn t a lot oftime and I m counting on you.
Yes, thank you.
It s really dangerous, Mom.
I m really worried, you havent seen this guy in forever,
he could be a psychopath or something.
Honey, why don t you get offthat little high horse of yours?
What did we come here for?
To celebrate! So, glasses up!
Let s wait for Dad.
Cheers!
Oh, my love!
Gorgeous.
Oh, my love.
What s wrong with this guy?
Sir?
Sir! No!
Oh, no, what are you doing?
What s happening?
Clau
What s up, you can t sleep?
No.
Do you miss Daddy?
Sometimes.
I always do.
Is that why you bit your classmate?
No. He was bothering me.
Honey, sometimes people dothings that you don t understand,
but that doesn t meanyou have to hurt them.
Give me that, let me help you.
Thank you.
Hi, honey, how are you?
Let s play by the tree, come on.
How are you, Anita?
Good, Rita, and you?
Good. Thanks, honey.
Rita, can you watch Chocolito, please?
They re going to fire me ifI take him to work again.
Don t worry, I ll see what I can do.
Your dad is in bed sohe won t even notice.
Is he OK?
I don t know, he doesn t feel well,
he s been locked up inhis room since yesterday
And Mom?
In the garden.
Watch my car for a sec,I m going to say hi.
Yes, go ahead.
Girls!
Hi, honey.
Hi,
is Dad sick?
He has a UTI.
But you know how he is, he exaggerates.
Don t you think maybeyou can delay your trip?
Why would I do that? My God!
Your father is a hypochondriac.
If you re so worried takecare of him yourself.
Hi, Grammy.
Hello, my granddaughters,
let s do Tai Chi,
feet together,
one leg here,
lower and raise the energy,
lower the energy,
put your foot there,
do the urn,
comb the hair.
I remember when we werepacking to come here.
Me too.
I ve never been more scared in my life.
I thought they were goingto detain us in the airport,
that Marito was goingto be born on the plane.
I would have liked
for things to have been different.
Isn t a lot of stufffor such a short trip?
OK, alright already.
Write me when you got there.
Yes, honey, I ll write you, don t worry.
Let me know when you re comingback and I ll pick you up.
Well, I don t know yet.
What do you mean?
I ll let you know.
I don t want to miss myflight. Kisses to the kids,
I love you a lot, I love you.
When did you buy the ticket for?
Where is Grandma, whyhaven t we gone to see her?
She s in another countryseeing her boyfriend.
Isn t Grandpa her boyfriend?
No, silly, he s her husband.
Mommy it itches!
What s going on?
Mommy, come, it itches.
Claudia!
Why would you do that to your sister?
Can t you see she s sick?
But she looks like a Pegasus.
A mess is what this is.
Go get a bowl to clean this up.
But Mommy she looks pretty.
Claudia go! I m not messing around.
Hurry.
Honey,
What did you sister do!
Clau, open the door.
I m going.
- Hi - Hi, Clau.
What happened?
I m in trouble with my mom.
Why?
Because I made Cami a costume.
What do you mean?
A Pegasus costume.
Where is your mom?
In the bathroom.
Let s go.
I don t understand it, but I like it.
Thank you.
Don t encourage her, sheshouldn t have done it.
I think I should just stayhome, this is a disaster.
I ll stay with the girls, I ll fix it.
I don t feel I even want to go.
Go for a little bit, ifyou don t like it come back
and I have wine.
And that s it.
He probably got married anddoesn t feel like coming.
Hi.
Ay, how are you?
Anita!
How are you?
It s been forever! I m so glad you came.
It s so great to see you guys!
How have you been?
Great.
Super.
That s great, I m happy to hear that.
You didn t bring thatgood-looking husband of yours?
He s not my husband anymore.
Aw, I thought so, theother day I saw him...
Hello.
Ana, right?
Yes.
And you re...
Federico.
I m sorry, I m the worst,I have a super bad memory.
It s fine.
Bored?
Well, yes, actually, I am.
I don t know why I even came.
Morbid curiosity, same as me.
Probably.
That chick back there, you know?
Yeah, you know.
You re awful!
And I m not totally sure,
but I think maybe her over there,
although they look pretty natural.
But with that dress...
It s hard to tell.
How many have had a gastric bypass?
Me.
No, I m serious.
I m serious too.
No.
Because of my thyroid.
I m sorry, I m the worst.
I m sorry.
Don t worry.
It wasn t my intention, really.
Relax, it s fine.
But there s nothing wrongwith getting a gastric bypass.
Of course not.
You know you re the lastperson I d have imagined here.
Why?
You were one of the popular girls.
I was not popular, not even close.
At least one of the pretty ones.
What a clown!
I m serious.
I was crazy over you in high school.
I really liked you a lot.
A lot.
Chapter 3. Andrés.
Today we re going to talk abouta series of political movements,
from the wars of independenceup to the present,
that have influenced the realityof Latin America in some way.
Hello?
Yes, I have it turned off.
What happened?
What?!
No. I m coming.
Yes, I ll be there in 20 minutes.
OK. Bye.
Thank you.
I talked to the doctors.
He s fine, he has an infection,
he didn t take care of itproperly, it caused complications.
They still have to do some exams.
They re recommending he doesn t stay alone
because he s depressed,
we have to figure outwhat we re going to do.
And with Mom on vacation.
What are we going to do?
We were thinking and maybewe could pay someone.
Like split the cost of a carer.
Well, we could pay for her, andhe could stay at your house.
But my house is so smalland now I have a dog, too,
how would I do it?
No, I can t.
In Diego s apartment it s impossible
and in my house he won t be happy...
There s a spare room inyour house, it s bigger.
We were thinking aboutthe emotional aspects,
that he feel encouraged.
He s not going to feelbetter in a tiny little room
than in your house in a bigger room.
You re his favorite,he s always said that.
He can t stay at my house.
Excuse me.
Hello, yes?
Doña Ana, I m sorry,
can I speak with you?
Of course,
what s up?
It s about your Dad.
Did he say something to you?
Treat you badly?
No, that s not it.
But he does bad things.
Like what?
It doesn t matter.
But I think I can t work here anymore.
Esmeralda, why?
Anita, my tea!
Ay, Dad, I m coming!
Look, let s talk later, OK?
Yes, OK.
He was already annoying, and now this.
Yeah and now that Momabandoned him, worse.
Mom didn t abandon him,Mom went on vacation.
But since he s used to everyonedoing everything for him.
Well I m sick of that, tiredof wondering what s wrong,
or if he s OK. I shouldn t care anymore.
If he s already being such apain it s because he s better.
Dad!
What s up, honey?
Why are you walking around like that?
I feel more comfortable.
Yes, Dad, but not here.
Now I understand poor Esmeralda.
I thought she had left.
That s why there are gardensfor the kids to play in.
They can play tennis, goswimming, go riding, and they can
even go to the stadium.
And I can go there?
Of course you can go.
Now it s time...
What are you doing here? Whydidn t you get on the school bus?
Grandpa said so.
It s just kindergarten,it s not a big deal.
No, Dad. Now I have to take her to school.
And I m late. Come on Cami, get out here,
go find your shoes.
We ll finish it later.
It was too much Dad.
Hi, Mom, since you leftDad is doing poorly
and everything is chaos.
Hi, Mom, I m happy you re having fun
but Dad isn t doing well alone.
Maybe it s better if you come back
soon.
Kisses.
Mommy
Mommy!
What s wrong?
Where s Pop Pop?
What?
Pop Pop.
Your grandpa went home.
But why?
Because he felt betternow, and he has a home.
First you kicked Dad out, now Grandpa
and next you re going to kick us out.
Why did you kick me out?
I haven t kicked anyone out andI m not going to kick you out.
You re bad, bad bad bad.
Yeah, bad, bad bad bad.
Come on, Cami
and forgot the content of the environment.
Why not be contemporary
from the tropics with local answers.
I m going to show you seriesof floor plans and elevations.
I like that.
For example, in thisimage from the master plan
we can see the whole design andits relationship to the land.
We re definitely getting much closer.
Hi, Rita, how are you?
Anita how s it going?
Fine.
I brought some bread.
That sounds delicious!
How s Dad?
I thought he was with you.
What?
Dad hasn t been with me for like a week.
I don t know, Anita.
I took some days off,doña Julia said I could.
That s weird.
Didn t he leave a note or anything?
I haven t seen anything, but I can check.
That s strange.
Excuse me, miss, I wantedto check if an older man,
a Mr. Aravena, was checked in.
He was here a few days ago, with a UTI.
One moment, let me check.
You said Aravena?
Yes, Andrés Aravena Fernández.
What relation are you to the gentleman?
I m his daughter.
Mr. Aravena came in foran oncology appointment,
but that was a few days ago now.
Oncology?
Yes
Hello, good afternoon, I mtrying to reach dean Gomez.
I m sorry. Thank you.
Hello?
Hello, don César, how are you?
Really?
That s good news.
Of course, I understand.
Yes, I just need a few daysto take care of some things.
No, just a few days.
A week
OK.
No, thank you.
Thank you.
What do we know?
There s no one with that name,there are three unidentified bodies
and one came in yesterday,
but it doesn t seem like it.
It ll be better to make sure.
Yeah, we ll just ask andit ll make us feel better.
He s only been gone like aweek, he s drinking somewhere
or something.
Dad is not doing so well.
The doctor said he shouldbe in chemotherapy.
This is the one who is over 70.
Are you ready?
Thank you.
You have keys to the house?
Yes.
Is it open?
What s with the cop?
Weird.
Your love is escaping me
Like water through my fingers
And I can t avoid it
Though I'm dying of sadness
I was the owner of your heart
This pain is my fault
Don t take your love away
I can see my mistake
Hi, girls, how are you?
Good?
It s so nice to see you here!
To what do we owe the honor?
I came to leave them herebecause something came up and
I need you guys to watch them.
But, did you talk to Daniel?
We re about to leave for the beach.
Girls, do you want to go to the beach?
Yes!
Can we bring Chocolito?
Of course.
We d better call your Dad.
Don t worry. I ll call him later.
We d better call him.
Thank you!
Girls, hugs for your mom.
Bye, Mommy.
We would like to offer you
a warm welcome aboard to ourflight 610 to Mexico City.
Capitan Serrá assistedby first officer Alvarez
Attachment