(CRACK!)
WOW.
AT LEAST WE KNOW THEY HAVE
TECHNOLOGY
IN THIS WORLD. LET'S SEE IF WE
CAN BUY SOME REPLACEMENT
MIRRORS.
WHAT IF SOMEONE FINDS THE BOAT?
NO ONE CAN USE IT NOW.
DO WE HAVE TO FIND MIRRORS?
WON'T SOMETHING ELSE DO? THE
MIRRORS THAT ELVO SMASHED ALIGN
THE SYSTEMS
THAT GUIDE THE BOAT. IF WE
CAN'T REPLACE THEM, WE'LL HAVE
NO CONTROL OVER OUR DESTINATION
AND WE'LL NEVER GET HOME?
WE'LL GET HOME.
(CLATTER)
IS THIS ANY USE?
NO. BUT IT'S A GOOD SIGN. THEY
HAVE GLASS HERE.
THEY PROBABLY HAVE MIRRORS TOO.
MEK! OVER HERE!
WHAT IS IT? I DON'T KNOW.
SOME KIND OF VEHICLE?
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN FIND A WAY
IN.
HERE!
(CREAK)
IT'S RUSTED.
SHH. PRINCESS AYA,
I'VE HAD YOUR ADVISOR DRAW UP A
PROCLAMATION.
IT PROCLAIMS ME THE NEW DRAGON
LORD.
SIGN IT. ONLY MEMBERS OF MY
FAMILY
CAN BECOME DRAGON LORDS. THEN
YOU WILL HAVE TO MAKE ME
A MEMBER OF YOUR FAMILY.
YOU'RE MAD.
THAT'S NO WAY TO TALK TO YOUR
FUTURE HUSBAND.
WE WILL HAVE A ROYAL WEDDING.
EVERYONE LOVES A WEDDING.
I WILL NEVER MARRY YOU.
REMEMBER THAT YOUR BROTHER
IS MY PRISONER. I WILL GIVE YOU
SOME TIME
TO CHANGE YOUR MIND. TAKE HER
AWAY.
(INDISTINCT) THE PEOPLE WILL
HAVE
TO ACCEPT HIM AS THE DRAGON
LORD.
CONSULT THE DIVINER AND DECIDE
THE BEST TIME FOR MY WEDDING.
AND CLEAN THE PALACE OF
SPIRITS. THERE ARE EVIL FORCES
PRESENT.
I CAN FEEL THEM WATCHING.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE WE CAN FIND
ANY FRIENDLY GHOSTS?
ANCESTORS, TELL ME HOW TO STOP
SHARAK FROM MARRYING MY SISTER.
SUN, I DON'T THINK THEY CAN
HEAR YOU. (CLASH OF SWORD BLADE)
THEN I'LL DO IT ON MY OWN!
SUN, NO!
SUN!
SUN! DON'T BE AN IDIOT!
YOU CAN'T SAVE AYA THIS WAY.
WHO'S THERE?
(DOOR SHUTS)
WHAT WERE YOU GONNA DO, HUH?
TAKE ON THE WHOLE OF
SHARAK'S ARMY? I HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING. (THINGS CRASH TO
FLOOR) SUN!
THEY'RE FIREWORKS! WHAT, ARE
YOU TRYING
TO BLOW US UP?
NOW THERE'S AN IDEA.
(CREAKING, CLANKING)
(CLANK)
(CLANG)
IT'S LIKE A BOMB'S GONE OFF.
BOMB? AN EXPLOSION.
SOMETHING THAT BLOWS UP
EVERYTHING. I CAN'T SEE ANY
MIRRORS.
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLE) IT'S
STILL GOT POWER!
HOW DID YOU DO THAT? IN YOUR
WORLD, YOU GET YOUR ENERGY FROM
LIGHT.
IN MINE, AND THIS ONE, WE USE
ELECTRICITY. IT TRAVELS THROUGH
WIRES
LIKE THESE. IT'S FASCINATING.
LET ME SEE. MEK, DON'T --
(CRACK)
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU GOT AN ELECTRIC SHOCK. IT
BURNT ME. ELECTRICITY CREATES
HEAT.
THAT'S HOW WE HEAT OUR HOMES
AND BOIL OUR WATER.
WOULD A MACHINE THIS BIG
CREATE A LOT OF ELECTRICITY?
I GUESS SO. WHY?
IF I CAN REPAIR IT, I MIGHT BE
ABLE
TO GENERATE ENOUGH HEAT TO FUSE
THE BROKEN MIRRORS IN THE BOAT.
THE JOINTS WON'T BE PERFECT BUT
IT MIGHT GET US BACK TO THE
LAND OF THE DRAGON LORD.
♪ (STRINGED ASIAN MUSIC)
♪
SHARAK!!
YOUR IDIOT MEN LET SUN ESCAPE!
WELL, GO AND FIND HIM. DON'T
GIVE ME ORDERS. GET BACK!
GO ON, BACK! MY ANCESTORS WILL
BURN YOU ALL UP!
SPELLBINDER! USE YOUR MAGIC
SUIT! IF I DO, HE'LL EXPLODE
AND KILL US ALL. THROW THE
WATER OVER HIM.
PUT DOWN THE TORCH, SUN. YOUR
PLAN HAS FAILED!
THEN I'LL GO AND JOIN MY
ANCESTORS! THROW THE WATER!
(BOOM!)
AFTER YOU.
(COUGHING)
I'LL LET YOU TELL HIS SISTER.
(CLUNK)
(BOOM!)
SHARAK.
SHARAK. (ECHOING) WHO ARE YOU?
I AM THE GHOST OF SUN. I WILL
NOT GIVE YOU
A MOMENT'S REST UNTIL YOU LEAVE
MY LAND.
(THINGS RATTLING TO FLOOR) NO!
DIVINER! DIVINER!
AYA'S GOING TO BE HORRIFIED
WHEN SHE HEARS THAT I'M DEAD.
MEK, YOU'RE BRILLIANT. NOW,
HOW DO WE CONVERT
THIS ENERGY INTO HEAT? FIRST
WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO
START THIS THING.
IF THIS IS LIKE THE VEHICLES IN
MY WORLD, THE ENGINE HAS
TO BE RUNNING TO GENERATE A LOT
OF POWER.
THERE'S NO IGNITION KEY AND NO
STEERING WHEEL OR DRIVER'S SEAT.
WHAT IS THIS THING?
MEK, IT COULD TAKE AGES TO GET
THIS THING GOING.
WE HAVEN'T EATEN SINCE
YESTERDAY. WHY DON'T I GO OUT
AND LOOK FOR SOME FOOD? NO!
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT'S OUT THERE.
I WON'T GO FAR.
I'M STARVING. ALL RIGHT.
BUT DON'T BE LONG. AND DON'T GO
FAR.
AND BE CAREFUL. YES, DAD.
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(SOUND OF FLOWING WATER)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
JEZ!
JEZ! IT'S ALL RIGHT. I'M JUST
TAKING
A COUPLE OF APPLES. I'M OUT OF
HERE. OKAY?
OH! MEL, GO AND TELL ELIN.
WAIT!
I'M HUNGRY. I JUST WANTED SOME
APPLES. ELIN ALWAYS SAID THERE
WERE OTHER PEOPLE.
HAVE YOU COME FROM ACROSS THE
SEA? UM -- YES.
IN A BOAT. WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
KATHY.
MY NAME IS JEZ. ELIN WILL WANT
TO MEET YOU. COME ON!
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF OUR
VILLAGE? IT'S VERY NICE.
OUR LAST TWO CROPS HAVE BEEN
SUCCESSFUL,
AND OUR CATTLE ARE THRIVING IN
THE PASTURES.
ACROSS THE RIVER. I'LL SHOW YOU
THEM LATER. GREAT.
I LOVE COWS.
ELIN, THIS IS KATHY. SHE'S
COME FROM ACROSS THE SEA
IN A BOAT. I KNEW THAT ONE DAY
SOMEONE WOULD COME.
WELCOME, KATHY.
ARE YOU ALONE? I HAVE A FRIEND.
HE'S NOT FAR AWAY. YOU MUST GO
AND GET HIM. CAN I TAKE HIM
SOME FOOD?
WE'RE BOTH STARVING. OF
COURSE. I WILL PREPARE YOU A
BASKET.
WHILE YOU ARE WAITING, YOU CAN
EAT AND TELL US ABOUT WHERE YOU
COME FROM.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO CLEAN UP?
I'LL SHOW YOU THE WELL.
OH -- DO YOU HAVE A MIRROR I
COULD USE?
A MIRROR? WE USED TO CALL IT A
LOOKING GLASS. NO, KATHY,
I'M AFRAID WE HAVE NO MIRRORS
HERE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT YOUR
APPEARANCE. YOU ARE THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL THING
I HAVE SEEN SINCE WE EMERGED.
SHARAK NEEDS
A VOLUNTEER TO CLEAN THE TOILET.
JOSH. GEE, THE CAR NEEDS A
BIT OF A VACUUM, DAD.
YOU'RE RIGHT. YEAH.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO MOM. SHE'S UP THERE.
HOW'S SHE HOLDING UP?
I'VE GOT TO GET A MESSAGE TO
AYA.
SHARAK'S PLANNING TO MARRY HER.
SO HE CAN LEGITIMIZE HIS RULE.
WE'VE GOT A PLAN TO STOP HIM.
WE THINK.
DON'T GIVE UP HOPE, AYA.
KATHY AND MEK CAN STILL GET
BACK WITH THE INTERFACE IN TIME.
OKAY JOSH, SHE'S SEEN IT.
IT'S A MESSAGE FROM SUN. HE'S
SAFE,
BUT SHARAK THINKS HE'S DEAD.
YOU MUST PLAY ALONG WITH
WHATEVER HAPPENS.
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING FOR?
HAUNTING EQUIPMENT.
MAYBE I CAN USE THIS TO GET
YOUR CHAIN OFF.
SHARAK'S COMING. GET OUT.
KATHY --
THESE ARE FOR YOUR FRIEND.
THANK YOU, JEZ.
HOW LONG WERE YOU UNDERGROUND?
WE CAME UP NEARLY FOUR YEARS
AGO.
YOU LIVED UNDERGROUND? I WAS
BORN THERE.
BUT I'M NEVER GOING BACK. ARE
YOU THE ONLY PEOPLE AROUND HERE?
UNTIL YOU ARRIVED, WE THOUGHT
WE WERE THE ONLY SURVIVORS IN
THE WHOLE WORLD.
SURVIVORS OF WHAT? ELIN, ELIN.
WE FOUND ANOTHER ONE. EXCUSE
ME, KATHY.
WHAT HAVE THEY FOUND? COME
AND SEE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK IT WAS?
IT LOOKS LIKE SOME KIND OF
MOTOR.
LIKE A CAR ENGINE. YOU KNOW
ABOUT MACHINES? TAKE IT TO THE
GRAVEYARD.
CHILDREN, THIS WAY. COME ON,
COME ON.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY AND REPAIR
IT?
NO. THE MACHINES MUST BE
DESTROYED. ALL OF THEM?
DON'T YOU PEOPLE DO THE SAME?
UH - -OF COURSE.
WHERE EXACTLY DO YOU COME FROM?
LOOK, I'D BETTER GO AND FIND
MY FRIEND MEK. HE CAN EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING TO YOU. GOOD. I
WILL PREPARE A BED FOR YOU. YOU
MUST BOTH
STAY WITH US. WE WILL HAVE A
GATHERING
TONIGHT TO CELEBRATE YOUR
ARRIVAL. GREAT.
WE'LL SEE YOU THEN. BYE. KATHY!
YOU FORGOT THIS. CAN I CARRY IT
FOR YOU?
WHAT ARE THEY GOING TO DO WITH
THAT MACHINE WHEN
THEY GET IT TO THE GRAVEYARD?
THIS IS THE GRAVEYARD.
DON'T YOU HAVE ONE WHERE YOU
COME FROM?
JEZ!
(CLANKING)
WHY DO YOU TRASH ALL THIS
STUFF? YOU COULD USE IT. IT
WOULD BE WRONG
TO USE MACHINES. WHY? BECAUSE
OF THE WAR, OF COURSE.
WAR? JEZ! I FOUND A NEW TYPE
OF MACHINE.
COME AND SEE! YOU GO. I'LL
FIND MEK AND MEET YOU BACK HERE.
MEK -- MEK!
I FOUND A VILLAGE. THE PEOPLE
ARE FRIENDLY. THEY GAVE ME
FOOD. DO THEY HAVE ANY MIRRORS?
NO. NEVER MIND. COME AND SEE
WHAT I'VE DONE.
THIS PLACE IS WEIRD, MEK.
THE PEOPLE HAVE BEEN LIVING
UNDERGROUND
FOR YEARS. AND THEY'RE
FRIGHTENED OF MACHINES.
WATCH THIS.
(LOUD RUMBLING SOUND)
IT'S A COMPUTER! A COMPUTER?
IT'S A BIT LIKE THE ORACLE.
IT STORES INFORMATION. MAYBE
IT CAN TELL US HOW TO START THE
MOTOR.
THERE'S NO KEYBOARD. KATHY,
HAND ME THAT TOOL.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD SHOW THIS
MACHINE TO ELIN. WHY?
SHE TOLD US TO DESTROY THEM
ALL. THAT SOUNDED LIKE JEZ.
MEK, LOOK!
I'VE SEEN THIS IN MOVIES. IT'S
USING SENSORS TO DETECT THE
KIDS OUTSIDE.
IT'S PICKING UP THE HEAT OF
THEIR BODIES. COME AND LOOK!
SEE? IT'S THE KIDS FROM THE
VILLAGE.
COME AND MEET THEM. I'LL JOIN
YOU SOON.
I JUST WANT TO FINISH THIS WORK.
(DRILLING SOUND)
(BEEPING)
JEZ, STOP! THAT'S OUR BOAT!
IT'S A MACHINE. ELIN SAYS THAT
ALL MACHINES MUST BE DESTROYED.
BUT IF YOU WRECK IT, WE CAN'T
GET HOME.
SORRY. WE THOUGHT IT CAME FROM
THE MOLLOCHS. MOLLOCHS?
WHAT'S A MOLLOCH? THAT THING.
THEY TURNED ON US IN THE WAR
AND TRIED
TO KILL ALL THE HUMANS. WHY
DON'T YOU KNOW THAT?
NO! KATHY,
I'VE FINISHED. MEK, WE'VE GOT
TO GET BACK INSIDE AND PULL OUT
THE WIRING. WHAT?
(LOUD MACHINE SOUNDS)
RUN, KATHY!
GET AWAY FROM THERE!
MEK, WE'VE GOT TO SHUT IT DOWN!
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT'S
HAPPENED.
(BOOM!)
JEZ, LOOK OUT!
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS. WE HAVE TO
GET BACK TO
THE BOAT AND GET OUT OF HERE.
THE CRYSTAL.
I LEFT IT INSIDE THE MACHINE.
WE CAN'T LEAVE WITHOUT IT.
MEK, GET DOWN! (BOOM!)
MEK!!