(eerie music)
- Hello.
- Is it on? - Yeah.
- Mr. Future Farmer of America.
- Yes. - And I'll be the future
Owning My Own Travel Agency of America.
- Yes.
- And we're going to travel everywhere
in America and outside of America.
- How many children-- (static buzzing)
- But we'll wait a while before we have children.
- Okay.
- So that we can travel and see things.
- Okay, oh good idea. - That's what we'll do.
- Yeah-- (static buzzing)
(groaning)
It's exciting.
(static buzzing)
(eerie music)
Look at the big guy.
(static buzzing)
(eerie music)
(insect buzzing)
(static buzzing)
(insects buzzing)
Hey Beth, keep him in the shade.
(static buzzing) (eerie music)
He's probably getting tired.
Maybe we should go in.
Hmm?
Let's go inside.
Go ahead and turn it off.
- [Beth] I think he should have a blanket.
- Let's just get him in, my knees are killing me.
(machinery squeaking)
(crickets chirping)
(cows mooing)
(unnerving music)
(baby crying) (dramatic eerie music)
Okay, it's okay.
Shh.
Come here Michael.
(groaning)
Oh there you go.
How you doing?
You okay?
(unnerving music)
(dog barking)
(door squeaking open)
(howling)
(eerie music)
(gun cocking)
(gun firing)
God damn coyotes.
(dramatic eerie music)
- Good morning. - Good morning.
How many times you gonna read that?
- It's only my third time.
I poured you some orange juice.
- Can't see how it could be any better after the first.
What's it about again? - Dreams.
- That's too much pulp.
Did you make this? - Yes.
Fresh this morning.
- You know you're just wasting your time reading that junk.
- Well it's my time to waste now isn't it?
- Where's Michael? - He's still sleeping.
I'm gonna wake him up here
in a few minutes and feed him though.
- Okay.
I'm gonna get to work.
Bye.
(birds chirping)
Yes, it's the second one this month
and no one at your office
has been able to give me a straight answer.
(unsettling music)
What about infection?
In another week I may lose my whole herd.
(cows mooing)
Yeah, well your best isn't good enough.
And what about them samples your people
took over a month ago?
Listen, I got a dead patch of land
the size of a god damn football field.
(eerie music)
(flames crackling)
(laid back music)
- Except it was Greg with a shovel.
(laughing)
I thought that was pretty nice of him.
(chattering)
That's the only way I can. - Yeah.
- Here he comes.
- How you doing Jacob?
- I'm alright.
- [Man] How's the wife?
Haven't seen her around here in a while.
- She's fine.
Keeping busy around the homestead.
- What about your boy?
- [Jacob] Michael's doing great.
Getting bigger every day.
(laughing)
- Yeah, they're so full of life at that age.
- A handful, yeah. - How old is he anyway?
- Just six months.
- Wow. - Oh yeah,
they keep you up at night at that age.
- That's for sure. (laughing)
- [Man] Twins, yeah, that's for sure.
- Oh that's right, I forgot. - Yeah.
- Hey listen guys, has anybody seen
anything of Lyle Johnson?
- Not since the Grimshaw wedding a couple weeks ago.
You? - No.
- How about you, Jacob?
He's your neighbor. - No idea.
- Maybe he's at one of those librarian conventions.
(laughing)
- Stacking the books.
- Nah, he's probably just up at the home
in Norfolk seeing Marge.
Wouldn't be too worried about it.
- I'm gonna get a refill.
- He's always got something going on lately.
- [Man] Won't be a refill coming back here to the table.
- Oh that's for sure. - Must be for him.
He's a seller not a buyer.
(chattering)
(eerie dramatic music)
(door creaking open)
(engine starting)
- [Jefferson] Whoa.
- Are you okay?
- [Jefferson] Yeah, yeah, no harm done.
- Jefferson I am so sorry.
I didn't even see you.
- So what's the big hurry?
- I have to get home to make dinner
so I was just thinking about everything
and I wasn't paying attention, I'm sorry.
- That's alright, you just drive careful now.
- I will. - Alright.
- I promise.
- And try not to hit anybody. - I won't.
(laughing)
Bye, I'm sorry. - Bye bye.
(dramatic music)
(crickets chirping)
(cows mooing)
(sizzling)
(muffled talking on radio)
(laid back pop music)
(crickets chirping)
(door creaking open)
- Hey. - Hey.
How was your day?
- Busy.
- Is Michael upstairs? - Yeah, he's sleeping.
I think I tuckered him out today.
- Well good.
(unsettling music)
(crickets chirping) (unsettling music)
- No Jacob.
No Jacob, not tonight.
No Jacob that's not okay.
- Come on. - No.
Not tonight, just, Jacob no.
- [Jacob] Come on.
- Leave me alone.
Jacob leave me alone.
Leave me alone.
Stop it.
God.
- [Jacob] What is wrong with you?
(horse neighing)
(unsettling music)
(horse neighing) (unsettling music)
- [Evan] Damn this is a fancy vehicle.
- Well Evan it's the same vehicle
I picked you up in three days ago.
- No.
- Out in front of the store, that's right.
- I'll be damned.
- You alright there buddy?
How're you feeling?
- Oh, I've been better.
(unnerving music)
(screaming)
- Hand me the flashlight.
(car door beeping)
(suspenseful music)
(dramatic eerie music)
(sirens blaring)
(muffled talking on police radio)
- [Beth] Jefferson.
- Honey I think you should go on home.
- Why, what's going on?
- You know Lyle Johnson's been missing for a couple days.
- Yeah.
- Well some of the townspeople came out
looking for him and they found him.
- Oh my god.
(muffled talking on police radio)
- [Jefferson] Yeah, you need to go on back to the house.
(dramatic eerie music)
I'll come by and let you know what's going on okay?
- Okay.
- Go on home Beth.
- [Beth] Jacob I'm not gonna be a prisoner in our home.
- I don't want you running into town
or visiting the neighbors, not without me.
- But Jacob I can leave this house anytime I want to.
- [Jacob] No you can't Beth, especially if you're always
gonna be in an emotional state.
- [Beth] Excuse--
- Listen, I am sorry that you had to see that with Lyle
but you cannot be going into town.
- Jacob I need to live my life.
- [Jacob] Beth you need to stay here.
- I can't just be cooped up in our house.
- [Jacob] Yes you can.
Shopping for you, whatever it is
you need to do I will do it.
- I don't need your help.
- [Jacob] You need to stay in this house.
(phone ringing)
- Hello?
- Hey Beth. - Oh, hi Holly.
- [Holly] I heard the news.
How you holding up?
- I'm fine.
I'm just a little bit shook up that's all.
- [Holly] Well, it was probably a heart attack you know?
I mean he was pretty active.
His heart probably just gave up.
- Well I saw Jefferson from the road
and you know I thought I should go
see what was going on, but--
- Okay sweetie just take a deep breath okay?
I mean Lyle wasn't a spring chicken, these things happen.
Listen some of the gals are getting together
for drinks this afternoon and I think you should stop by.
- [Beth] I don't know.
I have Michael.
- [Holly] Well that's okay, just bring him.
I don't want you staying inside the house all day.
- [Beth] You're right.
- [Holly] I know I am and god forbid
you get to know any of the ladies.
They've been wanting to see Michael for months.
- Thanks.
Evan.
- Jefferson.
- [Jefferson] Malcolm.
- Well?
- Well what?
- [Evan] Do you know what happened yet?
- No, I don't think we'll know for a couple days.
I think it was natural causes.
- Natural causes?
- Lyle had more energy than most men half his age.
- Yeah.
- [Woman] I wonder what this little one will do some day.
- He's gonna go fast too. - Yeah.
- About when he's 18 he'll be gone.
- [Woman] Well I worry about the schools here though.
- [Woman] Right.
- [Woman] We have to hold on to him as long as we can.
- Uh-huh, yeah he's anxious to take on moving.
- You know it's neat to be around
a little baby like this 'cause you forget.
- Oh it goes-- - So fast.
- That's Michael. - Michael.
- And Michael is talking to us.
- [Woman] I remember when David started school.
It just seemed like his whole life started and,
just before you knew it he was ready to--
- Yeah, I'm afraid so. (chattering)
- [Woman] Before you know it he'll be gone.
- [Woman] I know, with all the other kids,
they'll all be gone. - Right.
- [Holly] I wish you would just try to have a good time.
- [Beth] I know.
- I know they're not the most exciting group.
- I'm sorry.
I just still feel kind of uncomfortable around everybody.
I mean I only know Carol and Jody.
- And me. - Well besides you.
- Oh thank you. - Oh thank you.
I don't know.
Why didn't you and Bill ever have any kids?
- Why do you ask?
- Oh I'm sorry.
You don't have to answer that question.
- No, it's okay.
(sighing)
We were trying and that was the plan
and then Bill got sick so I have a dog.
I guess that's like having a baby you know
except you don't have to worry about
them growing up or leaving town.
- I wish I could leave town.
I hate it here.
- You're just upset.
God I've lived here my whole life.
I actually like it.
I'm gonna stay.
- Yeah.
Well I better get going.
I have to go to Norfolk before suppertime.
- Your mom, how's she doing?
- She's okay. - Yeah?
- She's not remembering things very well.
- Hey, okay, how about this,
you go see your mom and I'll watch Michael for you?
- Really? - Yeah.
He'll be fine.
Half the women here are grandmothers.
- Oh I don't know. - Go.
It'll be easy.
We'll spoil him and I'll take him by your house tonight.
(dramatic music)
- Hi Mom.
Sorry I haven't been to see you much lately.
Things have been kind of busy.
You look good.
You always do.
(muffled talking)
(dramatic music)
- Hey, excuse me.
- Yes?
- I'm sorry I don't normally do this,
but I need a ride to the bus station.
I was wondering could I hitch a ride with you?
- I don't know, I'm kind of in a hurry.
- I'm sorry if you're uncomfortable.
- Oh no it's not that I'm uncomfortable, I just--
- Don't worry I'll-- - Need to get going.
- Find somebody else.
- You know what, it's okay, I can give you a ride.
I'm going that direction anyway.
- It's only a couple miles.
- I'm just parked right over here, so.
- So you're just visiting then?
- Yeah, my mother actually.
- How is she?
- Well, getting older is just taking its toll.
- Yeah.
Yeah I know what you mean.
- But I get to go home and see my little boy.
- [Man] Wow.
- He is going to be six months.
- Oh really, wow. - Yeah.
It's hard to believe though.
They just, they grow so fast you know?
- Yep, time flies.
- So what brings you to Norfolk?
- I was just visiting my mother too.
- Oh really?
- Yeah, got in on the bus yesterday.
- Well I'm sorry, is she okay?
- It's hard to tell.
I'd rather not talk about it.
You can just let me off right up here.
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
- You sure? - Oh yeah, yeah I'm sure.
Yeah, this is a good spot right here.
(frogs croaking)
(door closing)
- Where have you been?
- I went to Norfolk.
- Why did you leave Michael over at Holly's?
- Holly offered to take care of him for me.
Why, he's okay isn't he?
- He's upstairs asleep.
I thought I said earlier today
I didn't want you running around.
(eerie dramatic music)
- This used to be quite a place.
- Is everything okay?
He stop crying?
- He's fine.
- You know you were supposed to keep him with you all day.
- Why Jacob, so you could spend
the whole afternoon at Carlson's?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I think you know what it's supposed to mean.
You've been spending a lot of time there lately.
But let me guess, it's me right?
(unsettling music)
- I'll spend as much time at Carlson's as I want to.
- That's real mature Jacob.
- It's better than being here. (baby crying)
(unsettling music)
(baby crying) (unsettling music)
We'll continue this in a moment.
(unsettling music)
Beth?
(heartbeat thumping)
I looked under clothes.
I looked over the perimeter.
Everywhere I could, where is he?
- [Beth] I don't know.
- Where is he? - I don't know!
(unnerving music)
(muffled shouting)
- Where is he? - I don't know!
(phone ringing)
- [Holly] Hello?
(unnerving music)
- [Jacob] Michael!
- [Beth] Michael!
(dramatic music)
(unsettling whooshing)
- We haven't found anything.
No sign of a break in.
No sign that Michael got out on his own.
And you say the window was left open last night?
- Yes.
- Yes the window was open.
- And you were both just downstairs?
- Yes we were in the living room.
- Okay.
Now usually when there's a break in
we'd be able to turn up some kind
of evidence, traces, something.
Are you sure you haven't seen anything unusual
around the farm the last couple of days?
Anything out of the ordinary at all?
- [Beth] No.
- Alright.
Well we dusted for prints around the crib
and around the windows.
If somebody was up there last night we'll know about it.
Well if this is a kidnapping something's gonna turn up.
- [Man] You want me to call someone in Osage?
- [Jefferson] No, I got that handled.
(unsettling music)
- [Man] You really think that baby
could've come out this far?
- We're just looking for anything suspicious.
Tracks, footprints, anything out of the ordinary.
Just keep looking.
- Why do you keep looking at me like that?
- No reason.
- Do you think this is my fault somehow?
Answer me.
(sighing)
- No.
I don't think this is your fault.
- Alright.
- Why the insistence on leaving the god damn window open?
- What?
- You know damn well what I'm talking about.
- We always left his window open Jacob.
- Because you insisted on it.
- The room was too hot for the baby, you know that.
- If the window would've been shut and locked
this would've never happened.
- How can you blame me for that?
(door opening)
(eerie dramatic music)
(laid back music)
- Hey Jacob.
- What do you want Evan?
- I just heard about your son.
Anything I can do?
- Any idea who might've took him?
- Well a few nights ago we saw a guy
running across the road not too far from your place.
- Did you get a good look at him?
- Not really.
It looked like a man, but it might've been a teenager.
- Who was with you?
- Jefferson.
Yeah, we were going down Country Road C.
He thought it looked like a teenager, you know?
Maybe a kid from one of the field parties or something.
- What night?
- Just this last Saturday.
- It's probably one of those god damn Henderson kids.
- Hey, hey Jacob, it could've been anybody.
You know, I just thought you should know.
- Why didn't you tell me you saw somebody two nights ago?
- What are you talking about?
- You know what I'm talking about, on Road C two nights ago.
- Now Jacob I'm looking into that alright?
- Someone has my son dammit.
Now was it one of the Hendersons?
- I'm gonna go see the Henderson boys tonight.
You just need to stay clear of this one Jacob.
I know how your temper can get.
Jacob listen.
I'm turning up leads alright,
but the last thing this town needs is to get into a panic.
People feel safe in this town
and I need to keep it that way.
- If you have a suspect I'm the first one
who should know about it.
I don't want to hear it from Evan.
- Okay, alright.
And as soon as I do you will be the first one I tell.
- I damn well better.
(dramatic eerie music)
(crying)
(vomiting)
- [Holly] Have you been home long?
- No.
I've been in town searching.
I've been talking to anybody who will listen to me.
Just asking them if they know
anything or if they see anything.
Showing them pictures.
- What about Jefferson, what did he say?
- He searched Michael's room, nothing.
What about you?
Have you seen anything strange or out of the ordinary?
A person or anything?
No? - No.
- You know the past few nights
I've been hearing some things out in the field.
- [Holly] Simon's been barking every night.
It's probably just coyotes.
- He blames me.
- Who blames you?
- Jacob.
I left Michael's window open.
It's my fault that Michael's gone.
- Don't say that.
- He blames me for having Michael in the first place.
I don't think Jacob ever even wanted children.
At least not with me.
- You know that's not true.
(sighing)
- I'm sorry Holly.
I'm sorry.
I'm just really tired.
- Your restroom's upstairs right?
- [Beth] Yeah, up the stairs to the left.
(eerie music)
- [Holly] Hey, hey.
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, everything's fine.
I'm gonna get going so you can get some sleep okay?
You look awful.
I mean, not awful, but anyway I should go check on Simon.
- [Holly] Okay.
- Let me know if you hear anything okay?
- Sure. - Okay.
- Give me a hug. - Okay.
(dramatic eerie music)
(phone dialing)
(eerie music)
(pills rattling)
(unsettling music)
(baby crying)
(screeching)
Michael?
(eerie dramatic music)
(baby crying)
(panting)
Michael?
(baby crying) (unsettling music)
Michael!
(phone ringing)
- [Holly] Hello?
- Holly. - Beth.
- [Beth] I heard him Holly.
- Slow down. - Michael.
He's somewhere out in the field.
- [Holly] You heard what?
- Just now, but I can't find him.
I heard him crying the field.
- [Holly] Slow down.
- Dammit, I heard him Holly.
(baby crying)
Michael.
(dial tone humming)
(baby crying)
Jacob I heard him.
I heard him cry.
- [Jacob] What?
(gun cocking)
(hooting)
(distant barking)
(door creaking open)
- Where is he?
Did you see him?
- You sure you heard Michael?
- Yes Jacob I heard him.
You believe me don't you?
- I'm going to bed.
- Wait Jacob, I heard him.
You think I'm crazy don't you?
God.
That's why you want me in this house all day.
Because you're afraid I'm gonna embarrass you or something.
- That's enough.
- [Beth] Well what is it then Jacob, huh?
Are you afraid they might think
your wife's a mental patient?
- Shut your damn mouth.
- Where were you tonight Jacob, huh?
- In town. - I know you were in town.
I saw your car parked at Carlson's.
- [Jacob] Mm-hm.
- You know I really don't think Michael's
going to turn up at the local bar.
- I was asking some of the farmers
if they've heard or seen anything.
- And?
- And Jefferson thought he saw somebody suspicious
the other night out on Road C.
Thought it might be one of the Henderson boys, alright?
Satisfied Beth?
- And that took you all night?
Your son is out there somewhere
and you spent the whole night drinking.
- Oh come on.
- I can smell it on you Jacob.
Do you think I enjoy being married to a drunk?
(slap thwacking) Ow.
- Now as long as you choose to live in this house
you're gonna watch and remember who you're speaking to.
I'm going to bed.
I suggest you do the same.
(unsettling music)
- It's okay.
God no.
I'll do it.
(unsettling music)
- So where am I taking you?
- It's five or six miles up the road.
- You get in an accident or something?
- Yeah.
(unsettling music)
(laid back music)
(eerie music)
(muffled talking on police radio)
- [Jefferson] Well when did she call?
- [Holly] 11 o'clock.
- [Jefferson] And what did she say exactly?
- Well she was really upset and she was crying
and she said she could hear the baby in the field.
- Crying? - Mm-hm.
- Where was Jacob? - Not home.
I think he's been spending a lot of time at Carlson's.
- Yeah.
- I mean I'm not trying to cause a problem,
I just, I thought you ought to know.
- [Jefferson] Why did they call
you when Michael disappeared?
- I don't know, I guess Beth and I are kind of close.
I mean she doesn't know very many people.
(dramatic music)
- [Man On Radio] The local police
continue to be puzzled by the events.
It's only a matter of time before the parents
become the prime suspects in the disappearance.
(eerie dramatic music)
- Jefferson's over there right now.
I don't know.
I guess to check up on her.
Yeah, Jacob stayed in town all night.
Well I sorry for him too.
Well he's probably afraid of her.
(laughing)
Okay, I'll keep you posted.
Call me tonight, bye.
- Any news?
- The Henderson boys were in Octavia both nights.
It could've been anybody.
- It's been almost two days.
Nothing's turned up.
(dramatic music)
- [Man] I can't imagine how Jacob must be feeling right now.
- [Man] Yeah, he's a had a run of bad luck, that's for sure.
- [Man] If it were me, I'd cut my losses and hit the road.
- [Man] No you wouldn't and neither is he.
He's not going anywhere.
He's got this place in his blood.
(static buzzing) (dramatic music)
- [Man] You know I've been hearing
some crazy rumors about town.
- Yeah, like what?
- [Man] Oh just some about Jacob's wife.
- [Man] Let me guess, Holly Stevenson is your source.
- [Holly] Mm-hm.
That's interesting.
Do I think she had something to do with Michael?
I don't know, maybe.
You know she takes medication.
(dramatic music)
(crickets chirping)
(static buzzing)
(eerie music)
(dog barking)
(eerie whooshing)
(dog barking) (unsettling music)
(unnerving music)
(baby crying)
(birds chirping)
(unnerving music)
(baby crying)
(static buzzing)
(unnerving music) (baby crying)
- Michael.
(static buzzing) (baby crying)
Oh my.
(baby crying) (eerie music)
(dog barking)
(baby crying)
(panting)
Michael.
(baby crying)
(dog barking) (baby crying)
(unnerving music)
- Simon!
Come here buddy.
Simon.
Come on Simon.
Come on buddy.
Come on.
(unsettling music)
(static buzzing) (eerie music)
(baby crying)
- I saw Sue there. - Sue.
Yeah let's go to Bobby's.
- I don't want to go to Bobby's.
- Why not?
- Why don't you want to go to Bobby's?
- Because Tyler is gonna be there.
(unsettling music)
- Oh right, this is Miller Road right up here.
- [Woman] Oh yeah the Olson property's on that road.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Okay, we can go check that out.
- Okay let's do that.
(unnerving music)
(thumping) Oh my god.
- [Man] Hold on, hold on.
Hey.
Hey!
(eerie music)
- [Woman] Dale.
- [Man On Radio] A bunch of disappearances, not just here,
but in surrounding counties very similar in nature.
None of the local authorities seem to be able
to explain the kidnappings.
(eerie music)
(baby crying)
(roaring)
(phone ringing)
- Jefferson.
Yeah.
Slow down.
Okay.
Yeah, when's the last time you saw her?
Yeah we're on it.
(dramatic music)
- [Man On Radio] For those of you just tuning in
we've been discussing the latest on the missing child,
Michael Nance who was taken from
a local home several days back.
The local police continue to be puzzled by the event.
Beth Nance is with us.
She is the mother of the missing child Michael.
- Okay.
Please.
Please help us.
Or look around.
Even if you could just help us search for him.
If you're out in the fields or anywhere.
I heard him, I heard him.
And he's out there somewhere.
And we can find him, please.
If you're able to help please help.
(dramatic music)
Hey Mom.
Can you hear me?
I really need you right now.
(dramatic music)
(eerie dramatic music)
- Who are you?
- Oh I'm sorry.
I'm Beth Nance, I live on the farm just east of yours.
- Have you seen my husband?
He doesn't come here anymore.
- Is this your artwork?
- Why do you care?
- [Beth] Is it a field?
- It's our farm.
- [Beth] I like it.
- Never did much work until I came to this hellhole.
Didn't see the point to it.
I still don't.
- [Beth] And what's this?
- It's nothing.
- [Beth] Nothing?
- Nothing, that's exactly what it is.
The same nothing that's sucking the life out of that town.
There's nothing good to ever come from that town
and there never will be.
It's going to waste away.
Get out.
- Excuse me?
- I said get the hell out of my room.
Nurse!
Get, Nurse, Nurse!
Get.
(dramatic music)
(muffled talking on police radio)
- The town went all funny.
But people started disappearing.
Clarence Anderson's son, he was the first one.
And then other people would disappear without a trace.
Not just people either, cattle.
Cattle disappeared.
They found old Elmore Cogdell
and Becky Larson, what was left of 'em.
They weren't exactly spring chickens
but they used to be the liveliest people this side of plat.
The land went all funny too.
It started on the old Marshall place.
That's where they found the missing cattle.
Oh hell there ain't nobody left,
but me and a couple of old timers.
They're all gone.
- [Jefferson On Phone] So did you learn anything up there?
- [Man On Phone] Well the town's pretty dead.
No families, nothing.
Just a few old timers giving me the same bullshit story.
- [Jefferson On Phone] Alright, head on back to town.
Let's get a patrol car out on Road C.
(eerie music)
(muffled talking on police radio)
(car door opening)
(wind chimes ringing)
(knocking on door)
- Come on.
No, I won't let her in.
I won't let her in.
(eerie music)
No.
Okay.
(eerie music)
Hey, can I help you?
- I saw your light on from the road.
I remember you from a couple days ago.
What are you doing here?
- Oh I'm sorry.
I wasn't very upfront that day.
I'm Phillip, I'm Marge and Lyle's son.
- I see.
Why didn't you tell me that?
- Well I didn't know you.
And with my father passing and my mother being sick
I just didn't want to trouble you.
See I came to Norfolk to visit my mother.
She didn't even recognize me.
I was gonna leave town that day,
but my father passing so sudden,
there's just so much to do.
Hey you live nearby here?
- Yeah I live next door.
I have for a couple of months.
- You want to come in and have a drink?
- No, I need to get back.
My husband's expecting me.
- Oh come on, just for a while.
Get to know the neighbors.
- Alright.
(muffled talking on police radio)
(dog barking)
(eerie music)
- Have a seat.
- Is this Lyle?
- Yeah.
Pretty adventurous, huh?
- [Beth] Wow, I didn't know he did all this stuff.
- Yeah.
Mom never appreciated it.
Always thought he should stay
here and take care of the farm.
It had been in my mother's family for a long time.
Kind of got dumped on him.
He never left because of it.
- We only spoke on occasion.
He let me check out library books when he wasn't there.
- I should've made it to his funeral.
I didn't even know he had a son.
- I was adopted when I was three.
Don't remember anything before that.
(muffled talking on police radio)
(unsettling music)
Oh.
(water running)
Why don't you have some water?
It's all we got.
- [Beth] Thank you.
- Something bothering you?
- My son, Michael, he was stolen
from my house a few nights ago.
- Stolen, how?
- He was just taken from his bedroom.
There were people searching all around the home.
I assumed that you knew.
- I've been in town.
I'm sure the sheriff's been here,
but I've been trying to do some
legal stuff with the house in town.
Do you know who did it?
- No.
(eerie music)
- Well, if there's anything I can do to help let me know.
I've been a little dehydrated lately.
(unsettling music)
(dog barking)
- Simon?
- I really want to get to know you.
What brought you here?
- Here?
- Yeah.
Why'd you come to this dying little burg?
- Well, I should be getting back.
- It's okay, you don't have to answer
if it makes you uncomfortable.
(sighing)
- Jacob and I, my husband, we met a few years back in Osage.
I was going to go to college,
but I couldn't afford it.
- Where did you want to go?
- Anywhere far from here.
I still think about it though.
It's the only thing that's been keeping me going lately.
- You could still go you know?
- I thought I could take some classes,
kind of a home school approach to college,
but I didn't do it.
And then I got pregnant and then we got married.
And then we found a farm out here that was affordable.
And here I am.
But it's all different now.
Michael was the only thing that ever kept us together.
He was the only thing that ever made me happy.
I thought about leaving here
and taking him with me but I can't leave.
But you got away somehow.
(unsettling music) (dog barking)
- Simon.
(dog barking) (unsettling music)
(dramatic music)
(dog barking)
- [Man] How old did you say he was?
- About seven and half years.
- Holly this dog's at least 16 years old.
- That's not possible.
- Well I could do a throat culture
to determine cause of death but I think it'll
just come out natural causes or dehydration.
- Dehydration?
- His throat's completely dry.
- That can't be Simon.
(dramatic music)
- Well, what about you?
You haven't talked much about yourself.
- Not much to say.
- [Beth] You've been gone for a while haven't you?
- I suppose.
- Well?
- Nothing much to tell.
I guess you could say I've been living in a dream.
(dramatic music)
- Well, goodbye.
Thank you.
(dramatic music)
(door opening)
What's this?
- I thought I'd ask you that.
- These are my letters.
- Someone left them in the doorway.
And whose money were you planning on using
for some of them subscriptions?
- I don't know.
- And the other letters?
When were you gonna tell me?
(unsettling music)
- All I wanted was a job.
Some place close, some place I could drive to.
- And what were you planning on doing with Michael?
Why don't you just admit it?
That you want out of here.
This is your life, our life, you belong here.
- Nothing is right here and you know it.
- This is your home.
(unsettling music)
Just because Michael's gone doesn't mean you can leave.
- [Beth] Those are mine.
- [Jacob] Beth, you are my wife.
- Leave her alone.
- Who the hell are you?
- [Beth] Phillip get out of here.
- Phillip?
How do you know my wife?
- [Beth] Jacob.
- Huh? - Jacob.
- How do you know my wife? - Leave him alone.
- No.
No, Beth. - How do you know her?
- Wait.
- Get the fuck off of my property.
- Jacob stop. - How do you know my wife?
- Beth. - Jacob.
Jacob leave him alone.
- [Phillip] You don't even know what I want.
- Leave him alone.
(thumping) - Oh no.
(groaning) (thumping)
- Jacob. - Come here.
(unnerving music) (groaning)
Huh, huh?
- [Phillip] No.
- What are you doing with my wife.
Huh?
(mirror gouging) (groaning)
(whimpering)
(groaning)
(coughing)
(thunder booming)
- Stay back. - It was an accident.
- Just get out of here. - Are you alright?
(crying) (roaring)
- What was that?
- Oh we gotta get inside.
- [Beth] What?
- Trust me.
(unsettling music)
What are you doing here?
I'm here to help.
Put the knife down.
(breathing heavily)
I know where your son is.
- What?
- You have to trust me.
Put the knife down.
- Do you have him? - No.
I don't have him.
Put down the knife and we'll talk.
This may be hard to understand.
I don't even understand it myself.
It comes to me in flashes.
I remember being taken.
My parents were fighting downstairs and I
just escaped, it took me away.
That was a year ago.
I was 13.
I remember living my life, leaving here, everything.
All those memories were just lies.
It takes you to a place where you can't be seen.
And it feeds off you.
Whatever it is has your son.
(crying)
- How do you know this?
- When I left I must've taken some of it with me.
It's like it wants me to know.
It'd take years off your life.
When it's done it just spits you out.
That's how it spreads.
But now it's feeding faster.
It's spreading from that dead acre.
It's killing everything as it grows.
When it takes you all you see is darkness,
then the dreams begin.
And after a while you start believing in it.
All the lies and everything it sort of feeds off of.
Your son, how old is he?
- He was six months.
I heard his cries from the field
but now they just sound different.
- He's young.
All he'll ever see is what it really is, it's nothing.
The young ones last the longest.
- Have you seen it?
- No, it doesn't have a shape.
I don't know why it came here.
But I know what it needs and I know when it's close.
It only feeds off me a little at a time.
It's coming for you next.
- What?
- It's been watching you for a while now.
I know everything it's thinking.
And it knows everything you're thinking.
All your thoughts.
Your hopes and dreams.
It's what it needs to survive.
Oh god.
Oh it's coming.
It's coming.
(unsettling music)
(phone ringing)
- Beth?
- [Beth] Yes.
- Hey, how are you?
I haven't seen you in a while.
I've been worried about you.
Where's Jacob?
- [Beth] I thought he was still in town.
- No, he left Carlson's the same time I did.
Is everything alright?
You sound kind of nervous.
Do you want me to stop by?
I could.
- No really I'm fine. - I don't mind.
Okay, well, I was just concerned.
(knocking on door)
(dial tone humming)
- [Jefferson] Beth, it's Jefferson.
Come on, open the door.
- [Beth] What's wrong?
- [Jefferson] I gotta talk to you.
- What? - It's okay Beth.
Come on, open the door.
(unsettling music)
(phone ringing)
I just got a couple of questions.
Just a quick follow up and then I'm out of here.
- Hello?
- [Jefferson] Beth it's Jefferson.
- [Beth] Jefferson are you outside?
- [Jefferson] No I'm on the road.
Are you alright Beth?
Beth? (dial tone humming)
(rattling)
(unsettling music)
- [Holly] Come on Beth open up.
Beth it's fine. - Honey.
- Jacob, what? - Beth.
- Beth we're gonna help you. - It's okay sweetie.
You need help. - It's okay sweetheart.
- What, no.
- [Jacob] Sweetheart go ahead and open the door.
- Leave me alone.
- [Jefferson] Beth everything's gonna be fine.
- [Jacob] I'm right here.
- [Jefferson] We're gonna take care of you.
- Just leave me alone. - Just open the door.
- I just want my son.
- [Holly] Beth open the door.
- Let them in. - Everything's gonna be fine.
- Beth, let them in.
- [Jefferson] Just open the door and let us help you.
- He is safe. - We're all here for you.
- [Jacob] Everything is going to be okay.
- [Beth] Go away.
- It's over sweetheart. - Leave me alone.
- [Jefferson] Beth come on sweetie, open the door.
- Michael!
- Come on, we need you to-- - It's Jeff--
(unsettling music)
- Come on honey open up. - Leave me alone.
- Open the door. - We're gonna help you out,
just open the door hon, let us in.
- Beth we're here for you. - I've changed.
I'm different now. - Come on, open up.
- [Phillip] Let go.
- [Beth] Just get out of here Phillip.
- I want to see you Beth. - Just let me go.
- [Jeffery] Beth just open the door.
We're gonna go get Michael. - You don't need to be afraid.
Don't be scared. - We're going to take you
to see Michael, come on.
(baby crying)
- [Holly] Everything's fine, open the door.
- [Phillip] Beth.
Let them in.
You can get your son back.
But you gotta give in to it.
- I'm so tired.
- [Phillip] They need you.
- [Beth] I'm so tired.
(baby crying)
- [Holly] It's fine, we're not mad okay?
Just open the door.
(baby crying)
- Trust me Beth. - Come on sweetie.
- [Jacob] I need you to listen to me right now.
- We wouldn't lie to you. - We're super close.
(unnerving music) (baby crying)
(heartbeat thumping)
(unnerving music)
(dramatic music)
(gun firing)
(eerie music)
(static buzzing)
(speaking backwards)
(eerie music)
(dramatic eerie music)