(dramatic music)
(emotionally stirring music)
(men yelling)
(dramatic music)
(hand grenade exploding)
(men yelling)
(regal dramatic music)
Your Holiness, thieves
have stolen our God Mara,
what shall we do?
Journey south to Wingpoo at once
and give this message to the Governor.
The God Mara and the thieves who stole it,
must be delivered to me,
or I will destroy Wingpoo
and everyone in it.
But what of your long-standing treaty
with the villagers of Wingpoo,
that no harm shall come to the settlement.
Shall I break the word
of the great Dragon Lady.
You have your orders, do as you're told.
Yes, Your Holiness.
(dramatic music)
You are the great Governor,
I am the High Priest.
It is urgent that we talk.
All right, you're
here, so start talking.
I bring terrible bad news.
Our great God Mara has been stolen.
Oh, that is bad news,
how do, you don't suppose...
I tell you it was stolen.
The God Mara and the two white
thieves must be returned,
so that justice may be served.
What, two white thieves?
I know what he's talkin' about.
Those two suspicious
characters looking for Dr. Lee.
All right, all right, I'll look into it.
And next time, I'll hear
more of this fine story.
You must catch these
thieves in three days,
if you want to save Wingpoo,
or the Dragon Lady will destroy you all.
Now the way I see
it, it's something were
to happen to the village.
Why?
You'd be the first person they'd blame.
You're the Governor,
you should do something.
You know, you're right.
I should go for the village tonight.
(dramatic music)
(men yelling)
Gee Pat, must be some
sort of a festival.
Everybody sure looks happy tonight.
Come on, let's have some fun.
Men, your homes are in danger.
The jungle people will attack,
unless we destroy the thieves
that stole their God Mara.
Are you with me?
(men yelling)
He sure knows how to rattle 'em.
Go tell Stanton.
These two outsiders threaten
the safety of your family
and neighbors, will you let that happen?
(men yelling)
Hey, he could cause a lot of trouble.
Men, thieves are
already on their way here.
And when they come...
Men, look.
After them.
(men yelling)
Gosh Terry, they're
after us, come on let's go.
(dramatic music)
Now all we have to do, is
wait 'til they're finished.
I suppose we should go.
Governor, the acts of
this crowd are barbaric.
You should do something.
Why, why should those
two little old lie,
although now I'm sure you can see
for yourself why they
must be sent on home.
Wan, go into town and
find the police chief,
tell him to find out who's responsible
for these shenanigans and lock 'em up.
(men yelling)
(gun firing)
[Mr. Drake] Unhand those men.
If they're guilty, they
should stand trial.
Get out of here, nobody want
to hear what you have to say.
(men yelling)
[Mr. Drake] Unhand me, let me go!
You have no right to do this.
Unhand me, I tell you.
You'll never get away with this.
I'll ring the American
Consulate finds out,
he'll send repres...
(men yelling)
Wait a minute, you can't
go out there with a weapon,
someone will get shot.
Better give me that.
He's right you know,
somebody will get hurt.
Yeah.
Oh for Pete's sakes.
(dramatic music)
(men yelling)
The boys?
We can't help them.
Are they guilty?
[All] Yes.
Then the law says, you must die.
(gun firing)
Look!
Senor Stanton, it's no good.
Somebody tip off police,
now they go to jail.
We still got those box of bombs.
Miguel's right, it's worth a try.
All I know is, bombs better cinch it
because fire didn't.
Hold it Captain, you make mistake.
These are our friends.
Are you kidding,
I've never seen these
guys before in my life.
Have you Terry?
No, never before now.
Come on, let's get started.
(dramatic music)
Ow!
Inside, inside, inside.
Hi boss.
We here to help.
I appreciate the sentiment Connie,
but frankly you'd be more
help if you were outside.
(men yelling)
All right, let's show 'em,
or the whole village will be wiped out.
These men are responsible
for endangering your families
and your homes.
They must be punished or
Wingpoo will be destroyed.
(men yelling)
Listen, there's only
one thing left to do
and that's burn down the jail.
(men yelling)
See, let's go.
Gosh Pat, looks like
the whole town's outside.
(men yelling)
Start diggin', right there.
[Henchman] The dynamite's
in place, Mr. Stanton.
Okay, light it.
Get that window open.
Hurry!
(building exploding)
Well, that settles it.
Now we can go finish our plans.
You two stand guard out here.
Remember, keep your guard up.
You stand guard first, me do.
I'm sure glad to see you alive.
I'm afraid, I wasn't much help.
You did more than enough.
Thanks for everything.
Sit down.
Now what happened?
We were ambushed.
Chased us, all the
way down to the river.
And Pat and I swam...
Just a moment.
Dow, that will be all.
He might be one of them.
Now, go ahead.
Anyway...
Hold it Terry.
You know, we explained to those people,
we were just scientists.
The problem is, why were
they trying to kill us?
I think I know.
A statue of some kind,
might have been stolen from
the Dragon Lady's temple.
They think you're responsible.
Well that's it then.
We were there, when the real
thieves made away with it.
But we had nothing to do with the plan.
However, the villagers now believe
that you are the ones who are to blame.
Maybe Fang's men stole it.
I bet I know where it is,
same place he took Normandie.
Let's just go to the temple and
tell her that's where it is.
You're right, it's worth a try.
Whatever you want.
I want to help you with
everything, is there any way I can?
I don't know.
That would be putting you and
your daughter in great danger.
Would it be asking too much for a shower?
Of course not.
Make yourselves at home.
- Please.
- Thanks.
Come on Terry.
He said, "Keep up your guard."
You no worry, I keep
it with me, I worry.
Take this away.
Well, better get going.
Better take my pistol.
Smart.
And a couple of rifles.
I'll get them.
Thanks for everything Mr. Drake.
You're quite welcome, my boy.
Thanks for the use of your camera.
[Mr. Drake] I hope to
get it back in one piece.
Watch out for Fang's men.
That'll be swell.
I'll be back in a minute.
Goodbye boys, you should be careful.
Are you safe here?
I'm sure we are.
All right then, come on.
(ominous music)
Two white man, looking
for Fangs hideout,
seek location of Mara, send message.
(drums beating)
Stop, what do you think you're doing?
You're one of Fang's men.
You'll get it when my
father finds out about this.
(dramatic music)
(drums beating)
Message all right.
Me go back to house,
before Master Drake find out.
(dramatic music)
Master Fang, Master Fang.
Message from Wingpoo,
saying two white men gone,
know all about statue.
Two men gone to Dragon Lady's temple.
The fools.
Stanton has failed.
They must be stopped, await my orders.
Now go!
Dr. Lee, it seems our
conversation has been cut short,
due to outside affairs.
However, we shall talk again.
Take him away.
Go into the jungle, find these men,
before they reach the Temple of the Dawn.
Remember, they must be
stopped at all costs.
Yes, Master Fang.
Ambo and I shall do your bidding.
See that you do, now hurry, hurry.
Ambo!
(gorilla growling)
Ambo, come!
(crickets chirping)
(dramatic music)
(thumping)
(snoring)
Normandie, where have you been?
I was worried about you.
Oh, I'm sorry dad, but
I was suspicious of Dow,
so I followed him.
I heard drums, what was that?
A message to Fang, telling
him all about our plans.
It's been hours, they're far away
but we have to try and warn them.
We have to do something.
There's only one choice, I have to,
oh, oh my shoulder.
You're too weak to be of any help.
I'll go myself.
[Mr. Drake] Normandy,
Fangs men are dangerous.
You could be killed, you
don't have to do this.
I'll be all right, you know
I can take care of myself.
See you at breakfast.
(dramatic music)
(tiger growling)
(rifle shooting)
That gunshot was mighty close by.
Maybe I should see who it was?
No, somebody might be
following, we better get going.
(gorilla growling)
(screaming)
Ambo, Ambo.
(speaking foreign language)
(screaming)
[Narrator] Sinister Fang
threatens to torture Dr. Lee,
if he doesn't decipher
the ancient scrolls,
revealing hidden
treasures of the God Mara.
Pat and Terry are captured
and taken to Fang's hideout.
Fang threatens to torture Terry and Pat,
if Dr. Lee doesn't cooperate.
When suddenly a fight breaks out
that will decide their fate.
These are just some of
the spine-tingling thrills
that await in "The Scroll of Wealth".
The next exciting chapter
of "Terry and the Pirates".
(dramatic music)