(dramatic music)
- [Edwina] Since we don't have enough fuel
to get us to Jupiter we'll
hitch a ride on the asteroid.
Gerard, report.
- Generators are at full capacity.
Range to asteroid, 5,000.
- I wasn't seriously suggesting
we attach ourselves to it.
I was joking.
I was trying to lighten
our impending doom,
not embellish it.
- Activate ion drives.
You should never try to be funny, Haskell.
It only gets you into trouble.
- Commander 4,000.
- Stand by.
I don't want to waste
a single rad of fuel.
- [Haskell] I must have been
mad to have even mentioned it.
- [Edwina] Don't worry, we'll
find you a straitjacket.
- [Haskell] Completely mad.
- Come on, Haskell!
I've already lost one ship.
I'm not keen to repeat the experience.
That thing could pulverize
us in a few minutes.
Stand by to bring us alongside.
- Range 3,000.
- Well, next time I'll
keep my thoughts to myself
and my big mouth shut.
- Haskell!
- Impact lance armed.
- 2,000.
- Full forward thrust.
Gerard, stand by for firing.
- Cable doors opening.
(ship rattling)
- You two should be in your room.
What are you doing in here?
- It was my fault, I
had to fix Quadro first.
- You'll have to forget about the robot.
- There's no time for that,
just sit down and hang on.
(ominous music)
- [Edwina] Four days on the asteroid,
and then we slingshot
ourselves to Jupiter.
- We've achieved comparative
velocity with the asteroid.
- Distance from target?
- 400 meters.
- Down thrust.
Get us closer and do it quickly.
We're using too much fuel.
- Down thrust 1/3.
To think I gave up a perfectly
safe job as a designer.
- You did ask for this job.
Gerard?
- 300.
250.
- Stand by forward lance.
- Standing by.
200.
- [Edwina] Wait for it, Gerard.
- 150.
- Fire!
(intense music)
- Yes, we're on!
Second lance locked in place and holding.
We're attached to the asteroid.
I'd like to see Selby
try and catch us now.
- You can open your eyes now, Haskell.
Looks like you won't need
a straitjacket after all.
- No I think I'll hang onto it, thanks.
We've still gotta get off this rock.
(ominous music)
- You know that woman has got
ice flowing through her veins.
- Slow down, what happened?
- May I remind you that your appointment
was for a probationary period only.
Sadly, your time is up.
- She sacked you?
- [Kumiko] She can't do that!
- [Michael] Didn't you
polish your buttons?
- [Kumiko] Michael that's not funny.
- Look Kumi, it's okay.
- It's not okay!
- Kumi, it's all right.
She didn't sack me.
She promoted me!
I'm now a fully qualified ensign.
- [Both] What?
- I'm on my way up the ladder,
and I need you to toe the line.
- Yeah right, says who?
- I do, and starting now.
All right, I want you to
get everybody together
for a meeting in half an hour.
(ship roaring)
All right, listen up everybody.
Operation Roid Ride.
Now because of the shortage of fuel,
the timing of the
slingshot could be crucial.
A little too early or too late,
we could shoot right past the colony.
- Great, we'll be slung
so far away from the sun
we'll become relics of the new ice age.
- I thought you'd be pleased.
You're the one that wanted
the cryogenic space travel.
(coughs)
- Now, the next five days are critical.
I want everybody to stick
to their regular routines.
No distractions, and no trouble.
That does go double for you pair.
- Why is it that everyone
assumes we're troublemakers?
- [Zac] We're just badly misunderstood.
- Michael, when the crucial time comes,
I want you to keep an
eye on this pair, okay?
- I'm not a babysitter.
- And we're not babies.
- Yeah yeah, you're just
very short intellectuals.
Kumi can do it.
- She might be needed here.
- Well then you do it.
- Listen Michael, you do it okay?
I'm a crew member, you're the civilian,
and I'm giving you the job.
- A couple of extra bits
of brass on his uniform
and he thinks he's a superhero.
- This is brilliant.
It's a copy of Selby's computer virus.
- Yeah well one day, Gerard's
gonna fall flat on his face
and I just hope that I'm there to see it.
- What a mind he's got.
- Yeah, sharp as a brick!
- I was talking about Selby.
This virus has an
exponential growth pattern.
Once it gets into a computer,
it could systematically destroy
an entire network in seconds.
- [Michael] Are you
listening to what I'm saying?
- Yes, and I think you're
overreacting a bit.
Gerard was only asking for your help.
- No he wasn't.
He ordered me around.
He made the distinction.
He said, "I am really
important and you are nothing."
- Come on, Michael.
You ought to be happy for him.
I am.
Gerard's worked hard for this promotion.
- Yeah well he better not
think I'm gonna bow and scrape
and be his obedient servant
for the rest of the trip.
- Shouldn't you be
checking on Abe and Zac?
- Don't you start.
(ship roars)
- How do you feel?
- Tampering with security
personnel is a punishable offense.
(electricity zaps)
- Ow!
What did you do that for?
- Security personnel?
- That boy there, don't
move another muscle.
Graffiti is not permitted on any wall.
- It's a calendar, you clown.
What's he raving about?
- [Edwina] We must use the asteroid
to slingshot us towards Jupiter.
It's our only chance.
We have three hours, so no slip-ups,
or we won't have enough
fuel to make it on our own.
Gerard?
- Commander, I'm still
getting the same warning.
Test run shows that the
forward impact lance
just won't release.
- [Edwina] Have you
double checked everything?
- Yeah but I can't pinpoint the fault.
- Haskell, this is your territory.
Get onto it, we're running out of time.
- Yes, but it's not a
straightforward problem.
The fault could be anywhere
on any of a hundred areas
starting here and going right through
to the lance mechanism itself.
There's a myriad of possibilities.
- Then I suggest you
narrow down your options,
because if you don't find the fault,
we'll have to rip the lance free.
- [Haskell] Ah no, you can't do that!
You'd need full power, and that'd use up
the rest of the fuel rods.
- Finally we agree, so I think
you'd better find me an alternative.
- Couldn't we just cut the cable?
- The cable runs through
a depressurized well.
It's a nice idea, but
it's far too dangerous
for anyone to be in there
when the thrusters are fired.
- I could give it a go.
- I can't take the risk,
please don't argue with me.
You're an ensign, not a service engineer.
Haskell!
- Yes, coming.
- [Edwina] Somewhere there is a solution
waiting to be found.
Let's not disappoint.
Where do you think you're going?
- [Gerard] I'm going
to check on the others,
see that they're toeing the line.
- Very good.
Anticipating a problem
before it happens, see to it.
Now, Haskell, I want some solutions.
- [Quadro] For your crimes,
this ship is to be cleaned bow to stern.
I want to see that wall spotless.
I want to see it so clean
I can see my face in it.
- I don't know why you want
to ruin a perfectly good wall!
Ow!
He's mad!
What have you done to him?
- Cut it out or I'll diffuse you.
(electricity zaps)
Ow!
You can't do that to me!
I'm your boss.
- I cannot disobey my primary functions.
- [Abe] What's he raving on about now?
- He used to be a security bot.
His old personality
chip must have kicked in
when his head fell off the table.
- Ah this is just great.
He doesn't have any other psycho
chips hidden away, does he?
- Enough chitchat, back
to mopping the floor.
It's much too slippery.
- Good, I hope he takes a dive
and smashes his head again.
(yells)
(groans)
What idiot spilled stuff
all over the floor?
- Don't blame me, it was the robot.
See he's turned totally mental.
See if you can do something.
- He's got us scrubbing the entire ship.
- Back to work.
A squillion apologies, Michael.
I do hope you're all right.
- [Michael] I'm fine, no thanks to them.
- I warned you two.
I'll see to it that they
get extra jobs for this.
(electricity zaps)
- Ow!
- I'm terribly sorry.
I do hope you won't lodge a complaint.
- Uh no, no.
But my room could do
with a bit of a clean.
- I'll have them see to it right away.
It's the last I could do for you.
- Michael, don't encourage him!
- Hey, if it keeps you busy
and Gerard off my back, I'm all for it.
- Indeed.
- Keep up the good work, Quadro
and how do you do that zappy thing?
- Oh, you mean this?
(electricity zaps)
- Ow!
- It's quite simple.
- This is unconstitutional!
(Michael chuckles)
- Well I'm sort of their insurance policy.
It's a titanium interlock cable,
but I should be able to
handle it with laser cutters.
- Handle what, what's with the hero suit?
- But Dent can't expect
you to do it on your own.
Someone should go with you to help.
- I'll be fine.
I've been trained for
these sort of emergencies.
That's why Dent specifically
asked me to do it.
- [Michael] Do what?
- She wants me to go
down to the cable well
and cut the cable.
It's the release mechanism.
- So, you should be able to do that
with one hand tied behind your back.
What's the big deal?
- It's a depressurized well.
I think you should stop
being a jerk and go with him.
- No way, don't look at me.
I'm a civilian, remember?
And besides, Abe and Zac
have been a real handful.
I have been unbelievably busy.
- Well I'll go with ya then.
- Fine by me.
- No you won't, all right?
I'm the professional here.
I can't expect you to
take these type of risks.
- What a hero.
It's amazing what some
extra brass buttons can do.
- [Kumiko] I don't know
what I ever saw in you.
- [Michael] Gerard,
wait, I'll go with you.
Seems you need someone to
keep you out of trouble.
- [Gerard] No you won't, I
don't need anyone down there
that doesn't know what they're doing.
Besides, Dent wouldn't allow it.
- We could talk to her, convince her.
- No you won't.
- Tell her you're
claustrophobic or something.
- Look just keep away from her, all right?
She's really busy.
Besides, I've already had a talk to her
and she flatly refused.
I'll keep in touch!
- Watch yourself down there, maverick.
Don't go trying to be a hero.
- [Haskell] The force has to
be in the retraction mechanics.
There's nowhere else.
Must have been damaged when
we crash landed on Mars.
- We're out of time.
We go with the alternative.
We'll have to rip it
free from the asteroid.
- Well perhaps Gerard was right.
Maybe there is a way that he
can cut the forward cable.
- That's not an option!
If we fire the thrusters,
he'll get sucked out
through the cable doors
like a leaf of limp lettuce.
(ominous music)
- [Quadro] You've missed a bit.
- Where?
- There, I can see a mark.
- [Zac] Impossible, we've
scrubbed the entire corridor!
- See, I've got blisters to prove it.
I think I'm gonna need medical attention.
- Ha, a mere blister never hurt anyone.
Back to work.
- Ow!
There must be some way to immobilize him.
- I've been thinking.
Maybe there is.
- It's Zac, your omnipotence.
I reckon it's cabin fever.
She's gone berserk with graffiti!
- Graffiti is a punishable offense.
She must be disciplined.
- Right, and a disciplined
ship is a happy ship.
- Excellent.
Perhaps one day I shall
promote you to hall monitor.
- Oh could I get one of those
zappy electrical fingers?
- That would be most inadvisable.
Humans are 90% water.
You'd electrocute yourself and die.
- Good point, never mind.
See there?
- Why are you wearing gloves?
- Blisters, so I can work
my fingers down to the bone.
- Excellent, and why
are you shaking so much?
- Nervous energy, so I can
obey your every command.
- Excellent.
Why is it so dark in here?
- Ah, so we can get you dumb schmuck, now!
(yelling)
Get him, Zac!
Got ya, ya maniac!
- [Quadro] Punishable offense.
Interfering with security staff
will invoke the--
- Tell it to the judge!
- [Quadro] Release me!
Release me this instant!
- [Computer] Warning, you are now entering
a depressurized zone.
(ominous music)
- I'm in the cable well.
Probably be a bit more
difficult than I thought.
It's pitch black down here.
I can't see a thing.
- [Kumiko] I knew one of us
should have gone with him.
- [Michael] Well he wouldn't let me.
- Well you didn't argue very hard.
- Why didn't you go?
- Well he wouldn't let me either!
- But as your warped logic would have it,
that doesn't seem to matter.
Why don't you just admit it?
You think I turned chicken on him.
- You said it Michael, not me.
Now tell him to sit tight.
(ominous music)
- Oh boy.
Don't worry, I'm not going anywhere.
I hope.
(machinery whirring)
Whatever you did, thanks.
I'm gonna start with the laser cutters.
(ominous music)
(laser crackling)
- He's a strong bucket of bolts!
Hurry up and do something, grab his fuses!
- [Zac] I'm trying, keep him still!
- [Quadro] Seemed like a millennium.
Please release me, let me go.
- Behold the victor.
- Now what?
- I'll have to rewire his circuits.
We'll need the tools to take him apart.
- Good, I'm gonna enjoy this bit.
- Stand by to release rear cable.
- Standing by.
Don't let me down, not now.
You'll make me look like an idiot.
- That wouldn't be terribly difficult.
Hold on everybody.
(laser crackling)
Reverse thrust quarter power.
Release rear cable.
(Gerard grunts)
(ominous music)
- The cables.
They're releasing them!
- But they can't do that, not
while Gerard's down there.
Dent knows he'd be in danger.
- Maybe they don't know he's down there.
- What are you talking about?
- Maybe that's why he didn't
want us to talk to Dent.
He wanted to play hero all by himself.
- He wouldn't be that stupid.
Gerard, Gerard, respond please.
You have to get out of there.
They're releasing the cables.
Gerard?
Gerard!
Respond!
Gerard, come in please.
Answer me.
Michael, he's not responding.
- All right, get up there.
You have to stop them
from firing the thrusters.
Do whatever you have to do.
- What about you?
- [Michael] I should have gone
with him in the first place.
- Commander Dent?
Come in please, Commander Dent?
- Forget about the screen,
she's gonna be too busy
trying to free the ship.
You're gonna have to get up there.
- Get out of the way!
- Okay, okay.
What's the hurry?
- Who cares?
Let's get on with the robot torture.
- All right, we'll go to
work on the forward cable.
We'll rip it free as planned.
- I must advise against
this course of action.
It could rip the bottom out of the ship.
- I'll be sure to note your objection
on the computer log.
30 degree incline.
Quarter thrust in 10 seconds.
(ominous music)
- Maybe it's like amnesia.
If we clobber him hard enough...
- [Zac] No!
You'll explode his neurons!
- It serves him right!
- It's not his fault, it's
the way he was programmed!
- So we'll have to make
sure it never happens again.
(rumbling)
- What's that?
- Thrusters, hang on tight!
(rumbling)
That should do his
neurons a world of good.
- [Computer] Warning, depressurized zone.
- Gerard?
- Do not enter.
All personnel must clear--
- Gerard?
- Central thrusters engaged--
- Gerard!
- [Computer] And ready to fire.
- That cable's still attached.
I want power in 25 seconds, standby.
Upthrust only.
- No, stop!
Commander you can't!
- 20 seconds.
Kumi this is our only chance
to clear the asteroid.
Please, don't interrupt.
- But you can't, you don't understand.
- Kumi, what's the matter?
- Haskell, I said full
power on all thrusters.
That's an order, in 15 seconds.
- Please listen.
You'll kill him!
Gerard's in the cable well.
He's trying to cut the cable.
You sent him there!
- I gave no such order.
- But he said you did.
You knew he was there and you
still fired the thrusters.
- I knew no such thing.
He had no right to be in there!
I ordered him not to.
- Kumi, it's true Commander.
Six seconds, what do we do?
- Please listen, Michael's down there too.
- One second, Commander.
- Abort the firing!
(ominous music)
- [Michael] You all right?
Can you move?
- [Gerard] Feel like
I've been hit by a bus.
- Don't worry, I got its number.
Can you move?
- Oh my cranial cavity.
The indignity of it all.
I do wish people would stop
using me as a battering ram.
- I think he's back.
- [Michael] He's taken a hit on the head,
but I think he's okay.
- Can you get him out of there?
- In 11 minutes?
- It's 11 minutes or we'll be
past the point of no return.
Can you get him out?
- [Michael] Yeah, I think so.
He's okay, he's coming round.
- [Gerard] I must have
hit my head on the wall
when they released the rear cable.
- [Michael] Come on, I'm
gonna need your help.
What were you trying to
prove down here, anyway?
- [Gerard] I knew Dent was
worried about the cable.
I could've cut it if I
hadn't smashed my head.
- [Michael] Well you're
lucky you're still alive.
- [Gerard] Wait, the cable.
I've got to cut it,
where's the laser cutters?
- [Michael] You're not in
any condition to do anything.
You've gotta get that wound seen to.
- [Gerard] We gotta cut the cable,
or else my career's history.
- [Michael] You should've
thought of that before.
Now go on, get out of here.
Kumi, what about the cable?
- Eight minutes.
- Forget the cable!
We'll use the thrusters
to rip the lance free.
- I repeat, I can't
give you any guarantees.
- Then I'll give you a guarantee.
If we don't get clear of this
asteroid, we're finished.
- Well if you use up all
the fuel, we're stranded,
same result by my reckoning.
- You better hope we're
close enough to Ganymede
to be picked up by their scanners.
Clear the cable well.
You've got seven minutes.
(ominous music)
- [Gerard] Thanks for
trying to convince her.
- [Michael] Forget about
it, just keep moving.
I'll be right behind you.
We're on our way.
Seven minutes.
Lucky seven.
- Bring the ion drives to full capacity.
I want everything it's got
in five minutes, stand by thrusters.
- Standing by.
(intense music)
(hatch creaks)
- [Zac] Gerard, what happened to you?
- [Abe] Where have you been?
- You're bleeding!
- I'm fine.
- [Quadro] Oh goodness me, no.
A definite laceration to
the upper left forehead.
In my medical experience, we
should apply firm pressure
to prevent excessive blood loss.
- [Gerard] Can you tell him to stop?
- [Zac] He was just trying to do his job.
- And it's a nice change from psycho bot.
- That was a really dumb thing to do.
You could've been killed.
- I know all right, but save it.
I've already had the lecture from Michael.
- Where is he?
- He's right behind me.
- [Kumiko] We'll have
to get you to first aid.
- [Gerard] I'll be all right, just--
- Uh-oh.
Michael!
(laser crackling)
- [Michael] Come on, cut!
I could go faster with a blunt spoon.
- [Edwina] All right Haskell,
let's rip that cable out.
- Two minutes remaining.
Ion drives engaged.
- Stand by thrusters.
- Michael, get out of there!
I've gotta get him out of there.
- There's no time!
(laser crackling)
(intense music)
- Edwina, we've lost the cable!
♪ We've lost the cable
we've lost the cable ♪
♪ We've lost the cable yes ♪
- Well done, Haskell.
- I didn't do a thing.
I wish I did, but I didn't.
I just don't know what's happened.
- Let's not worry about it now.
Just get us away from this rock!
- We've lost him.
- Exit denied.
- Come on!
- [Computer] All service hatches secured.
Exit denied.
- [Michael] All right
then, stupid computer!
(intense music)
(dramatic music)