♪♪
Everything okay?
Uh, just the situation here
with these European people,
want to merge or somethin'.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
If there was an award
for the world's busiest man,
you'd definitely be a contender.
Well, the bills are paid,
right?
Mmm. Bills are paid.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
[ Laughs ]
What's so funny?
Uh, this, uh, Kareena,
you know, uh, we had this joke
about, uh, those cats in Europe
and how they talk
and how they act.
It's -- it's -- it's crazy.
It's a little inside joke.
An inside joke, yeah.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
[ Laughs ]
You, uh, would you like me
to make you a lunch to go,
or...?
Nah, babe, I'm good.
I'm good.
...these European cuts
are so hard to get on.
Kareena said that they, uh,
make you look more powerful
in a -- in a business meeting.
Kareena is a fashionista,
too.
All right. Love you.
[ Laughs ]
What's up, Carl?
Hey.
Yo.
Hey, hey. I got your e-mail.
Okay.
And I got to be honest,
Carlos is gonna say this
is just decent.
Decent?
Well, why just decent?
Because the numbers
are too conservative
for the Latin market.
Too conservative?
Yes.
Come on, Omar. You know you can
do these numbers in your sleep.
Think so?
I know so.
And I know you can do better.
Hold on.
I got to make this call.
Okay.
[ Cellphone rings ]
Hey.
Hey, uh, I got your text
about dinner.
Um, yeah, babe, whatever you
want to make, I'm -- I'm easy.
I don't have a, you know,
preference.
Okay, sure, sure.
Also, um, while I have you on
the phone, I wanted to ask if
it's okay that we can RSVP for
the gala I was telling you
about.
Uh, the gala, the gala.
That's t-the 12th, right?
Yeah, the gala I've told you
about a couple times.
Um, see, yeah, the 12th --
the 12th, babe, um, we are --
This merger -- we are so busy
right now that I will not be
able to make that.
Um, it's the numbers.
There's a lot goin' on.
So I think that --
[ Cellphone chimes ]
Look, I got to get this phone
call -- Rosa's Wagon is callin'
in from New York, and I got to
close this deal.
So let me call you back, okay?
All right. Um...
All right. Bye.
B --
Bye.
My bad. Um...
It's okay. I understand.
I know that, uh, checkin' in
comes with the territory once
you're married.
So I totally get her.
Yeah, of course you do,
'cause you girls stick together.
That's right! Girl power!
[ Both laugh ]
That's sweet, though.
What's that?
You know, checkin' in.
You love your wife?
Yeah, I love my wife.
I mean, yeah.
I mean, I've known my wife since
we were in the fourth grade.
I mean, we were --
we weren't married that long.
I mean... [ Laughs ]
Um, but yeah, I mean, we have
our ups and downs, but, uh,
I love my wife. A lot.
Wait a minute, what's go --
what's goin' on in that head,
Ms. Kareena?
Okay. I -- I said okay.
I -- I believe you.
Okay, well, I believe I need
to make a phone call to
Rosa's Wagon in New York.
So get back to work.
You know what? Fine.
'Cause I got a client to call,
too.
You ain't the only one.
Okay.
'Cause money calls.
I know, Ms. Money.
Go make that money, then.
That's right.
Mm-hmm.
You know what?
Whatever, I'm comin' back here
in 15 minutes when I'm done.
I bet you are.
15!
Yeah, yeah.
Greg.
Rosa's Wagon. Omar Wright here.
Hey, Ms. Wright.
Hey, sweetie. Thank you.
Dad isn't home yet?
No, he's still at work.
Come on in.
Oh, Ms. Wright,
did I tell you?
I'm in the summer aviation
program.
Aviation program?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So you want to fly planes?
Well, I want to start off
as a pilot then,
one day, own my own airline.
Aw, Noelle, that's amazing.
Keep your head right where it's
at.
You have my class next year?
Mmm, third period.
Hey.
You know, Ms. Wright,
I could have jumped that fence
and went through the window, but
I was so hungry.
Thank you so much for this meal.
You're welcome, sweetie.
But isn't that crazy dog
over in the next yard?
Yes, ma'am.
Noelle, don't you
ever jump that fence.
I can outrun that dog.
No, you can't.
The dog has four legs.
You only have two.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, hey, Mr. Wright.
Hey, what's up, Noelle?
Hey, your father's outside in
the front for you.
Oh, okay.
Well, thank you, Ms. Wright.
You're very welcome.
See you later, girl.
She's a good kid.
I mean, she seems trustworthy.
I don't know why her father just
doesn't give her keys to the
house.
He's a man.
Sometimes men do stupid things.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing, nothing, just a
joke.
Maybe you'd have got it if I
sent it via text or e-mail.
maybe.
[ Laughs ]
I know what you tryin' to do.
Mm-hmm.
Tryin' to bait me
into an argument.
Hmm, but I'm not
gonna go for it.
What's up your butt?
We are disconnected, Omar,
like, seriously.
I mean, I've said it before.
But you don't get it.
Our communication sucks.
Okay.
So, we're disconnected. Okay.
So, you want to communicate?
Okay. If you want to
communicate, let's communicate.
I can't remember the last time
you asked me how
Wrights Investments was doin'.
Okay.
How's your business goin'?
Oh, it's great, honey.
It'd be even better if my wife
was a little bit more supportive
of me.
You need me to be more
supportive of you?
Did I really
just hear you say that right?
Yeah. You heard me.
I mean, come on.
When's the last time you came up
to the office and helped around?
Excuse me, when was the last
time I was even invited to your
office?
Carmen, come on. I mean,
you really got to be invited up?
You can just come.
That just goes to prove
that you've been slackin'.
Slacking?
Wow. Really?
Who helped start your business
from the ground up?
'Cause it sure
as the...wasn't a slacker.
Did a slacker pay the mortgage
and all the other bills for a
year-and-a-half when you started
your business?
Did a slacker do
your business proposal
or prepare your paperwork for
three years before you could
even afford to hire someone?
I'm sorry.
Is that not supportive?
I didn't say you weren't
supportive.
Okay, you want to know what my
problem is?
It's the rollin' of your eyes,
the suckin' of the teeth every
time I have to go on my phone
or whether it rings or --
or you trippin' out
when I come home late.
It's like you have a problem
with the success of me
and my business.
No.
I have a problem with the fact
that we don't spend quality time
together, Omar.
And I don't think that's asking
too much.
Seriously, it's like you have
a better relationship
with your electronic devices
than you do with your own wife.
What are you talking about?
You have too many
distractions
in your life, plain and simple.
Look, all I need from you
is some more attention.
And I need some more time.
That's it.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
Oh...
Okay. [ Laughs ]
I didn't plan that.
You did plan -- I think you
did plan it.
Babe, it's business, okay?
Okay, I got it.
It's business, whatever.
Answer it.
You gonna answer it anyway.
Radiation to the brain.
Wait, now,
you know there was a study done
that pets can improve marriages
and relationships?
Maybe -- maybe you guys
should consider getting one,
since you're having issues
conceiving.
Samira, did you forget
I'm allergic to cats?
And he's allergic to dogs.
So we can't even get a pet.
I got it.
A romantic vacation.
Mm-hmm.
Sandy beaches,
a little bikini.
Yes.
Oh, I can't even remember
the last time
we did one of those.
Okay, well --
well then, here's what you do.
Just -- just pack his clothes
and throw it in the trunk, okay?
And then, tell him
that you want to go somewhere
driving or something.
And then, just mysteriously
end up at the airport
on your way to Tahiti.
That's how you do it.
Mmm, Tahiti, yes!
I like that idea.
Yes.
But if it doesn't work,
Samira, I'm flyin' my butt to
divorce court.
Mnh-mnh.
Oh, y'all don't find that
funny?
I don't find it funny at all.
Just a little joke. Okay.
Unh-unh.
All right.
You need to get on that
vacation...
Yes.
And force that excitement and
the adventure right out of that
black man -- you can do it.
Stop, that's what I'm talkin'
about.
That's what I'm talking about.
Shoot, make me want to go home
to my husband and just get it
in.
What --
What, did you...
It's just too bad he's at work.
Gonna get it?
Yeah! I'm gonna get it!
Omar and I, we --
We haven't, uh, gotten it in a
couple months.
Was that months with an S?
Like, plural.
With an S.
Yes.
That's a shock value.
More than two?
No.
'Cause it's workin'.
This shock value is definitely
workin'.
No, I'm so serious,
like, I'm dead serious.
Yeah. I mean,
don't judge me with those faces.
When you guys get 8 years in
your relationship, and, I
mean...
I guess marriages sometimes just
get rocky.
Uh, well, you know
I had my issues with my husband.
I mean, I --
I was gonna do somethin' really
bad, like, really, really bad.
I was gonna be on the special
edition of "48 Hours."
Like, yes, I mean,
I was facing 25 to life
on principle alone.
But what did you do?
You put on that cape.
And you came
and saved Damon's life.
That's what you did,
took all the guns
and knives out my house.
But you did that for us.
And I just know you can get
through this with ease.
Yes, girl, yes.
Look, you and Omar have been
a great example
for me and Jahaad.
Wow. I didn't know
you guys felt that way.
Yeah.
Well, listen, heifers, it's
time for you to put on your
capes.
Well then, uh, girlfriend
superheroes to the rescue.
United!
Exactly.
Capes unite.
I love y'all.
Mmm, this is good.
I appreciate you comin' home
early for dinner.
You know, I heard you the
other night.
I was listenin', and you're
right.
I'm sorry.
Thanks, babe. So...
Mm-hmm?
...I was thinking.
We have not been on a vacation
in quite a while.
Mmm.
And the girls just happened
to be talkin' about Tahiti.
What do you think about that?
Dope. Tahiti sounds dope.
Yeah?
Yeah. I'll mess with Tahiti.
You know, as long as they got
Wi-Fi, I'm good. [ Chuckles ]
Oh, gosh.
I'm playin'.
That's okay.
I mean, is there someplace else
you'd rather go?
Um, we could always go back
to Cancun.
Mmm, I don't think we're
allowed back there.
We've been banned from a couple
of places.
Yeah, we have.
Miami Beach...
Spring break! [ Laughs ]
Okay, lemme just say you was out
of control.
That balcony...
Not my fault.
Well, you and that dark
liquor.
I can't handle my dark
liquor. [ Laughs ]
Yeah.
That's why your boobs came out.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
You, uh, you --
You want to go ahead and get
that?
[ Cellphone chimes ]
Uh, let -- You know what?
Let me just -- just check.
Um... But no, babe, I -- I --
I just want you to know that
I'm -- I'm -- I'm --
I'm listenin' to you.
And you -- You are right.
And...
And I hear everything that
you're sayin'.
So that's why I'm sayin', like,
you know, like, I mean, do you
have any other suggestions?
Um...
What do you think about Mars?
Mm-hmm.
I've always wanted to go there.
I mean, I can probably call
my travel agent.
Omar, give me your phone.
What? We -- we...
Please...
What're you talkin' about?
Please hand me your phone.
Please! Give me your phone.
I would gladly give you my
phone, but I don't bring my
phone to dinner, nor do I sleep
with my phone or shower with my
phone.
I mean, is there
something you're hiding?
How dare you accuse me...
No, no, no, no,
I'm not hiding anything.
Okay, then, fine,
give me your phone.
No!
[ Clears throat ] Okay.
Then can you please
put your phone away because
this is supposed to be my time.
Remember that little promise
you made me today?
My time.
Phone stays where it is.
Now...
What about that vacation?
It's all itemized.
If you guys look at, uh,
line 29, you'll see how much you
made off your investments
in the, uh, 770 accounts.
If you guys have any questions,
e-mail me.
Mmm, nah, nah, we good.
We good. Thank you. Thank you.
First of all, thank you for
givin' us the opportunity
to invest in your, you know,
urban development program.
Thanks, bro.
Yeah.
No, it's cool.
But, uh, you good?
Yeah, I'm cool.
Sure, man?
Okay, it's Carmen.
Like, she's been trippin'
lately, man.
Like, the other night, she
dropped my phone in a glass of
water.
Mmm.
That ain't trippin', man.
That's crazy.
She's been, like, complainin'
and naggin', tryin' to bait me
into arguments.
I -- I -- I don't know, guys.
I'm just gettin' sick of it.
I'm gettin' sick of it.
All right. Look, if you --
if you want an outside opinion
on your marriage, and you're
ready to, you know, listen,
you can handle it, let me know.
So you Dr. Phil now?
No, no, uh, I'm not Dr. Phil.
I'm just sayin', look,
honestly, no disrespect, right?
When we go out as couples,
Jasmine, you know,
she all on my lap.
Samira, she all on his shoulder.
You know, you and Carmen,
you on one side of the room.
Way over there.
She on the other.
For real, it's like the other
night, like, game night.
Y'all look like y'all was about
to have a boxing match or
somethin'.
No, no.
I'm tellin' you. Look --
Look, whatever, man. look.
That's your wife, right?
All she wants is affection.
That's it.
How you think she feels if she
see us with our wives and -- and
you over there in the corner on
your phone?
On that phone, man.
Okay, now, you're just makin'
stuff up.
I'm makin' it up?
Oh, I'm -- I'm tryin' to holla
at you from a place of love,
right?
When the last time you tap that?
Dude, that's...
When the last time?
Disrespectful, man.
What?
Dude, you ain't got no chill.
So disrespectful.
Why you all up in the man's
business?
I'm just sayin', look, I
remember her, like, walkin'
around, right, with the...
She actin' like -- she looked
like she was full of life.
She had a glow.
She had this light about her.
Now, she -- she got this sad
face all the time.
Like, she, you know,
mean-muggin' us and stuff.
Look, enough about my wife,
all right?
I'm sorry I even brought it up.
Look, I'm just sayin'.
That's your wife, right?
She's a woman.
She needs attention -- you know,
she's like a little flower.
You got to water it, show it --
show it attention, love, and
affection.
She wants that from her husband.
I'm tellin' you, you better do
that 'cause there's a lot of
thirsty dudes out there in the
streets.
They could see her comin' from
100 miles away.
Whatever, man.
It's whatever?
It's not -- I mean, that's
not what I mean.
That's not what I'm sayin'.
I see it.
Yeah, yeah.
You got a little side piece.
You got the side joint?
What? No! I love Carmen.
To tell you the truth, I can't
remember the last time we got
busy.
What? What's that?
Can't remember?
That's not cool, dude.
That's no bueno, dude.
That's -- that's no good, homey.
That's bad. That's real bad.
No married man should go 3 days
without havin' sex with his
wife.
Mnh-mnh.
Real talk.
I'm just keepin' it real.
You ask me when's the last time
me and Jasmine did it, I'm gonna
be like, "About an hour ago,
Unh, aye, yeah!"
You ask me when we doin' it
again, I'm gonna be like,
"As soon as she pick me up,
we gonna stop at McDonald's"...
Look, D, I don't want to hear
about your sex life with you
and your wife, all right?
All right, look, I don't care
what you do with your wife.
And I don't care what you do
with your wife.
All right? I've been focusin'
on my business, and that's
probably the reason why I
haven't been thinkin' about sex.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on.
If you havin' problems
down there, I mean, you should
start by changing your diet.
Try, uh...
They got pills.
Organic...
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, you guys don't get it.
Check your e-mail.
No, I'm just sayin', look...
Wait a minute...
It don't matter if you eatin'
organic lima beans or you
gettin' baby-back ribs.
Tap that. Tonight.
♪ So baby let's fire it up ♪
♪ I wants to get funked up ♪
♪ I want to get funked up ♪
♪ From the house back to the
truck, I wants to... ♪
[ Music stops ]
[ Scoffs ]
♪ From the house back to the
truck ♪
♪ I wants to get funked up ♪
♪ Unh, I'm gonna go tonight ♪
♪ Me and my brothers ♪
♪ Gonna roll tonight ♪
What are you doing?
♪ We got it goin' on tonight ♪
Come on, girl.
You know is our thing.
Aw, our thing.
Almost didn't recognize it since
I haven't seen it in months.
So what you sayin'?
You don't want to make love to
your husband?
Of course, I'd like to make
love to my husband, but my
husband's been doin' a...poor
job of showin' his wife
that he loves her.
What? I mean, we can't even have
a simple conversation at dinner,
and you don't pay me attention
on a regular basis.
Yet, all of a sudden,
you want some.
Boy, you need
to try way harder than that.
My god. It's -- it's --
It's like I don't know
who you are anymore.
Like, and for you to insinuate
I don't love you is insane.
Well then, I guess I'm insane
because that's how I feel, Omar.
You drive a luxury car,
you have all these fancy
clothes, you got a successful
husband, you don't have to want
for anything, okay?
You live a comfortable life.
That's comfortable?
I don't give a...about any of
that.
Babe, what happened to flowers
and cards for no reason,
just because,
weekly date nights,
intimate, passionate kisses that
led to hours of love-making?
What happened to that?
Girl, this ain't no romance
novel.
This is the real life,
right here.
Well, that -- that's not the
life I signed up for.
And by the way, romance novels
used to be our life.
Stop. Wait. Where you goin'?
Noelle, you need to ask your
father for a key to the house.
I did ask him.
What he say?
I'm not responsible enough.
Noelle, you 16 years old.
Like, what're you doin'
over there that's makin' you
so irresponsible?
I don't know.
He just says it.
Girl, you better not be
sneakin' no boys over there.
What? I don't even date.
Well, I don't want to kick
somebody's butt.
No, no boys.
But I will need your
Social Security Number.
My Social Security?
Mm-hmm, to claim you on my
taxes for all the food you eat
and all the water you waste.
Funny, I'm a growin'
teenager.
I have to eat.
Hey, Ms. Wright.
Hey, sweetie. I got you
some of those airplane books.
Sweet, did you bring them?
Of course.
Hmm. Ha!
[ Door closes ]
So, um, have you recovered
from last night's episode of
"Scandal," Ms. Washington?
What's this?
I hope you don't fight me.
Are you serious?
As a heart attack.
So this is how you gonna do
me?
You're just gonna give up on us?
You've given up on us
a long time ago, Omar.
Now, you can have everything,
even the house.
I've already closed on another
one, and I'm movin' out on
Sunday.
Wait -- You --
You closed on a house?
And you're movin' out on Sunday?
How long you been plannin' this?
Just think about it.
I really thought I knew
you after all these years.
But right now, you just showed
me who you really are.
This is not about
who I really am.
This is about us and a marriage
that has been tumbling for a
long time.
Well, what if I don't sign
'em?
Then, I'ma show you who I
really am.
I'm gonna go after
Wrights Investments.
So my suggestion to you is just
sign the papers.
I want out.
So you're leaving me?
You left me a long time ago,
Omar.
Please, just sign the papers.
I'm leaving with or without.
Well...you might as well
leave 'cause I ain't signin'
them things.
I'm not signin' them, Carmen!
[ Dog barking ]
You know, we really need to
get out and have a real lunch.
In fact, you know what?
I'll do you one better.
How 'bout one day, I make you
lunch and I bring it here?
Mmm, that sounds great.
Yeah?
...it.
What's wrong?
The Latin accounts, I --
I can't seem to close it.
Like, uh, Carlos is --
is -- is so difficult.
And I, like, I don't know.
I just can't get through to him.
Okay. Pull up the account.
Lemme see it.
Lemme see. Lemme see!
All right.
Okay, would you mind if I gave
him a call?
Sure, be my guest.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. Can I...
Yeah.
[ Clears throat ]
Buenos días, Carlos.
It's Kareena. Ah, gracias.
Muy bien, y tu?
Sí. Bien, bien.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Mm-hmm?
Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Laughs ]
Sí. Gracias.
Adios.
[ Clears throat ]
You should receive that
paperwork in about an hour.
[ Laughs ] Bravo.
Thank you.
Bravo.
Yes.
So you -- you got the deal
closed?
I don't know. Tell me.
How'd you do it?
I'd tell you.
But then, I'd have to kill you.
[ Both laugh ]
No, really, you know what?
All it needed was a little bit
of a woman's touch -- that's it.
I see.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, hey, before I forget...
Uh-huh?
Peter wanted me to ask you --
Are you ready to move
Wrights Investments to Europe?
Oh, come on, Europe again.
Okay. He already mentioned that.
Um, but I turned him -- I turned
it down because my wife and I
wasn't ready to move to Europe.
I mean, it's so far away.
And then, not to mention, I
still have my North American
client list.
I mean, who's gonna take care of
that?
Hello! I would. I can do it.
You?
Yes, me. Come on.
Then, you and your wife can go
off and have an amazing life in
Europe and live happily ever
after.
[ Sighs ]
I, uh, I never even thought --
I just, uh, I just never thought
of it.
But if it's you who's gonna take
over the client list, I actually
really might consider Europe.
Yeah?
Yeah, but I'd be goin' by
myself.
What? Wait, why?
I'm getting a divorce.
Omar.
Yeah.
Oh, my gosh.
I'm so -- I am so sorry.
As of when, though?
As of it just kinda
came out of nowhere.
Oh, gosh, um,
do you want to talk about it?
No, nah, it's cool.
I mean, it's --
it's my cross to bear.
So, I mean, it's whatever.
But, um, but goin' back to Pete,
let's -- let's set that up.
Yeah?
Um, let's get that going
'cause I think, uh, I mean,
Europe sounds nice right now.
Yeah, yeah. Okay. Done.
Wow, I am so scared of marriage.
Why is that?
Oh, if you're scared of
marriage, you're probably just
sayin' that 'cause you haven't
found the right guy.
Uh, thanks. Don't remind me.
What're you talkin' about?
Kareena, you probably got tons
of guys knockin' your door down.
Negative. You know why?
Because guys find successful,
independent women...
They're intimidated by us.
Not me. I think it's sexy.
[ Laughs ]
No, seriously -- In fact,
I think it's your best feature.
So you're sayin' I'm ugly?
No...no!
I think you super bad.
But, you know,
I'm married so I -- I --
I'm not even gonna go there.
I thought you said
you were getting a divorce.
My lasagna's getting cold.
Jahaad.
Yeah?
Turn to me.
What's up?
Are you happy?
Happy?
What do you mean, happy?
I mean, are you happy
being married to me?
Most times, yeah.
I'm very happy.
Just perfect for me.
I just don't ever want us
to get a divorce.
Well, that's not even
on the table for discussion.
Good.
'Cause you know I love you.
I know.
Carmen and Omar
are divorcing.
What? Are you --
Are you serious? Stop playing.
Come on, now you know I
wouldn't play with something
like that.
I was just over at their
house a few days ago.
He did not mention that.
I did call him
a couple times today.
He didn't pick up, though.
Wait, is that why you're asking
if I'm happy?
Mm-hmm.
You know you my other half.
Ain't nobody else
gonna love them dirty underwear.
I don't have dirty underwear.
Wow.
Sorry to hear that about Carmen
and Omar.
That's crazy.
Yeah, it's crazy.
It's just a huge wake-up call.
Look at me.
I'm here, all right?
I ain't going nowhere.
You understand? You understand?
Yes.
Good night.
Give me some covers.
We go to people's weddings.
Mm-hmm.
We throw rice.
We celebrate them.
And then where are we for them
when it's time for them to talk
about getting a divorce?
The...are you talking
about?
You know what I'm talking
about.
Carmen loves this man.
I need you to talk to him today.
Okay.
Don't just, "Okay," me,
Damon -- I'm serious.
I said, "All right."
Shut up and give me a kiss
before you go to work.
Yummy.
Strawberries, I like it.
Gonna take you back in that
house.
Yeah -- Oh, girl, please.
My back, I can't take it.
But if you love me like you
say you love me, go and get get
that door like you would
Halle Berry's.
Get it. Get it.
Hmm. I'm -- I'm bet you I get
that door better than I'd get
Halle Berry's.
Let me see.
Oh, you better get.
[ Laughs ]
Get in the car, woman.
Come on!
That's how I talk to
Halle Berry.
Get in the car! Get in the car.
I can't stand you.
Just 'cause she light-skinned
don't mean I won't tell her
what to do. Come on!
I love you. Have a good day.
I got you.
But call him.
I will.
You promise?
I promise.
Today.
Right now.
Mm-hmm.
You promise?
Twice.
Twice. Twice I got you!
I can't stand you.
You do me like that every day.
All right.
Bye!
Bye.
Wait! I didn't...
I forgot I need a ride to work!
You know what?
You just want to get some in the
car, don't you?
[ Laughter ]
[ Doorbell rings ]
Hey, how are you?
Hello there. How are you?
Good to see you.
Really?
We're past the handshakes.
Give me a hug, woman.
Okay. Oh, gosh.
How's everything?
I'm good, thank you.
Good. Good, good, good.
Um, would you like something
to drink?
Can I get you anything?
No, I'm good.
All right.
I got some bad news.
Have a seat. I won't bite.
Oh, okay.
And I got some bad news.
Okay.
So which one do you want
first?
Uh, I guess
I'll take the bad news that's
right underneath the bad
bad news, so.
It's amazing
what you guys did to this place.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Well, let me get these papers.
Listen, um, this is the dilemma.
The bank is holding things up
because with your name being
on this house with your husband,
and doing a few of
the other properties, and then
you doing this by yourself,
it's kinda, like...
I got you. I got you.
I'm gonna take care of you,
okay?
Okay.
I remember when I first
sold you guys this house.
Mm.
Listen, um,
I really just wanted to say...
Mm-hmm?
I'm sorry to hear
about the divorce.
Thank you. Thank you.
But you know what they say,
right?
One man's trash is
another man's treasure.
I'm pretty sure you won't have
no problems finding you a good
guy.
Did you just call me trash?
I did not.
I think I heard you say
I was trash.
I did not call you trash.
I didn't mean it like that.
It's okay. It's okay.
Thank you.
You welcome. Here you go.
All right, so, what am I
supposed to do with all these
papers?
Just take them to your
attorney and let him look over
them, and then, you can bring
them to our lunch date.
Our lunch date?
Yeah, our lunch date.
Yeah, well, depending on, uh,
how bad this other news is,
it's gonna be a bottled water
lunch.
I like how you slid that in.
It's pretty slick, buddy.
All right.
All right, let me know
the rest of the bad news.
Well, um,
so I went past your place today,
and it's probably gonna be,
like, a week before everything
is done.
No!
Yes. I know.
No! Oh, man.
I've already told Omar I was
gonna move out a couple of days
ago.
Do you know when it's gonna be
ready?
Should be ready by Wednesday,
but, um -- That's all right!
That's all right. I got an idea.
If it's too much problem with
you being here with Mr. Wright,
I mean, I have a few extra rooms
at my place.
You can always stay there.
Really?
What?
I can't do that.
You're not holding up this
process to make me stay with
you, right?
I would never ever do
anything like that.
Just checking.
But it does sound like a
pretty good idea.
No, really, sweetie, I just
want to -- just want to help
you, that's all.
Thank you.
So listen, I know
it's a pretty difficult time,
and probably even a premature
time to ask, but why don't you
let me take you to dinner?
[ Door opens ]
Wright, sir!
How you doing, man?
I'm good.
Good, good. Good.
I had to drop some papers off.
I hope that's okay with you.
Okay. Yeah, it's cool.
How you doing?
I'm good. I'm good, I'm good.
It's amazing what you guys
did to the house, man.
It's absolutely beautiful.
Yeah, well, you know,
we got taste. We're not slobs.
Well, I guess I'll be going
now.
Ms. Wright, think about that
offer, okay?
I will.
All right, now, thank you
for your time.
Thank you.
Mr. Wright.
Always a pleasure, sir.
Yes, sir.
You guys have a good one, okay?
You know what,
let me get the door for you.
Excuse me, honey.
All right, brother.
All right, sir.
Yeah. Have a good one.
You, as well.
Really?
See, that's what I'm talking
about!
Yo, that...me off, man.
I'm telling you.
I hate that snake dudes, right,
just -- just chilling in the
cut, lurking.
Do you not care that your wife
could be cheating on you?
I know my wife better than
you, all right?
Just remember that.
No, I'm just saying, why
am I more...off than you?
Just saying.
No, 'cause you always
overreact.
Uh, what?
No, you overreact.
I'm going to my lawyer today,
getting those divorce papers,
giving them to Carmen --
Whatever makes her happy.
Who is she, man?
Boom.
Yo, that's what I'm saying.
Who's who?
Hoo hoo! What are you, an owl?
Who is she? Or who's he?
Shut up.
I mean, this is Atlanta.
No, you so stupid, all right?
Atlanta.
Well, if you're referring
to Kareena, she's just a friend.
A colleague,
someone who I work with.
♪ But you say she just a
friend ♪
Now the truth comes out.
But you say -- yeah.
Yeah. You see it?
Okay, listen. For the record,
I haven't slept with her.
Okay.
All right -- no, if I --
if I did, I would have told you!
Look, see, all this time
we thinking it's her, and it's
this dude.
Mm-hmm.
Well, she is bad.
Yeah?
But, you know, when me
and Carmen got married,
I was about my baby, man.
You know?
It was like that for my parents,
I thought it was gonna be
like that for me.
Okay, so, after the divorce,
you gonna hit it?
Man, I don't know!
God, what is wrong with this
guy?
No! Listen.
Since I been married,
Carmen's all I've ever known.
Okay?
I don't know, maybe you guys are
right.
Maybe it's time to start
looking towards new things.
Have you guys ever cheated?
You know, I've thought about
it.
With this little honey dip at
work, man.
Was fine, too, but, I --
I -- I had to nip that.
Nip that in the bud.
What?
...please. Right?
Right. "I had to --
I had to nip it in the bud."
You bit her in the butt is what
you did -- don't act like you
wasn't -- stop playing, man.
To tell you the truth,
tell you the truth, I think
about it all the time.
...yeah. Plenty of times, man.
Matter of fact, on the way over
here, I, you know, was driving.
I seen two little shorties cross
the street, looking like
Laverne and Shirley.
I was like, boom, immediately,
thought popped into my head,
right?
See, that's what I do.
I let my thoughts play out.
For a very long time.
See, I ain't never
physically cheated.
But in my mind? I'm a ho.
Yeah.
And for that very reason,
I know I'm going to...
Yeah, absolutely.
See, me and the devil,
we on a first-name basis,
you know what I'm saying?
He got my cell phone. Hold up.
I think he texting me right now.
Hold on. Let me see.
Yes, Lucifer. Yes.
What is wrong with you, man?
Nah, I'm playing.
But yo, I-I understand what
you're saying, man.
I love my wife, too.
But it's hard, you know what I'm
saying?
How you gonna not think about
it, at least?
Well, Carmen's my first love.
And I thought she'd be my last.
Look, I've been a loyal husband!
Okay?
Like, when we went to the altar,
and we saying our vows, man,
I meant it -- I meant it.
Yeah. At that time.
We all do.
No, I did!
I know. Then, yeah, I did
too!
I still do!
And I think she did, too,
but now it doesn't matter.
So if anyone's cheating,
it's probably me.
I cheated Carmen out of being
number one, man. Your wife?
Should not have to compete
with anyone or anything.
So focused on my business, I
lost sight of what's important.
You know what's crazy?
Carmen helped me start the
business.
I messed up, fellas.
What about counseling?
You guys ever thought about
that?
Nah, I think it's too late
for that, man.
She don't want nothing to do
with me.
Plus. those counselors, they
don't know -- they don't know
you, they don't know what they
talking about.
It's like, I wish I could just
go back to the beginning and
start over.
Not having Carmen by my side,
man, I feel like I'm out of
business.
Yeah.
So -- So, next week,
after the divorce.
You still gonna hit?
Man, shut up, Damon.
What is -- Ugh.
Just saying.
I can't with you. I can't.
Just trying to live.
Can a brother live?
Hmm, so, thank you
for bringing me to lunch.
No problem!
I know this is about more
than lunch, because not often
do you ask me out
in the middle of the week.
That bozo August?
He asked if I'd like to stay
in his spare room
until my place is ready.
And you said?
Well, I told him no.
But the more I think about it,
I should take him up on his
offer.
Um, Samira and I both have
rooms that you can stay in.
So you're fine.
I know. I know, but the thing
is, I don't want to impose on my
best friends and your
relationships just because mine
is in the can.
Um, ma'am.
Do you hear yourself?
'Cause you sound crazy.
You will stay with us.
Oh, no, but you know what,
if you do stay with him, let
me tell you how it's gonna go.
Oh, you're gonna get there,
y'all gonna cuddle.
You gonna spoon with him
a little bit.
Then you're gonna have sex with
him, then you're gonna become
another notch on his belt.
And then, boom!
He's gonna throw you out
like an orange peel.
Carmen, you are slipping.
Really, Jasmine?
That's a lot.
What do you mean, I'm slipping?
You have completely lost your
mind!
Do you hear yourself?
that fool should have not even
had the audacity or the balls,
even, to ask you any mess like
that.
The Carmen that I know, love,
and admire for the amazing woman
that she is would have
told him off very kind-like.
I just don't want to impose
on you and Samira.
Plus, I don't have the money
for a hotel right now.
I mean,
I'm giving Omar everything.
That's just as much
your house as it is Omar's.
You sleep in the bed,
and put him on the couch.
Did Omar ask you to leave?
No.
Oh, good,
'cause he know I'm crazy.
I'm sure Damon has told him
a whole lot of stories about me.
I mean, but my marriage
is practically over, right?
I don't see the problem in me
taking that man up on his offer.
Do you hear the insanity
that continues to spew out
of your mouth?
You have lost
your mind completely!
Carmen, inviting a third party
into a pending marriage is
insane.
A few days. That's it.
That's all it is.
Just a few days!
Okay, you know what?
This is simply disappointment.
Because they say
disappointment triggers
temporary insanity, and, honey?
You are acting out.
You are completely irrational.
I just hate that Omar is
coming out of this relationship
and this marriage without a
scratch.
Waiter, come on. You -- okay.
This is all about Omar.
You're doing this to get back at
him!
I can eat now.
I'm gonna need a dessert and a
key lime pie to go with my
order.
Where is the waiter?
Let me get this, um, six fried
chicken wings, two coleslaws,
and a basket of fries.
And let me get a Diet Coke
with that.
Yeah.
Hey.
Uh, did you want a sandwich?
No, I, um,
just had lunch with the girls.
Papers are on the counter.
And yeah, I signed them.
Yeah, no.
Yeah, you did sign it.
Um, my place won't be ready
until the end of the week,
so I was wondering if I could
stay here on the couch until
then.
So how about a hotel?
Just figured I asked.
You know,
it's that attitude of yours,
is why we're here now.
Are you seriously telling me
that I can't sleep here?
I mean,
why did you even ask me?
Out of respect, Omar.
Why are you so callous
about everything?
Everything like what?
Everything like everything!
...Carmen, I signed the
papers!
What more do you want from me?
I'll just go to a hotel.
Oh, yeah, there goes Carmen,
acting like a spoiled brat
again.
Spoiled brat?
I'm a spoiled brat?
I am leaving this marriage
with nothing but my clothes.
Now, this relationship
has been in trouble a long time.
And you know that.
No, I didn't know that.
Yeah, Carmen, we had problems,
but every married couple does.
You were working on a divorce
right under my nose, and then
you go and close on a place?
Baby, you leaving me.
So you really think I give
a...where you lay your head
at night?
Please.
Look, Carmen. I'm sorry.
Okay, you can stay here
as long as you'd like.
It's okay.
I'll get a hotel room
until my place is ready.
No, just stay.
No, I don't want you
to have to do me any favors.
I'm not.
But I'll sleep better knowing
that you're safe.
Omar.
Yeah?
What happened to us?
Geez, Carmen, I don't know.
I mean, I guess couples
just grow out of love, I guess.
I don't know.
[ Sighs ]
♪ Sweet Sunday ♪
♪ Waiting for you all night ♪
♪ When you kissed me ♪
♪ You lovely boy ♪
♪ You give me sweet ♪
Car. Car, sit up.
[ Coughs ]
Here, I made you some tea.
Thank you, baby.
But you need to go away
before you get sick.
Mnh-mnh.
When you sick, I'm sick.
Thank you. [ Coughs ]
♪ Lifeless time ♪
♪ Sweet Sunday ♪
♪ We feel alive ♪
Everything okay?
They've got me jumping
through these unnecessary hoops
for my broker's license that
they don't have everyone else
jumping through.
Like, I just want to say,
"Forget it."
No, you don't.
You can do unnecessary
hoops in your sleep.
You smart like that.
You the man like that.
You see, that's one of the
billions of reasons why I
married you.
Yes, I can't wait to tell
Jasmine and Samira a billion.
I beat ya. [ Laughs ]
Man, they can't hold a candle
to us.
They can't, huh?
Or the moon, or the sun?
You believe in me?
Yeah, baby.
All day. Every day.
Hungry?
Uh, yeah.
I mean, in a minute.
Sit out here and take it all in.
Okay.
♪ Just watching ♪
♪ Sweet Sunday ♪
♪ You gave me a life ♪
Uh, hey. I, um -- Morning.
I made some, uh, extra
breakfast -- a little too much,
probably.
Force of habit.
But I can make you a plate
if you like.
No, it's okay, I have a
breakfast meeting with Kareena,
which I'm already late for,
but, uh, I'll take you up
on your Waffle House-smelling
breakfast next time.
Okay.
Have a good one.
You too.
So, thanks for signing
the rest of the papers.
We should have you squared away
in a few days.
Oh, finally. Thank you.
Yeah.
But, thank you for this
breakfast.
It is absolutely delicious.
You're welcome.
Listen, I really appreciate
this and all, but, uh, how about
that dinner we talked about?
Okay, this isn't
a breakfast date, August.
It's just leftovers.
Just, you know,
not made for you, specifically.
Mm-hmm.
Just me being thoughtful.
Bit of my Southern hospitality.
Okay, um. Dinner?
You keep stressing
this dinner thing.
Yes, because dinner
ain't never killed nobody.
Well, I watch the news,
and it's gotten a couple people
killed, dinner. [ Laughs ]
Yes, dinner.
And don't make me beg, because
it don't look good on my résumé.
Okay.
Well, I mean, it's just dinner.
Mm-hmm. Just dinner.
Yeah, I mean...I've been
stressed a lot, so, uh, I could
use a night on the town.
Why not? It's just dinner.
Yeah, let's -- let's --
Let's do dinner.
But we're gonna do it Dutch.
Please, Dutch is not
an option.
Oh, come on, isn't that what
the cool kids do these days?
Mnh-mnh. Not an option, lady.
Okay. But you cannot
come pick me up here, okay?
That would not be a good idea
with Mr. Wright.
7:00?
7:00 it is.
Tell you what.
I'm gonna text you a time and a
location in about an hour.
Okay.
All right?
Mm-hmm.
Let's shake on it.
You all right with me.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, Noelle, how's that, uh,
fall program going?
It's good. Here's your mail.
Thank you.
What's going on?
Why you sitting out here
looking all sad?
Is it true?
Is what true?
You and Mr. Wright are
getting a divorce?
I -- I wasn't eavesdropping.
I just heard you guys talking
when I was coming up from the
basement.
So, is it true?
Yeah. It's true.
But why?
I guess sometimes people
just fall out of being in love.
Like my dad and Ms. Louis?
I don't know.
What's going on with your dad
and Ms. Louis?
They had this big argument
about my dad loving my mom,
but I don't understand.
I understand.
See, it's probably a lot more
than just about your dad
loving your mom.
Love and being in love --
two totally different things
to us grown folks.
So, wait.
Your dad's dating Ms. Louis?
Yeah.
So why don't you just
sometimes go down to her place
when you're locked out?
She's only a few doors down.
Because I like being
around you and Mr. Wright.
It's fun being in a two-parent
household.
And I know you guys
don't have the perfect marriage,
but I see how you guys look
at each other, Ms. Wright.
And that's love.
But why don't marriages ever
work out?
No, come here.
Look at me. Now, look.
I know your parents had a
divorce and I know that
Mr. Wright and I are going
through a divorce, but there are
plenty of marriages out there
that work.
It's just that both parties have
to be willing to work at it.
You understand?
Yeah.
Ms. Wright?
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Wright is a good person.
And he teaches me a lot about
life.
Can you please just take him
back and show me that marriages
work?
Come here.
[ Sighs ]
Absolutely. Okay.
Talk to you soon.
[ Laughs ]
Whoo!
Kareena, sweetheart,
I would like to thank you again,
on a job well done.
Uh-huh. You rock.
You know, Peter's still
hounding me about that answer
from you.
I'm gonna take it.
You are?
Mm-hmm.
Yep, I already put my house
on the market, so if you know
anyone who's looking for a
five-bedroom house in Buckhead,
okay?
Let them know about my place.
Duly noted.
Well, then I guess I should
thank you for leaving me
with all of your clients here.
Hey, no problem.
You know, I think
you're gonna be great, you know?
They're gonna really like you.
Oh, I know.
I agree -- [ Laughs ]
Um, so, thank you.
Um, I couldn't have done it
without you.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Mm!
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah.
[ Clears throat ]
I should probably go.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, I got to go to, um...
What? I mean, it's happy
hour, downstairs at the café.
Yeah?
Want to grab a drink?
You want to do something?
No, that sounds great.
That's -- yeah.
Okay.
Well, let me close up here, and,
uh, I'll hit you in a minute.
Okay. Okay, cool.
Okay.
Hey.
Wow, um, I haven't seen you
dress like that in a long time.
Where you going?
Just out.
Out where?
To dinner.
So, you bought a new dress
just to go to dinner?
No, Omar.
This dress has been in the
closet for a very long time,
actually.
Oh, well, I -- I've just
never seen you wear it.
You've never given me
a reason to.
Uh, so, um, who you going to
dinner with?
Just a friend.
O-One of the girls?
No, with a guy friend.
Okay, um...
Look, I'm allowing you to stay
here until you get your place
situated, but I will not
let you disrespect me.
Oh, no disrespect. Mnh-mnh.
But how was your breakfast
meeting with Kareena?
That was business, Carmen!
And besides, I told you
who I was having breakfast with!
I mean, you really think I'm
gonna be cool with you going to
dinner with some dude dressed
like that?
Dressed like what?
Look, I told you
I could stay at a hotel.
Would you like me to stay
in a hotel?
Man, do whatever you got to
do.
I don't need you to tell me
that.
I'm grown.
Not to mention, almost single,
since you signed those stupid
divorce papers.
Okay, you acting
real out-of-pocket right now.
Here we go.
Yeah, here we go!
You're playing games, Carmen,
and you know it!
I am not playing games, Omar.
I am just wearing
a little red dress.
You know, people get dressed up
when they go out to dinner
to restaurants.
I know it's been a long time
and you probably don't
recognize that,
Mr. Soon-to-be-Ex-Husband.
Okay, now, you listen to me.
I am still your husband
and you are still my wife
until that judge stamps
those divorce papers,
do you understand me?
Okay. But I'm not having this
conversation with you right now.
Wait a minute,
I'm not done talking!
No, come here!
I'm not done talking to you!
What are you doing?
You're not going.
Stop it.
[ Moaning ]
♪♪
So, you put it down, he fell
back in love, and your marriage
is saved, right?
I don't know.
I woke up this morning,
he was already gone for work.
But I do love that man.
That is so obvious.
What do you want Omar to do?
I want him to fight!
Fight for me.
Fight for our marriage.
the same way he fought for his
company to be where it is today.
So why are you going through
with this divorce?
I didn't think he'd actually
sign the papers.
[ Laughs ]
Stop. Don't laugh.
Okay. Yeah, no.
He called your bluff.
Yes, he called my buff.
But I didn't know what else to
do!
I felt like -- I felt like
I was at my wit's end.
All I can say is,
we're here for you.
So you guys -- you guys think
it was wrong for me to make him
sign the papers?
Uh, yes, ma'am.
You were dead-wrong.
You ambushed the man!
It was like a --
[ Imitating machine gun ]
Mob hit!
He didn't even know what to do!
I -- I'm sorry. You know what?
We're not here to beat you up.
We're here to build you up.
Well, I have no doubt that
you guys are gonna get back
together, okay?
He's not gonna let you get away.
He's way too smart to be stupid.
Well, let's hope so.
Yes.
Because I just
want my husband back.
I want you to have
that man back, too.
[ Door opens ]
What's -- What's going on?
Uh, you were gone
this morning when I got up.
And when I didn't hear
from you all day,
I just, uh, I didn't want
to steer away from plans.
I just kept packing.
So you're taking the dishes?
Because I thought you said
you weren't taking anything
outside the house
except your clothes.
Well, I don't have to take
the dishes, if that's a problem.
No. No, baby, it's cool.
I mean, if you need them, take
them.
I'm just saying, whatever you
take, just let me know
because I'm gonna have Kareena
put most of this stuff on eBay.
I'm so tired of hearing
that name.
Um, why are you selling things
on eBay?
I'm selling the house.
This house?
Yeah.
Why are you selling our
house?
Peter made me an offer
and asked if I would take
Wrights Investments to Europe.
I said yes.
Wow.
I leave next month.
Congratulations.
You're finally able to go
to Europe.
I'm sure that, uh, that success
should make you happy.
How long, um...
How long was this offer
on the table?
A few days after you gave me
those divorce papers.
So that's why you didn't
put up a fight to sign them.
Well, have fun in Europe.
Finally done.
Yes, yes, yes.
This is, like, so surreal.
What is?
This.
Oh, August.
Um, we should probably talk.
Okay, well, talk.
Look, I don't want to mislead
you or anything.
No! I really think you're a nice
guy, but this all pulling me in
and getting close, that's a
little too soon, it's a bit
much.
So how much time do you need
me to give you?
That's the thing.
I don't know.
I mean, my divorce isn't even
finalized.
Okay, well,
take as long as you need.
Thank you.
You know the first day
you walked in my office,
I wanted you.
August! I was married!
And I totally respected that.
But now you're single.
And still so, so fine.
I mean, you can't blame me for
being the first guy putting my
bid in.
I don't know what to say,
though.
Don't say nothing.
Tell you what.
Let's just take it one day
at a time, can we do that?
Yes. Please,
let's do one day at a time.
One day at a time?
Yeah, that's good.
Let me ask you a question.
Do you still love Omar?
I do. I do.
That's good.
Because that tells me
you're a good woman.
But, one thing for sure,
two things for certain,
you spend enough time with me?
I'm gonna break the wall in.
Oh, are you? [ Laughs ]
I am. I am!
Okay, well, can you help me
break with these boxes for now?
I can do that.
Oh.
Thank you.
[ Dog barking ]
Noelle! What are you doing?!
No. No, no, no.
This can't be true.
Oh, gosh.
Oh, I can't believe this is
happening.
[ Gasps ]
I wasn't gonna
let him kill me.
I was just gonna let him bite me
a few times.
Girl, what?
What am I gonna do with you?
I thought that maybe if I got
hurt, then you and Ms. Wright
would work out your marriage.
Oh, sweetheart. No.
No, no, no, no.
Listen, don't worry about me
and Mrs. Wright.
I mean, I appreciate it, but
we'll -- we'll -- we'll work it
out, okay?
Okay.
You're too smart and pretty
to be doing stuff like that.
Okay, here comes my dad.
Are you gonna tell him?
No, but you pull a stupid
stunt like that again, I will.
I think divorce is stupid.
Okay, now I'm gonna tell him.
Okay, okay!
Sup, Mike?
What's good?
Hey, Daddy!
Sup, baby girl, how you
doing?
Good.
You all right?
Yes.
Good, good. Good.
Hey, run over to the house.
Let me holla at O real quick.
Okay.
Bye, sweetheart.
Hey, what's up, buddy?
What's good, man?
Look at you. How's work?
It's work. You know.
Yeah.
Listen, man, I want to thank you
guys for everything y'all have
done for my daughter, man.
Hey, no worries.
You know, Noelle's welcome
over here any time.
She's like family.
Yeah, man.
You doing a great job with
her.
Well, you know,
I'm trying, man. I'm trying.
Hey, can I holla at you real
quick?
Yeah.
Um, listen.
Noelle was crying the other
night.
Yeah, and when I asked what was
wrong, she said it was because
you guys was getting a divorce.
Yeah.
Listen, brother.
Look, I know it's none of my
business, but if you can work
that thing out, try to.
Don't make the mistake I did.
You know?
Y'all are good people, man.
Y'all good for each other.
So.
Yeah, thanks.
All right.
All right. Thank you.
I understand.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Hey, um, my company gets those
tickets for the Hawks game.
We'll go check one out.
That's what's up.
First round on me.
Let's go.
All right, let me hook up
these noodles.
Yeah, yeah.
Holla at you later.
See you, buddy. Yeah.
[ Doorbell rings ]
Hey!
Hi.
Come on in.
Thank you.
Ah, Kareena, thank you.
Well, I, uh, whipped up some,
uh, spicy teriyaki shrimp
with sauteed spinach and
garlic-dipped roasted redskin
potatoes.
Mmm.
And if you have some room
in your stomach for some dessert
after that, I made my
grandmother's homemade recipe
for her baked apple crumb pie,
with in-season Kelly Green
Granny apples.
Oh!
[ Laughs ] Go ahead.
[ Clears throat ]
Voilà.
And you're welcome.
I do not know what to say.
This -- This looks great.
Kareena, thank you.
You're welcome. Here you are.
Mm-hmm.
And...ahh!
Thank you.
Mm-hmm! So?
Are you excited about the move
yet?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, actually, I am.
Good!
Because I was thinking that
I could take my two week vacay
and I can come out there and
help you set up.
Oh! Okay, that's great.
I mean, so, where would you be
staying?
With you.
Kareena, my wife already
thinks we're messing around.
But we're not.
Okay, you know what, it --
Wow. It makes me laugh that
two good-looking professionals
who are of the opposite sex,
what, we can't work together
without somebody thinking that
we're sleeping together?
Relationships and marriage
I guess are just something that
I will never be able
to figure out, I don't know.
Yeah. Makes two of us.
Yeah, because I haven't --
I haven't been in a relationship
in about three years.
And when I was, I was actually
supposed to get married.
But the week before my wedding,
he tells me that he's been
hiding his newborn.
...
Yeah.
So what'd you do?
Everything.
I bounced back, okay?
I focused on me, I went to
school and got my master's, and
look -- now I'm working with
you!
And I am really, really looking
forward to Europe.
God.
I love a woman with tenacity
and ambition.
Thank you.
And I know what I want,
and I want you to be successful.
Kareena, I -- I don't get it.
What?
How are you single?
I got to tell you,
that guy messed up.
He didn't see a good thing
right in front of him.
I know. And neither does she.
You are so beautiful.
Thank you.
And your wife is really lucky,
because if I had somebody like
that, I would never give him up.
Just...
Carmen. Oh.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Um.
Carmen...
Is that why you did not fight
for our marriage?
Carmen, what are you talking
about?
You're the one
who wanted a divorce, not me!
Is that really
all you have to say to me, Omar?
Look, what are you even doing
here?
Why is she here?!
You'll never know why I'm here.
You think I wanted this?
I didn't want this!
They better be glad
I was nowhere near there.
Body parts would have been
flying everywhere.
Y'all know we have been
trying to have a baby forever.
And then this happens --
This happens now?
I never even thought I would
think this, but I might consider
just getting rid of it.
Wh -- Okay, now you just
talking stupid.
Jasmine.
My plan was never to have a baby
by myself.
No, no, no, no.
You know we don't believe
in abortions, okay?
We got your back. All right?
I mean...you can give
the baby my last name.
You guys have been trying
to have a child for a long time.
Yep.
This -- Oh, I can't believe
this happened.
This baby is a blessing.
I'ma be an auntie.
At the end of the day,
I'll be an auntie.
And we got to celebrate that.
It -- girl,
where you put the glasses at?
Is the vodka in there?
Well, you gonna have some milk.
It's okay, baby.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, so this is, uh, my home.
So, what do you guys think?
It's amazing.
It is perfect.
God.
And how about that bathroom?
Right. And the closet? Oh!
She loved the closets.
Already on it.
Love it. I love to hear that.
I loved the patio, too.
It's perfect.
I'm not sure if you guys have
any kids, but we have a great
school system, so, I mean...
Yeah.
This house is great for
children.
Oh, and the living room
is gonna be the perfect size
for all of them.
Yeah, so hopefully we can do
some business, sell the house
rather quickly 'cause I got some
business in Europe, uh, so,
yeah, but, uh, thank you.
Absolutely, Omar.
Thank you so much for the
opportunity to check it out.
Thank you so much.
Mr. Wright, thanks for your
time, I really do appreciate it.
Oh, this -- come off, Lis,
you know you my girl.
Thank you, guys.
Have a good day, okay?
Thank you.
Hey, um...
Uh, excuse me,
what are you doing?
Well, I just came by to --
Wait, wait, wait.
You -- I know you're not about
to sell the house, right?
Yeah, Samira,
I'm about to sell the house.
Don't act like you don't know
what's going on, okay?
Look, I'm not
in the mood to talk.
I appreciate, you know, you guys
trying to...
Okay, well, look, I just came
over because I need to talk to
you about something, so...
Talk to me about what?
You know what, forget it.
No! But, I just...
Bye! I'm not in the mood.
Goodbye.
Oh, hey.
Hey, Kareena.
Um, I called you, earlier.
I know. I'm sorry,
I couldn't take your call,
but I knew you wanted to talk to
me about something. What's up?
Yeah, well,
I heard from Peter,
and he suggested that
I take you to Europe as my VP.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Oh my -- Are you serious?
Yeah.
Wow. Okay, first -- don't
look at me that way -- I didn't
have anything to do with this.
I'm not, no. No, I know.
I swear. I promise you.
No, I promise, I believe you.
Okay, so, what did you tell
them?
I told him that I would
c-consider it.
So you're consi--
You're considering taking me
to Europe?
As my VP. Europe, yay.
Oh, my gosh, this is awesome!
This is awesome. Thank you.
No, I mean.
You will not regret this.
I promise you.
You and me, together in Europe?
We're gonna make magic together.
Yeah, take on Europe
by storm, huh?
Yes we will.
I mean, think about it!
Europe has a slough
of untouched territory.
And it won't take us long to
launch, because think about it,
all we have to do is use the
same formula that we use here
over there, and then by the
time...
Hey.
Okay, what's wrong?
Nothing.
Omar?
Okay, does this have anything
to do with what happened,
you know, the other night?
Um...
Because...
Your wife.
This is about your wife.
Yeah, um, Kareena,
I like you a lot.
But I love my wife.
And this between you and I?
It can't happen.
So, unfortunately, I'm gonna
have to say no to Europe, but
I'm gonna tell Peter yes for
you.
Yeah, I think you will be great
in Europe.
No, no, Omar. I can't do it.
Listen to me, listen.
Just hear me.
You worked so hard --
Just listen to me.
I think you can take Europe
by storm and set up your own
brand, your -- your own name.
You're that good.
Yeah, that sounds great.
That sounds really great.
So, um, I'll --
I'll talk to you later.
Yeah, sure.
We can talk about
the numbers tomorrow
and all the logistical stuff.
You know, how we do.
Yeah.
Okay. See you later.
♪ My type of lady ♪
♪ Street sweeper baby ♪
♪ Whoa, my type of lady ♪
All right. Bye.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
Yo.
Hey, what's up, man?
Sup, man? You all right?
Oh, yeah, I'm good.
Samira asked me
to bring you a plate, man.
We know you over here starving
to death.
Man, make sure you tell her
I said thanks.
No doubt.
You know I put your wife
out yesterday, right?
Yeah, she told me, man.
They're only looking out
for you guys, you know?
Yeah, but it's over
between me and Carmen.
Yeah, I --
I don't understand that, O.
I mean, you guys are meant
for each other.
Well, she's divorcing me, Ja.
What don't you understand?
She just did that to get
some attention.
Okay, now you sound
like your wife.
You don't give someone divorce
papers for attention.
She's a woman.
Do they ever really need an
excuse to do anything?
By the way, Carmen's pregnant.
I will dump that whole plate
of food on your head.
She's pregnant, O.
That's impossible.
I'm sterile, and I've been that
way for years.
What are you talking about?
Well, I guess those sperm
counts have risen from the dead,
huh? [ Chuckles ]
Carmen's -- What?!
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Okay, if Carmen's pregnant,
it's probably because she was
messing around.
Oh, come on, man.
Nah, man, she has been
talking to this -- this
Boris Kodjoe real estate-looking
cat.
Really?
Now you're talking crazy.
O, you -- you know Carmen better
than anyone, dawg, and it --
She isn't out there like
that and you know it.
No, no, no, no.
Maybe she's doing this
to keep me from going to Europe.
Come on, dawg. She loves you.
Besides, Samira and Jasmine were
there when she took the test.
Four times. All positive.
[ Chuckles ]
We've been trying to have
children for years.
But now we're going to divorce
court, so -- so what does this
all mean, Ja?
Wait a minute.
I think -- But --
[ Laughs ]
Yo, I'll give up everything for
her and that baby.
I know you will, man.
You better not be playing
with me. You think it's mine?
Of course it's yours, man.
[ Laughs ]
Whoo! Yeah!
I'm having a baby!
Oh, man.
Jahaad, this whole time,
I been pushing Carmen away.
Because part of me felt guilty
that I couldn't give her the
family that she always wanted.
Put my -- my business first,
trying to become this ultimate
entrepreneur.
This whole time
I've been neglecting my baby.
Taking her for granted.
I was selfish.
Yeah.
[ Laughs ] Not any more!
There you go.
Okay, you hear me?
I hear you.
Because I am ready to be a
father.
Man.
But I'm gonna start by being
a better husband.
There you go --
That's what I want to hear.
You better be.
Yeah, you feel me?
Give me some. Give me some!
Congratulations, man.
Thank you, brother.
And that's the night
it happened.
Why I missed dinner.
Mm-hmm.
I am so sorry.
For what? It's for the best.
I mean, congratulations.
What's with the change
of heart?
'Cause you love him.
I can't compete with that.
...I got a better chance
of swimming -- backstroking
across the Pacific Ocean
before I break a woman
who purely loves her man.
You know, I was, um, I was once
married to a woman quite like
you.
You were once married?
August was married.
Really?
Yes, he was.
18 years old, fresh out of high
school, and I was working
on my real estate business
and she, um, she signed up for,
um, the military and eventually
got sent off to war.
She, um, she calls me one day,
and hears this female's voice
in the background.
Uh-oh.
Yeah.
It was the first time we ever
got off the phone without saying
we love each other.
Two days later, I get a call
that my wife, um....
My wife was killed.
But, you know, I mean.
The female's voice she heard was
my, um, my roommate's
girlfriend's voice, I mean.
You know, I was having problems
with the bills and took a
roommate and had too much pride
to tell my wife.
I'm really sorry to hear
that.
Yeah, well.
My motto now is --
"If you love them, tell them."
Because believe me when I tell
you, a person is here today
and they gone tomorrow.
Carmen, if you love your
husband, tell your husband.
Thank you, friend.
You're welcome.
Now, um, that bed over back
there that you set up?
Stop it.
You can't blame me for
trying!
I can, but I won't.
I know.
Listen, um,
I'm sure you'll figure it out,
but, I better be going.
I got a meeting
in about an hour, okay?
Thank you.
Okay? We'll talk later.
Yeah, mom.
Yeah. No, everything's --
Everything's great -- I've just
been really, really busy.
Yeah.
How's Carmen?
Carmen is Carmen.
Hey, mom, when dad was alive,
how'd you guys make your
marriage work?
'Cause I want to work.
♪ Silence is loveless ♪
♪ The words you don't speak ♪
♪ Speak for you ♪
♪ If the caged bird don't sing ♪
♪ then what's it's use to me ♪
♪ It's like a chef ♪
♪ without a recipe ♪
♪ No food for thought ♪
♪ I hope that clarity ♪
is saving you, saving me ♪
♪ From a broken heart ♪
"Dear Carmen,
Would you please be my
girlfriend?
Yes, maybe, no.
♪ Today I'm gonna find
a better way ♪
P.S., please say yes.
What are --
What are you doing?
♪ Oh, that's right ♪
I wrote it in fourth grade.
Carmen, I know you're pregnant.
I came here to fight for you.
You are going back home with me
if I have to burn this house
down.
Baby, I hear you. I see you.
I'm so sorry for all my selfish
crap, pushing you away.
I always felt bad I couldn't
give you the family that you
deserve.
That family we always wanted.
Carmen,
I don't even know what --
Okay. Okay.
Remember six years ago,
when we went to the doctors,
a-and he said, um, it would be,
like, one-in-a-billion chance
that you would be able to
conceive?
Carmen, the fact that you are
pregnant is a sign.
It's a sign, baby.
And I'm willing to do whatever
it takes to win you back.
♪ Today is a miracle ♪
This is me and you.
It's always been me and you.
♪ Oh, that's right ♪
Carmen.
Carmen Elizabeth Wright.
I love you. And I always have.
Since the fourth grade.
I don't want to lose you.
And I don't want to lose you.
I love you, Omar Wright.
I love you so much.
And then some. A whole bunch.
Nice.
Yeah.
And I love her even more.
You know what?
What?
I love her more, too.
Let's have another.
I'm -- Let's start now.
[ Both laugh ]
♪♪