- There exists within the planet Earth a fantastic lost world.
In this inner world, elite warriors ride huge spiders
and bravely fight against evil. When the wicked rise,
the word goes out... "Calling all Spider Riders!"
- ♪♪ Calling all Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride, ride, ride
♪ Spider Ride like we do If you're true then you could be too ♪
♪ It's cool, you can join our team no matter how tough it seems ♪
♪ If you look, the power's inside ya, so strive to be a brave rider ♪
♪ We're riding on So now we're calling all ♪
♪ Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride Yes, let's ride ♪
♪ I'm holding on the line, yeah I know I will survive ♪
♪ We ain't afraid to fight In the heart of the dark we are the light ♪
♪ Your faith in the battle's sealed 'cause we trained to gain the skills ♪
♪ Yup, we're the ultimate The power that's within waves in the hand ♪
♪ We're riding on So now we're calling all ♪
♪ Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride Yes, let's ride ♪
♪ I'm holding on the line I know I will survive ♪
♪ Calling all Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride! ♪
- I wouldn't celebrate yet!
- Buguese!
- Big mistake, Buguese! - That's right! Let's stomp some bugs!
Electra Twist!
[Screams]
- Hunter!
- Aqune!
- Oracle's Light!
- I don't believe it...
- It can't be!
- Aqune!
[Evil laugh]
- No, Aqune!
- The Oracle Key...
- ...and all its power...
- ...taken away!
- Ha! Ha! Ha!
At last, we Invectids have reclaimed
what is rightfully ours!
How does it feel, knowing you've been betrayed
by one of your own, Spider Riders?
- The Spirit Oracle has abandoned you, Hunter.
- Give it back, Aqune!
[Screams]
- [Both]: Hunter!
- Please, give it back, Aqune!
The key belongs to us!
- You're wrong, Hunter Steele. - Huh?
The power of the Oracle
is for all living things...
We simply choose to use it
to destroy you pathetic Spider Riders!
- You're all heart, Buguese.
- And while you fight your last battle here,
Beerain will snatch the Oracle Key of Nuuma!
- Find the Oracle Key of Nuuma
and destroy the city!
- No! Arachna is defenceless!
- Sparkle is in danger!
- Igneous, Prince Lumen,
leave Buguese and Aqune to us. Protect Arachna!
- Hunter!
- No, he's right! Good luck then, Hunter! - No worries!
Never give up, Prince Lumen!
- Igneous, let's ride! - Flame! Go!
- And now to finish you... Aqune!
- Portia!
Come to your senses, Portia!
- Ha!
[Scream]
- Magma's been hit!
- It's the Oracle Key's power!
- She's using it against her own kind!
Hunter, I know Aqune is your friend
but somehow we have to stop her!
No matter what it takes!
- It's an Invectid raid!
- Run for cover!
- Let no one stand in your way, my lovelies!
We will find the key, no matter what!
- They're swarming the city!
- Help the people find shelter!
- Just as I feared, the Invectids have come
for the Oracle Key.
Oh, my Queen,
I hope I am brave enough to protect it...
[Door opens] Huh?
- We must get you to safety!
- Let's go then!
- Arrow of Light!
- Hunter, aim for Aqune's mask! - You got it!
[Battle cry]
- Magma!
- Spider Threads!
- Even our spiders can't stop them!
- What do we do?
- Then, we'll have to attack them all at once!
- It won't matter... Show them!
- You have barely scraped the surface of Oracle's power...
Why don't I summon it
and give you a taste?
- Oh man! This is gonna hurt!
- I dreamt this!
- Tornado Whip!
[Screams]
- Oh!
- There are too many of them...
We can't protect the castle much longer!
- Don't give up! We must protect
the Princess and our people!
- Yes, sir!
- Huh?
- Prince Lumen!
- Commander Igneous!
- Sergeant, are the people safe?
- Yes, Prince Lumen!
- Well done! - Where is Princess Sparkle?
- In the castle's shelter, my prince.
- Gather your men.
- Another wave is on the way! - [Together]: Yes, sir!
- We're safe now. There's no way the Invectids will find us here.
- Nothing to fear.
- Are you sure about that, little Spider Rider?
- Huh? - Ha! Ha! Ha!
- I think it's Beerain!
- Beerain of Mantid's Big Four!
- Ha! A dignitary!
- This doesn't have to hurt.
Just hand over the box...
And the Oracle Key inside of it!
Don't worry.
I'll take good care of it!
- Ha! Ha! Ha! How delicious!
The Spirit Oracle's mighty Spider Riders
defeated by her own power!
By one of her own warriors!
Finally we are free to remake this world
in honour of our great Mantid!
Thanks to my Aqune.
The era of the humans is over.
Now we Invectids will rule!
[Evil laugh]
- You cannot take the key!
Oh, my Queen!
- No! Wake up!
- He was a fool to resist me...
He could have spared himself that pain.
- Princess!
- At last I hold it in my hands.
I have the Oracle Key!
With this key's power...
...we Invectids will once again rule Arachna!
- Ha! Ha! Ha!
- Hi there!
- Grasshop?
- Ah! I see congratulations are in order, Beerain!
I have always admired your cleverness...
You might be smarter than great Mantid himself!
How wonderful that someone as wise and powerful as you
is willing to share your victory!
- Huh?
- Not very quick, are you?
- Huh? - See ya! Wouldn't want to be ya!
Goody, goody! I've got the key! Now Mantid will like me best
and I'll get to sit next to him at lunch!
- Hey! Give me that back!
- You're not going anywhere, Beerain. - Huh?
- That's right!
- Lumen, what are you doing here?
- Don't try to turn your charms on me.
- Give us the key... Right now!
- I'd love to help... But I don't have the key!
- Huh?
- Won't Mantid be pleased when I hand the key to him?
He'll give me a big hug and he'll say, "Grasshop, you're the best!"
And then he'll give me a fat raise.
- Where's he going?
- Then I'll come home to my beautiful wife and kids and say,
"We're moving out of this nest into a bigger nest!"
And all the Invectids will look up to me,
even the ones who are taller than me! Huh?
That looks like Buguese and his Robo-Bug
on their way to battle the Spider Riders.
Oh well, let him waste time.
I've got the Oracle Key and from now on, I'm top bug around here!
I can't wait... When I tell him I've got the key,
he'll go green with envy and his antennae will curl.
Maybe he'll cry and then I'll go, "Nyah, nyah!"
- Give me that key! - What?
- You heard me. It's not nice to steal, you know! - Hoo hoo!
Oh my! If it isn't Princess Sparkle
and her insufferably sweet spider...
The Spider Riders must have been desperate...
Why don't you go home and play with your dollies?
This is no place for an iddle-widdle girl like you!
- Kyuuu! What did you call me?
Arachna Power!
Spider Rider! Kyukyuu!
- Ho! Ho! Ha! Ha! Ha!
You are the most adorable Spider Rider I have ever seen...
Oh, I'm so scared! Oh, how will I defend myself
from her terminal cuteness?
- Don't say I didn't warn you! - Huh?
Oh! No fair.
That really hurt!
- Return the key!
- Hey, look! You shouldn't throw that thing around!
You could really hurt somebody!
- Return it!
Return it! Return it! Return it! Return it! Return it! Return it!
- Lay off me, you evil little elf!
Stop that, or I'll tell on you!
- Return it!
- And now that we've destroyed the Spider Riders,
it's time we went to the castle
to check on Beerain. - Yes, Buguese.
- Wait!
- So the poor, defenceless Hunter
still has some strength.
- The key!
Return the key!
- Oh...
- The time has come
to finally say goodbye to this world,
Hunter Steele!
- Please don't!
- We got the key back! Kyuu!
- It's too late
to save your friend.
- I... I'll never give up!
- Ha! Ha! Ha!
- Aqune, listen... We don't have to fight each other!
- Huh?
- Quiet! All of you!
- Nooo!
The key flew away.
- Kyuu?
- Something's happening!
- Yes...
- It can't be!
- The Oracle Key... No!
- [Both]: Ah!
- What happened? Shadow?
- The Oracle Key from Nuuma
has given us a new power.
- He even has the ability
to call the new key to him! Aqune!
- Shadow! - Right!
- The mask!
- Yes!
- Oh! - Aqune! Are you OK?
I'm sorry, I just couldn't adjust my power!
- What happened?
- You're safe.
- Here, take this... - Huh?
- It's yours...
The Oracle's gift... Take it.
- Attack!
- Shadow?
- Yes, Hunter!
Let's ride! - You got it!
- Good luck!
- Hunter!
- Look! They've transformed!
- Incredible! - Amazing!
- How did he do that?
How did Hunter Steele combine the power
of 2 Oracle Keys?
- Attack! Robo-Beetle!
- Ready? Take him!
- Just try!
- Blue Bolt!
- No! It can't be!
Once again, Spirit Oracle has chosen
to align herself with the humans.
- So this amazing transformation
is the result of 2 Oracle Keys combining forces within you?
- What did it feel like, Hunter?
- Come on, tell us!
- It felt like Shadow and I were one being.
- I agree.
It was as if we had been touched by the Oracle herself.
- Celebrate all you want,
Hunter and Shadow!
Next time, you will both pay for this!
I will be back!
- Spider Riders,
I've made my decision!
Now that the Oracle has given me the power of 2 keys,
I've decided I'm going to Nuuma
to drive out the Invectids.
I know it's the right thing to do!
- You're right.
- It's going to be tough, Shadow,
but with Arachna Power on our side,
we can't lose!
Closed Captioning by SETTE ltée