- There exists within the planet Earth a fantastic lost world.
In this inner world, elite warriors ride huge spiders
and bravely fight against evil. When the wicked rise,
the word goes out... "Calling all Spider Riders!"
- ♪♪ Calling all Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride, ride, ride
♪ Spider Ride like we do If you're true then you could be too ♪
♪ It's cool, you can join our team no matter how tough it seems ♪
♪ If you look, the power's inside ya, so strive to be a brave rider ♪
♪ We're riding on So now we're calling all ♪
♪ Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride Yes, let's ride ♪
♪ I'm holding on the line, yeah I know I will survive ♪
♪ We ain't afraid to fight In the heart of the dark we are the light ♪
♪ Your faith in the battle's sealed 'cause we trained to gain the skills ♪
♪ Yup, we're the ultimate The power that's within waves in the hand ♪
♪ We're riding on So now we're calling all ♪
♪ Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride Yes, let's ride ♪
♪ I'm holding on the line I know I will survive ♪
♪ Calling all Spider Riders
♪ Let's ride! ♪
- Have you ever seen this wooden box?
- Oh... you have found it! - Yes.
- I was sent by our Queen to give you this.
It must be very precious.
She told me to deliver it at all costs.
- Wow!
- Oooh...
- Oh...
- Ooh...
- It's another Oracle Key!
- Yes, this treasure has been in the possession
of the Royal Family of my homeland, Nuuma.
Please, Spider Riders, I implore you to protect this Key
and keep it out of the Invectids' evil hands.
- Protect it from the Invectids?
- Are you saying that Nuuma has been invaded?
- Yes... and without your help we shall be lost.
[Sniggering]
- This is even better than I thought...
Just think, the Spider Riders have two Oracle Keys
so when I beat them... Ha! Ha! Ha!
I will capture both Keys!
- So, this is an Oracle Key too?
- Yup! You got it, Sparkle!
Just like the one I already have.
- It was lucky this Key fell into our hands
instead of the Invectids'.
- [Shadow]: Legend has it that there were actually
two Oracle Keys in Nuuma.
I wonder if that's true.
- One way to find out...
Anyone want to take a trip?
- Take a trip? Where?
- To Nuuma. If the Invectids have invaded,
and another Oracle Key is really there then we have to go.
You know, it's our duty as Spider Riders.
[Sighing]
- Magma? - Hmm-hmm.
- Is there another... Oracle Key?
- You delivered an Oracle Key to us...
and we had one Key...
Is it true there is another Oracle Key in Nuuma?
- It's true, there is another Oracle Key in Nuuma.
Our Queen is protecting it.
- So... she sent you to deliver one key and kept the other.
- Yes. She insisted on staying behind in Nuuma
for the sake of her people.
I begged her... to let me take her away.
Come with me.
I promise I will not fail you.
- Hmm...
- She sent you... to get us?
- Prince Lumen, please come to the aid of Nuuma.
You and your Spider Riders are our only hope.
- [Both]: Hmm?
- Hmm-hmm... - Why, Dungobeet...
- Hmm? - Good to see you...
But I have to apologize for what I'm about to do to you.
I can't allow you to get to Mantid first.
[Moaning]
I don't want you to spill the beans...
He's going to find out about that Oracle Key
when I hand it to him.
Then I'll become his favourite instead of that snooty Buguese!
And don't worry, if Mantid asks about you,
I'll just tell him you got tied up...
[Evil laugh]
- [Hunter]: What's the matter with you, guys?
We just found out that Nuuma is being attacked by Invectids
and there's a third Oracle Key there...
It's a no-brainer!
We should be calling all Spider Riders!
- [Lumen]: You're right, it sounds like something we should do...
But I can't allow... all Spider Riders to be called away.
- Why not? - Hunter, do you have any idea how far away Nuuma is?
- Hmm-hmm, no clue.
- Figures...
- Hunter, Nuuma is far from here.
In order to reach Nuuma,
we have to cross an ocean of dangerous water.
Many have tried and failed.
We may not survive.
- That's a chance we'll have to take.
- Just answer one question, Hunter.
Who's going to protect the people of Arachna
while the Spider Riders are far away?
- Uh?
- If the Invectids attacked, Arachna would be defenseless.
- We can't just abandon our country.
We are responsible for Arachna.
- But, as Spider Riders, aren't we responsible
for protecting everyone?
Corona, you agree?
- Uh... Well... I, uh...
I'm not sure what's best to do...
It's complicated.
- What's with you, Corona?
You drummed it into me...
Spider Riders must fight the Invectids.
- Yes, that's true... but still...
- Then I don't understand what the big problem is.
It seems clear to me.
- I'm uneasy.
- Uneasy? About what?
- Nothing specific...
I just... I feel like something bad is going to happen.
- Corona...
- According to my sources,
Goldenbore should live right around here.
No! Aaaah!
Aaah... Maybe this wasn't such a good idea.
- [Monstrous voice]: Who is there?
- Uh? Uh oh!
Aaaaah! Aaaah!
- Who are you, little bug?
- Oh! Uh, I am Grasshop, one of the Big Four.
I've come to ask for a favour... Boy, you're big!
I mean really big. Like the size of a small fishing village.
[Moaning]
Please... accept this gift from me.
- Mmm... Regurgitated grubs, my favourite.
- So... you're telling me
the Spider Riders have gained yet another Key?
- Hmm-hmm! Hmm-hmm!
- That means two of the Oracle Keys
are in the Spider Riders' hands.
- What are your orders, Great Mantid?
- Buguese... Beerain...
go to Arachna and capture both Oracle Keys
from the Spider Riders.
The time has come to bring sunlight
back to this dark land of ours!
[Agreeing]
- I made a promise...
[Knock! Knock!] Yes?
- Hello!
Do you mind... if I ask a question?
I'm wondering...
why there are two Oracle Keys in Nuuma.
- Well... It's said the Spirit Oracle
bestowed upon the Queen of Nuuma
a Key for safe keeping many years ago.
And then there came the second Key...
It is said the Hero Quake brought it with him
when he came to Nuuma.
- That is so cool!
It proves the Hero Quake existed.
- Well... that is what I believe.
- Good! Then this is really meant to be.
I've decided. - What?
- I will make the journey to Nuuma.
And with the power of my own Oracle Key,
I'll defeat those evil Invectids once and for all.
- There'll be no stopping Hunter... I'm sure of that.
- Magma... have you...
ever wondered why the Spirit Oracle left four Keys in this world?
What does she wants us to do with them?
- I'm not sure... but I do know
that they have incredible power.
And that the Invectids will go to any lengths
to get their hands on them. That's for sure.
- Seems like a good reason to go to battle.
- I agree with you.
- Why am I so worried?
Hunter is right. As Spider Riders, it is our duty
to protect everyone who needs our help.
- Brother?
Will you rescue the people of Nuuma?
- I don't know, Sparkle, it's hard to say.
- But why?
- Oh, Sparkle... I dream of a place where no one has to fight.
Where everyone lives in peace and harmony.
But of course... that's just a lovely dream. Ha!
- My poor brother...
[Distant rumbling] Uh?
- Do you hear that, Sparkle?
- Out there in the distance...
It's coming toward us.
- Whoa! What is it?
- That's huge!
- That can't be good.
- That's impossible! - Shadow: [Hunter!]
- I see it! How could I not?
Whatever the Invectids are up to, it's big!
- W-What is that? - It's the Invectids!
- [Grasshop]: HA! HA! HA! - Run!
- I still know how to make an entrance!
Thank you! You're a great crowd!
Today is the day that I, Grasshop, finally defeat
those pesky Spider Riders and retrieve both Oracle Keys!
With Goldenbore's might and my brains I can't lose!
This, without a doubt, is Grasshop's greatest plan ever!
I will be famous for it!
Charge, Goldenbore!!! Aaah...
- [Goldenbore]: Do not order me, bug!
- I'm so sorry, Goldenbore!
Will you crush the Spider Riders for me?
I'll be your best friend!
- What's the magic word?
- Pretty please? With sugar on top?
- Well... Okay. I can't resist sugar! Yum! Yum!
- Really? Good! 'Cause here they come!
Hi!
- Arachna Power!
- ♪ Calling all Spider Riders
♪ Calling all Spider Riders
- Spider Riders!
- Sheesh! You guys sure took your time transforming, didn't you?
- Grasshop! - That's my name, don't wear it out! Ha! Ha! Ha!
Let's see how you fare against the new and improved,
extra-strength Grasshop!
- [Goldenbore]: It's not your strength they face!
- I know... I know... Don't be such a party pooper.
Now Spider Riders,
you must face Goldenbore and me... in the Coliseum!
- Oracle... help us.
- [Grasshop]: Ha! Ha! Ha! It looks like we've got a packed stadium
for the main event!
- That thing is humongous!
- Yes... And I suspect his power matches his size.
- So? The bigger they are... - ...the harder they fall!
- Shadow, let's ride!
- Here they come! Now crush them, Goldenbore! Please!
[Tremendous roaring]
- Gold Rush!
- Uh?
- Our webs are useless!
- Ha! Ha! Ha! Ready to give up yet?
Oh! - Quiet, little bug!
- I'm so sorry. Please, go on with your attack, Goldenbore.
I promise I'll be good.
- We'll fight lightning with lightning!!
Firebolt!
- Ha!
- Oh... He barely noticed my attack!
- My turn... Morning Star!
- Nice try...
- He's as tough as he looks! - Never give up, Magma!
- Now for a taste of Gold Fever!
[Screaming]
- They'll be all right, Hotarla.
I hope.
- Ooh... Medic!
[Moaning]
- Well, well...
This is better than I dreamed of.
Do you know what this means?
My wife and children...
will finally know that Grasshop is a winner!
- Aren't you forgetting someone?
- Of course I'll tell them that you're actually the winner.
- Hunter? - Yeah?
- Use the Oracle Key.
- And we'll create an opening for you!
- When the moment arrives, don't hesitate.
- Are you ready, Hunter?
- I'm always ready!
- Arrow of Light!
- Ha!
- Never give up! Lava Light!
- Morning Star!
- Spinneraxe!
- Oh! Ow! Ouch!
Oooh... - [Grasshop]: Uh oh!
[Moaning]
Oh no! I forgot! Goldenbore's only weakness
is that when he falls on his back he can't get up again!
- Say it louder why don't you! - Oops! My bad.
- Did you hear that, Hunter? - Loud and clear!
Oracle's Light!
- Let's ride! - You've got it!
- This is gonna hurt!
- Electra-Strike! Ah!
- [Goldenbore]: It's been a blast!
- Curse you, Spider Riders! You break it, you buy it!
- Hunter! - Arachna Power!
- I wouldn't celebrate yet! - Uh?
- Another Invectid?!
- A very special one.
- Buguese!
- Big mistake, Buguese!
- That's right! Let's stomp some bugs!
Electra-Twist!
Uh?
[Screaming]
[Moaning]
- Hunter!
- Ha! Ha! Ha!
Someone... got a taste of their own medicine.
- Uh?
- Portia!
- If Portia's here, her rider can't be far behind.
- Hmm?!
Aqune!
- Oracle's... light!
- I don't believe it.
- It can't be!
- The Oracle Key...
- All that power...
- ...in the hands of...
- ...of a traitor!
- Aqune!
- [Buguese]: How ironic!
The end of the humans will be brought about by a human.
[Sniggering]
[Loud evil laugh]
Closed Captioning by SETTE ltée