SOLDIER 1: Move it on in. SOLDIER 2: Keep moving.
SOLDIER 1: Come on, keep moving. Get along in there.
Move it along.
SOLDIER 3: Come on, get moving.
Move in that truck. Come on, move it.
Faster.
Hey, where do you think you're going? Get in the truck.
SOLDIER 4: Come on, move. No talking.
Keep moving in there.
Come on! Move it.
SOLDIER 5: Get in there. There we are.
Get in there.
NERZHIN ( narrating ): My number is BS1968314.
Who's been here before me?
And how many will come after me?
GUARD: BS1968314.
NERZHIN: Nerzhin, Gleb Vikentyevich.
Mathematician, engineer.
Nerzhin, Gleb Vikentyevich.
Captain, artillery. Red Army.
( mysterious theme playing )
( man singing in Russian )
( suspenseful theme playing )
WOMAN ( over PA ): Leningrad. Leningrad, booth number 3.
We have your call.
MAN 1: Hello? Tashkent.
Stop cutting us off.
What? Are you flying in tomorrow?
I can't hear. Tomorrow night!
MAN 2: Hey, citizen,
it's 3,000 kilometers to Tashkent.
Why don't you talk louder?
Bring a kilo of butter, will you?
There isn't any here in Moscow. Butter. Butter!
MAN 3: You're last in line, comrade.
WOMAN ( over PA ): --ready in booth number 18.
Eighteen.
MAN 2: I've been trying to get us on...
VOLODIN ( thinking ): Should I say anything or hang up?
What if the phone's tapped?
Hang up. Just hang up.
I can't, I'm not an animal. I have a conscience.
They can't tap all the phones in Moscow.
It's impossible.
Should I change my voice?
Is this Professor Dobronravov's house?
WOMAN ( over the phone ): Yes. Who shall I say is calling?
You don't know me. I wanna speak to the professor.
Just give me your name, please. Who's calling?
Is this the professor's wife?
I don't have to tell you who I am.
Who is this? What's going on?
Listen. Please, listen.
I have to warn him. He's in danger.
In danger? When he was in Paris recently,
he promised the French doctors he'd give them something.
Some kind of medicine. The formula for new medicine.
Do you understand? He mustn't do it. Tell him not to do it.
It could be used as provocation.
But-- Hello? Hello?
SECRETARY: Would you like tea, Innokenti Artemyevich?
No, thank you.
The vice minister has called twice.
He wants you to phone him at 4:00--
Fine. Put me through to him then.
I'm not to be disturbed now. I have work to do.
( door closes )
VOLODIN ( thinking ): What an awful coincidence.
Why did it have to be the same doctor
who saved Mother's life?
Maybe it won't do him any good to know anyway.
Why did I do it?
Stupid. Stupid.
And naive.
Oh, I must be mad.
Oh, God, why did I call?
I'll lose everything now.
Six years in the diplomatic corps.
Councilor of foreign affairs,
lieutenant in the foreign service.
I have the very best background.
Mother was a revolutionist in 1917.
My wife's father is state's prosecutor
and a general.
And I only found out about Dobronravov by mistake.
No.
No, it wasn't really a mistake.
When I started working to be sent to Paris,
I knew I'd be involved in these things.
They have to be sure of you to give you a job like that.
What's the matter with me?
You only live once. That was always my motto.
But Mother always said you have only one conscience.
Why did I call him?
What am I waiting for? The police to come for me?
( phone rings )
Yes?
Volodin speaking.
Yes, I'm listening, comrade vice minister.
Your transfer to the Paris embassy
is all settled, Volodin.
What I want to know is can you be ready in three or four days?
I understand the post in Paris must be filled immediately.
I'll be ready.
Fine. Then I'll send the confirmation around
for the minister's signature.
That's all, Volodin.
( phone rings )
I asked not to be disturbed.
SECRETARY: But it's your wife. Shouldn't I put her through?
Innokenti, Clara is here.
She came over especially to remind you
that Daddy's banquet's the day after tomorrow.
VOLODIN: What Clara? What are you talking about?
My sister Clara. Silly.
This is Dotty. Dotty.
Have you forgotten you have a wife?
Dotty, I'm really busy.
All right then,
Innokenti Artemyevich,
I summon you officially to the banquet
given in honor of your father-in-law
Major General Makarygin
DOTTY: On the occasion of his being awarded
his second Order of Lenin.
It is his wish
that his whole family be present,
including his son-in-law, Innokenti Artemyevich Volodin,
consulate to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Period.
Bye-bye.
He's so hard to live with these days.
He just refuses to forget
about, you know, that officer and me.
Hmph.
To Stalin.
Bottoms up.
( upbeat theme playing )
( indistinct chattering )
I told you Father would drink a toast to Stalin's health.
to Stalin's health.
My giddy old father.
Do you think of Stalin when we're in bed together?
A visit to your bed is not on my agenda.
You're too hospitable.
Here, have a drink.
MALE GUEST: Comrade major general. We're celebrating
your second Order of Lenin here tonight.
Here's to your third.
To the whole Makarygin family.
I'll have to think that one over. Ha-ha-ha.
I can't say that I am completely satisfied
with all the members of my family.
My son-in-law here,
first lieutenant to the diplomatic service
and the future ambassador.
I can praise for his work.
And for knowing how to appreciate
the finer things in life.
He took my daughter.
But I don't see the results.
Where are the children? I want to know.
( laughing )
And then-- Then there is my other daughter, Clara.
She's got her engineering degree
and that's fine.
She's 24 years old and that's fine too.
But it's the same thing again.
Where's the husband?
Where are the children? I want to know.
We Makarygins are an old proletarian family.
Oh, go on about our proletarian family, Father.
You once worked in a factory for two years.
But for the last 30 years, you have been a prosecutor.
We went into exile and hard labor.
Saviors of mankind.
What do you mean "went into hard labor"?
They're still going.
( laughing )
( indistinct chattering )
MAKARYGIN: Must be the switch. Let's have some candles.
CLARA: You heard about the job?
It's the one I didn't want.
I begin Monday.
It was my own father who arranged the job.
Stop torturing yourself.
Every political system has its security machine.
Security machine.
WOMAN: Aah.
( indistinct chattering )
Why don't we stop fighting?
You yourself say we only live once.
And you didn't miss any of it, did you?
Didn't I always give you everything you wanted?
Not only me.
Oh, that's not fair.
I told you myself about that officer.
It was during the time,
and don't try to forget it, when you'd had enough of me.
Innokenti, we had six beautiful years together.
America,
and then Paris after the war. And those were years
when other people were separated from each other
and dying at the front. Innokenti.
Don't start that, like Daddy.
( siren wailing )
GUARD: Halt. Take front.
Comrade major, transport 3326.
Igorvorov, Pavol Ivanovich, mechanical engineer.
Yes.
Vacinavich. Nicolai Vacinavich,
construction engineer.
Yeah.
Vasioshanko, Nicolai Yuriyavich,
construction engineer.
Yes.
( indistinct chattering )
How much bread do you get here?
Fourteen ounces of white bread and black bread...
MAN 1: What do you mean?
On the table, it's fine. You want it, you take it.
You don't want it, you don't take it.
What else do you get?
Well, professors get one and a half ounces of butter.
Engineers get three-quarters of an ounce.
Professor, it's you.
My God, it's you.
Tomorrow, they won't drag me out into icy water?
One and a half ounces of butter?
The guards don't beat you?
You can shave?
Maybe I'm dreaming. It's paradise.
Not at all.
We're still in hell.
But you've been brought to its highest level.
In the Institute for Scientific Research number 3251
or Special Prison number 325.
You are in the first circle of hell. Remember Dante.
Lev Grigoryevich, you're too much of a poet.
You only have to read the newspapers.
There was an article. It has been shown
that better sheep are fed and looked after,
the higher the yield of wool.
We work 14 hours a day.
The directors of our institute
recognize the full meaning of your engineering degrees.
They represent hard work. Well done.
And another addition to our new Soviet intelligentsia.
Young patriots worthy of our confidence.
I congratulate you.
Major Shikin, our chief security officer here,
is responsible for the safety and order
of our institute.
If you please, major.
SHIKIN: We have taken over this old mansion
on the outskirts of Moscow.
It's been divided into two parts.
The prisoners are not allowed to cross that dividing line
without a special pass.
The prisoners sleep here, where the chapel was.
The laboratories are here.
Over here is the administration.
You may enter the laboratory only at designated times.
As officers of the Ministry of Security,
you'll receive the rank of lieutenant junior grade.
I want to impress upon you that your work here
is of the highest responsibility
and extremely dangerous.
The scientific and experimental research
conducted here under the direction
of Colonel Yakonov
is very important to our country.
You're all party members,
all members of the Young Communist League.
But if, due to inexperience,
one of you should fail to observe the rules,
even in the smallest detail, for instance,
lending a book to a prisoner,
you will be discharged.
I may add that any liaison of any kind with a prisoner
will be punished under the criminal code
with up to 25 years of hard labor.
YAKONOV: This is Nerzhin, engineer.
Bulatov.
Bobynin, engineer.
Rubin.
And our eminent Professor Chelnov.
Adamson. Comrade Adamson.
Here, sir.
Dr. Rubin and Bulatov will explain the nature
of our experiments.
And your place is over there.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Comrade Yakonov, thank you.
Good luck.
( clanging and whirring )
Yes. Yes, Comrade Shikin.
Yes, I understand.
Prisoner Doronin will report Thursday.
Yes, everything's fine.
Really, they behave very well
for criminals and saboteurs.
Of course. Yes.
He'll report on Thursday.
Doronin.
Prisoner Doronin!
Doronin!
Aah! How dare you?
You have to watch your step here, citizen engineer.
You have a nerve.
Major Shikin warned me about prisoners like you.
I've already got 25 years.
Call Major Shikin.
I'll tell you what to say.
"Please tell me if socialist justice
will change after Stalin's death."
And he'll answer, "In principle, yes.
"Execution of the accused
before the verdict's given will not be allowed."
You just say that to Shikin.
Go ahead.
How old are you? Twenty-three.
And you've got 25 years? What for?
Nothing.
For nothing, you get five years.
So you must have done something.
Why?
Why did you lift me up like that?
Because I haven't had anything like you in my hands
for years.
( buzzing )
What is it, Doronin?
You sent for me, major?
Can't you wait?
Before you were convicted, you were a party member.
I've never stopped being a communist.
So I've heard.
You said that in front of the other prisoners.
Since you hear everything anyway, citizen major,
why ask me?
Now, listen, Rubin. That's my party duty.
You ought to know that. We have to know
what the prisoners are saying and thinking.
It's state security.
And if you're pro-Soviet, then you'll help me.
If you're not pro-Soviet than you're an anti-Soviet.
How do you want me to write the denunciations?
In ink or pencil?
Well, ink would be better.
I've already proved my devotion to Soviet authority in blood.
I don't need to do it in ink.
You must help us, Doronin. We must know everything.
Everything there is to know about the prisoners.
And we know more about you than you know yourself.
( romantic theme playing )
I'm not going to fool around with you.
You wanna go back to Siberia?
Do you pay for this work, citizen major?
Hundred-and-fifty rubles a quarter.
But don't worry, it'll be in the form
of a money order from your family outside.
From an uncle, say.
Couldn't it be from a woman?
That's always nice.
A hundred-and-fifty rubles from a woman.
( Shikin chuckles )
Actually, you'll get 147 rubles
because the post office deducts 3 rubles for sending it.
I had just finished school when they arrested me.
Because I went fishing twice with some Americans
who rented a summer house in the village next to ours.
( chuckles )
I was green then.
They tried to make say
that I'd received instructions from the CIA.
I just cried all the time.
Then, suddenly, they let me go.
I knew they would get me sooner or later.
They let me go so they could keep a watch on me.
I couldn't take that, so I ran.
I changed my name, forged my identity card.
I was in Uzbekistan and the Crimea for two years.
Then finally they got me,
when I tried to get into the university.
Doronin, you see,
you really did want to be a good citizen.
Call me Ruska.
They sent me to Siberia, to the mines.
I worked in the water right up to my waist.
But I got out.
Those bastards.
Oh, excuse me.
They teach us such nice things in school,
and then right after, everything,
every other word is son of a bitch.
But to be such an outcast...
Was I?
You've been to Tashkent,
to the Tezik bazaar.
Who's running it now?
Who's got the money there?
You can buy authentic war medals
with blank citation certificates.
For money, you can get anything there.
But you can't make that kind of money
by doing an honest day's work.
Yes, I saw it too.
( romantic theme playing )
Who sentenced you?
Which prosecutor?
DORONIN: I don't know. Why do you ask?
My father's a state prosecutor.
( alarm ringing )
A toast to Nerzhin, 31 years old.
Not bad.
( explosion )
( Vladimir laughs )
Salute to Stalin.
A birthday celebration.
How many years did he take from you, Gleb Vikentyevich?
What's the difference, Vladimir Ivonavich?
Better not to think about it.
Not enough vodka.
All right.
I propose the next toast.
To the 15 million
distinguished citizens of the Soviet Union.
Here's looking at you, Gleb. It's your day.
Which 15 million distinguished citizens, Vladimir Ivonavich?
Why, those 15 million that the father of our country
and all of progressive mankind have sent to rot
in Siberia and camps in Latyga.
And in the Institute for Scientific Research,
Lev Grigoryevich.
Here's to you, Vladimir Ivanovich,
but we're disposable.
Our screwed up lives won't change
the historical evolution.
Stalin knew this development would have--
Ruska, I'll strangle you with my bare hands
if you don't come off it.
Today on Gleb's birthday, that bullshit contamination.
Who are you trying to kid?
That's not what you learn here in prison
from your own buddies, historical biographies.
PRISONER: For Christ's sake, let's drink.
The night guard could come barging in here any minute
and we'd lose the vodka
that we risked our pretty necks for.
Here's to all of us.
To the brilliant defender of the wronged
and downtrodden in the camp of world imperialism.
To the brilliant teacher
and wise councilor to all the races.
Colors of the world.
To the son and hope,
to our revered fellow countryman,
our dearly beloved Comrade Stalin.
( glass breaks )
Listen, I'm just the same as the rest of you.
Caught in the roundup of 45 hours.
I was four years at the front.
Got a big chunk of shrapnel in my side
and a five-year prison sentence.
But don't let my own troubles change my perspective.
Stalin is a rogue spear and Napoleon of the revolution.
He sees ahead. He sees the end.
The end?
The end justifies the means, is that what you mean?
That's one of the dirtiest tricks of all.
It's just the opposite.
Dishonest means destroy the ends themselves.
And who beat Hitler?
Stalin? Yeah.
Hitler was the only person he believed in.
He didn't believe in anybody else,
not even Churchill, only Hitler.
It cost us 20 million people.
Gleb Vikentyevich, there's a rumor
that you've got a copy of Yesenin's poems. Lend it to me.
Damn it, you can't keep anything quiet around here.
I'll loan it to you. Only don't go yet, Adamson.
Why not?
I've been in 15 years, and it's always the same.
I know what Rubin's going to say.
The great idea.
Ten years ago, there were already camps
and they were living off the people
and tearing them apart for the great idea.
When I won't be here anymore, or Stalin either,
they'll get a new brilliant defender
of progressive mankind.
We've got a piece of land in Siberia.
The size of France.
And you know what it's peopled with?
Slave camps.
Pretty soon they'll need a hunt the size of all Europe.
For what?
The great idea.
It's a goddamned whorehouse.
No, it's a whorehouse on fire.
PRISONER: No, during a flood, there's a fire in the whorehouse.
No, it's a whorehouse on fire during a flood,
and there's just been an earthquake.
Cost is just too damn high, buddy.
Gleb, lend me the Yesenin book.
Give me a woman.
That's the biggest screwing we got from Stalin.
No woman for 25 years.
Can anybody know what it's like
to be without a woman?
I want to make love.
Give me a woman.
( thinking ) Give me back my wife.
We'd get together with our friends, read poetry.
Maybe it was Blok, maybe Yesenin.
We'd have long discussions about them,
about Russia, so deep within them,
about our lives.
Somebody squealed.
One of us was a squealer.
SOLDIER 1: All right, everybody. Stay where you are.
You're under arrest. get going.
SOLDIER 2: Let's go, let's go.
No, no, no, that's my husband.
That's my husband.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( wind whistling )
Here, have some vodka.
( glass breaks )
( whimpering )
( sobbing )
( groaning )
You don't know.
You don't know what it's like for a woman in a camp.
I can't sleep.
A woman.
A woman trembling in my arms.
Oh, God, I've got to have her.
Who? Clara.
Clara? The prosecutor's daughter?
Ruska, you're out of your mind.
I tell you, Nerzhin, I'll have her.
She can threaten to send me back to camp.
I told him I'd turn informer for her.
BULATOV: You won't do it. I lost my wife because of a squealer.
( Ruska groans )
You goddamn fool.
I wouldn't tell you if I was really going to squeal.
Gleb, I want her. I want her.
( thinking ) Nadya.
( explosion )
My Nadya.
When was the last time I saw you?
When?
MAN: Volga. Volga.
Kiev calling.
Come in, Volga.
12396.
( explosion )
Come in, Volga.
Kiev calling.
12396.
Come in, Volga.
Come in, Volga. Kiev calling.
Volga.
( explosion )
Hey.
Is Captain Nerzhin here?
Why do you wanna know?
I'm his wife.
Oh, he's in the corner. Oh.
See, over there.
Oh. Oh, Gleb.
It's me. It's me. Gleb.
( gasps )
NADYA: Aah.
GLEB: Nadya.
( explosion )
How did you make your way up here to us?
First, I thumbed my way on trucks, then I walked.
MAN: You mean you came right through the front lines that way?
And you weren't afraid of the Germans?
Did they fire at you?
NADYA: Oh, yes.
MAN: Gleb. What?
Is that really a woman?
GLEB: I swear it.
MAN: Ivan. Ivan.
Ivan, look at him.
I think he stopped breathing. He's dead.
IVAN: What was he supposed to do?
MAN: He was alive a minute ago. What are we going to do?
IVAN: Nothing. You can pray.
MAN: The Lord have mercy.
The Lord have mercy on our souls.
On those of us are here
and on those of us who have gone beyond.
Accept the prayers of your servant.
Is he dead?
He's been dying all day.
We can't evacuate the wounded.
There's no letup in the firing.
Oh, it's a miracle you got through.
Gleb.
What is it, sweetheart?
They told us we were so well-prepared,
that we were so strong.
Stalin?
We weren't at all prepared.
It was a massacre.
Oh, Nadya. Oh.
( explosion )
( indistinct chattering )
NADYA: Oh, Gleb!
Be careful, Nadya!
Gleb!
( gunfire )
GLEB ( narrating ): For four years, I fought in the front lines.
I even got a citation.
But they got hold of a letter I wrote to Nadya.
I wrote about Stalin and what was going on,
and what I thought of it.
So I didn't get to march in Red Square
in the triumphal parade when the war was over.
They marched me to the north instead.
To the far north.
SOLDIER: March.
( dogs barking )
March. March!
NADYA: Gleb.
SOLDIER: March. March!
Nadya!
SOLDIER: Come on.
( dogs barking )
Gleb!
Ugh.
Nadya.
( dogs barking )
I'll wait for you. I won't leave you.
SOLDIER 1: Keep moving out.
Gleb. SOLDIER 2: Come on.
I won't leave you.
( sobbing )
I wrote her not to wait for me.
( chuckles )
They don't understand on the outside.
Abandon hope all ye who enter here.
This is the last of it.
In fine birthday tradition,
we'll drink to your health, Glebvichka.
Let's drink to those
who have bound themselves to our lives.
We have no choice, so they are the real heroes.
To our wives.
( melancholic theme playing )
I think it's snowing outside.
GLEB ( narrating ): Colonel Yakonov was in charge of our work on a device
known as the absolute encoder. According to plan...
GLEB ( narrating ): A telephone ordered by Stalin
that would be impossible to tap.
Tap-proof.
I made a breakthrough on the design
and felt certain that it put me
far ahead of the others. All the experiments...
GLEB ( narrating ): However, I kept it secret,
since I was working for my freedom.
Only Professor Chelnov could tell me
whether I was really on the right track.
Professor Chelnov, please excuse me.
But have you had time to study my drawings?
Let's go to your board.
SOLDIER: Show your passes.
SOLDIER: All right.
Very good.
I think you have finally got the absolute encoder.
And the telephone line can be used by Stalin
with the utmost trust anywhere in the Soviet Union.
And you can begin a new life outside.
( thinking ) And the old one?
Is it finished?
NERZHIN: Ugh.
Ugh.
GLEB ( narrating ): They can only really be sure of you when you're dead,
so they bash your skull with a mallet.
Just to be sure.
( mallet bangs ) ( man groans )
GUARD: This one's still alive.
Lucky bastard.
Of course, you still have a way to go,
but your construction design is unparalleled
by any of the other engineers.
It will bring you freedom, a clean slate
and an apartment in Moscow.
And how are they going to use this machine?
And who is it for?
It's up to us.
Have they finished their production conference
( over the intercom ) in there or not?
GLEB: Don't you have any moral objections?
What were you talking about with Chelnov?
About our work, according to regulations.
I am the head of this laboratory.
I want to know exactly about what you were speaking.
I'm sure you're informed about the work we do.
What were the moral objections
you were talking about with prisoner Chelnov?
Professor Chelnov.
There are only prisoners here.
There are Russian scientists here.
Please, answer.
What moral objections
were you talking about with prisoner Chelnov?
Prisoner Chelnov has degrees
from the Sorbonne, Cambridge and Yale.
He was personally acquainted with Einstein and the pope
before it was his great pleasure to meet you
and all the other officers of the NKGB.
That will do.
Please show me those drawings.
You can see them for yourself.
Show them to me immediately.
Look at them yourself.
Prisoner Nerzhin asks permission
to return to Colonel Yakonov's meeting.
MAN: We've tuned it up to clear it at every 16th impulse
and it's much better, citizen colonel.
It seems as though the reception is better.
However, let Rubin listen.
He has a good ear.
Stupidity.
One step forward and two steps back.
There's no point in feeling it out by guesswork.
You have to have a method.
I must remind you that according to plan,
the main circuit of the encoder
was to be ready by the end of the month.
I don't think we are there yet.
We'll have to work Sundays.
Yes. Yes, of course. That would give us an extra--
( phone rings )
Hello. Yakonov speaking.
Yes, sir.
I'll be in comrade minister's office
at 12 midnight. Yes, sir.
He has arrived, Deputy Minister Sevastyanov,
Head of the Special Equipment Section,
Major General Oskolupov.
Chief Engineer, Colonel Yakonov passed through.
The minister is in Comrade Stalin's office.
You may be seated.
Will Comrade Stalin see me tonight?
I don't know. You'll have to wait.
( buzzing )
Josif Visarionovic.
You have a Abakumov down for 1:00.
Will you receive him?
We'll see. I don't know.
Well, he can wait.
These two new biographies have been sent over.
Are five million copies enough? Not too few?
Is it interesting? Have you read them?
Oh, yes, most interesting. It's all based on fact.
"His strategic genius, his wise foresight,
"his powerful will.
"It was our great good fortune that in the difficult days
of the Great War, we were led by Stalin."
That's right. That's right.
And I have Tito's biography here.
Read it.
"Hopeless blockhead, perfidious evil tyrant,
cowardly traitor..."
Give it to me.
Disgraceful. How can you trust people like that?
You have to be more careful.
He wants to know about the secret telephone.
Your briefcase, please.
( buzzing )
Good evening, Josif Visarionovic.
May I come in?
Well, what is it?
Now, what was it I was going to ask you?
Now I can't remember.
You can go.
( buzzing )
( door closes )
( footsteps )
MAN: You may be seated.
Well, when will the secret telephone be ready?
You keep stringing me along.
August the 1st, the November celebrations.
Then for New Year's Day. Well?
Comrade minister,
Comrade's Major General Colonel,
let me assure you that we will spare no effort--
I'm asking you what date.
Comrade minister,
in the frequency range up to 2,400 cycles,
given an average transmission level of 0.9--
Cycles, cycles. I want the telephone.
Two complete units.
When can I have it? Well?
Please, let me know what you have in mind,
Viktor Semyonovich.
Two way conversations
and we still don't have absolute encoding?
Why are you trying to make an idiot out of me?
What do you mean don't have absolute encoding?
Another month.
Just one more month.
Until the 1st of February.
All right. Make it the anniversary of Lenin's death.
Do it and you will all receive a Stalin prize.
Sevastyanov, will it be ready?
Yes, it will.
Oskolupov, I'll have your neck.
Will it be ready? Yes.
As for you. You know what you're risking.
Will it be ready?
One month.
The 1st of February.
Well, just remember, I didn't make you say it.
I can forgive anything.
But if you let me down in front of Comrade Stalin,
I won't forgive you.
You can go.
( phone ringing )
Abakumov.
Aah.
Yes, Josif Visarionovic.
Comrade Stalin, I'm right here, sir.
STALIN: Listen, Abakumov.
You forgot to tell me about my secret telephone.
How long am I going to have to wait?
Oh, by the way, the death penalty,
we're going to give it back to you.
( alarm ringing )
Attention!
Bobynin, get up and get dressed.
What's the idea? It's the middle of the night.
Don't ask questions. Get up, Bobynin.
On the double.
GUARD: Vladimir Ivanovich Bobynin, comrade minister.
You work with the group on the secret telephone.
Or technically, the absolute encoder, Bobynin.
BOBYNIN: Voice coder. Coded voice.
Sit down.
Thank you.
I want you to speak frankly without being afraid
of getting into trouble with your superiors.
When will the voice coder be ready?
Tell me the truth. In one month? Two?
A voice coder in a month?
Heh. You-- Ha-ha-ha.
You obviously don't understand anything about it at all.
It's very complex.
Uh-- Uh...
Do you have a piece of paper?
I'll try to explain it simply.
Prisoner Nerzhin, comrade minister.
Should I turn on the lights?
No. Just send him in.
( door closes )
NERZHIN: You sent for me?
( sneezes )
Why did you sit down without permission?
Well, there's an old Chinese proverb.
It's better to stand than to walk,
it's better to sit than to stand.
And best of all is to lie down.
Do you realize who I am?
No, who are you?
Someone like Marshall Goering?
Like who? Marshall Goering.
You don't see any difference between us?
Between you and him or between us?
Between us, I see it very clearly.
You need me and I don't need you.
Listen, prisoner,
I want to talk to you like a human being,
but don't forget yourself. I don't talk at all
unless I'm treated like a human being.
We can make you talk when we want to.
You are wrong, citizen minister.
I don't have anything.
Do you understand? Not a thing.
My family is dead.
You don't let me see my wife even once a year.
You took my freedom away long ago
and you can't return it to me
because you don't have it yourself.
I've already been in Siberia. I've been in chains.
You taught me to sit bare ass in the snow.
What else can you threaten me with?
What else can you take away from me?
My work as an engineer?
You'll lose more than I will.
I'm going to smoke.
Here. These are good.
Thanks, but I don't change brands.
Makes me cough.
Just understand one thing,
and pass it along to anyone at the top,
that you only have power
as long as you don't take everything away from people.
Because a person you've taken everything away from
isn't afraid anymore.
He's free again.
Engineer Nerzhin, I didn't call you in here
to get your views.
You're working on the voice coder.
Please tell me when it will be ready for use.
Well, there's something new.
Isn't there anybody higher than me you can ask?
I want to find out from you personally.
Will it be ready by February?
By February?
( chuckles )
You are joking.
Maybe next year.
Nerzhin, weigh your words carefully.
What can be done to hurry it up?
I don't know any way.
But why? Who is to blame?
I want to know. I don't care who it is.
I'll destroy him.
I'll send you off to the North Pole.
And as for you, Yakonov,
I'll put you in your special prison
as an inmate instead of chief.
And you can finish the voice coder
with your own two hands.
This is your last deadline.
The Lenin anniversary and not one day more.
Viktor Semyonovich, I have something else for them.
We're not going to keep paying them for nothing.
See if they can't identify the voice of a criminal
from a magnetic tape.
And if they can't, throw them out.
I'll take care of them, Mikhail Dmitrievich.
What are you talking about?
It's very simple really.
Some bastard, some pig, probably a diplomat,
telephoned the professor,
Professor Dobronravov I think it was,
and warned him not to give the French
some new medicine. The rat was giving it
on an exchange basis or something.
Actually, we wanted him to give it to them
so we could catch him in the act
and then make a big political case out of it.
Consorting with a foreign power.
We have the voice on tape of the sly,
miserable bastard who warned him.
I don't understand. How can you find a man
when all you have is his telephone voice?
Only five or six people in the ministry
could have known about it.
Well, arrest them all, the bastards. Six people.
We are a big country. They won't be missed.
We can't. It's the Foreign Affairs Ministry.
We have to find out exactly who did it
as quickly as possible.
Comrade minister, I think we can do it.
The other scientists who are working with me,
and I call it visible speech device.
Voice printer.
Every voice has its own individual visual pattern,
which can be recognized
even if the speaker disguises his voice.
This could become a new science.
Like fingerprinting. Voice printing.
Rubin, you're a prisoner,
but there was a time when you were a communist.
Maybe some day you'll be one again.
Our organization has confidence in you.
You're about to hear a state secret from this tape.
We have to find this bastard
who warned a traitor to our country.
You have the disguised voice--
Turn on the recorder there, please.
--of the criminal himself here.
And later, we'll put on the recorded voices
of six suspects who knew this state secret.
Sit down.
VOLODIN: Listen, please listen.
I have to warn him. He's in danger.
WOMAN: In danger? When he was in Paris recently,
he promised the French doctors he'd give them something.
Some kind of medicine, a formula for a new medicine.
Do you understand?
He mustn't do it. Tell him not to do it.
It could be used as provocation.
WOMAN: But-- VOLODIN: Hello? Hello.
May I hear the tape again, please?
( tape rewinding )
VOLODIN: Listen, please listen.
I have to warn him. He's in danger.
WOMAN: In danger? When he was in Paris recently,
he promised the French doctors he'd give them something.
Some kind of medicine, a formula for a new medicine.
Do you understand?
He mustn't do it. Tell him not to do it.
It could be used as provocation.
WOMAN: But-- VOLODIN: Hello? Hello.
( thinking ) Heh. That's ridiculous.
Why shouldn't the French have the medicine too?
Medicine should cure, not ask your nationality.
The man who warned the professor sounds all right.
It took courage to do that.
But what if making
a scientific discovery's important?
Necessary to the state?
Then it was wrong.
And his courageous act is harmful
to the Soviet Union.
Heh. God almighty,
how disgusting they are, these generals.
Guiltless pigs like them who put me away for nothing.
God, how ironic.
Still, they represent historical progress.
VOLODIN: Is this Professor Dobronravov's house?
WOMAN: Yes. Who shall I say is calling?
VOLODIN: You don't know me. I wanna speak to the professor.
WOMAN: Just give me your name, please. Who's calling?
VOLODIN: Is this the professor's wife?
WOMAN: I don't have to tell you who I am.
Who is this? What's going on?
VOLODIN: Listen, please listen.
Give me time till tomorrow. I have to think.
WOMAN: In danger? When he was in Paris recently,
he promised the French doctors he'd give them something.
Some kind of medicine...
VOLODIN: What do you mean the minister's blocked it?
I'm all set to leave.
I'd like to speak to the minister, please.
He's not in?
( dialing )
Volodin speaking. May I speak to the vice minister, please?
Well, when will he be back?
I'd like to speak to the department director, please.
Yes, I'll wait.
What's that? Just left the office?
I'd like to speak to the supervisor, please.
Volodin.
Uh, hello? Hello?
DOTTY: Believe me, Innokenti.
We have only one life.
We have only one conscience.
What are you talking about, Inni?
Did something happen?
( thinking ) It's contemptible.
Crazy.
After what she had with someone else
that I should want her so much.
She'll suffer enough when I'm arrested.
( slow theme playing )
A056, comma 1,
times 6 comma 7-- Six...
Six.
Six comma, 6...
Serafina Vitalyevna, could you help me in here?
The microphone is dead.
Six.
A, A. No, it's not working.
The door is open.
It will be hard to say that we are satisfied
with your behavior here.
Citizen major, I observe the regulations.
When do I see my wife?
Tomorrow at 3.
Tell me, prisoner Nerzhin, who's book is this?
Oh, it's mine.
Yesenin, collected poems.
It's not forbidden.
Only books published between 1917 and 1938
are forbidden.
For instance, what does this mean?
"In earthly wedlock,
I would join the pure white rose
and the black, black toad."
Oh, very simple.
You shouldn't try to reconcile the white rose of truth
with the black toad of evil.
Did you call me in to discuss literature?
Where did you get the book? Who gave it to you?
Nobody gave it to me. I brought it with me from camp.
I want it back. It's mine.
You can forget about that visit from your wife, Nerzhin.
Could you help me over here, Gleb Vikentyevich?
It can't last long, Simochka.
Shikin's after my neck. He wants to have me sent away.
Sent away?! Where?
What do you mean where?
We come from the depths of hell
and that's where we'll go if we have to go back. Camp.
Oh.
Back to the camp.
What about your work?
I don't understand?
What will happen to the work you do?
You know, by yourself? Please, you can trust me.
I don't get what you mean.
Oh, you get it all right, that I'm an officer
and I'm supposed to be watching you
and reporting on you.
There's only one thing you don't get.
And that's if someone had come in just a minute ago
they'd have put you in solitary for 10 days, and nothing more.
But I could have lost my job. They'd have put me in prison.
Now, do you get it?
You're marvelous.
I'd like to take your body away with me.
You know what used to upset me?
That I don't have any children.
And when I get out of here, that it will be too late.
Funny, isn't it? I want to leave you with my child.
I'll wait for you.
When you get out, you'll come to me.
You haven't anyone else? A wife.
But you haven't been together for so many years.
Eight. Is she still waiting for you?
I told her not to.
I could go back completely changed
after 14 years in labor camps.
I tried to get to see her just now,
but I'm right up against Shikin.
Please listen. You have to trust me.
If anything happens I'll keep anything
you want me to.
( buzzing ) Is she very pretty?
Let me go.
Go ahead. You can check if you want.
Rope, soap, hope.
Please. Let go. Please.
( continuous buzzing )
Two plus two, shoot.
Please.
I won't let you go. I won't.
Not now. Now, here.
( buzzing )
On Monday I'll be the only duty officer.
I'll be alone then.
What?
We don't have any new dual tryout?
Yes. Thank you.
( alarm ringing )
( indistinct chattering )
( coughing )
Gleb, I asked you for Yesenin. When can I have it?
Haven't got it anymore.
Someone stole it and turned me in to Shikin.
Worst thing is they won't let me see Nadya.
Again?
She's in a very bad way.
I tried to get a visit out of Shikin
and got this business about the book.
Who talked? Do you know?
Stop yelling. You'll wake the whole place.
How should I know?
I tell you, we have to get the squealers.
What squealers? How do you know who?
Him. He said himself he was squealing.
( indistinct chattering )
PRISONER 1: Stop it. Stop it.
PRISONER 2: What are you doing?
( indistinct chattering )
Kill the dirty squealer. Kill him.
I didn't squeal on anybody.
Who stole it? Nerzhin's book and gave it to Shikin?
I saw it in Shikin's office right after Siromakha was there.
He's lying, the bastard. You're crazy.
Siromakha goes there all the time.
All right, we'll believe him this time, but I'll get him.
PRISONER: Can you prove it, Ruska?
Siromakha sleeps in another cell.
He almost never comes here.
I'll prove it in black and white.
How?
Listen, an informer gets paid 150 rubles.
They send it from outside so it looks better,
but the post office takes out 3 rubles.
So that makes 147 rubles that you get.
Tomorrow it's mail day,
and anyone who gets exactly 147 rubles,
a country should recognize its squealers
so that you'll recognize them.
And you lousy Tatar, watch out.
PRISONER: Did you get your money order?
You know who it's from? Look.
Claudia Kudratova. What a doll, eh?
Who's had lunch? Is it worth going in?
Yes, you got a lot, didn't you?
You can buy your own lunch. What do you mean a lot?
A thousand rubles.
You can spit in our chow from now on, eh?
What do you mean 1000? Look.
147 rubles?
Funny. Couldn't they make it an even 150?
You pig! Squealer!
What did you get it for and who did you sell out?
You dirty bastard!
PRISONER: Go to lunch. That was today.
Idiot. We were just going to find out, that's all.
Doronin has blown everything.
He's going around telling everybody
that whoever receives a check for 147 rubles
is an informer for you, comrade major.
Please, please, comrade major, cap me off.
I'll pump 9 grams of lead into that son of a bitch.
Doronin.
Kalyakov sent for you. It's very urgent.
Please go immediately.
( whirring )
Please, go immediately.
Doronin. Kalyakov sent for me.
There's been a phone call.
You're to be taken to Major Shikin immediately.
Prisoner Doronin reporting, citizen Major.
Ugh.
You bastard. Selling us out.
Say goodbye to life, Judas.
We'll shoot you like a dog.
You'll never leave here alive.
As for shooting,
we'll see about that, citizen major.
You just write down Ruska Doronin
under my very nose,
in my own prison, informed on all my squealers.
Everybody's laughing at you
and you're still picking up major's pay.
I won't give up Nerzhin.
Your prison is in position 134-4 plus 0.
In our human labor supply program
for the North Siberian Mine Plan.
We have to have 20 prisoners from here.
It only comes to 19 without this Nerzhin.
This Nerzhin of yours is poisoning the morale.
All you need is one rotten apple in the barrel.
We've had several incidents already.
It's the political atmosphere of the whole prison.
We found a volume of Yesenin on him.
Come, Yakonov, let's not overdo it.
One more or less, you'll get along.
No. Now, comrade, let's show a little flexibility
in our bureaucratic decisions.
As long as Comrade Yakonov has so decided.
GUARD: Attention.
Order of the day.
On duty:
Marcenko, Filipov.
Now, Ivanov, Kovalov, Bobynin, Nerzhin, report downstairs.
You have visitors today.
The day before yesterday Shikin said
it'd be a cold day in hell before I'd get a visitor.
Something has to have happened. Something great.
PRISONER 1: Something great?
How about a beautiful funeral? Stalin's.
No, we'd know his successor's name by now.
When they lock us in here for the night, something--
Anything could happen outside.
Blood, fire, a Soviet could land on the moon.
We wouldn't know anything about it shut up in our arc.
If we were going to the moon first,
they'd have to have a meeting,
and everyone would take a production oath.
PRISONER 2: There would be a report to Stalin
and a rallying call to all the colored people's of the earth
trampled by imperialists.
CHELNOV: No, no, not at all. It won't be like that.
Not at all. Don't worry.
Why not?
The Americans will get there first.
BULATOV: Have you seen Doronin?
Ruska? He wasn't here last night.
That means he didn't come back from Shikin's office.
Attention.
You all know the rules. Give nothing to,
and take nothing from your relatives.
Don't talk about your work, don't mention any names.
So, what do you talk about, politics?
About your guilt and your repentance.
You may not talk about your indictment.
There's a new rule.
From now on holding hands and kissing are forbidden.
GUARD: Attention.
Visiting time, 30 minutes.
Give nothing to, and take nothing from the prisoners.
You are forbidden to ask the prisoners
about their work or about their life.
There is a new rule.
From now on holding hands and kissing are forbidden.
If there is a violation,
the visit will be terminated immediately.
That's all.
Kopolev, here.
Lukashenko, third.
Nerzhin, here.
Bobynin, fifth.
( door closes )
( door opens )
You may not touch.
Sit down at the table.
Nadya.
Happy birthday, Gleb.
I baked something for you.
Silly, you shouldn't have.
We have everything.
I hope you like it.
Do you still read Yesenin?
Yes.
You don't look well.
You're so thin.
Show me how you look.
( melancholic theme playing )
I'll bet you don't eat well.
You don't like me anymore.
I'm old.
You're as wonderful as ever.
It is your suit?
For three hours.
( chuckles )
That's how it is.
Obstacles everywhere.
Are you still mine? Mine?
I'm the one you loved.
I'm no worse.
How's your work going?
They make it very difficult for me.
What do you live on?
I have a temporary job.
No fixed pay, no apartment.
Obstacles.
Very difficult ones, my darling.
I wanted to tell you,
only don't take it too hard.
You once tried to talk me into
asking for divorce.
( thinking ) Once yes, not now.
Yes, of course.
You should have done it long ago.
Would it upset you awfully if I had to do it?
It wouldn't be serious.
She's not wearing her wedding ring.
What does it mean?
You can't hope too much for the end of my term.
It's conditional.
I can't believe it.
Do you really think that I want to leave you?
No, no, Nadya, I believe you.
( thinking ) He doesn't really need me.
He was always so strong.
Does he really need a faithful woman?
Nadya.
Don't be alarmed if they send me away for a while,
and if I won't able to write.
Can they?
Where? God knows.
Oh, don't tell me you're beginning to believe in God.
Why not?
Pascal, Newton, Einstein, they were believers.
GUARD: You were told not to mention names.
End of the visit.
GUARD: What's going on?
Do what's best for you, darling. Don't worry.
GUARD: The visit's over!
Go ahead, take her. To hell with you!
Tell me something about yourself.
I know things are hard for you.
Alyosha, tell me.
Do they let you out earlier for doing good work?
No, dear.
You have to invent something.
Something special.
Alyosha, please,
invent something then.
Well, the trouble is that the inventions are--
Well, extremely undesirable.
I only have three years more.
Only three?
For you it's only.
For you it would be extremely undesirable
to be free before your time.
I've been fired from my job.
I have nothing to live on.
No one-- No one anywhere will give me work.
My husband is an enemy of the people.
I can't go through another month of it.
Alyosha, I'm 37 now.
In three years I'll be an old woman.
Alyosha, my darling,
my dearest, do something.
Make them free you.
You have a brilliant mind. Invent something.
Alyosha, save me.
Save me.
( narrating ) My secret design for the encoder was ready.
I knew it would work.
Should I place it into their hands or into the fire?
SIMOCHKA: How many sheets? Two? Please take it down.
All waste must be reported.
One.
How many do you have?
Serafina Vitalyevna,
you look like you're dressed for a wedding.
Six. Put it down.
Well, since you are so very interested,
I'm going to my uncle's birthday tonight.
Two.
How many, Gleb Vikentyevich.
None. Thank you.
169 used sheets of paper,
officially burned.
Hmm.
WOMAN: Simochka, you're up early.
Yes, I have to be at work at 7.
Also, I'm on night duty tonight.
Could you fry me some potatoes, Mama?
WOMAN: I dreamed all night about that girl at work
that you told me about.
She's taking an awful chance.
Uh, you know what?
I think she really wants to have his child.
But I'm sure she'll look after it
and wait until he gets out.
WOMAN: It's a terrible risk all the same.
How can she give her virginity to a prisoner?
( chuckles )
Oh, Mama, you know how girls are now.
For a while, their virginity is all that counts,
but then it becomes a bore.
Serafina Vitalyevna, here are a few more.
Three.
You don't need them?
No, I don't. Put down three.
OFFICER ( over the PA ): Nerzhin,
report to Colonel Yakonov's office immediately.
Please, sit down.
Please, sit down, Gleb Vikentyevich.
I'm glad to see you.
Well, apparently you've prepared
a pleasant surprise for us.
Professor Chelnov tells me
that he's looked over your drawings
for the main section of the encoder.
Why don't you sit down?
I'm very anxious to see it in detail.
You're wrong, Anton Nikolayevich.
I worked on it for a while, but it didn't come off.
Now, now, no false modesty.
Chelnov is the best judge,
and he gave it the highest praise.
I'm going to give instructions
that we are to be left alone now.
Go and get your drawing.
Anton Nikolayevich, you've made a mistake.
It's not worth looking at.
Just a sketch.
Well, we'll see. Go and get it.
I don't have the sketch.
I found irreparable mistakes in it and...
I burned it.
What do you mean?
You burned it yourself?
No, I turned it in to be burned.
According to regulations.
Then maybe it's still there.
No, it's burned.
I saw it.
( sighs )
Nerzhin,
Chelnov told me your plan was the real thing.
I've informed the Minister Abakumov
that the secret telephone will be ready in a month.
Come over here.
Are you from Moscow?
Yes.
Look down there.
Do you see the bus stop?
It's half an hour on that bus
to the center of Moscow.
Nerzhin, you could be getting on that bus yourself next July.
And in August, you'd be on holidays on the Black Sea.
How many years since you went swimming, Nerzhin?
Prisoners are never allowed that.
We can, cutting timber.
Oh, not where you're going to end up, Nerzhin.
In the north, where the rivers never thaw.
Listen, I can't believe there's anybody on Earth
who doesn't wanna get the most out of life.
Why did you burn your drawing?
Why do you think?
I don't know.
I've heard that you were in prison for five years
before you came back to this job.
So I'll tell you.
I don't want any part of this.
I don't understand.
It's suicide.
( light switch clicks )
We have to have a talk, Simochka.
What's happened?
I saw my wife yesterday.
Why didn't you tell me that before?
It happened suddenly, I didn't know.
I hadn't seen her for two years.
But now, when I saw her,
I know I am still in love with her.
Simochka, what can I do?
She's given me her whole life.
Who else would do that?
Are you sure you could?
Didn't she ever want to divorce you?
Oh, well--
No.
Is she pretty?
Yes. To me, yes.
Gleb, she won't wait for you.
Not if she's pretty.
If she's young and beautiful,
she could have-- She may--
She may live with other men.
She won't wait.
She's waited eight years.
Of course, the last years will be the hardest.
She won't wait.
She doesn't have to.
But I don't want to be the one...
If one prison visit counts so very much,
what can I do?
( whimpers )
( melancholic theme playing )
No. Turn it on.
( woman singing in Russian )
Louder.
Forgive me, Simochka.
I'll get over it.
You can still give me your work.
I'll keep it for you.
I already did. You burned it.
Citizen general, we've narrowed it down to two.
Chevronik and Volodin.
Please give us one more day at least.
Please give us a chance to prove the identity
of the guilty man beyond a doubt.
We'll pick them both up.
We'll put a microphone on the interrogation table.
And you can hear their voices.
But one of them is not guilty.
What do you mean not guilty?
Not guilty of anything at all?
The Security Police will sort it all out.
But-- What "but," Rubin?
If you can arrest both of them, then why not all five?
Why try at all?
What are you trying to say, Rubin?
Do you mean the other three are still in the picture?
Well then, we'll pick up Chevronik and Volodin.
( suspenseful theme playing )
DOTTY: It's not for us.
Somebody got the wrong apartment.
Oh.
Why are you so nervous, Inni?
I wouldn't want any uninvited guests
to spoil this evening.
We haven't been to the theater together for so long.
Are you expecting someone?
( phone rings )
You get it. I'm not here,
and you don't know when I'll be in. Go on.
Hello?
He's not home.
Who?
Oh. Good evening, comrade general.
Yes, of course, I recognize you now.
How nice of you.
Just a minute, I heard the door. Maybe--
Oh, yes, it is.
Inni, come quickly, the general is on the phone.
Hello, comrade general.
Yes.
Of course.
By all means, comrade general.
Everything's all right. I'm flying to Paris on Wednesday.
The general's sending a car.
There are a few details to go over.
Don't you think maybe I could be one of those details?
I want to go with you.
I'll see what I can do.
Now, get dressed. I'll be right back.
We won't make the first act,
but I don't think we'll miss much by it.
Already? That was fast.
I don't seem to remember you.
Have you driven me before?
Twice.
I even remember your stairway, comrade councilor.
( tires screeching )
That's our mechanic from the garage.
Ugh. It always gets stuck.
Comrade councilor, could he possibly ride with you?
You see, he's my boss.
I really should pick him up.
Of course.
You don't mind?
( coughs )
You might open the window.
Would you read this for me, comrade chief?
I'll put a light on it for you.
"Warrant for the arrest
"of Volodin, Innokenti Artemyevich...
"Volodin, Innokenti Artemyevich.
Born 1919."
Take it easy and don't move or I'll break your neck.
Let go of me. Let me go.
Driver, I hold you personally responsible for this.
What sort of outrage is going on?
Let me go!
( Volodin groans )
Get out.
Hands behind your back.
What are you doing? Shut up.
Ah. Hands behind your back.
My epaulettes. Hands behind your back.
Take your handkerchief.
After you've had your dirty hands on it?
You'll get a receipt for your valuables.
Get going.
Keep moving.
GUARD: Sleeping is not allowed.
( mysterious theme playing )
( coughing )
Air!
Open up. Open up, I'm suffocating!
Why were you banging? I felt sick.
Just remember, don't bang or you'll be punished.
I don't feel well. Give me some water.
Shouting is not allowed either.
I don't feel well. I've gotta lie down.
Sleeping is not allowed here in the box.
Listen, call the lieutenant.
Why am I arrested?
Listen, lieutenant. What's the meaning of all this?
It's a mistake.
Show me the warrant for my arrest.
Name?
Volodin. Latter name?
Innokenti Artemyevich.
Date of birth?
Twenty-second of January, 1919.
Place of birth? Leningrad.
Hands behind your back. March.
( alarm ringing )
( indistinct chattering )
Stand at attention.
Attention.
You all know the order of the day.
First, prisoners will be permitted to decorate a tree
for the New Year.
Next, the following will not report for work this morning,
but will prepare for transport from this room:
Kobarov, Mikalov, Bobynin,
Bulatov, Nerzhin.
That's all.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Listen, old boy,
for three years we haven't agreed once.
We've argued all the time, ridiculed each other.
But now that I'm losing you, maybe forever,
I fear that you were one of my best friends.
Thanks.
Undress.
VOLODIN: What for? Are you Russian?
Why? Non-Russians don't have to?
Undress.
Throw it on the floor.
Strip.
What do you mean?
If you don't, you'll be stripped by force.
Let's see if you have anything hidden.
Open your mouth.
Wider.
Lift your tongue.
Turn around.
Feet apart.
On your heels.
Again.
Get dressed.
Strip naked.
But I'm just getting dressed.
Why didn't they tell me to wait?
Strip.
Name, latter name, date of birth, place of birth.
Have you got lice?
I'm a diplomat. So what?
Have you had syphilis, gonorrhea,
leprosy, tuberculosis?
Anything else?
Quickly. Why aren't you dressed yet?
Sit down.
This is it.
The corpse died happily.
And with a smile on his face.
GUARD: Face the wall.
Don't move.
OFFICER: Volodin?
Innokenti Artemyevich, born 1919?
Do you have so many Volodins?
Could you get confused?
Hands behind your back. March.
Come on, get in there. Get inside.
SOLDIER 1: Come on! Move it on in.
SOLDIER 2: Come on, keep moving.
Move it along.
SOLDIER 3: Come on, get moving.
Move in that truck. Come on, move it.
Faster.
SOLDIER 4: Where do you think you're going? Get in!
SOLDIER 3: Get in there. SOLDIER 5: Keep moving. Get in.
SOLDIER 4: Move it along.
SOLDIER 3: Come on, get moving.
Move in that truck. Come on, move it.
SOLDIER 6: All in the front.
SOLDIER 3: Faster, move it. Come on.
SOLDIER 7: Close it, close it.
Now and again on the streets of Moscow,
one sees food delivery vans.
Clean, well-designed and hygienic.
One must admit that the city's food supplies
are extremely well-organized.
Brothers!
I'm going to Butierki.
For interrogation. Who's there?
Who's being transported?
Ruska! Nerzhin!
Bulatov! Bobynin!
OFFICER: No talking during transport!
Quiet, damn you! Fucking son of a bitch.
We're just saying goodbye!
( all laughing )
MAN: Ruska, did they beat you?
Yeah! They beat like hell.
Now we are going to the real hell, Ruska.
All that before was the highest circle.
Almost paradise.
Ruska, we'll meet in camp!
Don't be afraid, Ruska.
They are frightened themselves.
( melancholic theme playing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( wind whistling )