MICHAEL: Hey li'l Patty, here you are my buddy.
Eh, how's my little bear doing?
Got some treats for you, here you go.
You've got the most beautiful face.
Hey, how you doing man?
♪
NARRATOR: You're about to experience something rare,
something controversial, and yet, there's no question --
this is something extraordinary.
[ Growling bear and MICHAEL chatting to the bear. ]
NARRATOR: Throughout history, there have been stories handed
down to us -- stories of unusual connections
between man and animal.
Some are true.
Some we aren't so sure.
But you won't meet a man more true than Michael Scheibler.
MICHAEL: Want to go digging in there, eh?
We do offer rides.
Bare back bear rides.
Five hundred dollars for a female
and one thousand dollars for a male.
That includes the coffin.
♪
NARRATOR: Join us for an unexpected journey.
It's more than a connection with nature.
It's a connection with the past, and a connection
with the power of redemption.
Near the shores of the Rainy River in northwestern Ontario,
lies the little town of Emo.
Population of about 1300.
Including Michael and Betty Scheibler, a dog, a cat,
a raccoon, a pigeon, a wolf, lots of deer,
and of course, the bears.
In 2002, Michael and Betty bought 320 acres of this land.
They had big plans.
Michael, a landscaper by trade,
dreamed about building a golf course here
and a motocross track for bike enthusiasts.
Something to support themselves and live out their dream
of living off the land.
But little did they know there was something unusual
about this place.
They got a hint shortly after they moved in.
MICHAEL: One day Betty was here with her youngest daughter.
We were looking at things, we were renovating
and trying to make it our home.
So we were in the bedroom.
I had just put in the screen door,
because it's plastic screen,
and this great big male bear is walking up.
And her daughter, Tricia, is like, "Hey, how are you?"
And there's a big male bear the size
of the guys you saw this morning.
And I'm going, "Eh, you guys...?"
And she, and the bear come and...
[ sniffing ]
...and he sticks his nose
up against the plastic screen , okay?
And Tricia, she just kind of sticks her knee over to him
against the screen and he's sniffing her knee.
And I'm going, "You guys are nuts!"
[ chuckle ]
So we put some food out for them.
So now this bear's been fed.
Tricia goes home and Betty goes to work.
So now guess what?
I gotta feed the bears!
I know nothing about feeding bears, I got not training.
I just, "There you go!"
I just throw it, "There you go!"
It was my introduction into the bears.
The next year thirteen showed up and a bunch
of deer we had in the wintertime.
We're up to seventy to a hundred deer a day
in the wintertime here,
and we're up to almost sixty bears now.
BETTY: It is really neat, really.
I've always had a love for animals, always.
Like, my dad always brought animals home
that he found orphaned or wounded or whatever
and so I kind of grew up in it.
MICHAEL: In October of '03 we got a phone call from friends
of ours in Stratton, about 25 miles west of here,
that this little cub was
up in their crab apple tree for two weeks.
Some idiot had shot the mother.
So he was the first cub we rescued.
We brought him over here.
I got a picture of him 15 minutes later by the pond there.
BETTY: The day we brought him home I was sitting at the cage
that we had him in, talking to him softly, calmly.
You know, telling him, "What a cute little baby you are."
And I was trying to feed him stuff through the mesh wire.
Of course he was scared, and he was growling
and he was making sounds.
He didn't want nothing to do with me.
From that time on, even the following year when he came back
out of hibernation I was the one that seemed
to go out and feed him.
Mike got some pictures of it and whatnot, but it just seemed
like the two of connected more so that any
of the other animals that were here.
He still holds a special spot in my heart.
He always will.
MICHAEL: You know, he's just a really nice bear.
He's so passive, he won't get into fights with anybody.
No matter how hungry he is if another bear comes,
he wants to join him, he just lets him.
He won't chase him off like the other bears.
He's one bear that will not.
BETTY: I wake up in the morning, sometimes I wake
up to the sounds of the bears outside.
That's what wakes me up.
Sometimes there's one, up to five
and six bear out there eating.
It's really neat.
It's better than waking up to traffic,
sirens, stuff in the city.
It's peaceful, it's calming, it's cool.
MICHAEL: He was the first one to take a doughnut
out of my mouth when he was little.
As he got bigger, every fall, he'd bring cubs with him.
It is odd that a male bear would bring cubs.
They're supposed to kill them, everything I'd ever learned.
And one year he brought five cubs.
They were either orphaned or abandoned, we don't know
where he picked them up.
He'd bring them to the troughs, they ate,
he lay down while they ate, then he ate, then they'd all go.
Betty, my wife, wondered
if perhaps he knew what it was like to be an orphan.
We don't know what's going on in his head.
But it was those instances and other things
that were happening here why I remembered somewhere back
in my youth, either hearing a scripture or having read it,
something about a bear and a calf, and a lion and a kid.
And so I started researching my bible and I found Isaiah 11.
And so I believe this was a foreshadow of what is coming.
It's not here yet but it's a blueprint of what's coming,
in that day when all will be at peace.
The lion will lay with the lamb, the bear will graze
with the calf, as I've got written there,
and a child shall lead them.
So I'm like a child, I'm leading them.
I may be fifty-eight years old, but my head,
I don't think it's got past my teens yet.
[ chuckles ]
Let's go get that, yeah!
NARRATOR: Michael calls his little piece
of paradise the Isaiah 11 Wildlife Rescue
and Rehab Sanctuary.
Isaiah 11 refers to an ancient prophecy from Scripture.
[ NIV ]
The wolf will live with the lamb,
the leopard will lie down with the goat.
The calf and the lion and the yearling together;
and a little child will lead them.
The cow will feed with the bear,
their young will lie down together.
And the lion will eat straw like the ox.
Michael believes that ancient prophecy may just be coming
true-right here in his back yard.
MICHAEL: That's pretty cool, these two playing.
NARRATOR: Sanctuary is not just in the name
of this unusual place.
It's a special word for Michael.
A sanctuary for the injured, the abandoned, the orphaned.
MICHAEL: Well, every year, the third weekend in August,
they have what's called the Emo Fair.
I get a call the day that they're setting
up from this guy telling me he's got a raccoon,
he's been carrying it with him for two months.
He was trying to find a place to bring her because it just lives
in a trailer with him, traveling all over the place.
He wondered if we could take care of her,
so I said, "I'll be right down."
I picked her up, heard the story of where they found her
in a camp ground almost dead.
Just barely able to navigate at night.
He figured the mother had been hurt and he did a great thing.
He did call the government, they insisted that it was illegal
for him to have her and that he bring her
down so they can give her a needle and put her down.
He said, "No, that ain't happening."
So, I picked her up.
And I told the daughter, who was 15, I told her that I'm going
to call her "Destiny" because of all the different things
that had to happen.
All the perfect timing, all these things had to happen
for her to end up here at Isaiah 11.
That's the only name I could give her, "Destiny."
It was her destiny to be here.
I give her milk, and all raccoons
for some reason just love Butter Tarts.
So she gets that, she gets raisin bread soaked
in milk and corn on the cob.
She loves corn on the cob,
which I guess is a natural raccoon diet.
You're not going under the deck, it's a little too early.
She's number fourteen.
Fourteen raccoons we've rescued and released.
Some of them, when they got here they were
so small their eyes were just opening.
Everybody gets along here.
The birds play.
. . the bird plays with the cats and...
It's just amazing the stuff that goes on here.
Say bye! Bye bye!
Bye bye, bye bye!
NARRATOR: As Michael opened up his property and his heart
to these animals, unusual things began to happen.
MICHAEL: A mother with three cubs shows up.
She brings the three cubs on the deck and leaves.
I'm going, "I don't believe this is happening."
Why would this strange bear bring her three cubs here?
I'm bottle-feeding them, they're fighting over treats,
and then twenty minutes later she comes
and all she does is eat out of my hand, too.
What is going on here?
And then all these other bears, all these things that happen.
I've got no training for this.
I don't have any degrees or initials
in front or behind my name.
What is going on here?
That's why I call it Isaiah 11.
A male bear is not supposed to share cake with cubs.
I've got photographs.
There he is.
Big, big male sharing a cake with three cubs and the mom.
This is just one of the trails I've blasted through here.
Man, I used to walk, and my wife used
to walk all the time around the property.
The other thing I've noticed
about the bears is how sociable they are
and how they remember each other from generation to generation.
Sometimes they'll be separated from the fall before
and they'll come together for the last couple of months.
They'll remember, "Oh, there's food here."
And all of a sudden they'll show up.
There will be a little bit
of nattering then you'll see them going slowly towards each
other, sniffing noses, they eat,
then they romp, playing together.
I know who they are.
I'm like, "You're the generation before.
This is your step-sister, or your step brother."
Or something, whatever.
So I know when one of these are killed a whole bunch
of them are affected by that.
I see it when there's one that arrives sick.
They seem to sense that there's something wrong with this bear,
and they'll do like a protection to make sure he's getting food.
They'll back off and let it eat.
Oh, there's one sitting right there.
Hey, there we go.
That's Milo.
C'mon Milo.
See, he wasn't worried about our voice,
he was just wanting to hit that brush.
One thing I notice about bears, see this one here ran,
not because of our voices or because they saw us,
but because I brushed against that branch.
One thing I noticed early on is bears actually use weapons
as a tool against something they want
to chase away, to scare away.
And what they'll do is they'll simply go in behind something
like this, and they'll smack it down.
Just smack!
One time I had, when I was first starting this, I had a mom,
two moms and their cubs by this one tree here and I was going
over there to feed them.
Both moms charge me at the same time.
Each had their own little tree.
They smacked it on the ground and warned me.
So I said, "Okay, here you go."
And I just threw it to them and they were okay.
I don't know if anybody knows this,
that bears actually use tools as a weapon
to help drive off something they want to chase away.
They'll use a tree, a small sapling, and to whip it down.
It just makes a sound like a whip hitting the ground.
That's pretty cool.
So, I'm not a bear expert but I am learning all the time.
Different things I pick up.
I have to keep my little trail clean, you know?
Well, back when I was six years old I was given the choice
about a puppy in a basement
in Winnipeg cause we were leaving the city
to move onto a farm.
They took me down some stairs to the basement, there was a litter
of puppies and one of them left the litter
and come running over to me.
I picked him up and figured that's the one,
cause he likes me.
So, I figured I'd take this one, and I called him Moxy.
I have no idea where that came from.
I don't even know what it means but that's what I called him.
This puppy, he brought a connection to me.
He was something that loved me no matter what.
No matter how bad I was, no matter how many spankings I got
from my parents he still licked my hand and my face.
To him I wasn't a bad person.
So I grew this really, really tight bond with this little dog
that we then went to the country with.
So, with this puppy called Moxy, it was my first introduction
to an animal that I can remember.
A couple of years later we had some company from Winnipeg
and we had very little food.
The fact that we were even alive is a miracle
because there was no welfare back then.
There was no back up system.
So, I remember the dog eating basically scraps.
Potatoes! Can you imagine dog eating potatoes?
Whatever we had, so the dog was always
on the verge of starvation.
I mean, so were we.
We had some people come over.
This little girl went over to his dish
that he'd just been given some scrap food
and she went over to his dish.
The dog nipped her just above the eye.
And of course she comes in screaming,
got everybody all upset.
My dog's full-grown now.
The next thing I remember, I see my father has my dog on a rope
and he's got the twenty-two in his hand
and he's walking off into the bush.
I'm screaming and yelling, bawling my head off.
I don't know what he's going to do
with it, it doesn't look good.
Then I watched them fade off
through the meadow and into the trees.
You know, that day was a turning point
in my life towards how I saw my father.
And it wasn't good.
A murderous spirit rose up in me that was just so violent.
And unfortunately I took it out on my siblings.
I was very cruel to them.
I had a real resistance to anything
that wanted to be attached to me.
Because something was going to happen to it.
It was going to either die or be killed.
NARRATOR: Running Paradise isn't easy.
In fact, it's a lot of hard work.
There's no such thing as Purina "Bear" Chow.
So, four times a week, Michael gets
in his 1998 GMC pickup truck
and makes the 70 mile round trip into town for food.
His truck has over 270,000 miles on it.
MICHAEL: I just call my buddy and he just nods his head,
"Yeah, you're right, yeah, yeah.
You got that right, yeah.
Oh yeah, oh yeah, oh yeah."
[ chuckle ]
It's a 24/7, 365 days a year job with this wildlife sanctuary.
There is always food to be gathered up.
The one break I get is in the wintertime
where I only have to go twice a week.
But in the summer time I've got to go four times a week
into Fort Francis to pick up this food
because we're always day-to-day.
Isn't that right buddy?
"Yeah, you got it."
I hate when food is wasted.
I just can't stand it because of the way I grew
up we didn't have much.
It would be perfectly fine with me
if there was never any stuff thrown away,
it all went to people.
That would be fine with me
because then I know God would provide some other way
for the animals.
But in the mean time,
while they're doing this why take it to the dump?
Might as well make some good use out of it
and feed the wildlife that needs it.
I mean, it sounds like a simple meal for bears,
but there's so much minerals and vitamins and stuff in bread.
That's why their coats are so healthy looking.
Isn't that right buddy?
"Yeah."
[ chuckle ]
One time I had two guys and their girlfriends here
in their mid-twenties.
The girls were in the back and this whole trip
through here they were laughing and giggling.
I got to about there and I turned around and I said,
"I realize you guys aren't laughing
because something's funny, you guys are laughing
because you're scared stiff, right?"
Then one of the girls says "Well, we were talking about,
what are we going to do if a bear comes out of the woods.
What are we going to do?"
I said, "Well, you can pray."
[ chuckles ]
NARRATOR: Michael's parents left Nazi Germany
after Hitler's defeat and immigrated to Canada.
Life was harsh, and cruel.
And sometimes, so were they.
There was a lot of abuse from the parents towards us.
Some of the abuse I don't want to, you know, it's...
From a young age my sister and I were planning on running away.
And actually one day we did.
In the middle of winter we packed our little slay
and we were running away from home.
We were five and six years old probably.
Or four and five.
Something like that.
I was terrified of my father.
Both parents, terrified of them.
My sister and I would, she's a year and a half younger than me,
I'm the oldest of eleven.
If our parents left the house
to go somewhere we would secretively, quietly whisper
in a corner of the, wherever we were, try and come
up with a plan of how we could kill them.
Whether people like to hear it or not it's part of my past.
It's part of the healing that my gracious heavenly father brought
me through.
The first time I attempted suicide I was nine years old.
Now, can you imagine a child?
I had witnessed my uncles and my father killing an animal.
What they did was they took a hammer and they hit the calf
or the cow on the head with this hammer.
It fell to the ground and then they would cut the throat
and bleed it.
Well, in my young little mind it was the hammer blow
that killed the animal.
So one day when I was down in the barnyard working with the,
whatever I was doing there, I took a hammer
and I walloped myself right
between the eyes with this hammer.
And all I ended up with is this great big mouse on my head
and I had to lie to my mother how it got there.
Then a couple of years later I tried to hang myself.
I got scars on the bottom of my neck here, but the rope broke.
Going to Fort Francis, which is
like a thirty-five mile one way trip and picking
up at the different destinations.
It usually takes me a couple, a couple and a half,
it's sometimes even three hours cause I might have to wait
for one of the bread trucks to come back.
So there goes the morning.
Then I go home and I sort
through everything, separate everything.
There goes another hour.
And then it's feeding's another hour.
So the whole morning is until noon, one o'clock,
is usually dedicated every two days just
to get the food together.
Get it in the tubs and get it sorted out.
Get the doughnuts and the cakes sorted out.
Then the doughnuts and stuff I hold back,
they're just treats for...
The little girl waved.
The horns, they love the horns on the truck
[ chuckle ]
. Some people might think that bears,
that all they're getting is the sweets and stuff,
but they're just the treats.
The cakes are held back for the moms with cubs
so they can produce milk better and the doughnuts
and the cookies are all held back, always,
for when people show up.
If nobody shows up and I've got pails left,
then I just fire them out for them.
So the bears have an all-raw, very, very healthy diet.
I get them what fruits I can when I find them.
They love cabbage, they love lettuce.
A lot of times stores throw it out because it's out-dated.
When I get milks or yogurts, cheeses, that all goes
into one of the troughs there.
They have a good life.
This truck has hauled a lot of stuff, man!
It's a tired, old truck too.
She's got 432,805 kilometers on it.
The body's falling apart now.
And I want a Ford!
[ Michael chats to dog ]
NARRATOR: This is how Michael forages for food
for his beloved bears.
They're only three weeks away from hibernation
and the bears need a remarkable 24,000 calories a day
to store fat for the winter.
So, Michael's made friends with the folks
at local grocery stores,
where they donate their excess or expired food.
Michael is deeply grateful.
Along the way, he never misses an opportunity
to talk about his passion.
MICHAEL: Good morning!
Would you like a brochure?
If you want to come with your family it's free, come out
and visit, feed some bears if you want to.
WOMAN IN CAR: Okay.
MICHAEL: Have a good day, God bless.
There's three more boxes inside.
A lot of times I'll get seven, eight, or nine boxes.
Today it's a little bit skimpy but it's better than nothing.
Every little bit helps.
This is lots of fun when you're in the middle of a sleet storm.
Boy, snowing, wet, rain!
But the show must go on!
I will not let these animals go hungry,
I don't care what it takes.
They've never yet gone without.
I will go without first.
And I do go without a lot.
It's been a really neat experience having what the Bible
would call "sparrow faith."
When God says, "The sparrow don't worry
about what he's going to eat, I feed him every day."
So he says, "don't worry about what you're going to wear,
don't worry about what you're going to eat.
I'll look after you."
That was the plan all along.
Right from Adam on, that was the plan.
And we're getting back to that so I have
to remind myself every day not to worry about the supplies,
not to worry about the food.
That some how God is going to see it through.
I've got to have sparrow like faith that he is going
to provide the manna every day.
In the spring or summer we were each given a little ducking,
my sister and I, to look after.
It was our job to raise it, make sure they had food,
make sure they had water.
We assumed they were our pets.
And we treated them as such.
We had no idea that they were going to go on the dinner plate
when they were bigger.
So one day, out of the blue, my mother tells me to go down
and get one of the ducks and kill it on the chopping block.
And I was, "What?!"
I mean, I did't say that because you don't question anything.
When they said do something you...
See, there was no communication
in our house except, "yes" or "no."
You don't ask, you don't question, you just do.
I remember picking up this duck, which was a good size now
and walking what seemed like a long walk from the building
where it was up to the woodshed to where the chopping block
and the ax were, and apologizing to it profusely.
I said, "I don't want to do this.
I don't want to kill you."
But my, I had, my mother want...
"I don't want to do this."
And so then she opens the door and hollers out, again,
in German you know, "Have you got that done yet?"
And I'm standing there with the duck and I said,
"I don't want to do this!
I don't want to kill!"
And then she started hurling insults at me.
Cutting me down, you know.
"Being stupid, you're the man of the house.
Do I have to come and show you how to do everything?"
That kind of stuff.
And I refused to do it.
She comes over and she grabbed me
and like this, kinda shook me.
Took the duck out of my hand, put it on the block,
took my hand, put it on the duck.
Put the ax in my hand, took her hand over my hand,
lifted up the ax and chopped its head off.
The second that ax chopped that ducks head off...
the fury, the anger, the murderous spirit
in me towards my mother now, was almost out of control.
Rage. That is not something you put a child through.
A child should not have to kill anything
because it will set the tone in your spirit for years to come.
Years, the damage that something like that does.
And it damaged me tremendously.
I had no regard for life anymore.
I came within hairs, sometimes, of almost killing a human being.
I was so enraged.
I had so much rage and anger.
That's the reason I left home and was in a motorcycle gang.
That's why the gang took me in, cause they realized
after a few days of working with their president
at their job site what kind of an idiot I was.
I hated everybody and was afraid of nothing.
In fact, I invited death.
But I dared somebody to try it, kind of thing.
Are you going to help me unload, Buddy Coo?
Eh, Cameron, you going to help me unload?
Let's go unload for the bears.
They always come to help.
Hey, Clyde, you come to help me, too, and Buddy Coo?
♪
C'mon guys, come and get her!
Come and get it!
Lunch is being served!
Come on! Come and get it!
Come and get it!
Now I'll throw the bread on top,
then I'll get two more pails of chop.
Throw those on top, then I'll get the grease.
[ Dog barking ]
Hi there!
[ People talking in the background ]
How are you?
Hey there, come and get her, here we go.
Come and get it.
Uh, I'll dump this over here.
Oh, buddy, here you go.
I'm going to keep this out of the mud and just put it
over in the grass for today.
That's Panda here.
Here you go.
Here ya are.
Here ya go, yeah.
Sunflower seeds.
I learned bear talk, where I can talk bear cubs away
from their mom.
What I did is I'll listen to the mom's, the noises they make,
then I'll watch the cubs and see how they responded,
and then I practiced.
Then the first time a mom I'd never seen before showed
up with three cubs and I practiced that sound.
Even though they had doughnuts
in the tub the three cubs left their mom.
She was going crazy, she was just pacing back
and forth grunting and snorting.
The three cubs came and just sat in front of me
and I just hand fed them some special treats.
And then I realized this actually works.
It's just some guttural sounds that you make,
[ making gutter sounds ]
you know something like that...
And the cubs know what that means.
They either go up or they come down.
[ chuckles ]
It's amazing.
I thought, "I just called these three cubs
from their mother, this is nuts!"
It was so much fun!
♪
[ Michael chats to the bears ]
Anybody getting hungry?
There's french fries in here, and gravy.
This happens twice a day.
[ Bear growling in the back ground. ]
[ Michael makes guttural sounds ]
Here comes their mom.
Come on Flicka, hey girl.
Hey little Patty.
NARRATOR: Michael's sanctuary is a peaceful place.
But it was a dark and painful journey to get here.
MICHAEL: All I wanted was love.
I remember one time standing in Calgary at nighttime all
by myself looking at all the lights at all these apartments
and just screaming out, "God,
if you're out there why won't somebody just love me?
Why? Why am I all alone, why won't anybody love me?
Why can't I love anybody?
Why are you always so angry at me?
Because that's what I was taught in church.
Lightning bolts, two by fours.
It was so bad that if I hurt myself
on a job I'd just scream out, "Why, what did I do now?"
But that's the theology that I'd had drummed into me
from my parents at home and from the church I went to.
That God was a god of judgment and anger and wrath.
God was wrought!
You are good for nothing.
You'll never amount to anything.
Famous words of my parents.
So you start believing it.
And then as the pressure builds you just want out,
you want to check out.
I'm out of here.
So I didn't care.
You know, all these questions, what is going on here?
I wanted to know, I wanted to have a relationship with you.
I am fed up, sick and tired of religion.
I want nothing to do with religion.
I want a relationship with my heavenly Father
who says that He loves me.
And that through these animals he has been reintroducing his
incredible love for me through them,
and giving me this love for them.
This compassion and then reopen my heart
to be also compassionate and more loving to people
because I'd written people off.
I'd just had it with people, humanity.
[ Honks horn ]
That's an old Buick horn I put in here.
Well, today we're going to go down about a mile into the bush.
An area where I first started logging with the tractor
and I put brush piles together
so the bears could use them as dens.
I know of at least one that's used every winter as a den
so we're going to go have a look at it.
We should see some evidence of the hole where they go in.
If there's any trampled grass or whatever.
You might even see a bear or two.
You can see where the bear have all been active,
where all the grass if flattened out.
Look at that.
They've been very active in here.
There's a den.
There's a den, the entrance is on the other side of there.
Yeah, you can see they've been flattening down trees.
There's a lot of action here.
There's a regular trail right
through here you can see is used.
This is one of the first piles I put together for the bears.
You see the hole in here?
That's the hole there, that's where they go in.
And it looks like it's been freshly used too.
There's some evidence of some fresh trampling going on.
Anybody home?
Hello? Anybody home?
It's me, come to say hi!
Nobody home.
But these are the kind of piles I put, I mean hundreds
of these all over the place, specifically for bears.
Even when I didn't know that there were bears here,
I figured, how many places...?
If I build it they will come.
And they did.
I saw that movie, that was a great movie.
Look at all the evidence of the bear, all traffic.
Look at all the flattened grass.
All the trails.
I noticed a few years ago when I was back here cleaning up I saw
that a lot of them, they'll go right in this tall grass
and you can see the areas where they've lain down.
See, that's pretty cool.
So, when they're buried into that the flies are harder to get
at them, it's cool and moist.
The swamp is moisture so it cools them down.
And they use this whole are, it's full of sleeping patches.
One year I know that in this grass one bear hibernated here
for the winter because come the spring break up I saw
in the snow tracks coming out of what looked like a den,
but it was just the snow that had crystallized and frozen
around him in the grass.
That's when I started realizing that bears don't all den up.
Only the females that are pregnant den up or the ones
that have their first year cubs with them for the second winter.
They'll den up.
All the other bears, they'll just back themselves
into tall grass like this
and cover themselves and get snowed over.
We have a number of bears that half their ears froze off.
The top part because their head wasn't properly buried.
Blondie, one side of his one ear half gone one side
because he didn't have that head protected too well enough.
Because they'll just back themselves under a fallen balsam
or something, or into tall grass,
and just let themselves be snowed over.
Bear in the tree!
A couple of them, one in each tree there.
Three cubs.
Out in the middle of nowhere, isn't that cool?
NARRATOR: At one time,
Michael could have been driving a golf cart along the green.
Instead, he drives an All Terrain Vehicle
through the brush.
He's been feeding and caring the
for bears every day for over eight years.
It's hard work, but it's no chore for Michael.
To him, it's a reward.
MICHAEL: Oh, raccoons!
Raccoons are in here.
How you doing?
That's the one's we raised last year.
Sorry to startle you like that, did you get your doughnuts?
I remember going to the Winnipeg Zoo and being fascinated
but also it wasn't very long and I felt sorry
for those animals being caged up in these places like this.
And I wanted to set them free.
So, that's why the sign here I have, "The Perfect Zoo!!!
People Caged.
Wildlife Free."
I couldn't understand why people would want
to put these big animals in such a dirty little spot.
And they were just pacing, I knew that they were unhappy.
And so when I went to the Vancouver Zoo I tried
to plot and I planned.
How can I set them free?
But I realized that if I set these wolves and tigers,
they're all going to get killed
because they're going to be in the city.
They're going to be shot.
I can't just release them.
So I turned away from going to zoos cause I couldn't handle it.
What you doing up there, eh?
Here you go.
There you go.
Come on Anson, come on Lightning, come on Milo.
Come here.
Here you go.
Whoops. Yes sir.
So I try to study characteristics of the bear,
because that's the only way to remember them.
Because when they're cubs, like these cubs, okay,
I might be able to tell a difference between some of them.
But when they come back next spring I'll have no clue
who they are.
So by paying attention to different movements
that they make or how they, just even a movement of the head
or whatever, I can pin them and say, "Okay.
Oh, this is so-and-so."
See I'm still trying to catch up from last year.
Just the other day I'm going, "That's Otis.
That's who that is!"
Cause him and Milo, I know that's Milo because one,
he had a limited amount of black female cubs
and this is the right size.
Well, that's Milo.
Well, what happened to Otis?
Well, forgetting that he'd grown much bigger than her already
and he's now a big male.
I was like, "Ah!
Otis!" All of sudden it clicked where I remembered something
that he did spending the whole summer with him.
♪
NARRATOR: For the first two years of the sanctuary,
Michael would throw the food to the bears.
But as Michael and the bears developed a mutual trust
in each other, he began to do the remarkable.
Maybe unthinkable.
He began to feed the bears by hand.
MICHAEL: Here you are.
Good girl.
That's my Saga.
Here you go, come get you're cake.
Oh, you want to ride the mower.
Here you go, come on.
Come and get it, there you are.
Come and get it, there you go.
Good girl, here she comes.
Stay, don't, don't move.
Here she comes.
Here you are, good girl.
Good girl.
That's some pretty sticky stuff, eh?
Worse than peanut butter, oh my.
[ chuckle ]
Boy, oh boy, that is so rich, eh?
Double-chocolate German cake.
♪
BETTY: Only once was I ever afraid.
I went out and I took a pail of goodies.
I knelt down, big Blondie come up to me and I'm feeding him.
I heard this noise from my left side and I thought,
"What in the world is that?"
But I didn't want to take my eyes off of Blondie
because making eye contact with the bears is really important.
So I kept feeding him and then I heard the noise again.
Only I think it was a little bit louder.
I so much wanted to look to see what this noise was
because I could see Blondie was starting
to stiffen a little bit.
At the same time the noise got louder, and Blondie then turned
and looked to my left at the same time I took a quick look.
And here come Mike out of the one building
where he had three raccoons, I think it was at that time,
with a bunch of people.
They were a making all these, laughing and going on, eh.
And I thought, "Oh, Lord!"
You know, and Blondie's looking
and I could tell Blondie was scared.
And I thought, "Oh, okay.
If this is going to happen it's going to happen this time."
You know, because his whole body was stiff.
His front legs were just planted right there
and so I just sat there and then Mike saw me
from when he come out of the building.
Then he had everybody quiet down,
then everything just went still.
Blondie relaxed.
[ nervous laugh ]
He didn't take no more doughnuts or nothing, but he just kind
of relaxed and he backed, took about two
or three steps backwards and he went back into the bush.
I left out a sigh of relief and I thanked the Lord for that.
Because I knew just one swat and that was the end of me.
[ laughing ]
MICHAEL: There's Blondie.
Hey Blondie!
There's our alpha male, he does all the breeding.
Blondie is the father to all the cubs you see,
all eighteen of them.
Looks like sometimes the black genes were stronger than his.
Hey Panda, hey girl.
Here you go, yeah, there you go.
Come on. There you go, good girl, there you are.
She's pregnant and going to have babies here next spring.
Eh, how many are you going to bring me?
Here you go girl, here you are.
Here you are, good girl.
Aw, yeah, good stuff.
I'm coming, Ti Chape, I'm coming.
Here you go girl, good girl.
Yeah! Good girl, yeah, good girl, good girl.
Hey Milo there you go girl.
Good girl, yeah, you're such a good bear.
Such a good bear, yeah.
A little while longer and you won't be here no more.
I'm going to miss you again.
Yeah, you got, here you go sweetie.
Here you go buddy, here you go.
Good boy. Yeah it's coming, it's coming.
Here you go Milo, here you go buddy.
Hello Missy, you don't want that one?
Yeah, you're always so fussy, aren't you, eh?
Always such a fussy bear, you.
Here you go, here you go.
Here you go, good.
Here you go.
Hey, hey! Come on you two, what's the matter?
You're brother and sister, stop that.
This is Isaiah 11, behave yourselves.
Even though bears chase each other around here I've never
yet seen one attack another bear with killing in mind.
It's just a warning: This is my territory, this is my space.
This is my food.
This is my cubs.
And they may just reach out sometimes
with one of their claws.
They'll hook and they'll do a little rip, but that's all.
Never have a fight to the death.
I've just never seen that.
There you go see, you're hungry today.
You know bad weather's coming, don't you, eh?
Might not see you for a couple of days.
♪
BARB: I work as an R.N. at a small hospital
in Rainey River, Ontario.
And so of course it is a very stressful type of career.
So as a way of de-stressing, the best way is to come out here,
socialize with the bears, spend time with the bears.
I love it!
It's a haven for my husband and I to come here.
Nice and relaxing.
BETTY: I've had so many people that have come to see
that bears that comment on how relaxed,
how peaceful it is here.
They come here afraid.
A lot of them has come here afraid, and we have to talk them
out of the vehicle to come and see the bears.
And then you can't get them to go home.
You know?
You can't go three or four blocks down the road
and see somebody else doing this same thing, eh?
It's... yeah.
MICHAEL: Well, we have critics near and far.
NARRATOR: Not everyone has been supportive of Michael
and his special sanctuary.
While many people would have no problem feeding wild birds
from a bird feeder or putting food out for squirrels
or any other wild animals,
some critics believe it's morally wrong to feed the bears.
MICHAEL: Well, you shouldn't feed the bears
because you should let Mother Nature take its course.
We're supposed to be caretakers.
So I'm just taking care of my little spot
of creation, is all I'm doing.
That my feeding these animals is to help them survive.
What is so wrong with that, why are you so upset?
Well, these bears are going to go kill people.
No they're no.
I've got people phoning me up, coming here and mocking me,
saying, "Well, Michael, how many born again bears do you
have now?"
Here you go, come on Anson, come on Lightning.
Here we go, here we go.
Come on, here you go.
Here you go, there you are.
Here you are, come one, here we go.
Here you are.
Here you guys go, good shot.
Here you go, here you are, here we go.
Good girl, come on.
This is Anson, little Missy, and that's Lightening.
These cubs are disciplined by their mom for a reason.
To learn how to survive they must obey.
They must obey everything the mother tells them.
As I watch them, every single detail
that she teaches them, it's incredible.
It's all to survive.
What to eat, when it's going to be where.
You know, when to run, when to attack, and to listen.
What noises to respond to.
It's amazing.
Want some pie Milo?
Eh, want some apple pie.
Come and get it.
Her and Otis were abandoned by their mother in the middle
of May because that bear Chocolate came around
and he was determined he was going
to breed her even though she had these new born cubs.
And I called them Milo and Otis
because of the Walt Disney show The Incredible Journey and I
thought these two guys are kind of lost, you know.
Like all these cubs, we've got eighteen of them here.
Eighteen little ones this year, they're all going to be
in for a nasty shock come next spring.
About May the mothers will start driving them off.
We're going to have a whole yard full
of confused cubs not knowing why their mothers don't love
them anymore.
The cubs will go up, they'll be way up on top of those trees,
laying out on top of the boughs sound asleep.
A nice little breeze, and the mom's sometimes will lay
down at the bottom and sleep with them.
Or they'll go up the tree part ways and sleep with them.
Or they'll just leave, for hours.
This year we have eighteen cubs.
Eighteen cubs.
I had a bear come here so sick, about a three year old
and it was just about dead.
But I already knew what to do
because I realize it was anti-freeze poisoning.
I had learned from a guy when the first cub arrived
and he told me, I was just starting this.
I was only the second year, I was just still throwing food.
And he said well, it sounds like anti-freeze poisoning to me.
Get some raw eggs, cook up some...
some oat...
some oatmeal, and put cream in it.
All the rich stuff you can get, then separate it
from its mother, and give it to it.
And I said, "I'll get right on that.
What do you mean separate the cub from its mother?
You nuts?"
Well I did manage to pull it off.
I kept the mom and the two eating cubs busy and then I went
over and gave the pot, and he ate the whole thing.
The next day he didn't show up and I thought he'd gone,
but the next day he came and he's one of our bears.
In fact he's the bear we call Big John.
Yeah, Charlie came here, he's been with us four years.
I'm guessing he's about seven or eight.
Last summer he arrived with a gunshot wound.
I talked to some people about that and they said
that there are guys around who just love to gut-shoot bears
and let them run off and die whenever.
They just gut-shoot them just for the sake
of it, for the fun of it.
Obviously they didn't hit any vital organs.
He's pulled, he's made it.
Eh, Charlie?
Good boy! Now, this year you can't see the entry
would anymore.
The hairs all grown over, the skin's grown back
because it's just a small little hole.
But that side was a horrible mess.
What? He's about six hundred pounds, this boy.
Hey, hey Smoke.
There you go buddy.
There you go, good boy.
They're naturally grazers.
I've got video of a bear going around here
in the spring just mowing my lawn beautifully.
Then I started studying up on bear and going back to Genesis
and realized that when Father had made them all everything was
to be eating the grasses and the herbs of the field.
So, that means everything, including us,
we're all vegetarians when we start with.
NARRATOR: Michael has a special bond with his animals.
But of all his animals, few have touched him
like a bald eagle he named Skywalker.
Although it's illegal to keep a bald eagle in captivity,
Native Americans are exempt.
And so, when a local Indian tribe found an eagle
that had been shot, the First Nations Police called
to Michael for help.
Michael began to care for the injured animal and slowly,
day by day, he nursed the eagle to life.
MICHAEL: I sat up here
until about midnight journaling everything that happened,
all of the details while they were still fresh.
July the 7, 2010
In Memory of Skywalker, the Eagle
Ten thirty in the morning I received a call
from Sabaskon Reserve, Nestor Falls, Ontario,
that there was an eagle with a bad wing,
trapped in the fenced area of a baseball diamond, would I come
and take him to our sanctuary?
I said I'd be there as soon as possible.
On the drive up, I had already decided
to call the eagle Skywalker.
I was finished around 7 p.m. and he was lying on his stomach,
legs outback, and talons .
. . talons clenched tight
and only breathing every ten to fifteen seconds.
His whole body was limp.
Then I had no choice but to leave him in the Father's hands,
He had created him and was well capable of restoring him
if it was in His will and plan.
I had done all I could do.
The next morning I climbed up the ladder and said,
well Father lets see what you have done and there he was.
Perched on top of a cedar pole, standing as proud as could be,
just looking at me with those piercing white eyes
as if nothing had ever happened or was wrong.
I just rejoiced and thanked the Father for this miracle and went
to pat Skywalker on the head and spoke to him
for about five minutes.
I was ecstatic and full of joy for him because just hours ago,
he would have been considered clinically dead.
By evening he was perched on a board at the highest point
in his cage, a feat only a strong bird could climb to.
Skywalker would not take any food on Monday,
but he climbed everywhere and seemed to take water.
Tuesday morning no change, did not accept any food,
just tasted it and spit it out.
At eight fifteen on Wednesday morning I went to check
on Skywalker and he was lying on his stomach.
He had passed away not much earlier.
[ crying ]
I was devastated and asked God, why?
Why? Why? I petted his head as I knelt by him and apologized
that I had not done more, and I wept over him.
I was devastated and sobbed so hard and so long that I was weak
and barely able to walk to my truck
and drive the thirty miles to town.
At Wal-Mart I picked up a replacement bottle of peroxide
for my neighbor and while at the checkout,
where one of the ladies had called me over to serve me,
we got to talking and I broke down.
She told me that God had promised never
to give me more than I could bear.
I thanked her for reminding me of that scripture
and while I was still crying,
she came around and gave me a hug.
I got a warm caring hug from a total stranger
and I thanked my Father for her.
After arriving home and unloading,
I knelt beside Skywalker again and stroking
that gorgeous white head and looking into his beautiful,
fiercely white eyes said,
"Skywalker, you are free and I'll see you on that day
when all creation will worship the Lamb."
I then got up, dug a hole, and buried him.
A few steps from your special place,
I stopped, looked back and said,
"You know, you will greatly enjoy soaring in the heights
of your new sky, Skywalker.
I loved you dearly and am truly grateful that God saw me worthy
in trusting me with you.
Isaiah 40:28-31 promises me that I too will one day soar
on wings like an eagle.
I'll be seeing you then.
Skywalker, my heart is heavy but I cannot allow it to break.
You saw all the others God has sent to me to help.
They need me and I must carry on with my destiny
until that day Father says to me, 'Well done, come on home,
your journey that I set before you has come to an end
and now you will start your new one.'
I must go on."
It is now Wednesday, July eighth and it is midnight.
May the peace of God that passes all understanding be
with me tonight as I try to go to sleep.
[ Michael cries ]
This day has been hard.
Goodnight Skywalker.
God created you and said it was very good.
Did you know in His word He mentions eagles 34 times?
He is truly in awe and proud of His creation of your species.
I will now wear my eagle head necklace again in memory of you.
God, please use this to draw people to yourself.
Amen.
Excuse me, I can't see anymore.
My glasses are all fogged up.
So why does this happen to me?
Only a few days, a few days involved with an animal?
NARRATOR: Just a few days,
and yet there was a deep and powerful bond.
That's Michael Scheibler.
And that's the heart of this special refuge.
♪
BETTY: I think only the Lord could bring together what's
happened here.
People themselves can't bring this together.
MICHAEL: Once this place got set up
and the bears started coming,
people started showing up from Europe.
People started showing up from America.
Some local people started showing up.
Then one day I was standing out in the lawn and I'm looking
at 13 or so people that were standing there and all
of a sudden it hit me: I said, "Father, only you!"
How are you?
Hi.
NARRATOR: This is more than feeding wild animals.
This is about taking a place of personal pain and turning it
into a haven for healing.
MICHAEL: If God can raise animals from the dead,
how much he cares about them, how much more you?
Of course he's going to heal you.
[ laughing ]
There we go buddy, yeah.
There we go buddy coo.
NARRATOR: Michael is living out his love for animals.
And the animals have helped bring him healing as well.
MICHAEL: See it wasn't,
I can't say like so many other testimonies that I've heard
that it was over night -- just whoa, there was my life this way
and now it's this way.
For me, it's still a work in progress.
You know, you can get so busy
that you totally miss the whole thing.
God, you're bringing this together
for a reason and a purpose.
And if this is part of my destiny,
and as long as it is, I want to walk in it.
BETTY: I don't have a clue where it's going
but I just take one day at a time.
And wherever the Lord takes it that's where we'll be, I guess.
MICHAEL: God, you...
[ chuckle ]
you really do care.
NARRATOR: From a dark past, Michael has found redemption.
He's found a home for the animals...
and for himself.
MICHAEL: I don't care what people think.
I'm not going to try to please people anymore.
Because I realize I can't do it.
If you want to come up with something negative I can't deal
with that, you know?
You're not in my space, you haven't walked in my shoes
to understand why I understand what I understand.
That's okay.
God bless you anyway, that's fine.
NARRATOR: It's an extraordinary journey.
An extraordinary place.
Truly, a sanctuary...
♪