- Welcome to the F Word,
it's going to be hot
in the kitchen tonight.
Mica Paris and the family battle it out
to become my best performing Brigade.
- Okay guys, you are falling asleep,
you've got to wake up again.
- [Gordon] By cooking a three
course dinner of Mackerel
and warm potato salad.
A mouth watering pigeon casserole
and a gorgeous strawberry glory.
Plus Janet get's arsey
with the British Public.
- Oh, yes, just like your size in'it?
- What do you mean, just like my size?
Right, get rid of him.
- And I go back to the floor
to learn how to make one of the greatest
of all Chinese delicacies, Dim Sum.
I have never been in a kitchen where
I have never been in control,
so this is really fucking weird.
♪ The F-Word's here ♪
♪ The F-Word's bad ♪
♪ Cuss my mother ♪
♪ And cuss my dad ♪
♪ But I love my mother ♪
♪ And I love my dad ♪
♪ Wanna have all that they never had ♪
♪ And the F-Word's here ♪
♪ And the F-Word's bad ♪
♪ Cuss my mother ♪
♪ And cuss my dad ♪
♪ But I love my mother ♪
♪ And I love my dad ♪
♪ Wanna have all that they never had ♪
(applause)
- Right, the Mica Paris
family, how are we?
Hello my darling, good
to see you, are you well?
Cherry, how are you sweetheart?
- I'm fine, thank you
- Who's the oldest?
- Oh.
- She is
- Oh, bless, how are you sweet?
- I'm the baby.
- Nice to see you.
- Trevor, how are you?
You and I are out numbered big boy, yes?
Three diva's against two talented cooks.
- Yes, yes.
- Basically, we're fucked.
- Yes.
- Meet tonight's Brigade,
the Mica Paris family.
Soul diva Mica is joined by big sister,
Paula, a hairdresser.
These two love to cook almost
as much as they love to fight.
Dad, Trevor, a retired chauffeur
worked as a chef in his 20s.
Can he still cope
with the fast pace of
a professional kitchen?
And mom Cherry, a retired Secretary
claims she's never messed up a meal,
let's hope it stays that way.
There's no room for divas
this family must pull together
if they are gonna get
out 50 perfect dishes.
Okay, I am going to show you
how to do the starter, yes?
Pan fried fillet of mackerel
on a warm potato salad.
Mackerel, a little seasoning,
salt and pepper, okay, good,
right, a nice hot pan.
Okay, mackerel in, okay
get that nice and crispy,
it will curl up naturally,
put your fingers on.
And then after about 30 seconds,
it starts to release the fibres
and then just settles back down.
Always cook mackerel skin
side first 90% of the cooking
will take place on its skin, yeah?
We cook it and turn it over
we get dry very, very quickly.
Mackerel's officially pink,
and you have a tartar,
you can eat it raw, you can marinade it,
so be very, very careful
when it over cooks,
it gets very, very dry.
Okay potatoes in, the
potatoes have been part boiled
all we want to do is give it a little bit
of colour in the pan.
Sour cream.
A little tea spoon of mustard, yeah?
Mix the mustard in.
- Did you put salt and
pepper on the potato?
- Yeah, a little bit of seasoning.
Potatoes, in.
Okay, Spring onions, mix
it up with the sour cream,
and the mustard, what you
want is a really light mustard
warm potato salad, a touch
of Chardonnay vinegar, yeah,
it just wakes everything up a little bit,
gives it a nice sharp contrast
to the richness of the sour cream okay?
Mackerel out, nicely coloured,
literally finish it on top.
Sour dough, nice and crispy on.
Potatoes, you have the
crisp mackerel, now okay.
And look, just to make
sure they don't slide
all over the place, take a
little spoon, put it on there,
and that just stops it from sliding, yeah?
Then, lambs lettuce again,
just gently on the seasoning,
little touch of salt and
pepper, and a little glaze.
- [Cherry] The heat's taking its toll now.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Of olive
oil, it's dressed good,
a little bit of green, okay.
Very, very simple, have a little taste.
- Oh, that is so lovely.
- Okay, concentrate I want
four covers on table nine,
four mackerel, four pigeon
and four strawberry glory.
- Yes, Chef.
- We will go in two
two's as a four, Trevor.
Trevor, we are doing that
as two two's as the four.
- Yes chef.
- You have got to put two more in there.
- Fuck me, its going to be a
long night, yeah holy Fuck.
- [All] Yes chef
- Harry, put your crisps
away, put your crisps away.
- I've put them away,
I've got to eat something decent tonight.
- You are going to get fed.
- Thank you very much.
Do you want a crisp?
- [Gordon Ramsay] Guys.
- You are taking really long, right?
- Who me?
- You are taking really long
with the potatoes, girlfriend.
- Come on, that's good, nice.
Right, let's do a bit each,
a little bit of salad around the outside.
- What you need to do, is get this ready.
- Salt and pepper.
- You want the salt and pepper?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Touch of salt, Trevor,
touch of salt, Trevor.
You are here to cook, yeah, not to watch.
Now, are you happy with those?
- Lovely,
- [Gordon Ramsay] Would you pay for them?
- I would pay for them, very nice.
- Good, so would I, lets go,
under the hot plate, lets go.
Table six, please Jose.
Now we are doing four more, yes?
- Here's a food skill I've
always wanted to learn.
(Chinese music)
I love Chinese food,
but there's one amazing
delicacy so specialised
that few western chefs
have ever mastered it.
So today, I'm off in search of
some eastern culinary wisdom.
This, is Chinese Dim
Sum an absolute staple,
eat it for breakfast lunch,
every day and for the first time,
I am going to learn how
to cook them properly
but under immense fucking pressure.
Dim Sum means touch the heart.
And it's easy to see why.
Here at London's Royal China Club,
they serve a vast array
of beautiful intricate
little dumplings and rolls
from regions all over China.
What began as a simple Chinese snack
has evolved over thousands
of years into big business
all over the world.
Helping me to demystify the
ancient world of Dim Sum
is Chinese Cookery Expert, Fuschia Dunlop.
- This is one of the
Dim Sum that sometimes
Westerners find a bit more tricky
because it has that slithery texture
which Chinese gourmet's
really adore to eat.
- [Gordon Ramsay] I'm used to being
the boss of the kitchen,
but as a Dim Sum virgin, today
I am happy to be a pupil.
- Here we have the main kitchen area.
- Now these guys are very
small, do you mean petit,
look at the space, it's
minute behind here.
- Yeah and it's like an inferno
when all the woks are going.
- Shit and this one here.
- It's for steaming the Dim Sum
so you could have a stack of them.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Okay on top.
Later, my challenge will be
to get through a busy service
at this top London Dim Sum restaurant.
But with just a couple
of hours before lunch,
I've got a hell of a lot to learn.
For now, I've been put under
the expert guidance of Jung.
If anyone can speed teach
me this incredible art,
he's my man.
In his 20 years as a Dim Sum chef,
he'll have made well over two million
of these tricky little parcels.
But there is one small problem,
So he doesn't speak any English at all?
- No.
- I am screwed then, nothing at all.
Hello, good morning.
No, I am fucked.
Luckily, Fuscia's on hand to
translate his instructions.
Good to see you.
- Good Morning.
- So, what is this rice flour?
My first lesson is how to make
a prawn filled potato flour
dumpling called Har Gow.
Fold it in?
Just like pasta, the
secret to good Dim Sum
is as much about the
wrapper as the filling.
That's what's going to hold all
the flavour and moisture in.
Hard.
- [Jung] (speaks Chinese)
- [Fuschia] He said he's going to show you
how to press the skins,
now on the dough.
- Press the skins.
Unlike an Italian kitchen,
there are no pasta machines in sight.
Jesus, he's using the palm
of his hand, my God, fuck.
They are beautiful, they are so soft.
Jung made it look easy, now it's my turn.
- Use the finger of this hand to push it,
just your index finger.
So you are holding this
and just pinching but you
push it with that finger.
- [Jung] Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- [Fuschia] He is saying Dim
Sum are particularly difficult
because of all this fine finger work
and you have to be a bit calm and patient.
- Calm and patient, well I
am screwed straight away.
Calm and patient.
I can't remember being
this nervous in the kitchen
and as any pastry chef will tell you,
hot sweaty hands are not what you need
with all this delicate work.
It's so intricate, so
difficult, Jesus Christ,
they are extraordinary,
that is a lot fucking harder
than it looks, I tell you, such intricacy.
And if I thought that was difficult,
I hadn't bargained on Jung's next lesson.
Cheug Fun, paper thin cheese
and rice and potato flour
batter wrapped around
a choice of fillings.
Fucking hell.
- It's really hot so
the most important thing
of this is not to be afraid
of scolding your hands
in the steam.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Right.
- After just three minutes
this skin-scorching
paper thin sheets of batter
are ready to be rolled.
It's sticking to the top
like shit to a blanket.
I hadn't felt this clumsy since
I first set foot in a
kitchen 20 years ago.
The real killer is to wrap the filling
tightly without splitting it.
Fuck me, that was hard,
I mean seriously hard,
it's very intricate,
its all in the manipulation of the dough.
With training over, next I will be
put to the test under
hard as nails, Henry Chau.
As the Kitchen's Head Chef,
I am told he's every bit as tough as me.
Fuck knows what service
is going to be like.
Mica, this is all overcooked.
- Oh, it is?
- [Gordon Ramsay] Touch it.
- I know
- [Gordon Ramsay] Absolute rubber.
- Oh, alright, sorry, what can I say?
Where is the love?
- I am trying to fucking get there.
- [Mica] You see that is the problem
you know what the problem was,
that was trying to help P.
- Oh, stop trying to blame me for it,
do you know what?
Take your own responsibilities, love.
- If I wasn't watching her,
I would have done the mackerel good.
- Whatever!
- [Gordon Ramsay] God, Cherry and Trevor,
I wish your daughters were
working as quick as you two, yes?
Look at them.
Right you two can you do something, yes?
- [Paula] yeah.
- Give me room, man, give me room.
- [Gordon Ramsay] So,
you get the salad now
and dress the salad.
- [Mica] Pea did you do that yourself?
Yea.
- Very good.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Come on, come on, guys.
Diva, are you happy with those?
- [Cherry] Let me see,
yeah, I'm all right with it,
I'm not too crazy about those two,
I'll be straight 'cause it's
curled up, is that alright?
- I'm glad you've
answered at least to Diva,
at least you know.
- See, you've got me again.
- Service.
Fucking hell.
Last table, well done.
- I really enjoyed it,
the mackerel itself was quite simple
but you get the kick from the mustard
and the spring onion afterwards.
Really livened the dish up.
- Visually it looked really great,
there was lovely green sort of colouring
and the yellow was you know,
the taste was great, so
yeah, it worked really well.
- OK, Jose, results please.
OK, the number of diners
that are willing to pay
for their starter is, oh shit.
45 out of 50.
- [All] Cheer
- There it is, amazing.
That is amazing.
Unbelievable.
Now, that is fucking good news, well done.
- Thank you Chef.
- Main course, let's get 50 out of 50.
- Yes.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Let's clear down,
get on your stations, let's go.
- Coming up, the Brigade
attempt to cook pigeon breast
with a summer vegetable casserole.
Out the way, fucking hell.
But things fall apart.
Now we just go down like
a fucking dog's dinner.
(title music plays)
- [Gordon Ramsay] Right, Cherry, get up,
- Yes.
- [Gordon Ramsay] let's go, good girl.
- We're on chef.
- Welcome back to the F word,
time for the main course.
Pigeon breast, with a
summer vegetable casserole.
One of my favourite birds,
very lean and very healthy.
Salt, pepper, hot pan, olive oil,
Pigeon breast, skin side down first.
(sizzle)
Turn.
The most exciting thing
about cooking pigeons
is they cook in minutes.
Rest.
Garnish for the casserole,
a nice alternative to potatoes
are puff pastry fleuron.
Puff pastry.
Cut your holes, and then
cut them in half again,
so you have got this really
nice sort of half moon shape.
Egg wash, salt, thyme,
200 degrees in.
We are serving the pigeon casserole
with a combination of delicious
and summery vegetables.
Smoked pancetta.
Give the pancetta a really nice colour.
Garlic, girolles.
That looks quite sort of autumnal,
this is the summery part.
Asparagus, baby carrots,
baby leeks, blanch, beetroot,
Look at the colours of that, beautiful.
Red wine vinegar.
You're going to glaze that down to a syrup
which will start to coat the vegetables .
Chicken stock, tarragon, broad beans.
Beautiful for the summer,
the smoked pancetta has given body
to the vegetable casserole,
but the flavours in
there are extraordinary.
Slice the pigeon in half,
and you will see the colour
of the pigeon, nice and pink.
Small drizzle of olive oil,
puff pastry case on top.
Pigeon with a summer
vegetable casserole, done.
Come on, Mica we get 50 out of 50 now.
- [Mica] I know, I know, I know.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Paula,
- Yes.
- I love this, hand on hip,
shake, shake, shake, Jesus Christ.
So, they come out yeah,
we rest them skin side up,
red wine vinegar in, let
that reduce down, now, Paula.
- Yes?
- Get your pigeons in,
let's go, two portions each.
Right Mica, the idea is to
colour them, not cremate them.
(laughter)
Trevor.
- Yes, Chef?
- [Gordon Ramsay] We are there,
beautiful, nice and pink.
Very, very nice, Trevor
are we happy with that?
- [Trevor] Yes, Chef.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Good man,
make them all like that.
- [Paula] You've done five.
- Fucking hell, Mica.
- [Mica] All right, calm down.
- [Paula] Why have you done five?
- Alright man
- I need the juice
- chill man, chill
- For fuck's sake.
Jesus Christ.
Right, look at me, look, Paula come here.
I've got one and a half pigeon,
I've only got three bits of pigeon there,
I've got two bits of pigeon there,
four bits of pigeon there,
and one, two, three, four,
and five bits of there,
come on guys, we are seriously
letting ourselves down.
Now, no, no, no, come here.
- [Mica] Nice.
- Holy shit.
What do you want me to
do, fucking floss with it?
Jesus Christ Almighty.
Watch out, Janet Street
Porter's getting fruity.
- [Janet] Smoothies,
heavenly fruit filled drinks.
Mango and passion fruit,
raspberry, coconut and banana.
The perfect way to get your five a day.
What, You've got to be joking,
who writes this rubbish?
My goodness, we love smoothies, don't we?
In fact, we drink so
much of the ruddy stuff
it could fill 14 Olympic
swimming pools in a year.
That's almost 60 million pints.
Personally, I can't stand smoothies,
but you lot seem to think that
they are a healthy antidote
to 21st Century excess, but are they?
If anyone bothered to read
the labels they might be
surprised to find out what
they are really drinking.
A typical 250ml portion is
packed with natural sugar.
A portion of this smoothie
has twice the sugar
and twice the calories
as this can of Tango.
This smoothie has got just as much sugar
in it as this chocolate bar.
Now this smoothie has
got twice as much sugar
and twice as much calories
as this can of Lilt.
It's not all bad news,
smoothies do contain vitamin C
and many contain fibre too.
Essential for a healthy digestive system,
but what about the natural sugars?
I want to hear the facts from
Kath Collins, an expert dietician.
I've never, ever, ever, drunk smoothie,
to me they are like green slurry,
but they are hugely popular.
- Well they are because they
count towards your five a day,
and everyone knows they should
be eating more fruit and veg
and they are a good
source of fibre actually,
they do contribute fibre.
The problem is they're full of sugar.
- I thought it was natural sugar.
- Sugar is sugar, it has
the same calorie load,
the same affect on your teeth,
if you're having an apple,
you've got about ten
grammes of sugar in there,
if you are having a smoothie,
you can be having three
times in one little drink
and you can swallow that
in less that a minute
and that's the problem,
it's just so much sugar
in a very small volume
taken in a very short period of time.
- What happens when you
drink too many smoothies?
- If you are in energy balance,
the amount of calories you are
eating from your daily diet
is the same as the amount your body needs,
if you have an extra smoothie each day,
its giving you at least 125 calories
and over a year that would
be an extra stone in weight, 13/14 lbs.
They are not a low calorie
drink and it is actually better
to eat the fruit than
it is to buy a smoothie.
- [Janet] It's official,
drinking to excess isn't good for you.
Oh, that looks disgusting.
This is certainly not going to convert me.
I've had enough of this trendy obsession
with drinking fresh fruit.
I'm on a mission to tell people
it's far better for you just to eat it.
now to really make my point,
I've got here this repulsive fake ass.
Now this weighs 13lbs
and that is the amount
of weight you could put on in a year
if you drank one extra
smoothie every single day,
than your body actually needed,
so let's try lifting it.
Help, come here!
Drink one smoothie a day
in addition to your normal
calorie intake and you
could put on weight.
But do people know this?
If they are not exercising
enough to burn off
their excess sugar,
they could be lumbered
with a fat ass like mine.
One portion of that has
got more sugar that that.
- No!
- [Janet] Did you know that?
- No, not at all.
- You always think that a smoothie
would be much better for
you than a fizzy drink.
- Wow.
- Let's see your ass.
- [Man On Street] It's heavy.
- [Janet] 13 lbs.
- [Man On Street] (laughs)
- [Janet] You won't be
doing any running in that.
(laughs)
What does it feel like?
- A bit heavy.
- Gross.
- I drink these because they
are meant to be good for you.
- The fruit is better
- I don't want that bottom.
- [Janet] Just hold this bottom, just try.
- This is from smoothies?
Yeah that's quite shocking, actually.
- When you eat an apple,
it takes twice as long to eat
than slurping down that smoothie.
Do you know how much
weight you can put on?
- I just drink once, one a day.
- (mumbles)
- Oh, yea, just like your size in'it?
- What do you mean just like my size?
- (laughs)
- Right, get rid of him.
I was going to give you a
smoothie, you can bugger off now.
Well I think I've made my point
with that horrible big ass,
and I hope, very much,
that the commuters of London
will now drink less smoothies
and try eating a few more of these.
There's only one old smoothie
that I've got left to convince.
- Janet, good to see you my darling.
- Hello.
- You are looking
absolutely ravishing, right,
what have you been banging
on about this week?
- I've been taking smoothies out
and trying to convert people
to drink less smoothies
and eat more real fruit.
- I love smoothies,
what's wrong with them?
- How many do you eat a week?
- One a day, seven days a week.
- One a day.
You don't.
- Yeah, no, serious.
- It's a good job you're hyperactive.
- Are they seriously that full of sugar?
- They are strong of
natural sugar fructose,
which is still sugar.
- So you are saying eat fresh
fruit instead of a smoothie?
- Yeah.
- I can see you are
wearing that rubber ass,
it suits you, it makes that dress.
- I have got the rubber ass here.
- Oh, you haven't got it on.
I thought you had it on.
- This is the rubber ass, that you--
now that is what Gordon's
ass is going to look like
if he carries on having a smoothie a day.
- For a year.
- And if you stop running marathons,
God help you,
because that's what your
bum's going to look like.
- That looks like a pair of boobs.
- Not that high up, over the bum.
- No, I know, it's a Simon Cowell,
it's going to sag, like everything at 60.
- Woo.
- Jesus Christ.
You look nice with a nice
firm buttock like that Janet.
Janet don't forget your ass.
Janet!
Cherry,
- yeah.
- Now the pigeon's burnt.
Fuck me, watch out, yeah, they are burnt,
they are fucking burnt, yeah,
when they are browned,
yep they are cooked,
when they are black they are fucked, yeah?
Fucking Hell.
Now we are just going down
like a fucking dog's dinner.
Mica.
- [Mica] Yes.
- Don't go sulking and don't give up.
- [Mica] No I don't give up.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Good, lets go then
- [Paula] Just focus, focus, focus.
- Thank you.
- Okay Put the pan down there.
Put the pan down you are on fire,
no, no on the stove, out
the way, fucking hell,
- [Mica] Why did you do that
- [Paula] Because it was burning.
- [Mica] Jesus.
OK then, nice one, P.
- Right, Cherry, table of four, yes?
- [Cherry] Table of four.
- Good girl.
Trevor, you've got a table of four, yes?
- [Trevor] Yes.
- [Mica] Four coming up.
- Put it on, cut the puff
pastry please Cherry.
Trevor, I am loving you, well done.
- [Trevor] Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
- [Gordon Ramsay] One talented Dad.
Mica, Paris, let's go.
- Oh, I don't like the
way you are doing that.
- Right, now look at me,
look, it's such a shame,
I have got all the fat
still in the lardons, look.
- I didn't leave them in long enough.
Don't worry, I'll do it again.
- Mica
- [Mica] Yea, coming man, chill.
- Coming man, chill.
- [Mica] Really, just chill.
- That's the story of tonight.
Right, how are we?
- Very well thank you.
- Good, nice to see
you, how was the pigeon.
The sauce that it went with,
I think we all sort of thought
it was very, very salty
and we couldn't really eat it.
- What a shame, it was
burnt chicken stock,
so it was there to act
as a bit of a broth.
- It almost felt as though
it felt it was misnamed,
if it had been pigeon and
summer vegetables with a "jus".
- A "Jus"?
Look at you.
You've done a Master Chef haven't you?
- The tarragon was fantastic,
it really came through,
really fresh liquorish flavour,
the pigeon was cooked really
well, crispy on the outside,
tender in the middle.
- I thought it was very flavoursome
and it was quite a strong taste and yea,
it was really lovely.
- Right, Jose, the amount of customers
that are gonna pay for the
main course out of 50....
35 out of 50
- [Mica] What did I say?
- [Cherry] Oh, it was me,
that's what I said, hey!
- [Mica] Well done, Mum.
- Let's get 50 out of 50 the desert,
back to sections, let's get going.
(theme music)
- Hello, and welcome back to the F Word
and now it's time for the recipe challenge
with internationally
acclaimed super model, Me.
Come on then.
- OK, what are you doing?
- I'm doing a veg curry.
- Oh, come on, Jo, for God's sake.
- You love a vegetarian.
- Yeah I do when they're fast asleep.
Why are you doing a veg curry.
- Well, because if it
doesn't taste nice enough,
I'll just chop up a
vegetarian and put them in.
- Now that I like the sound of.
Right, when was the last
time you practised the dish.
- [Jo] Oh, about 1947.
- Is it a dish made with rationing?
- It was, yeah.
- Right, vegetable curry
and Jo's doing a classic.
What's the ingredients?
Just quickly run through,
tell me what they are.
- That's an onion, have
you seen one before?
- Yes, that's something rather, scary.
You've been in Delia's cupboard,
What is that, a jar of what?
- That, it's a Balti curry paste.
- You lazy bugger.
- Well, what's wrong with being lazy?
I am just going to chop up some garlic
and a bit of ginger and
put that in as well.
- Jo, to my horror
brought in a curry paste,
so easy to make.
Coriander seeds, poppy seeds,
turmeric, garlic, ginger
and chilli powder into a pestle and mortar
and from there a tablespoon
of ground nut oil and then,
just a table spoon of white wine vinegar.
That forms a really nice paste
and it is ten times tastier than
- How do you know it's really nice?
- I know it tastes delicious
because I have made it before.
You do a lot of cooking
at home, don't you?
- Yea, just cooking that is simple.
That doesn't take very long,
so I can go and practise my other hobby
which is being an alcoholic.
- Now you've got two
beautiful little girls, yea?
- [Jo] Yes.
- Yep Maisie and
- Eliza.
- [Gordon Ramsay]
Lovely, how old are they?
- One's 43 and the other's 2.
- Seriously, now how old are they?
- Five and seven.
What do you cook at home?
- I do a very nice Haribo
stew which they like
and then I give them chocolate,
that's the main course.
- Lucky, lucky kids you know that?
They must love you.
On tour, yes?
- [Jo] On tour
- [Gordon Ramsay] What
kind of food do you eat?
- I like a nice pork pie when I'm on tour,
yea, anything you can get in a garage
made by Ginsters always does me a treat.
- Do you know what,
you just make me feel more
confident about winning,
you know that?
- I've browned my onions
and then I've put some pepper
and some aubergines in,
I am just going to dice up some
potato and some cauliflower
and bung that in.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Most
daunting gig ever was when?
- Well I think it was probably
a gig that I did up in Bolton
in a working Men's club.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Yep.
- And as one they all shouted
'fuck off you fat lezzer'
as I went on.
- And it's true in the early days,
the Lesbians used to complain about you
giving them a bad reputation, right?
- Over the years they've signed petitions
and sent them to me
telling me to tell everyone
that I'm heterosexual 'cause it's giving
lesbians a bad reputation.
- OK, sweat the aubergines
and the shallots down first,
garlic, chili's take the heat out of them.
In with the broccoli, and
a cauliflower, peppers.
- I am now grating some lard,
that's my secret ingredient.
- Lard?
- Alright, it's coconut.
- [Gordon Ramsay] It's coconut,
quite a jazzy curry this you know that?
- Is it?
- [Gordon Ramsay] Well it sounds it.
- You're from Scotland aren't you?
They are very healthy there aren't they?
'cause I always used to think
that Scotland, you know,
they've got the highest rate
of heart disease in Europe
which means you get decent grub there.
- You've lost a lot of
weight, haven't you?
- I've lost a bit of weight.
- Are you training or is it through diet?
- You know I trained for
the marathon years ago.
- I heard you trained for
the marathon, what happened?
- Thank Christ, I had
a virus the week before
so I couldn't do it.
- And all that training.
- Or should I say, I shouldn't say Christ
on tele because people
get upset, thank fuck.
(laughs)
- Were you looking forward
to running the marathon?
- Well what I wasn't looking forward to,
was dying in front of thousands of people
'cause I thought I might
because I am a fat person.
- I was a fat chef once.
- Were you?
- Seventeen and a half stone,
in fact just under 18 stone
when I ran my first marathon.
- Wow.
- It was a fucking nightmare,
I got back, it was dark,
the family had fucked off home
and I was picking cones
up on the way home.
- You see that's the
thing I was worried about,
because I estimated my
time doing the marathon.
- go on.
- About 12 and a half hours.
- You could do it within
12 hours Jo, come on.
- You reckon?
- Curry paste in, a handful of coriander,
rolled up and just fry up the coriander,
finish with a touch of garlic
and some chopped tomatoes.
Up to the boil and let it cook out.
- What does 'cook out' mean?
- Cook out is when the
raw paste, curry paste,
is very tart because its very raw,
so raw garlic, raw ginger, and
cook it out, let it mellow.
- Can I come and have a look at yours?
- You can come and have a look at mine.
Now its sort of disintegrated and--
- That looks like something you could
get out of a Heinz tin.
- Jo Brand.
Right, we are going to leave
both curry's to simmer now,
come back and Jo loses, simple as that.
- (Blows raspberry)
- Right, back to the Dim Sum
and its time for service.
In my quest to learn how to make Dim Sum
I am about to be thrown in at the deep end
of the Royal China Club in London.
This place can do over 200 covers
and like any Head Chef worth his salt,
the uncompromising Henry Chau,
expects his brigade to jump on the orders
as soon as they come on.
Trouble is, they are all in Chinese.
How the fuck do you understand
that, what does that say?
- That says the fresh shrimp Cheung fun.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Fresh shrimp cheung fun
- [Fuschia] So you already
know how to make it.
- I have never been in a
kitchen where I have never
been in control, so this
is really fucking weird.
But icy cold Head Chef
Henry is in control,
he's clearly a man after my own heart.
He won't let a morsel leave his kitchen
unless its absolutely perfect.
Understandably, he's watching
his most recent recruit
like a hawk.
So will my first effort pass muster
with my tough new master?
- No.
- No, what's wrong.
- [Fuschia] He says its not alright,
- [Gordon Ramsay] What's wrong with it?
- [Fuschia] it's not tight enough,
it's too lose its not
wrapped tightly enough
round the dough stack.
You have to do it tightly next time.
- Tighter.
Fucking hell, he's a fucking rotweiler.
More shrimp.
Coming now.
Jesus.
I am determined to get some
of my Dim Sum past Henry
and out to the diners.
I may be an award winning chef,
but as soon as I am sending plates out,
they are coming back.
Can someone go for the soup
and give the dumpling a rest.
I think Fuschia's enjoying
this a lot more than I am.
- [Fuschia] They are too
small and there is not
enough filling in them,
they should be fuller.
- [Gordon Ramsay] It's a
pleasure to learn a new skill,
but I hate getting a
bollocking, even in translation.
With service nearly over,
it's my last chance to
achieve Dim Sum perfection.
Fucking hell, he's worse than me,
that fucker, you know that?
Jesus Christ.
He's happy with that last one, yes?
- Very good.
- Excellent, happy?
Yea, good, fuck me, thank
fuck for that, I tell you.
Jesus Christ.
That was fucking phenomenal,
really tough to begin
with and very intricate
but who would have thought
that your spending £3, £4.50
for a bowl of fucking Dim Sum
and they are all made by hand,
extraordinary, just goes to prove
that fucking Chinese cookery
is not all about a wok.
Fucking hats off.
Working in Henry's kitchen
has really inspired me
and with lunch service out of the way,
I want to show him a dish of my own.
Right, I am going to do a
little dumpling that I make
and see what the guys think.
My Chinese style tortellini is
based on a mixture of prawn,
scallops and crispy duck.
The texture of the scallop
and the shrimp together, delicious.
I'm hoping Head Chef Henry
will be so impressed,
he will put it on his menu.
Oh, that fell off, just chop that off.
Really nice combination the duck.
I am adding finely chopped ginger,
garlic and a squeeze of lemon juice.
Lemon juice in, okay, coriander.
Finely, some finely sliced mixed veg.
Texture, good colour, in,
keep it nice and whole
so you can identify it.
Right, so, these.
I am borrowing a few of Jung's
expertly flattened skins.
The scallops, really nip it
together, little tortellinis.
Nice, very good.
We steam now.
Yea, 4 minutes.
Nice, they look good.
So what does the Dim Sum
Master and his Brigade
make of my Duck and Sea Food Tortellini?
Do you like, Henry?
- Little.
- What don't you like?
- [Translator] Five out of ten
- Five out of ten, little fucker.
Five out of ten!
Hey, tell him there's
no MSG in there either.
Jesus.
Five out of ten from these
guys is high praise indeed,
in another 20 years,
maybe I'll merit a six
So it's not going on the special tonight?
- No.
- Tell him when go goes back
to school, I'll take over.
Thank you very much, thank you very much.
Ah, fuck.
- [Mica] It's all going pear shaped.
- You're like a fucking
bull in a china shop.
For fuck sake, now whip
the cream up, let's go.
- Gordon! It just came off by itself.
- Fucking hell.
Guys, that's the eject
button, that's the on button.
- That's why it came off.
- Mica will blame the apparatus.
(music plays)
Strawberry Glory.
A great way of celebrating the
best of British Strawberries.
Strawberries, half.
Icing sugar, balsamic vinegar.
The combination of the
tartness of the vinegar
against the sweetness of the
strawberries is mind blowing.
Drizzle over the strawberries.
Icing sugar, pan,
Nice and hot.
Strawberries in.
Caramelise.
This needs 15 to 20 seconds, a
quick toss and then back out.
Crème patisserie
Commonly known as a
really nice thick custard.
Milk, cream, boil.
Egg yolks, sugar.
Whip, whip, whip.
Flour.
Take out one third of the cream and milk,
stir, this has liquefied,
all of your milk and your cream in there.
Put it back in the pan, bring
the custard up to the boil,
which will cause it to
go really nice and thick.
Into the fridge to cool down.
Cream, icing sugar.
Don't over whip the cream,
just as its starting to
fall through your whisk.
Get your thick custard,
take off one third.
Whisk.
and the rest of it straight in.
Look at that.
Nice, just falling through the whisk.
Now for the exciting part,
putting this little baby together.
Strawberries, juice, pastry
cream, crushed meringue, repeat.
Really nice ball of vanilla ice cream.
Sit that on top of the thick rich custard.
Juice, grated chocolate.
It wouldn't be complete
without one of these,
the good old fashioned British wafer.
Strawberry Glory, done.
Strawberries, meringue,
cream, strawberries, meringue,
cream, ice cream, chocolate, wafer.
- [Mica] Yea, OK.
- [Gordon Ramsay] Sprinkle the
chocolate on top, well done.
Good, off you go buddy.
Off you go.
If no one pays for this desert, yea,
they don't deserve to be in
here, go please, go please,
come on, go go go go let's go.
Mica, my Darling, are you with me?
- Yea, I'm along with you
man, alright, so there you go,
that's another four, yea?
- Earth to Trevor, Earth to
Trevor, wafers, wafers, fuck me,
wafers, I'm gonna need a fucking week
at the Priory after this fucking service.
Lets go.
Holy Fuck.
What was the naughtiest thing you two did
when you were kids?
- I know what she did to me.
What was naughty.
- Go on.
- One day, I think I was about nine,
and she stole my 2 pence,
do you remember that.
- I didn't steal it.
- She took my 2 pence
but you don't understand.
Back then 2 pence was like ten pounds
when you were a kid back then.
You know, it was a lot of money
- Serious
- I didn't steel it, I was teasing her.
- Can I tell him the story?
- She was indoors,
- yea, she ran off with my 2 p.
- And she ran off when
I was playing a game
- Can I just tell him the story!
- Oh, for God's sake.
- I was banging to door down,
I was like, "I want my 2 p."
I was screaming.
- Tonight, you are going
to forgive her, right now.
- Yea, I am sorry.
- Now, right, kiss and make up, yes.
Will you forgive her?
- Alright then, give it back, right now.
- I gave it back to you silly woman.
- Only two left, let's go,
make these perfect, right,
let's go, let's go, let's go.
Last table.
- Can I just say that I feel
like a weight has been lifted.
- Last table, Cherry,
Trevor, well, fucking done.
- [All] (Cheer)
- Coming up, will Jo Brand be laughing
at the results of the recipe challenge.
Is it going to be Jo Brand or Jo Bland?
Harry Enfield sorts out desert.
- Now Mitch, do you
remember you are taking Coke
and you are on smack now, aren't you?
- and we find out whether the
Brigade has what it takes to
come back to the F Word
Restaurant for final service.
The number of guests that are
going to pay for desert, is,
(Title music)
Right, welcome back to the F Word,
and time for the results
of the recipe challenge
and for Jo Brand to understand
why you should never use
a bought in curry paste.
Are you ready?
Now, this is the bit, I seriously like.
Side by side, you see mine looks delicious
and yours looks like it's out
of a jar, that's very chefie.
Jose, come back with the
right result and good luck.
- [Jo] Yea, good luck loser.
- [All] Thank you.
- Just got a big bit
of black pepper there.
- [Female Diner] Really, Mmm.
It's very mild though isn't it?
- [Male Diner] Its not hot at all.
- Its not got a massive
amount of flavour to it.
- [Male Diner] Next one.
There's a lot more going on there
- It tastes more like how you think
a curry should taste, doesn't it?
- Yea, a lot more flavour.
- And its got a good after
taste, a lot more punch.
- OK, here we go, how
are you feeling first?
- Oh, very confident.
- Very confident, yes,
is it going to be Jo Brand or Jo Bland?
- It was actually quite close.
- Right come on, they liked
both, who's the winner?
- Gordon, you did.
- Oh, bollocks.
- What was the, give us the,
- For Jo, the fresh flavours.
Certainly a bit more overpowering
on the coriander, I believe.
- Coriander.
I did put half a tree
in, look at your face,
you're loving this, aren't you?
- I am.
- Do you want to do a
little dance on the pass?
- Yes!
Excellent, you know I hate losing.
- Ha Ha!
- I've been waiting all
day for that one, yes?
Really good to see you,
thanks but no thanks.
Now fuck off out of my kitchen.
- Yea, up yours.
(laughs)
- How was desert?
- Absolutely delicious.
- I licked my bowl.
- You licked your bowl?
That's my kind of girl,
well done, excellent,
and did you manage to get your tongue
all the way down to the bottom?
- No, I had to put my finger in.
- Happy diners, I am so pleased
and are you going to pay for desert?
- Definitely, we'll pay for everything.
- Ladies, really good to see you, yes?
- It's extremely fresh, it,
everything complimented each other,
the juices were gorgeous,
and the strawberries just
melted in your mouth.
- Gentlemen, good to see you.
Harry, how are you?
- Hello.
- Welcome.
- Oh, thank you very much.
- Good to see you guys.
How was dinner?
- It was fantastic.
- What did you like about it?
- The salt,
- [Gordon Ramsay] The salt.
- Basically.
It was delicious.
- 'cause you're quite a foodie, right?
- Can't you tell I am a foodie?
I actually seduced my wife through food.
- Serious, what did you cook?
- Well it was something
from a Delia Smith book, but
- Get away.
- No, it was
- What, from cans?
- It was 15 years ago
- Oh 15 years ago
- Yea, and I remember it was Cod
and it had capers and it
was actually delicious.
- What was it?
- It was a coddy-capery thing.
Anyway, I won her with that meal
and I never had to cook
again, she's a very good cook.
- You used to date Lily
Allen's Mum at one stage.
You didn't know she was
going to be a potential star
did you, could you see it at that age?
- She was always very
clever and very, very funny
and slightly ahead of the crowd.
She was in my show, she was like a kid
and you know we did the old gigs,
and we'd scare a kid and she's be there
and Amy Winehouse was in the Fast Shows,
so, we were quite cool you know.
- Recently you've been
involved in dramas, yes?
- Yes.
- Did you run out of jokes?
Did you go dry, did you--
- Oh, no, I just got asked
to do this Skins thing.
I had done a bit of directing
and I had got asked to do--
- [Gordon Ramsay] I love it.
- some of that, so I did that.
They were all very good
all the people in it,
they were all very good,
but they're kinda young
so it's a bit like being a school teacher,
because they don't really
concentrate, do they?
You know they are busy
with their own lives
and doing what they do.
So you have to sort of go,
"OK, fine, come on everyone,
what at we doing, OK,
"now Mitch, do you remember you are taking
"coke in this scene.
"Have you got your coke, have you?
"Have you got your line
"and you're on smack
now, aren't you Jerry?
"Where is your smack?
"You haven't got it have
you, could we get the smack."
There's quite a lot of that
that goes on, OK, and turn over.
- That is so good
- Right.
Jose, please give me the results quickly,
I am shitting myself, yes?
(laughs)
Whatever happens, I thought
you did bloody well,
you were fast you were
good and more importantly,
you worked as a team again, yes?
And one thing that came out of it,
you are a lovely tight knit family.
Well done, really well done.
The number of guests that are
going to pay for deserts is,
- [Cherry] 50, 50.
44 out of 50.
- [All] (Cheer)
- That's good.
- Thank you guys.
- Well done, well done, well done.
So a grand total of 124
out of 150, well done.
Well done.
Now, Mica, here is the good news,
sadly you are not coming back.
(mumbles)
- On the menu next week,
I am bottling my own beer
for the F Word restaurant.
- This looks overfilled to me.
- [Gordon Ramsay] If there's any left.
Woo hoo!
I teach comedian Rob Brydon how
to shuck the perfect oyster.
You've left half the scale
on the top of the shell
- I know.
I am not a chef,
go and do some comedy you cheeky bugger.
- And it's the end of the
line for David and Elton
when Janet takes them to slaughter.
(Cow moo's)
- Thanks for watching,
try the recipes at home and believe me,
they are absolutely fucking
delicious, goodnight.
- I am walking away from here smiling
knowing that everybody
out there was happy.
- Once is enough.
(laughs) Can't take no more.
- I want to say experience of my life
which I never thought I could do.
- I am absolutely exhausted,
knackered, so, yea,
I'm thinking some bubbly
now, don't you think?
(guitar music)
- [Gordon Ramsay] I've got
a new series of kitchen
nightmares coming soon.
So if you need my help turning
your restaurant around.
Get in touch now by going to
channel4.com/takepart