(Narrator)  SUNDAY,
MARCH 1, 1998.
IN THE CITY OF MONCTON,
NEW BRUNSWICK,
A BRUTAL MURDER HAS
JUST BEEN COMMITTED.
(Michelle Guenard) THERE WERE
A LOT OF POLICE OFFICERS
WHO SEEMED TO BE
VERY DISTRAUGHT.
A LOT OF THEM HAD SAID
THAT THEY HAD NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING
LIKE IT.
BEFORE THIS
CASE IS CLOSED,
IT WILL OPEN
A PANDORA'S BOX
THAT WILL SHOCK
NOT ONLY A COMMUNITY,
BUT AN ENTIRE
COUNTRY.
(Allen McInnis) THERE HAS
BEEN A TON OF STABBINGS
AND VIOLENT
INCIDENTS,
TO THE POINT WHERE IT LOOKED
LIKE THERE WAS A SERIAL EPISODE
THAT WAS BEGINNING
TO SHAPE.
ALONG WITH
POLICE,
THERE ARE THOSE WHO CHRONICLE
THE INVESTIGATION UP CLOSE -
ON FILM, ON PAPER,
AND ON TAPE.
THEY ARE THE PUBLIC'S
FIRST WITNESS.
THROUGH
THEIR LENS,
THEY CAPTURE OUR DARKEST
CHAPTERS OF CRIME.
♪
(Electronic noise)
(Pencil rasping)
♪
(Narrator)
APRIL 24, 1985.
IN NOVA SCOTIA,
HALIFAX HARBOUR IS HOME
TO THE PROVINCE'S
TWO MAJOR CITIES:
ITS CAPITAL,
HALIFAX,
AND DARTMOUTH, ON THE
EASTERN SIDE OF THE BAY.
♪
ON THIS PARTICULAR
TUESDAY AFTERNOON,
17-YEAR-OLD GAIL TUCKER
IS GETTING READY
TO MOVE OUT OF HER MOTHER'S
DARTMOUTH APARTMENT.
SHE IS EXCITED ABOUT THE
PROSPECTS OF LANDING A JOB
AT A FISH PROCESSING PLANT
ON THE PROVINCE'S WEST COAST.
GAIL HAS SENT HER LUGGAGE
AHEAD WITH A FRIEND,
AND ALL SHE HAS ARE
THE CLOTHES ON HER BACK.
HER MOTHER, MARY LAKE,
OFFERS HER MONEY FOR THE BUS,
BUT CAN'T GET IT UNTIL
THE BANKS OPEN THE NEXT DAY.
♪
GAIL DECIDES NOT TO
WAIT FOR THE MONEY,
BUT TO HITCHHIKE
INSTEAD.
AT 5:00 p.m.
THAT AFTERNOON,
GAIL GETS INTO
AN OLD MODEL CAR
THAT LEAVES DARTMOUTH
AND HER OLD LIFE BEHIND.
SEVERAL
DAYS LATER,
MARY LAKE HAS NOT HEARD
FROM HER DAUGHTER.
SHE NOTIFIES
POLICE,
WHO BEGIN TO TRACE GAIL'S
MOVEMENTS ACROSS THE PROVINCE.
OVER THE NEXT
FEW MONTHS,
POLICE IDENTIFY
THE OLDER MODEL CAR,
BUT IT OFFERS
THEM NO NEW LEADS.
IT'S JUST ONE OF SEVERAL
VEHICLES THAT STOPPED
TO PICK UP THE
HITCHHIKING TEENAGER.
POLICE TRACK GAIL TO THE VILLAGE
OF WEYMOUTH, NOVA SCOTIA,
BUT HERE
THE TRAIL ENDS.
♪
OCTOBER,
1985.
SIX MONTHS AFTER GAIL
TUCKER'S DISAPPEARANCE,
A MAN WALKING HIS DOG IN A
WOODED AREA SOUTH OF WEYMOUTH
MAKES A GRUESOME
DISCOVERY:
THE SKELETAL REMAINS
OF A HUMAN BODY.
POLICE CALLED
TO THE SCENE
ALSO FIND A PILE
OF CLOTHES NEARBY.
NO ATTEMPT HAS BEEN MADE
TO BURY THE CORPSE,
AND DECOMPOSITION IS SUCH
THAT SHOVELS HAVE TO BE USED
TO REMOVE
THE REMAINS.
TWO DAYS
LATER,
THE BODY IS IDENTIFIED
THROUGH DENTAL RECORDS
AND JEWELRY FOUND
AT THE SCENE.
IT IS 17-YEAR-OLD
GAIL TUCKER.
FORENSICS DETERMINES THAT
THE GIRL WAS STABBED REPEATEDLY
IN THE SIDE WITH
A SINGLE-EDGED BLADE,
BUT POLICE ARE UNABLE TO
LINK THE CRIME TO ANY SUSPECTS.
FOR GAIL'S FAMILY AND THE
POLICE, IT IS A DEAD END.
BUT IN REALITY, IT IS
JUST THE BEGINNING.
AS THE YEARS PASS,
THE MURDER OF GAIL TUCKER
BECOMES ANOTHER
STATISTIC,
ONE OF HUNDREDS OF UNSOLVED
HOMICIDES ACROSS CANADA.
BY 1998, POLICE IN DARTMOUTH
HAVE ALL BUT CLOSED THE FILE.
THEY KEEP IT OPEN
ONLY AT THE INSISTENCE
OF THE VICTIM'S
MOTHER, MARY LAKE,
WHO STILL BELIEVES
THAT ONE DAY
THEY WILL LINK
A NAME AND A FACE
TO THIS
TERRIBLE CRIME.
FEBRUARY,
1998.
IN THE CITY OF MONCTON,
IT'S ANOTHER HUMID WEEKEND,
TYPICAL NEW BRUNSWICK WEATHER
FOR THIS TIME OF YEAR.
WITH A POPULATION
OF JUST OVER 100,000,
MONCTON IS A CITY WHERE MOST
PEOPLE FEEL SAFE AND SECURE.
♪
(Wendell Maxwell)
MONCTON'S BASICALLY A
PEACE-LOVING SORT OF A CITY,
AND A VERY
VIBRANT CITY -
GROWING, AND THE PEOPLE ARE
INDUSTRIOUS AND HARDWORKING.
♪
(Anthony Allman)
IT'S A SMALL CITY - IT HAS
A SMALL CITY MENTALITY:
NOT SMALL TOWN,
NOT BIG CITY.
IN AN APARTMENT BUILDING IN
ONE QUIET MONCTON NEIGHBOURHOOD,
48-YEAR-OLD
JOAN HICKS
GETS HER 11-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER, NENA, READY FOR BED.
THEY'VE ONLY BEEN IN MONCTON
FOR ABOUT SIX MONTHS.
THEY HAVE COME FROM MUSGRAVE
HARBOUR, NEWFOUNDLAND,
THE ISLAND
PROVINCE,
WHERE BOTH HAVE SPENT
THEIR ENTIRE LIVES.
BUT EXTRAORDINARY
CIRCUMSTANCES
HAVE GIVEN JOAN THE CHANCE
TO LEAVE HER HOMETOWN
AND START A NEW
LIFE IN MONCTON.
(Michelle) SHE HAD
BEEN HELPING PEOPLE
WHO WERE IN TROUBLE WITH
THE LAW IN NEWFOUNDLAND.
ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE WAS LATER
CONVICTED FOR SEXUAL ASSAULT
AND SENT TO DORCHESTER
PENITENTIARY.
SO, SHE WAS WRITING
LETTERS TO HER FRIEND.
THIS FRIEND
WAS ASKING HER,
"THERE ARE OTHER PEOPLE HERE
WHO WOULD LIKE TO GET LETTERS."
AND THIS IS WHERE
AUBREY SPARKS COMES IN.
HERE IS A MAN WHO WAS IN
PRISON FOR MURDERING HIS WIFE.
SHE STARTED
WRITING TO HIM.
THOSE LETTERS APPARENTLY
BECAME LOVE LETTERS,
AND SHE DECIDED THAT SHE
WANTED TO MOVE TO MONCTON
TO BE CLOSER TO HIM, TO SEE
IF THIS RELATIONSHIP WOULD WORK.
JOAN'S FAMILY
IS CONCERNED
THAT SHE HAS NEVER ACTUALLY
MET AUBREY SPARKS.
JOAN AND AUBREY'S
ONLY COMMUNICATION
HAS BEEN
TELEPHONE CALLS
AND THE EXCHANGE OF
LETTERS AND PHOTOGRAPHS.
(Michelle) ALL OF HER FAMILY
AND FRIENDS IN MUSGRAVE HARBOUR
TRIED TO TALK
HER OUT OF IT.
THEY EVEN ASKED
THE R.C.M.P.
TO TRY TO DISSUADE HER
FROM COMING TO MONCTON.
JOAN'S ADULT
DAUGHTER, JUDY,
IS ONE OF THE CONCERNED
FAMILY MEMBERS.
(Judy Pinsent) I DIDN'T
WANT HER TO GO,
BUT IT WAS HER DECISION
TO GO TO MONCTON.
THAT'S ALL
WE COULD DO.
NENA IS NERVOUS ABOUT MOVING
TO A STRANGE NEW CITY.
BEFORE SHE LEAVES, NENA GIVES
HER AUNT A PHOTOGRAPH OF HERSELF
DRESSED IN HER
SUNDAY BEST.
"IF ANYTHING HAPPENS
TO ME ," SHE SAYS,
"POST THIS PICTURE SO PEOPLE
WILL BE ABLE TO FIND ME
AND BRING
ME HOME."
(Judy) NENA
WAS 11,
AND SHE A LOVED
GOING TO BROWNIES,
TO CHURCH,
SUNDAY SCHOOL,
PLAYING WITH
HER FRIENDS.
THERE WAS
NO GOODBYE.
WHEN THEY GOT THERE,
THEY CALLED,
AND THAT
WAS IT.
FOR A SHORT TIME, JOAN AND NENA
LIVE AT A SHELTER IN MONCTON.
DURING THEIR STAY, JOAN
BEFRIENDS A YOUNG WOMAN,
22-YEAR-OLD
TAMMY MACLEAN.
TAMMY HAS BEEN HAVING
PROBLEMS WITH HER BOYFRIEND,
AND SHE FINDS IN JOAN
A COMPASSIONATE HEART
AND A WILLINGNESS
TO LISTEN.
THE SHELTER HELPS JOAN AND
NENA FIND A BASEMENT APARTMENT.
RESIDENTS CAN'T HELP BUT
LIKE THEIR NEW NEIGHBOURS,
WHO THEY DESCRIBE AS
FRIENDLY, POLITE AND SHY.
NENA ATTENDS A NEARBY SCHOOL
AND SEEMS TO FIT RIGHT IN.
(Judy) NENA CALLED AND
I ASKED HER ABOUT SCHOOL,
AND SHE LIKED
GOING TO SCHOOL,
AND THEY WERE INTO
THEIR APARTMENT,
AND SHE SEEMED TO
BE QUITE CONTENT.
TAMMY MACLEAN AND HER
BOYFRIEND ARE OFTEN GUESTS
AT THE
APARTMENT,
STOPPING BY FOR COFFEE
OR A GAME OF CARDS.
BUT ON THE NIGHT
OF FEBRUARY 28, 1998,
TAMMY MACLEAN
COMES ALONE.
(Michelle) WHAT WE DO KNOW
IS THAT, ON THAT DAY,
JOAN HICKS GOT A CALL FROM
HER FRIEND, TAMMY MACLEAN.
TAMMY WAS HAVING PROBLEMS
WITH HER BOYFRIEND.
SHE SAID SHE
NEEDED TO GET AWAY.
SO, JOAN INVITED HER
TO HER APARTMENT.
TAMMY WAS OBVIOUSLY
DISTRAUGHT.
THEY SPENT A LOT
OF TIME TALKING.
JOAN WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THAT SHE HAD A PLACE TO GO,
THAT SHE WASN'T GOING
TO BE VICTIMIZED
OR CAUGHT IN
A SITUATION.
AT 5:00 a.m.,
A TAXICAB PULLS UP
IN FRONT OF THE
APARTMENT BUILDING.
AS TAMMY LEAVES THE BUILDING
AND APPROACHES THE CAB,
THE DRIVER NOTICES
ANOTHER WOMAN WITH A MAN
AT THE
ENTRANCEWAY.
AS SHE
PULLS AWAY,
THE DRIVER SEES THEM GO
BACK INSIDE THE BUILDING.
IF THE WOMAN IN THE
ENTRANCEWAY IS JOAN HICKS,
IT IS THE LAST TIME
ANYONE SEES HER ALIVE.
♪
(Narrator)
MARCH 1, 1998.
THE CITY OF MONCTON AWAKENS
TO ANOTHER GLOOMY SUNDAY.
BUT ON THIS
PARTICULAR MORNING,
THE NEW BRUNSWICK COMMUNITY'S
SMALL TOWN SENSIBILITY
IS ABOUT TO BE
SEVERELY SHAKEN.
IN THE EARLY
MORNING HOURS,
A MAN NAMED GLENN BENNETT
ENTERS A MONCTON POLICE STATION,
AGITATED AND
VERY FRIGHTENED.
HE TELLS OFFICERS THAT HE HAS
JUST WITNESSED A BRUTAL MURDER,
AND COULD DO
NOTHING TO STOP IT.
(Anthony) HIS VERSION OF EVENTS
WAS HE WAS A TERRIFIED SPECTATOR
AT THE INCIDENT, AND THEN
HE DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
BUT AS SOON AS
HE GOT SEPARATE,
HE WENT TO THE POLICE
AND REPORTED IT,
AND THE POLICE SAID, "GO
AROUND, FIND THE BODIES,"
AND MATTERS PROCEED
AFTER THAT.
(Police siren
wailing)
JUST BEFORE 8:00
THAT MORNING,
RESIDENTS IN ONE
MONCTON NEIGHBOURHOOD
ARE SURPRISED TO SEE
POLICE CARS PULL UP
OUTSIDE AN
APARTMENT BUILDING.
OFFICERS ASK THE
BUILDING SUPERINTENDENT
TO UNLOCK THE DOOR TO
A BASEMENT APARTMENT
HE KNOWS BELONGS
TO NEW TENANT.
THE POLICE FIND
48-YEAR-OLD JOAN HICKS
LYING ON THE FLOOR
NEAR THE BATHROOM
IN A POOL OF
HER OWN BLOOD.
THEY IMMEDIATELY CORDON OFF THE
STAIRS LEADING TO THE BASEMENT
AND BEGIN SCOURING
THE AREA FOR EVIDENCE.
(Michelle) IT WAS
A PART OF TOWN
THAT IS JUST
ON THE BORDER
OF WHERE IT STARTS TO GO
A LITTLE BIT DOWNHILL.
IT WAS NUMBER
THREE, BASEMENT -
WHERE JUST THE WINDOWS
WOULD HAVE LOOKED OUT
ONTO THE
STREET.
POLICE TAPE
EVERYWHERE.
INVESTIGATORS DISCOVER THAT JOAN
HAS BEEN BEATEN AND STRANGLED,
AND HER THROAT HAS BEEN CUT
WITH A SERRATED EDGE KNIFE.
HER 11-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER
NENA IS MISSING.
THE BED IN THE BEDROOM
HAS BEEN SLEPT IN,
BUT DETECTIVES
FIND IT EMPTY.
THE BEDROOM CLOSET
HOWEVER, IS NOT .
♪
(Wendell) THE LITTLE GIRL
WAS HANGING IN A CLOSET
WHEN SHE
WAS FOUND,
ALTHOUGH PROBABLY WAS SMOTHERED
TO DEATH PRIOR TO THAT,
AND THEN JUST HUNG
IN THE CLOSET.
IT WAS NOT A
PRETTY SCENE.
THE SCENE WAS
APPARENTLY SO GRUESOME
THAT THERE WAS A SPECIAL
PSYCHIATRIC TEAM
THAT WAS
BROUGHT IN.
THEY WERE VERY UPSET;
A LOT OF THEM HAD SAID
THAT THEY HAD NEVER
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE IT.
(Allen) SOME CRIME SCENES
I'LL NEVER FORGET.
YOU HAVE TO BUILD UP A
CERTAIN AMOUNT OF IMMUNITY,
OTHERWISE YOU
CAN'T FUNCTION.
AND IT SOUNDS COLD,
BUT THAT'S THE REALITY.
YOU HAVE TO.
POLICE TALK TO
JOAN'S NEIGHBOURS.
ONE OF THEM RECALLS
HEARING LOUD VOICES
COMING FROM
AN APARTMENT,
BUT ISN'T SURE
WHICH ONE.
AS WORD
GETS AROUND,
RESIDENTS OF THE QUIET
NEIGHBOURHOOD ARE NUMB.
(Michelle) MONCTON
IS ONE OF THOSE TOWNS
WHERE PEOPLE REALLY
DO KNOW EACH OTHER.
THIS IS A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE
STILL DON'T LOCK THEIR DOORS,
TO THIS
DAY.
SO, TO HAVE SOMETHING LIKE
THAT HAPPEN IN THAT COMMUNITY,
IT DID
AFFECT EVERYBODY.
IT'S ALL EVERYBODY
WAS TALKING ABOUT.
JOAN AND NENA HICKS HAVE ONLY
BEEN IN MONCTON A SHORT TIME.
BACK IN THEIR HOMETOWN OF
MUSGRAVE HARBOUR, NEWFOUNDLAND,
POLICE ARRIVE AT THE HOME
OF JOAN'S DAUGHTER, JUDY,
AND HER
TWO SONS.
(Judy) MY GRANDMOTHER
WAS WITH ME.
AND TYLER AND DILLON
WENT TO THE DOOR,
AND THEY CAME
AND THEY SAID,
"MOM, THE COPS IS
IN THE DRIVEWAY."
I SAID, "OKAY, THEY'RE
PROBABLY JUST TURNING AROUND."
(Knock
on door)
AND THEN A KNOCK
CAME TO THE DOOR,
AND IT WAS THE
R.C.M.P. OFFICER,
AND THERE WAS A SALVATION
ARMY OFFICER AND HIS WIFE.
THEY COME IN AND
THEY WANTED ME TO SIT.
AT FIRST, YOU THINK
OF AN ACCIDENT.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE THEY
WERE IN A CAR ACCIDENT,
OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
BUT WHEN I
GOT THE NEWS,
WHEN I HAD REALIZED
HOW THEY DIED...
I WAS
DEVASTATED.
I PHONED
MONCTON.
THEY HAD A TOLD ME
THERE WAS AN EYEWITNESS.
THE POLICE TELL JUDY THAT
A MAN NAMED GLENN BENNETT
WAS A HORRIFIED SPECTATOR
AT HER MOTHER'S HOME
THE NIGHT OF
THE MURDERS.
I COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT
SOMEBODY HAD WATCHED -
HAD BEEN THERE
AND WATCHED.
BUT I LEARNED THAT
HE WAS THE ONE
THAT REPORTED IT
TO THE POLICE,
AND THAT'S HOW THEY KNOWED
WHO KILLED MOM AND NENA.
(Police siren
wailing)
ACTING ON ANOTHER TIP FROM
EYEWITNESS, GLENN BENNETT,
POLICE CONVERGE ON
A TWO-STOREY APARTMENT
IN ANOTHER PART
OF MONCTON,
NOT LONG AFTER
DISCOVERING THE BODIES.
IT IS THE RESIDENCE OF
22-YEAR-OLD TAMMY MACLEAN.
BUT AT
THE MOMENT,
POLICE ARE MORE INTERESTED
IN HER BOYFRIEND.
(Judy) I LEARNED THAT
HE WAS A FRIEND OF MOM'S,
THAT HE WOULD GO THERE,
HE AND HIS GIRLFRIEND,
AND THEY WERE VERY
CLOSE WITH MOM,
AND THEY WOULD PLAY CARDS
OR HAVE COFFEE, I GUESS.
ACCORDING TO
GLENN BENNETT,
THE MAN RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE MURDERS
IS 34-YEAR-OLD
MICHAEL McGRAY.
(Judy) IF THERE WASN'T AN
EYEWITNESS, HE MIGHT HAVE -
MICHAEL McGRAY MIGHT
HAVE WALKED AWAY.
♪
POLICE ARREST
McGRAY
IN FRONT OF HIS GIRLFRIEND'S
APARTMENT BUILDING.
HE IS THEN
HELD IN CUSTODY,
AND BROUGHT TO MONCTON'S
PROVINCIAL COURTHOUSE
FOR
ARRAIGNMENT.
(Michelle)
THE FIRST TIME I HEARD THE
NAME MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY
WAS WHEN I HAD CALLED THE
R.C.M.P. COMMUNICATIONS PERSON,
AS WE WERE CALLING
EVERY HALF HOUR,
AND HE SAID,
"WE HAVE A SUSPECT."
YOU GET A SENSE
FROM THE BAILIFFS
WHO ARE TRANSPORTING
THEM BACK AND FORTH
HOW THEY FEEL
ABOUT THE PERSON,
AND THEIR
LEVEL OF GUILT
BY HOW FAR THEY PARK
AWAY FROM THE DOOR,
BECAUSE THE MEDIA IS
WAITING WITH THEIR CAMERAS
TO GET
A PICTURE.
WHEN THEY SHOWED UP
WITH MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY,
THEY PARKED A LONG WAYS
AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
SO, WE DID GET SHOTS
OF HIM HANDCUFFED,
BEING LED IN
UP THE STAIRS.
AVERAGE-LOOKING GUY,
HEAD SOMEWHAT DOWN,
BUT HE WASN'T
TRYING TO HIDE.
HE KNEW THAT HE WAS
GONNA DO THE WALK,
AND HE DID
THE WALK.
(Judy) THEY WERE PRETTY SURE
THAT THIS WAS THEIR MAN.
AND I DIDN'T WANT
ANY OTHER FAMILY
TO GO THROUGH WHAT
I WENT THROUGH.
WITH THE SUSPECT
IN CUSTODY,
THE COURTS MUST
NOW FIND OUT
WHY THESE TERRIBLE MURDERS
HAPPENED IN THE FIRST PLACE.
THEY LOOK
FOR ANSWERS
IN THE MIND OF 34-YEAR-OLD
MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY.
BUT NO ONE IS PREPARED FOR
WHAT THEY ARE ABOUT TO LEARN.
♪
(Narrator)
MARCH, 1998.
THE CITY OF MONCTON,
NEW BRUNSWICK
HAS BEEN ROCKED BY A
TERRIBLE DOUBLE HOMICIDE.
THE VICTIMS, JOAN HICKS
AND HER DAUGHTER NENA,
ARE LAID TO REST
IN THEIR HOMETOWN
OF MUSGRAVE HARBOUR,
NEWFOUNDLAND.
NENA'S FRIENDS PLACE A
WHITE RIBBON ON HER CASKET,
AND HER CLASSMATES HOLD A
SPECIAL TRIBUTE TO SAY GOODBYE.
♪
(Michelle) MUSGRAVE HARBOUR
IS A VERY SMALL PLACE,
AND EVERYBODY
KNOWS EVERYBODY,
AND THEY WERE OBVIOUSLY
VERY TRAUMATIZED
BY THIS
WHOLE THING.
(Judy) WHAT KIND OF A HUMAN
WOULD DO THIS TO MOM AND NENA?
HOW COULD A MAN
KILL A CHILD AND MOM?
(Wendell) HE
WAS A DRIFTER,
AND I THINK NORMALLY,
FROM WHAT I READ,
A PSYCHOPATH DEVELOPS
THESE TENDENCIES
WHEN THEY'RE
YOUNG.
MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY'S CRIMINAL
RECORD COMES UNDER SCRUTINY
AS MONCTON
DETECTIVES
INVESTIGATE HIS
PREVIOUS CONVICTIONS.
MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY SPENDS
MUCH OF HIS CHILDHOOD
IN GROUP HOMES
AND REFORM SCHOOL.
IN HIS EARLY TEENS, HE IS
KICKED OUT OF HIS FATHER'S HOME
AND BEGINS DRIFTING
FROM ONE CITY TO THE NEXT.
AS AN ADULT, HE IS
IN AND OUT OF JAIL,
MOSTLY FOR ROBBERY AND
OTHER PROPERTY OFFENSES.
EARLY IN
HIS CAREER,
HE COMMITS ONE OF THOSE CRIMES
140 KILOMETRES FROM MONCTON,
IN THE CITY OF SAINT JOHN,
NEW BRUNSWICK.
NOVEMBER,
1987.
IN SAINT JOHN, A TAXI DRIVER
WORKING THE NIGHT SHIFT
STOPS TO PICK
UP THREE MEN.
(Inspector Bill Reid)
IN THE LATE 80's,
SAINT JOHN WAS VERY MUCH
AN INDUSTRIAL CITY,
AND OUR INVESTIGATORS
CERTAINLY INVESTIGATED
A LOT MORE CRIME WITH
RESPECT TO VIOLENCE
THAN THEY WOULD
BE DOING TODAY.
ESSENTIALLY
WHAT HAPPENED -
THREE PEOPLE GOT TOGETHER
AND CONJURED UP A PLAN
TO ROB A
TAXI DRIVER.
ONE OF THE MEN,
MARK DANIEL GIBBONS,
SITS IN THE FRONT SEAT
BESIDE THE TAXI DRIVER,
WHILE HIS TWO
ACCOMPLICES,
NORMAN WARREN AND
MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY,
GET IN
THE BACK.
(Inspector Reid) WHEN
THEY GOT TO THE LOCATION,
THEY INFORMED
THE TAXI DRIVER
THAT IT WASN'T HIS
NORMAL DRIVE TODAY -
HE WAS
BEING ROBBED.
HE MADE A MOTION TO
GO INTO HIS POCKET,
BUT MARK GIBBONS
HAD A KNIFE
AND WAS ABLE TO STAB THE
CAB DRIVER IN THE HAND
WITH
THE KNIFE.
THEY LEFT THE SCENE
AND THEY RAN AWAY.
POLICE ARRIVE
AT THE SCENE
AND BEGIN SEARCHING
FOR THE THREE SUSPECTS.
THE FIRST ONE THEY
FIND IS MARK GIBBONS,
BUT IT IS TOO LATE
FOR AN ARREST.
HE MADE HIS WAY DOWN
TO MARKET SQUARE,
WHICH IS A MALL
IN SAINT JOHN.
AND HE WAS FOUND,
ACTUALLY, BY A JANITOR,
WHO SUMMONS
MALL SECURITY,
WHO IN FACT SUMMONS US,
AND HE HAD EXPIRED.
INVESTIGATORS QUICKLY
ESTABLISH THE CAUSE OF DEATH:
A SINGLE STAB WOUND
JUST BELOW THE HEART.
(Inspector Reid) THE WOUND
ACTUALLY WAS JUST BELOW -
JUST AT THE VERY
TIP OF THE HEART,
AND HE BLED OUT, ESSENTIALLY,
IS WHAT HAPPENED.
HE WAS OBVIOUSLY
GOING FOR HELP.
IN A MATTER
OF MINUTES,
A BOTCHED ROBBERY HAS
BECOME A BIZARRE MURDER
WITH NO
CLEAR MOTIVE.
(Phone ringing)
THE NEXT DAY, IT TURNS
EVEN MORE UNUSUAL
WHEN THE MURDERED
MAN'S ACCOMPLICES
CALL THE POLICE
THEMSELVES .
(Inspector Reid)
THEY MAKE A PHONE CALL
TO THE POLICE STATION,
WANTING TO KNOW IF WE
KNEW THE WHEREABOUTS,
OR IF WE HEARD
FROM MARK GIBBONS.
WELL, AT THAT TIME,
WE HAVE A MURDER SCENE,
AND THUS WE ARE VERY
INTRIGUED BY THE PHONE CALL.
WE TRACE THE PHONE CALL BACK TO
THIS GERMAINE STREET APARTMENT.
OUR OFFICERS
ARRIVED THERE,
AND SOME PEOPLE LEAVE
THE BACK DOOR, RUNNING.
POLICE ARREST MARK
GIBBONS' ACCOMPLICES
IN THE TAXI
CAB ROBBERY,
WHO ARE NOW ALSO
MURDER SUSPECTS.
AT THIS POINT, McGRAY HAS HAD
A FEW RUN-INS WITH THE LAW,
MAINLY FOR
BREAKING AND ENTERING.
NORMAN WARREN HAS A LONG
RECORD OF VIOLENT CRIME,
INCLUDING THE MURDER
OF A CAB DRIVER,
FOR WHICH HE SERVED
17 YEARS IN PRISON.
♪
McGRAY TELLS THEM THAT
WARREN STABBED MARK GIBBONS
FOR BOTCHING
THE ROBBERY.
COMBINED WITH
STATEMENTS MADE
BY THE GIRLFRIENDS
OF THE THREE MEN,
POLICE ARE CONFIDENT
THAT THEY HAVE THEIR MAN.
(Inspector Reid) THE
INVESTIGATORS OF THE DAY
TALKED TO ALL THE
POTENTIAL WITNESSES,
BASICALLY FEMALES THAT
WERE IN THE APARTMENT,
AND THEY SORT OF
SIDED WITH THE POSITION
THAT WARREN IN FACT
WAS PROBABLY THE ONE
THAT COMMITTED
THE MURDER.
NORMAN WARREN
WAS THEN CHARGED
WITH THE HOMICIDE
OF MARK GIBBONS,
WENT THROUGH TRIAL, AND
HE WAS FOUND NOT GUILTY.
DETECTIVES ON THE CASE
ARE SHOCKED BY THE DECISION,
AND MUST BE SATISFIED
WITH THE FACT
THAT NORMAN WARREN IS BEHIND
BARS FOR ATTEMPTED ROBBERY.
McGRAY ALSO RECEIVES
A FIVE-YEAR SENTENCE
FOR HIS ROLE
IN THE ROBBERY.
1998.
LAWYER WENDELL MAXWELL MUST
NOW DEFEND MICHAEL McGRAY
FOR THE MURDER OF
JOAN AND NENA HICKS.
BUT AS THE TRIAL
DATE APPROACHES,
WORD CIRCULATES
THAT JOAN AND NENA
MAY NOT HAVE BEEN MICHAEL
McGRAY'S FIRST VICTIMS.
THE SOURCE IS
McGRAY HIMSELF.
(Michelle) AT SOME
POINT IN PRISON,
AS MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY
WAS BEING INTERVIEWED,
HE MADE A PLEA BARGAIN
WITH THE POLICE OFFICERS.
WE FOUND OUT THAT
HE HAD CONFESSED
TO KILLING TWO GAY
MEN IN MONTREAL
IN THE
EARLY 90's.
DURING THE TIME
IN QUESTION,
MONTREAL POLICE
ARE BAFFLED
BY A STRING OF
VIOLENT STABBING DEATHS
IN THE HOMOSEXUAL
COMMUNITY.
OVER A 12-MONTH PERIOD,
6 MEN HAD BEEN MURDERED.
♪
IN MONTREAL'S GAY VILLAGE,
THERE IS GROWING CONCERN.
IN MAY,
1991,
LOCAL GAY ACTIVISTS
HOLD A MEETING
DEMANDING THAT POLICE
REVIEW THE DETAILS
ABOUT WHAT THEY FEAR
IS A SERIAL KILLER
STALKING HOMOSEXUALS
IN MONTREAL.
THAT FEAR IS COMPOUNDED
BY THE UNSOLVED MURDERS
OF TWO MORE GAY
MEN THAT FALL,
BOTH STABBED TO DEATH WHILE
TAKING LATE NIGHT BIKE RIDES
IN CITY
PARKS.
PIERRE SANGOLLO, DIRECTOR
OF THE MAJOR CRIME SECTION
OF THE MONTREAL URBAN
COMMUNITY OF POLICE,
ORDERS THE FILES TO BE PULLED
FOR THE FIRST SIX KILLINGS.
BY THE END
OF 1993,
INTENSIVE POLICE
INVESTIGATIONS CONCLUDE
THAT WHILE THERE
ARE DIFFERENT LINKS
BETWEEN SOME
OF THE KILLINGS,
THEY ARE NOT THE WORK
OF JUST ONE PERSON.
(Pierre Sangollo)
WE COULD BE TALKING
ABOUT TWO SERIAL KILLERS,
OR WE COULD BE TALKING ABOUT
ONE GROUP OF SERIAL KILLERS.
THE INVESTIGATION DOES
LITTLE TO ALLAY THE FEARS
OF THE CITY'S
GAY COMMUNITY.
BETWEEN 1989
TO 1996,
A TOTAL OF 21 GAY MEN
ARE MURDERED IN MONTREAL.
BY THE FALL
OF 1997,
SIX OF THOSE MURDERS
ARE STILL UNSOLVED.
AT THE TIME OF HIS
CONFESSION IN 1999,
THERE IS NO
EVIDENCE TO SUGGEST
THAT McGRAY HAD ANY
ROLE IN THE KILLINGS.
IN FACT, HE HAD BEEN
ELIMINATED AS A SUSPECT,
SINCE HE HAD BEEN INCARCERATED
AT QUEBEC'S LA MACAZA PRISON
AT THE TIME.
BUT THEN McGRAY REVEALS HOW,
RELEASED ON A THREE-DAY PASS
ON GOOD FRIDAY,
MARCH 29, 1991,
HE TRAVELS TO MONTREAL
AND MAKES A REQUIRED VISIT
TO A HALFWAY HOUSE
IN THE CITY'S NORTH END.
THE NEXT DAY,
MARCH 30th,
McGRAY GOES TO
MONTREAL'S GAY VILLAGE
AND MEETS RECENTLY
RETIRED HIGH SCHOOL TEACHER,
ROBERT ASSALY,
IN A BAR.
THEY ENJOY A FEW DRINKS
AND TALK HOCKEY
UNTIL ROBERT INVITES McGRAY
BACK TO HIS APARTMENT.
♪
AT ROBERT'S APARTMENT, THE
TWO MEN HAVE A FEW MORE DRINKS
AND WATCH TELEVISION
UNTIL McGRAY FALLS ASLEEP
ON ROBERT'S
COUCH.
WHEN McGRAY AWAKENS AT
6:00 ON EASTER SUNDAY,
HE HEARS ROBERT GETTING
DRESSED IN HIS BEDROOM
AND GRABS A KNIFE
FROM THE KITCHEN.
HE ORDERS THE
RETIRED SCHOOLTEACHER
TO LIE DOWN
ON THE FLOOR,
BUT ROBERT JUST
LAUGHS AT HIM.
McGRAY STRIKES HIM ON
THE HEAD WITH A LAMP,
THEN STABS HIM REPEATEDLY
IN THE CHEST AND THE THROAT.
HE LEAVES THE APARTMENT
WITH A BOTTLE OF LIQUOR,
BUT LEAVES THE VICTIM'S
WALLET AND CREDIT CARDS BEHIND.
IT WILL BE A WEEK BEFORE
ROBERT ASSALY'S BODY IS FOUND,
BUT THE STORY
DOESN'T END THERE.
WITHIN 24 HOURS OF
KILLING ROBERT ASSALY,
MICHAEL McGRAY IS ALREADY
STALKING HIS NEXT VICTIM.
HE RETURNS TO
THE GAY VILLAGE
AND MEETS UNEMPLOYED
SALESMAN, GAETAN ETHIER.
GAETAN INVITES McGRAY BACK TO
HIS SMALL BACHELOR APARTMENT
TO SHARE A BOTTLE OF WINE
AND WATCH A HOCKEY GAME.
McGRAY TELLS
POLICE
THAT AFTER TURNING DOWN
AN ADVANCE FROM GAETAN,
HE WATCHES HIM PASS OUT
ON A FOLDOUT BED
AND CONTINUES TO WATCH HIM
FOR THE REST OF THE NIGHT.
♪
THE NEXT
MORNING,
McGRAY WALKS
OVER TO THE BED
AND SMASHES A BEER BOTTLE
AGAINST GAETAN ETHIER'S HEAD,
THEN ATTACKS HIM
WITH A KNIFE.
GAETAN FIGHTS BACK,
TRYING TO GET TO THE PHONE,
BUT McGRAY
CUTS THE LINE.
WHEN GAETAN
IS DEAD,
McGRAY LEAVES THE APARTMENT
WITH THE BOTTLE OF WINE
THAT THE TWO MEN WERE
SUPPOSED TO SHARE
THE NIGHT
BEFORE.
HE THEN LEAVES
MONTREAL,
BREAKING THE CONDITIONS
OF HIS THREE-DAY PASS.
McGRAY GETS ARRESTED
LATER THAT MONTH
AND IS RETURNED
BACK TO JAIL.
IN HIS CONFESSION,
McGRAY REVEALS DETAILS
THAT ONLY THE
KILLER COULD KNOW,
SUCH AS THE BEER BOTTLE
AND THE CUT PHONE LINE,
HOLD BACK EVIDENCE THAT
THE POLICE NEVER RELEASED
TO THE
PUBLIC.
IT IS A STARTLING
CONFESSION.
HOWEVER, IT WILL
NOT BE THE LAST.
♪
(Narrator)
MARCH, 1999.
RENOUS PRISON,
NEW BRUNSWICK.
MURDER SUSPECT MICHAEL
McGRAY IS IN CUSTODY
FOR THE DEATHS OF
JOAN AND NENA HICKS.
WHILE AWAITING TRIAL,
McGRAY ASTOUNDS INVESTIGATORS
BY CONFESSING TO
TWO UNRELATED MURDERS -
THOSE OF ROBERT ASSALY
AND GAETAN ETHIER,
BOTH BRUTALLY SLAIN EIGHT
YEARS EARLIER IN MONTREAL.
BUT MICHAEL McGRAY
DOESN'T STOP THERE.
HE TELLS POLICE OFFICERS
THAT HE IS ALSO RESPONSIBLE
FOR A MURDER
IN NEW BRUNSWICK.
(Inspector Reid) IN 1999,
I RECEIVED A TELEPHONE CALL
FROM AN INVESTIGATOR
HERE IN MONCTON,
INQUIRING HAD
WE HAD A HOMICIDE
WITH RESPECT TO A CHAP BY
THE NAME OF MARK GIBBONS?
SURE ENOUGH, THERE WAS
AN UNSOLVED HOMICIDE.
WE DID CHARGE SOMEBODY, AND IT
DID GO THROUGH THE COURT SYSTEM,
AND THE PERSON WAS
FOUND NOT GUILTY.
AND WE WENT TO
RENOUS PRISON,
WHICH IS HERE IN THE
PROVINCE OF NEW BRUNSWICK,
A MAXIMUM-SECURITY
PRISON,
AND HAD A MEETING
WITH MR. McGRAY,
AND HE SAID, "I WANT YOU TO
KNOW SOMETHING RIGHT NOW."
AND THIS WAS BEFORE THE
ACTUAL CONFESSION UNFOLDED.
HE SAID, "I AM NOT DOING
THIS BECAUSE I HAVE EMOTIONS,
OR I FEEL BAD
FOR ANYBODY."
AS A RESULT OF THE
CONVERSATION WITH MICHAEL,
WE OBTAINED A VERY
DETAILED CONFESSION,
WHERE HE IN FACT WAS THE PERSON
THAT STABBED MARK GIBBONS
AND CAUSED
HIS DEATH.
SAINT JOHN,
NEW BRUNSWICK.
AS McGRAY
TELLS IT,
ON THE NIGHT OF
NOVEMBER 14, 1987,
HE JOINS MARK GIBBONS
AND NORMAN WARREN
IN A PLAN
TO ROB A TAXI.
WHEN THE PLAN GOES BAD, THE
THREE MEN TAKE OFF ON FOOT.
WARREN IS
THE SLOWEST,
AND McGRAY AND GIBBONS
SOON LEAVE HIM BEHIND.
THEY STOP TO CATCH THEIR
BREATH NEAR THE CITY'S Y.M.C.A.
(Inspector Reid)
AT THAT POINT,
McGRAY TOOK THIS
HOMEMADE FASHIONED KNIFE,
AND STABBED A GIBBONS IN THE
CHEST JUST BELOW THE HEART ONCE,
PUT HIM TO
HIS KNEES.
McGRAY WAS UPSET THAT THE
ROBBERY WAS A BOTCHED ROBBERY,
BUT HE ALSO TALKS
ABOUT THE FACT
THAT WHEN HE HAD MET GIBBONS,
HE DIDN'T LIKE HIM.
AND HE KNEW HE WAS GONNA
DO SOMETHING TO HIM,
BUT HE DIDN'T KNOW HE
WAS GOING TO KILL HIM.
McGRAY LEAVES
GIBBONS TO DIE,
AND MEETS UP WITH
NORMAN WARREN.
THEY MAKE THEIR WAY
BACK TO THE HOUSE,
AND ALL THREE OF THEM
HAD QUASI-GIRLFRIENDS,
AND THE GIRLS WERE STARTING
TO ASK, "WHERE DID MARK GO?"
BUT AT
SOME POINT,
McGRAY SHOWS THE GIRLS
A KNIFE WITH BLOOD ON IT,
AND PASSED IT TO THE GIRLS AND
TOLD THE GIRLS TO CLEAN IT UP.
AFTER THEIR
ARREST,
McGRAY USES NORMAN
WARREN'S VIOLENT PAST
TO PIN THE
MURDER ON HIM,
WITH THE HELP
OF WITNESSES.
(Inspector Reid)
HE HAD TOLD THE GIRLS
THAT HE WAS THE ONE
THAT KILLED MARK GIBBONS,
BUT THAT IT WAS IMPORTANT THAT
THEY STICK BY HIM AND NOT TELL,
AND THEY TOLD AS MUCH AS
THEY COULD POSSIBLY TELL
WITHOUT
IMPLICATING McGRAY.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THESE WOMEN ARE WOMEN
THAT HAVE ABUSED
ALCOHOL AND DRUGS.
THESE WOMEN SUFFERED A LOT
OF VIOLENCE OVER THEIR LIVES.
AND THEY WERE VERY
AFRAID OF McGRAY.
IF HE'S
KILLED -
AND THEY WERE SURE THAT
HE HAD KILLED SOMEBODY -
THAT HE WOULD ACTUALLY
DO THAT TO THEM.
MICHAEL McGRAY'S
CONFESSION IS ASTOUNDING ,
BUT REID AND HIS
PARTNER MUST CORROBORATE
EVERYTHING THE SUSPECT
HAS TOLD THEM.
(Inspector Reid) AND TWO OF
THE WITNESSES, CERTAINLY -
WHEN WE WENT BACK AND
SPOKE TO THEM AFTERWARDS -
TOLD US EVERYTHING
HE DID AND SAID.
IT WAS VERY EASY TO
LAY THE MURDER CHARGE.
BY THE TIME THE TRIAL
FOR THE MURDERS
OF JOAN AND NENA HICKS
IS SET TO BEGIN,
MICHAEL McGRAY HAS
ALSO BEEN CHARGED
WITH THE DEATHS
OF MARK GIBBONS
AND THE TWO MEN
IN MONTREAL.
THE MEDIA STARTS TO USE
THE PHRASE "SERIAL KILLER"
WHEN IT TALKS ABOUT
MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY.
YOU DON'T HEAR THAT
TOO OFTEN IN CANADA.
IT CERTAINLY
WAS SNOWBALLING,
BECAUSE McGRAY WAS -
HE WAS SORT OF COOPERATING
WITH THE MEDIA
AT CERTAIN POINTS,
IN RELEASING INFORMATION
ON HOMICIDES.
WHAT ISN'T CLEAR
IS THE TIE
THAT BINDS THE McGRAY
MURDERS TOGETHER.
SERIAL KILLERS USUALLY CHOOSE
VICTIMS OF A SIMILAR TYPE,
YET THERE IS NO APPARENT LINK
BETWEEN THE MURDERS IN MONCTON
AND THOSE IN SAINT JOHN
AND MONTREAL.
MONDAY,
MARCH 20, 2000.
TWO YEARS AFTER THE BRUTAL
SLAYING OF JOAN HICKS
AND HER
DAUGHTER NENA,
35-YEAR-OLD MICHAEL McGRAY
SURPRISES A MONCTON COURTROOM
BY PLEADING GUILTY TO
THE MURDER OF JOAN HICKS.
♪
(Wendell) HE DIDN'T
WANT TO GO TO TRIAL.
HE WANTED TO PLEAD GUILTY
TO THE MURDER OF THE MOTHER,
AND SO CONSEQUENTLY, I MADE
MOTIONS BEFORE THE COURT
AND HE PLED GUILTY TO
THAT PARTICULAR CHARGE.
BUT THERE WAS NO
EMOTION IN THE PLEA.
HE HAD SOME EMOTION
ABOUT GOING TO TRIAL,
BUT NOT ABOUT
HER, PER SE.
IN HIS
STATEMENT,
McGRAY DESCRIBES HOW HE SPENT
THE DAY MAINLINING COCAINE
WITH ACQUAINTANCE
GLENN BENNETT.
HE TELLS OF
BECOMING OVERWHELMED
WITH AN URGE TO KILL
SOMEBODY - ANYBODY.
McGRAY AND BENNETT GO
TO THE HOME OF JOAN HICKS.
(Judy) HIS GIRLFRIEND
WAS AT MOM'S THAT NIGHT,
AND HE CAME,
ASKED HIS GIRLFRIEND TO,
WELL, GO HOME, I GUESS,
AND SHE DID, AND
HE WENT TO THE WASHROOM,
AND CALLED
TO MOM.
HE WANTED
TOILET PAPER.
SO, MOM WENT TO THE CLOSET
TO GET HIM THE TOILET PAPER,
AND THIS IS WHEN
HE KILLED MOM.
(Woman screaming)
(Judy speaking emotionally)
I'VE LEARNED THAT
HE STRANGLED HER,
AND THAT HE
CUT HER THROAT
TO DO
THE JOB.
McGRAY REFUSES,
HOWEVER,
TO ADMIT TO THE
MURDER OF NENA HICKS.
(Wendell) HE WAS ADAMANT
ABOUT NOT PLEADING GUILTY
WITH RESPECT TO THE
11-YEAR-OLD CHILD, NENA.
MY GUESS IS THAT CHILD
MURDERERS IN THE PENITENTIARY
HAVE A VERY
DIFFICULT TIME.
THEY'RE LESS THAN A HUMAN BEING
IN THE SIGHT OF OTHER INMATES.
THE FIRST-DEGREE
MURDER CHARGE
FOR THE KILLING OF JOAN HICKS
CARRIES A LIFE SENTENCE,
WITH LITTLE CHANCE
FOR PAROLE.
THE PROSECUTION DECIDES
TO SUSPEND PROCEEDINGS
IN THE SECOND MURDER,
PENDING FURTHER INVESTIGATION.
(Judy) IT WAS HARD - VERY
HARD - WHEN WE GOT THE NEWS.
I WAS VERY PROUD,
IN ONE WAY, YOU KNOW.
HE'S GOING TO JAIL FOR
FIRST-DEGREE MURDER FOR MOM.
BUT NENA WAS -
LIKE, NOBODY.
MICHAEL McGRAY
HAS BEEN IMPLICATED
IN FIVE DIFFERENT
MURDERS,
BUT EVEN
MORE SHOCKING,
POLICE LEARN THERE
MIGHT BE MORE.
(Narrator)
MARCH 20, 2000.
MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY
PLEADS GUILTY
TO THE MURDER
OF JOAN HICKS.
WHAT IS EVEN MORE SURPRISING
IS HIS WILLINGNESS
TO CONFESS TO THREE
ADDITIONAL STABBING DEATHS,
ONE OF WHICH GOES BACK
MORE THAN A DECADE.
WHILE BEING TRANSPORTED
TO THE FEDERAL PENITENTIARY
IN RENOUS, NEW BRUNSWICK,
McGRAY TELLS A POLICE OFFICER
THAT HE IS WILLING TO
CONFESS TO 11 OTHER KILLINGS
IN CITIES ACROSS CANADA
AND IN SEATTLE, WASHINGTON.
IN EXCHANGE, HE WANTS
IMMUNITY FROM PROSECUTION
AND MEDICAL HELP TO CONTROL
AN OVERWHELMING NEED TO KILL.
WHEN POLICE REFUSE
TO MEET HIS TERMS,
McGRAY GOES
TO THE MEDIA,
INCLUDING THE NATIONAL WIRE
SERVICE, CANADIAN PRESS.
(Murray Brewster)
AND WHAT AMOUNTED TO ABOUT A
15-MINUTE INTERVIEW WITH HIM,
AND IT BLEW
ME AWAY.
I CAN REMEMBER LISTENING
TO HIS ANSWERS,
LISTENING TO HOW
DETACHED HE WAS.
THERE WAS NO RANTING,
THERE WAS NO RAVING.
IT WAS - IT ABSOLUTELY
BLEW ME AWAY
AS TO HOW DETACHED
AND UNEMOTIONAL HE WAS,
AS THOUGH HE WAS JUST TALKING
ABOUT GOING TO THE GROCERY STORE
AND WHAT HE
HAD PICKED UP.
SEVERAL TIMES DURING
THE INTERVIEW,
McGRAY TALKS ABOUT AN
IRRESISTIBLE CRAVING TO KILL,
AND HIS NEED
TO HURT PEOPLE
TO SATISFY THIS
HUNGER DEEP INSIDE.
McGRAY DESCRIBES DRIFTING
FROM VANCOUVER TO HALIFAX,
STALKING
THE STRIPS
WHERE JUNKIES AND
PROSTITUTES HANG OUT,
AND GAY DISTRICTS WHERE
STRANGERS ARE EASY TARGETS.
(Michelle) WHAT WE
KNOW OF SERIAL KILLERS
IS THAT THERE'S USUALLY
SOME KIND OF A PATTERN.
THERE'S A CERTAIN TYPE
OF PERSON THEY MURDER.
IN MICHAEL WAYNE
McGRAY'S CASE,
HIS MOTIVATION
WAS A NEED TO KILL.
WHO HE KILLED DOESN'T
REALLY SEEM TO MATTER.
(Murray) YOU KNOW,
I ASKED HIM, I SAID,
"WHAT PEOPLE WANT TO
REALLY KNOW IS, LIKE,
DO YOU HAVE
A CONSCIENCE?"
AND, YOU KNOW, HE
SAID THAT, YOU KNOW,
HE WAS GRAPPLING WITH THE
WHOLE IDEA OF CONSCIENCE.
IT BOTHERED HIM THAT, YOU
KNOW, IT DIDN'T BOTHER HIM,
WHICH MOST NORMAL PEOPLE
WOULD SAY, "WHAT?"
IT WAS JUST - IT WAS -
AGAIN, IT WAS SO SURREAL.
AS SURREAL
AS IT SEEMS,
McGRAY'S NEXT ADMISSION
IS A BOMBSHELL.
(Murray) I ASKED HIM, YOU KNOW,
"WHAT WAS YOUR FIRST MURDER?"
AND HE SAID IT WAS
GAIL TUCKER, IN NOVA SCOTIA.
♪
GAIL TUCKER WAS
A 17-YEAR-OLD GIRL
WHO JUST HAPPENED
TO BE HITCHHIKING,
AND HAD THE
UNFORTUNATE LUCK
OF RUNNING ACROSS
MICHAEL McGRAY
AND A COMPANION
IN A TRUCK.
AND HE JUST GAVE
A VERY BRIEF,
VERY DISPASSIONATE
DESCRIPTION
OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
(Murray) IT TOOK
MY BREATH AWAY.
BUT IT TOOK
MY BREATH AWAY
BECAUSE OF JUST HOW ABSOLUTELY
DEVOID OF EMOTION IT WAS.
OVER THE NEXT
TWO MONTHS,
McGRAY PLEADS GUILTY TO
THE FIRST-DEGREE MURDERS
OF ROBERT ASSALY AND
GAETAN ETHIER IN MONTREAL,
AND THE
SECOND-DEGREE MURDER
OF ROBBERY ACCOMPLICE,
MARK GIBBONS, IN SAINT JOHN.
A YEAR LATER,
IN MAY, 2001,
McGRAY FINALLY FACES THE
CHARGE OF FIRST-DEGREE MURDER
IN THE DEATH
OF NENA HICKS,
AFTER HER FAMILY REQUESTS
THAT THE STAY BE LIFTED
BY THE
PROSECUTION.
(Judy) I WROTE A LETTER
TO THE ATTORNEY GENERAL.
SO, THEY
CALLED US BACK,
AND THEY WERE GOING TO
TAKE HIM TO TRIAL FOR NENA.
BUT HE APPEARED AND
THERE WAS NO TRIAL.
HE JUST WENT TO A COURT
HEARING AND PLEADED GUILTY.
A FEW DAYS LATER IN
A HALIFAX COURTROOM,
McGRAY PLEADS GUILTY
TO THE 1985 MURDER
OF HITCHHIKER
GAIL TUCKER,
BASED ON HIS OWN CONFESSION
AND CORROBORATING EVIDENCE.
(Wendell) THEY QUESTIONED HIM
WITH RESPECT TO WHAT HE KNEW,
WHETHER IT WOULD MATCH THE
PHYSICAL EVIDENCE THEY HAD,
BECAUSE THE POLICE HAD
A LOT OF INFORMATION
THAT WAS
NEVER RELEASED.
BASED ON THIS
INFORMATION,
THEY PROCEEDED AND LAID THE
FIRST DEGREE MURDER CHARGE
AGAINST
MICHAEL McGRAY.
IN COURT, GAIL TUCKER'S
FAMILY HEARS DETAILS
OF THE TEENAGER'S
FINAL MOMENTS -
HOW, AFTER SHE REFUSES
TO PROVIDE ORAL SEX,
McGRAY DRAGS HER FROM THE
TRUCK, RIPS OFF HER CLOTHES,
THEN STABS
HER REPEATEDLY
WHEN HER STRUGGLING
INFURIATES HIM,
AND HOW HE AND A
MYSTERY ACCOMPLICE
DRAG HER BODY
INTO THE WOODS.
THEY DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
EVIDENCE TO ESTABLISH
WHO WAS
WITH HIM.
FROM WHAT I'VE READ, AND
FROM MY PERSONAL BELIEF,
I DON'T THINK ANYONE HAD
ANYTHING ELSE TO DO WITH IT,
OTHER
THAN HIM.
McGRAY IS AGAIN SENTENCED
TO LIFE IN PRISON,
TO RUN CONCURRENTLY WITH
HIS FIVE OTHER SENTENCES.
FOR GAIL'S MOTHER,
MARY LAKE,
IT HAS BEEN A
LONG, PAINFUL ROAD.
(Wendell) HER MOTHER
SPENT FROM 1985 TO 2001
TRYING TO FIND WHO
MURDERED HER DAUGHTER.
I THINK THEY WERE AT A DEAD END
FOR A GREAT DEAL OF THE TIME.
BUT THE FILE
WAS PUT TOGETHER,
WITH RESPECT TO
THE PHYSICAL EVIDENCE,
AND EVERYTHING
IN IT WAS -
IT WAS KEPT ALIVE,
IN OTHER WORDS.
IT WAS ALWAYS ACTIVE
BECAUSE OF HER PERSISTENCE.
MICHAEL WAYNE McGRAY IS
CURRENTLY SERVING HIS TIME
AT THE ATLANTIC MAXIMUM
SECURITY FACILITY
IN RENOUS,
NEW BRUNSWICK.
HE HAS STATED THAT,
IF GIVEN THE CHANCE,
HE WOULD MURDER A GUARD,
ANOTHER PRISONER,
ANYONE WHO COULD SATISFY HIS
UNCONTROLLABLE CRAVING TO KILL.
FROM HIS OWN EXPERIENCE,
McGRAY'S DEFENSE LAWYER,
WENDELL MAXWELL, KNOWS
THIS IS NO IDLE THREAT.
(Wendell) I WENT TO SEE
HIM, JUST TO GO OVER
WHAT WAS GOING TO
HAPPEN IN HALIFAX,
AND WE'RE PUT IN
THE INTERVIEW ROOM.
I WAS THERE PROBABLY
HALF AN HOUR, 45 MINUTES,
TALKED TO HIM,
THEN I LEFT.
WHEN THEY SEARCHED HIM, THEY
FOUND A HOMEMADE SHIV - KNIFE.
THE GUARDS SAID, "MICHAEL,
WHAT WAS THIS FOR?"
AND HE SAID, "OH, I WAS,
I WAS GOING TO DO WENDELL."
IF I'D HAVE BEEN
ALONE WITH HIM,
I WOULD PROBABLY WOULD NOT
BE DOING THIS INTERVIEW
WITH YOU
TODAY.
THAT'S WHY I REALLY BELIEVE
THAT MICHAEL'S A PSYCHOPATH.
HE HAS NO CONSCIENCE,
HE ACTS ON IMPULSE.
HE DOESN'T SIT AND WEIGH
WHETHER IT'S RIGHT OR WRONG.
IT'S JUST THE IMPULSE AND
WHEN IT'S DONE, IT'S DONE,
THERE'S NO
CONSCIENCE.
THERE'S NOTHING
AFTER THAT.
THAT'S THE WAY MICHAEL
WAS WITH THESE MURDERS.
(Murray) I DON'T THINK
THEY'VE NECESSARILY
ACCURATELY ESTABLISHED
WHETHER OR NOT
HE ACTUALLY DID ALL OF THE
16 MURDERS THAT HE CLAIMED.
MY OPINION IS IT
DOESN'T REALLY MATTER.
NUMBERS
DON'T MATTER.
NUMBERS DON'T MATTER
TO GAIL TUCKER'S FAMILY.
TO THE HICKS FAMILY,
WHO LOST, YOU KNOW,
THEIR DAUGHTER
AND THEIR
GRANDDAUGHTER.
YOU KNOW, I JUST - TO ME,
THE NUMBERS ARE IRRELEVANT.
(Judy) HE TOOK
EVERYTHING AWAY FROM ME.
ALL THE FAMILY I HAD
WAS MOM AND NENA.
IT CHANGED
MY FAMILY.
EVERYTHING.
YOU LIVE
DAY BY DAY,
AND THEY'RE ALWAYS
IN YOUR MIND.
ALWAYS.