(Narrator) MARCH 2000.
POLICE IN KANSAS
FOLLOW THE CLUES
BEHIND THE DISAPPEARANCE OF
A STRING OF YOUNG WOMEN,
CLUES THAT SOON LEAD THEM
TO THE ONLINE WORLD
OF SEX AND BONDAGE.
(Brad Hill) IT WAS QUITE A
SHOCK TO US - OBVIOUSLY -
TO FIND OUT ABOUT
THESE WEBSITES.
THERE WAS PROBABLY MUCH
GREATER FOLLOWING IN THIS
THAN WHAT WE WOULD
HAVE EVER DREAMED.
BEFORE LONG, A GROWING
SQUAD OF DETECTIVES
CLOSES IN ON THE WORLD'S
FIRST CYBER-KILLER,
A MAN KNOWN TO SOME
AS SLAVE MASTER.
(Brad) HE JUST DEVELOPED
INTO THIS PERSON
THAT COULD KILL PEOPLE
WITHOUT REMORSE.
ALONG WITH POLICE,
THERE ARE THOSE
WHO CHRONICLE THE
INVESTIGATION UP CLOSE -
ON FILM, ON
PAPER, AND ON TAPE.
THEY ARE THE PUBLIC'S
FIRST WITNESS.
THROUGH THEIR EYES,
THEY CAPTURE OUR DARKEST
CHAPTERS OF CRIME.
(♪)
IN THE LATE 1990s, THE
INTERNET WAS GROWING
AT AN EXPONENTIAL RATE.
WITHIN A FEW YEARS,
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
WERE SUDDENLY USING
THEIR COMPUTERS TO
KEEP IN TOUCH WITH FAMILY
AND FRIENDS, MEET
NEW ACQUAINTANCES,
EVEN SHOP OR LOOK
FOR A JOB ONLINE.
AT THE TIME, A YOUNG
WOMAN FROM MICHIGAN
NAMED SUZETTE TROUTEN WAS
AMONG THOSE EMBRACING
THE NEW TECHNOLOGY.
(camera shutter click)
SUZETTE TROUTEN
WAS A, A GAL
IN HER MID-TWENTIES.
SHE WAS VERY MUCH
INTO COMMUNICATING
OVER THE INTERNET,
VERY MUCH INTO E-MAILING,
VERY MUCH INTO INSTANT
MESSAGING, YOU KNOW,
AS WAS HER CORE
CIRCLE OF FRIENDS.
DURING THE DAY, SUZETTE
WORKS AS A NURSE'S AID
AND A COOK AT A
LOCAL RESTAURANT.
IN DECEMBER OF 1999,
WHILE AT HER COMPUTER,
SHE GETS WHAT SEEMS LIKE
AN INCREDIBLE BREAK.
SUZETTE MEETS A NEW FRIEND
AND POTENTIAL EMPLOYER
OVER THE INTERNET. JOHN
ROBINSON, OR JR AS HE OFTEN
GOES BY WHILE ONLINE,
LIVES NEAR KANSAS CITY.
(camera shutter click)
HE HAD OFFERED
SUZETTE TROUTEN A JOB
AT $67,000 DOLLARS
A YEAR TO SORT OF BE
A PRIVATE NURSE TO
HIS AILING FATHER.
FOR SOMEBODY LIKE
SUZETTE TROUTEN,
WHO'D BEEN WORKING AS A, AS
AN AID IN NURSING HOMES
IN MICHIGAN WHERE SHE
WAS FROM - $67,000 DOLLARS
A YEAR WAS A FANTASTIC SUM
OF MONEY THAT WAS MORE
THAN SHE'D PROBABLY EVER BE
ABLE TO MAKE UP THERE.
ALTHOUGH SOME FAMILY MEMBERS
FEEL THE JOB OFFER
IS TOO GOOD TO BE TRUE,
SUZETTE FEELS INCLINED
TO ACCEPT IT.
SHE SAYS GOODBYE TO
FRIENDS AND FAMILY
AND MAKES THE MORE THAN
700 MILE DRIVE TO KANSAS,
HER TWO SMALL DOGS
PEKA AND HARRY IN TOW.
JOHN ROBINSON GREETS HER
AND SETS HER UP IN LENEXA,
NOT FAR FROM KANSAS CITY.
FOR THE FIRST FEW WEEKS,
SUZETTE STAYS IN CLOSE TOUCH
WITH THOSE BACK HOME,
ESPECIALLY HER
MOTHER CAROLINE.
(camera shutter click)
SUZETTE HAD CONTACTED
HER MOTHER AND I BELIEVE
IT WAS EVERY SINGLE
DAY THAT SHE WAS HERE
SHE HAD, SHE WOULD CALL
EVERYDAY OR E-MAIL EVERYDAY
AND THERE WAS CONSTANT
COMMUNICATION.
BUT ON MARCH 1, 2000, THAT
CONTACT SUDDENLY STOPS.
CAROLINE RECEIVES NO
NEW CALLS OR E-MAILS
FROM HER DAUGHTER,
AND THE ATTEMPTS SHE
MAKES TO CONTACT SUZETTE
BRING NO REPLIES.
(Gerald Hay) THEY
WERE QUITE CLOSE.
WHEN SHE, YOU KNOW, THE
COMMUNICATIONS LINE
WERE QUICKLY SEVERED,
HER MOM IMMEDIATELY
KNEW SOMETHING WAS WRONG.
SUZETTE'S MOTHER CONTACTS
JOHN ROBINSON DIRECTLY.
HE EXPLAINS THAT HE TOO
HASN'T BEEN IN TOUCH
WITH SUZETTE FOR
SEVERAL DAYS.
HE GOES ON TO SAY THAT
SHE NEVER ACTUALLY TOOK
THE NURSING JOB HE OFFERED.
INSTEAD, SHE TOOK OFF
ON AN EXTENDED HOLIDAY
WITH A WEALTHY LOCAL
LAWYER NAMED JIM TURNER.
(David) CAROLINE HAD NEVER
HEARD JIM TURNER BEFORE,
SUZETTE HAD NEVER TALKED
ABOUT JIM, JIM TURNER
BEFORE. SUZETTE WOULD NEVER
TAKE OFF WITH SOMEONE
SHE HAD JUST
MET LIKE THAT;
THAT WAS TOTALLY
OUT OF CHARACTER
FOR WHAT CAROLINE
KNEW SUZETTE TO BE.
SHORTLY AFTER
THE PHONE CALL,
SUZETTE'S MOTHER AND
OTHER FAMILY MEMBERS
BEGIN RECEIVING E-MAILS
FROM SUZETTE AGAIN.
SHE SEEMS TO CONFIRM
JOHN ROBINSON'S STORY.
WITH HER DOGS PEKA AND
HARRY STILL AT HER SIDE,
SHE EXPLAINS SHE IS NOW
TRAVELLING OVERSEAS
WITH HER NEW
ACQUAINTANCE.
(David) THE THING THAT
CAROLINE AND OTHER FAMILY
MEMBERS NOTED ABOUT
THESE E-MAILS
IS THAT THEY WEREN'T WRITTEN
THE WAY THAT SUZETTE WRITES.
(Brad) ONE OF THE
DOG'S NAMES WAS
SPELLED INCORRECTLY.
AND SO THEY, THEY KNEW JUST
FROM THE WAY SHE WROTE,
THIS IS NOT FROM HER.
ALONG WITH THE
SUSPICIOUS E-MAILS,
FAMILY MEMBERS
ALSO RECEIVE
TYPEWRITTEN LETTERS
FROM SUZETTE.
(Paul) THE STYLE OF WRITING
WAS DIFFERENT FROM HER,
BUT YET WHAT WAS PERPLEXING
TO THEM WAS THAT HER
SIGNATURE WAS ON
THESE LETTERS.
THEY WERE TYPEWRITTEN,
BUT HER SIGNATURE
WAS ON ALL THESE LETTERS.
AND SO THEY DIDN'T REALLY
KNOW WHAT TO THINK,
BUT HER MOM WAS INSISTENT ON
THE FACT THAT SOMETHING HAD
HAPPENED TO SUZETTE AND THAT
SHE REALLY WASN'T TRAVELLING
WITH THIS GUY 'CAUSE IT
JUST DIDN'T QUITE FIT.
MARCH 25, 2000.
AFRAID THAT SOMETHING
TERRIBLE HAS HAPPENED
TO SUZETTE, HER SISTER
DAWN CONTACTS POLICE
IN KANSAS TO FILE A
MISSING PERSONS REPORT.
(camera shutter click)
WHEN WE GET A MISSING
PERSON REPORT IT'S SO HARD
TO TELL WHAT MAY HAVE
ACTUALLY HAPPENED.
A LOT OF TIMES THE PEOPLE
DON'T WANT TO BE FOUND.
SHE WAS OUT OF TOWN, SHE
COULD HAVE BEEN IN ANOTHER
TOWN AT THAT TIME, SHE COULD
HAVE MET SOMEBODY ELSE,
IT CAN BE ANY ONE OF A
MILLION DIFFERENT SITUATIONS.
FOLLOWING UP ON THE REPORT,
POLICE VISIT THE HOTEL
WHERE SUZETTE WAS
ORIGINALLY STAYING.
SUZETTE WAS LAST
SEEN ON MARCH 1st,
THE VERY DAY REGULAR
COMMUNICATION
WITH HER FAMILY
FIRST DROPPED OFF.
(David) THE STAFF AT THE
HOTEL SAID JOHN ROBINSON
CHECKED SUZETTE OUT. AND
JOHN ROBINSON WAS SEEN
COMING BACK IN HIS
TRUCK THAT AFTERNOON
REMOVING
HER BELONGINGS.
THEY HAVE VIDEO SURVEILLANCE
TAPE RUNNING 27/7.
THE VIDEOTAPE
SHOWING JOHN THE DAY
HE CHECKS SUZETTE
OUT OF THE HOTEL.
THE FACT THAT JOHN ROBINSON
WAS THE LAST PERSON
SEEN WITH SUZETTE'S
POSSESSIONS RAISES
POLICE INTEREST.
FURTHERMORE, THEY CAN FIND
NO RECORD OF A WEALTHY LOCAL
LAWYER NAMED JIM TURNER,
THE MAN SUZETTE
ALLEGEDLY RAN OFF WITH.
BACK AT THE STATION,
THEY UNCOVER MORE
DISTURBING INFORMATION.
POLICE RECORDS REVEAL THAT
SUZETTE'S PROSPECTIVE
EMPLOYER JOHN ROBINSON IS
ACTUALLY A CAREER CON MAN
WITH A CRIMINAL HISTORY
INVOLVING FRAUD AND THEFT.
(Paul) WHEN WE LOOKED
AT HIS LIFE HE HAD BEEN
SCAMMING PEOPLE
SINCE HE WAS A KID.
HE WAS VERY GOOD AT IT, HE
WAS ABLE TO TALK PEOPLE INTO
GIVING HIM LARGE QUANTITIES
OF MONEY OF COURSE
THEY'D NEVER SEE IT AGAIN.
MOST OMINOUS, HOWEVER,
IS THE FACT THAT JOHN
ROBINSON'S NAME IS ALSO
FLAGGED IN CONNECTION
WITH THREE OTHER MISSING
PERSONS CASES DATING BACK
TO THE 1980s.
(Paul) WE HAD ALL THESE
WOMEN THAT SPAN BACK ALMOST
20 YEARS AND THE ONE THING
THEY HAD IN COMMON IS THEY
HAD ALL HAD AN ASSOCIATION
WITH JOHN ROBINSON,
AND DURING THAT ASSOCIATION
WITH JOHN ROBINSON
THEY'D ALL DISAPPEARED.
(Brad) THE MINUTE THAT
THEY SAW THAT THEY JUST,
YOU KNOW, HAD A BAD FEELING
ABOUT IT: THAT THIS ISN'T,
THIS ISN'T LOOKING
GOOD, THIS IS ANOTHER,
THE PATTERN IS CONTINUING.
(Paul) LITERALLY WITHIN 24
HOURS WE HAD PUT TOGETHER
A TASK FORCE THAT WORKED
OUT OF THE LENEXA POLICE
DEPARTMENT THAT INVOLVED
SEVERAL DIFFERENT AGENCIES
AND WITHIN 24 HOURS WE WERE
MEETING AND COMING UP WITH
A GAME PLAN ON WHAT WE WERE
GONNA DO TO INVESTIGATE
THIS GUY AND, AND FIND
OUT WHAT THE TRUTH WAS.
(David) WE STARTED TALKING
AND SINCE WE'RE LOOKING
FOR SUZETTE AND WE KNOW
THAT SUZETTE IS ASSOCIATED
WITH JOHN ROBINSON, WE SAY,
OKAY, MAYBE THE BEST WAY
TO FIND SUZETTE IS IF
SHE'S ALIVE, IS TO START
SURVEILLING JOHN ROBINSON.
MAYBE JOHN ROBINSON WILL
TAKE US TO SUZETTE;
WE MAY GET SOME INDICATION
ABOUT WHERE SHE'S AT.
MARCH 29, 2000.
WITH GROWING UNEASE
ABOUT THEIR LATEST
MISSING PERSONS CASE,
POLICE BEGIN TAKING
A MUCH CLOSER LOOK
AT 56-YEAR-OLD
JOHN ROBINSON.
AT THE TIME, HE LIVES
WITH HIS WIFE NANCY
IN A LOCAL MOBILE
HOME COMMUNITY.
(Dan) EVERYDAY I WOULD MEET
A GROUP OF DETECTIVES;
WE WOULD ALL BE IN VEHICLES
THAT ARE SOMEWHAT LOW-PROFILE.
WE DRESSED DOWN IN
CASUAL CLOTHES.
OUR DETECTIVES WOULD HAVE
AN EYE ON HIS TRAILER
AND THE TRAILER PARK AND
WHEN HE WOULD START MOVING
WE WOULD FOLLOW HIM.
AT THE SAME TIME,
POLICE EMPLOY ANOTHER
INVESTIGATIVE TECHNIQUE
KNOWN AS TRASHING.
(Dan) WE WERE JUST TRYING
TO FIND OUT WHAT THE HABITS
OF JOHN ROBINSON WERE. SEEING
IF THERE WERE ANY CLUES
ABOUT THIS MISSING GAL
WAS IN HIS TRASH.
WE GENERALLY WENT BY THERE
EARLY MORNING HOURS.
(David) WE'LL REPLACE
GARBAGE BAG THAT WE WANT
WITH VERY SIMILAR-LOOKING
GARBAGE BAG SO THAT THE NEXT
MORNING, JOHN OR WHOEVER
IT MAY BE YOU KNOW,
SEES IT OUT THERE AND THE,
THE TRASH PEOPLE PICK IT UP.
(Dan) THE FIRST TIME WE
PICKED UP THE TRASH
HE'D SHREDDED A LOT OF
THE CONTENTS OF HIS TRASH
THROUGH THE PAPER SHREDDER.
(Brad) SO YOU HAD
THESE STRIPS OF PAPER
THAT YOU COULD TRY
AND MATCH UP.
YOU CAN SEPARATE BY
COLOR AND YOU KNOW,
IF THERE'S THINGS ABOUT THE
PAPER MAKE IT UNIQUE YOU CAN
OBVIOUSLY KNOW THAT
GOES WITH THAT.
BUT FOR THE MOST PART,
IT'S THE BIG PUZZLE.
AND THEN WHAT WE DO IS WE
TAPE ONE TO THE TABLE
AND THEN WE JUST TRY
AND KEEP TAPING PIECES
TO IT UNTIL WE GET
THE FULL DOCUMENT.
MOST OF THE GARBAGE
IS QUITE ORDINARY,
WITH NO LINKS TO
SUZETTE TROUTEN.
ON THE SURFACE AT LEAST,
JOHN ROBINSON LOOKS LIKE
THE LAST PERSON
TO BE INVOLVED
IN A MISSING
PERSONS CASE.
(Dan) WE DIDN'T SEE HIM
DOING A LOT OF THINGS
THAT WOULD RAISE THE
SUSPICION OF ANYONE.
HE WAS, HE WAS A FATHER,
HE WAS A GRANDFATHER.
WE SAW HIM ONE TIME
PICK UP HIS CHILD
AT A DAYCARE CENTER.
WE SAW HIM MAKE TRIPS
TO HARDWARE STORES,
MAKE TRIPS TO RESTAURANTS
WITH HIS WIFE.
A LOT OF THE THINGS HE DID
WERE JUST ORDINARY THINGS
THAT ORDINARY
PEOPLE DO EVERYDAY.
BUT IN THE DAYS AHEAD,
LINKS TO A WORLD OF SEX
AND BONDAGE AND A
MYSTERIOUS STORAGE LOCKER
MAY LEAD DETECTIVES TO
28-YEAR-OLD SUZETTE TROUTEN.
(♪)
(Narrator)
MARCH 31, 2000.
IN JOHNSON
COUNTY KANSAS,
POLICE ARE LOOKING FOR
MISSING SUZETTE TROUTEN,
A NURSE'S AID
FROM MICHIGAN.
ALTHOUGH THERE'S NO
EVIDENCE OF FOUL PLAY,
THE LAST PERSON KNOWN
TO HAVE SEEN HER
IS A 56-YEAR-OLD LOCAL
RESIDENT NAMED JOHN ROBINSON.
A CAREER CONMAN WHO IS
LINKED TO AT LEAST THREE
OTHER MISSING PERSONS CASES,
ROBINSON IS NOW UNDER
CONSTANT SURVEILLANCE.
POLICE HOPE HE MAY LEAD THEM
TO SUZETTE'S WHEREABOUTS.
(camera shutter click)
(Brad) WE JUST KIND OF
DID EVERYTHING WE COULD
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT,
WHERE, YOU KNOW,
WHAT'S GOING ON
AND HOW DO WE GET TO
THE BOTTOM OF, YOU KNOW,
WHERE IS THIS GIRL.
WHILE SOME OFFICERS
KEEP WATCH ON ROBINSON,
OTHER OFFICERS GO TO
MICHIGAN TO SPEAK WITH
SUZETTE'S MOTHER CAROLINE
AND COMPILE A DETAILED LIST
OF SUZETTE'S PERSONAL
POSSESSIONS.
(Brad) WE JUST DECIDED THAT
IF A PERSON WHO MOVED HERE
AND THEN SUBSEQUENTLY
WAS MISSING.
IF SHE WAS GONE MISSING
AND HER PROPERTY WAS GONE,
SOMEONE WOULD HAVE TO PUT
THIS PROPERTY SOMEWHERE.
THAT THE ONLY WAY THAT
YOU COULD GET RID OF THAT
OR YOU WOULD YOU, YOU NEED TO
PUT IT INTO A STORAGE FACILITY
SO LITERALLY WE JUST DECIDED
THAT'S A LEAD WE NEED
TO LOOK INTO, SO WE OPENED
A PHONEBOOK AND JUST WENT
RIGHT DOWN THROUGH THE
PHONEBOOK CALLING ANY,
ANY STORAGE FACILITY
THAT WE COULD FIND.
POLICE DON'T FIND
ANY STORAGE LOCKERS
UNDER SUZETTE
TROUTEN'S NAME,
BUT THEY DO FIND ONE
BELONGING TO JOHN ROBINSON
IN THE NEARBY CITY
OF OLATHE, KANSAS.
CURIOUSLY, IT APPEARS
ROBINSON VISITED THE SITE
ON MARCH 1st, THE SAME DAY
SUZETTE WAS LAST SEEN
AT HER HOTEL. A SIMILAR
LEAD MATERIALIZES
IN ROBINSON'S
SHREDDED TRASH.
OFFICERS RE-ASSEMBLE A BILL
FOR ANOTHER STORAGE LOCKER
IN RAYMORE, MISSOURI,
THIS ONE HELD IN
JOHN'S WIFE'S NAME.
PAYING A VISIT,
POLICE LEARN THAT JOHN
ALSO HAS HIS OWN STORAGE
LOCKER THERE.
ALTHOUGH POLICE FEEL THE
STORAGE LOCKERS MAY HOLD
CLUES ABOUT SUZETTE'S
WHEREABOUTS,
THEY ARE UNABLE TO LOOK
INSIDE WITHOUT SOLID
EVIDENCE AND A
SEARCH WARRANT.
(♪)
(camera shutter click)
WE HAD ACTUALLY SET
UP SURVEILLANCE CAMERAS
ABOVE THE ENTRYWAYS OF
BOTH STORAGE LOCKERS.
SO THAT WE COULD KEEP TRACK
OF HIM WHEN HE DID SHOW UP
THERE. IF WE WERE TO LOSE
HIM ON OUR SURVEILLANCE
WE WOULD BE ABLE TO TELL
WHETHER OR NOT HE WENT
TO THAT LOCKER OR NOT
BY VIEWING THE TAPES
ONCE WE HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY TO DO SO.
AT THE SAME TIME,
HOPING TO FIND LINKS,
POLICE TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AT
THE OTHER MISSING PERSONS
CASES THAT ROBINSON HAS BEEN
CONNECTED TO IN THE PAST.
ONE DATES BACK
TO THE MID-1980s.
A 19-YEAR-OLD WOMAN
NAMED LISA STASI
AND HER FIVE MONTH OLD BABY
TIFFANY WERE REFERRED
TO A PROGRAM IN KANSAS
AIMED AT HELPING YOUNG
SINGLE MOTHERS GET
BACK ON THEIR FEET.
AT THE TIME, IT HAPPENED TO
BE RUN BY JOHN ROBINSON.
(camera shutter click)
HE HAD AN APARTMENT
THAT HE WAS USING
FOR THIS PROGRAM THAT HE WAS
ALLEGEDLY RUNNING FOR YOUNG
GIRLS. BUT INSTEAD OF
PUTTING LISA AT THE SITE
OF HIS PROGRAM HE
PUT HER IN A MOTEL.
HER FAMILY HAD RECEIVED A
CALL FROM HER WANTING TO
KNOW WHY THEY WERE TRYING
TO TAKE HER BABY AWAY,
AND THEY SAID WE'RE NOT
TRYING TO TAKE YOUR BABY
AWAY, AND SHE'S CRYING
AND SHE'S HYSTERICAL,
SHE'S A YOUNG, 19-YEAR-OLD
YOUNG WOMAN AND SHE SAYS
THEY'VE MADE ME SIGN FOUR
BLANK SHEETS OF PAPER,
HERE THEY COME,
I HAVE TO GO.
AND THOSE WERE THE
LAST WORDS THAT ANYONE
EVER HEARD FROM
LISA STASI.
THE FAMILY DOES, HOWEVER,
RECEIVE A SIGNED LETTER.
(Stephen) AND BASICALLY,
THE LETTER SAID,
"I'M OKAY, I'VE, I'VE MET
SOMEONE ELSE, I'VE GONE OFF
TO START A NEW LIFE", YOU
KNOW, "I APPRECIATE THE HELP
I'VE RECEIVED FROM ROBINSON,
FROM THE ORGANIZATIONS
THAT HAVE HELPED ME
OUT BUT I'VE JUST,
I'M JUST GONNA GO
START A NEW LIFE."
(♪)
IN THE 1980s, PROBATION
OFFICER STEPHEN HAYMES MET
WITH ROBINSON TO DISCUSS HIS
PROGRAM FOR SINGLE MOTHERS.
(Stephen) HE HAD A LONG
CRIMINAL HISTORY ALREADY
BY THAT TIME: HE HAD
EMBEZZLED FROM,
FROM EMPLOYERS, HE HAD STOLEN
FROM, FROM SEVERAL EMPLOYERS.
JOHN JUST PROCLAIMED HIS
INNOCENCE OR INVOLVEMENT
IN ANY WAY WITH LISA, OTHER
THAN HELPING HER OUT.
SHE'S GONE OFF
WITH A BOYFRIEND,
HE DOESN'T KNOW WHY HE'S
BEING HASSLED AND BOTHERED
BY PEOPLE QUESTIONING HIM
WHEN ALL HE TRIED TO DO
WAS SOMETHING GOOD.
COMPOUNDING SUSPICIONS,
HAYMES LEARN THAT ONLY
SIX MONTHS PRIOR TO LISA
STASI'S DISAPPEARANCE,
AN EMPLOYEE OF ROBINSON'S
NAMED PAULA GODFREY
ALSO WENT MISSING.
HER FAMILY HAD RECEIVED
SIMILAR SIGNED LETTERS.
(Stephen) IT WAS TO ME MORE
THAN A STRANGE COINCIDENCE
THAT YOU HAVE TWO MISSING
PERSONS AND SIMILAR
CIRCUMSTANCE THAT ALL OF
A SUDDEN LETTERS START
APPEARING SIGNED BY
HER, SAYING THAT,
"I'M OKAY, I'M FINE, I'VE
JUST DECIDED TO GO OFF
AND START A NEW LIFE."
YOU KNOW THAT WAS
MORE COINCIDENCE
THAN I WAS WILLING
TO ACCEPT.
AT THE TIME,
HAYMES SPECULATED
THAT JOHN ROBINSON
MIGHT BE INVOLVED
IN A BABY SMUGGLING OR
PROSTITUTION RING.
POLICE INVESTIGATION
REVEALED THAT HE HAD
A SEXUAL FETISH FOR BDSM,
SHORT FOR BONDAGE,
DOMINATION, AND
SADOMASOCHISM.
BDSM IS A ROUGH FORM OF
SEX THAT OFTEN INVOLVES
WHIPS AND RESTRAINTS.
AT LEAST ONE WOMAN
IS ON RECORD WITH CLAIMS
THAT ROBINSON
HIRED HER OUT TO MEN WHO
SHARED SIMILAR FETISHES.
(Stephen) SHE ALSO TELLS US
A STORY THAT ROBINSON
IS INVOLVED IN A GROUP
THAT PROVIDES GIRLS
FOR SADOMASOCHISTIC
SEXUAL RELATIONSHIPS
AND THAT HE PAID HER
A LARGE SUM OF MONEY
AND THAT HE GAVE
HER SOME DRUGS,
BLINDFOLDED HER,
PUT HER IN A CAR
AND DROVE HER TO A, TO
A HOUSE IN A, IN A VERY
AFFLUENT PART OF TOWN AND
THAT SHE WAS TAKEN TO
THE BASEMENT OF THIS HOUSE,
AND IN THE BASEMENT
OF THE HOUSE THERE WERE
RACKS AND OTHER S &
M-TYPE TORTURE DEVICES.
WHILE A WOMAN NAMED
CATHERINE CLAMPITT WOULD
ALSO VANISH AFTER MEETING
ROBINSON IN THE 1980s,
THERE WAS NEVER ENOUGH
EVIDENCE TO CHARGE HIM
IN CONNECTION WITH ANY
OF THE MISSING WOMEN.
(camera shutter click)
(Gerald) THERE WAS
SUSPICIONS BUT ACT,
NO ACTUAL PROOF THAT
ANYTHING HAD HAPPENED
TO THESE WOMEN. NO ONE HAD ANY
PROOF THERE WAS ANYTHING WRONG.
FOR POLICE NOW SEARCHING
FOR SUZETTE TROUTEN
IN THE YEAR 2000,
THERE ARE FRIGHTENING
SIMILARITIES BETWEEN
THE OLD FILES AND HER
RECENT DISAPPEARANCE,
IN PARTICULAR, THE
BIZARRE SIGNED LETTERS,
LETTERS THAT
CONTINUE TO COME.
(camera shutter click)
SHE'D WRITE THESE
ELABORATE LETTERS ABOUT,
"I'M ON THE DECK
THIS MORNING,
WE'RE WATCHING THE DOLPHINS
SWIM ALONGSIDE THE BOAT AND
OUR TWO LITTLE DOGS PEKA AND
HARRY ARE OUT HERE BARKING
AT THE FISH" AND NONE OF
THESE LETTERS MADE SENSE
TO HER FAMILY BECAUSE
HER MOM KNEW THAT
SHE DIDN'T LIKE WATER.
(David) THEY KNEW THIS COULD
NOT BE COMING FROM SUZETTE.
MOREOVER, A GRIM LEAD SEEMS
TO CONTRADICT THE LETTERS
AND CONFIRM FEARS THAT
SUZETTE NEVER LEFT KANSAS.
OFFICERS LEARN THAT TWO DOGS
MATCHING THE DESCRIPTION
OF PEKA AND HARRY WERE
RECENTLY PICKED UP
BY A LOCAL ANIMAL SHELTER.
TO MAKE A COMPARISON,
OFFICERS USE PHOTOS
OF THE DOGS PROVIDED BY
SUZETTE'S MOTHER CAROLINE.
(camera shutter click)
CAROLINE TELLS ME THAT
THOSE TWO DOGS,
PEKA AND HARRY,
WERE, WERE HER KIDS.
SUZETTE WOULD GO NOWHERE
WITHOUT PEKA AND HARRY AND,
SHE SAYS IF YOU FIND PEKA
AND HARRY WITHOUT SUZETTE,
SHE KNOWS SOMETHING
IS SERIOUSLY WRONG.
ONE DOG HAS BEEN GIVEN UP FOR
ADOPTION TO A LOCAL FAMILY.
(Brad) I WENT TO THEIR
HOUSE AND I TOLD THEM WHY
I WAS THERE AND THEY WERE
VERY HELPFUL, VERY FRIENDLY.
I TALKED TO 'EM FOR AWHILE,
I LOOKED AT THE DOG,
I SHOWED 'EM THE PICTURE,
THEY AGREED IT LOOKED LIKE
THIS DOG PEKA AND THEN AFTER
I TALKED TO 'EM FOR AWHILE
I CALLED THE DOG BY NAME AND
IT CAME RIGHT OVER TO ME
SO WE JUST ALL, AND WE
KNEW THEN THAT WAS,
THAT WAS PEKA.
SUZETTE'S OTHER DOG HARRY
TURNS UP AT ANOTHER SHELTER.
(David) I FLEW UP TO TO
MICHIGAN AND MET WITH
CAROLINE AT HER HOUSE AND
DELIVERED THE NEWS
TO CAROLINE THAT YOU KNOW,
WE HAD FOUND PEKA AND HARRY
AND DESCRIBED THE
CIRCUMSTANCES.
AND THAT, THAT HIT
HOME PRETTY HARD.
YOU COULD TELL CAROLINE, YOU
KNOW, SAT BACK AND SAID,
"THEN THAT MEANS THAT
SUZETTE'S PROBABLY DEAD".
SO SHE REALIZED AT THAT
POINT THAT IT WAS VERY,
YOU KNOW, THE CHANCES OF
SUZETTE BEING FOUND ALIVE
WERE SLIM TO NONE.
(Paul) IT BECAME VERY,
VERY OBVIOUS TO US
THAT THIS GUY WAS
PROBABLY KILLING WOMEN.
BUT WITHOUT ENOUGH EVIDENCE
AGAINST ROBINSON
FOR AN ARREST WARRANT,
POLICE CAN DO LITTLE MORE
THAN WATCH AND WAIT.
NEW ANSWERS WILL SOON
COME FROM THE INTERNET -
AND FROM A STREAM OF NEW
WOMEN THAT JOHN ROBINSON
STARTS BRINGING INTO TOWN.
(♪)
(Narrator)
APRIL 2000.
POLICE IN KANSAS ARE
KEEPING A CONSTANT WATCH
ON 56-YEAR-OLD
JOHN ROBINSON.
ALTHOUGH THEY HAVE NO
EVIDENCE AGAINST HIM,
HE IS THE PRIME SUSPECT
IN THE DISAPPEARANCE
OF AT LEAST FOUR
YOUNG WOMEN;
MOST RECENTLY A
28-YEAR-OLD NURSE'S AID
NAMED SUZETTE TROUTEN.
(camera shutter click)
WE NEVER REALLY HAD SOLID
INFORMATION THAT ANYTHING,
OTHER THAN THE FACTS
THAT SHE'S MISSING.
WE DON'T KNOW
WHERE SHE IS.
WE KNEW SHE WAS WITH THIS
GUY AND WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT HE MAY HAVE
DONE WITH HER;
SHE MIGHT BE ALIVE,
SHE MIGHT BE DEAD.
POLICE TAILING ROBINSON
LEARN THAT ALONG WITH
KEEPING STORAGE
LOCKERS IN THE AREA,
HE ALSO HAS A HIDEOUT
FAR FROM THE MOBILE HOME
COMMUNITY HE LIVES
IN WITH HIS WIFE.
(camera shutter click)
ON ONE OCCASION
MR. ROBINSON WAS FOLLOWED
AND HE'D BEEN GOING FOR
QUITE A WAYS DOWN SOUTH
AND HE EVENTUALLY ENDED
UP IN LA CYGNE, KANSAS,
WHICH, AND IT WAS QUITE
A WAY TO TRAVEL.
AND THEY SAW HIM DRIVE
ON TO A PROPERTY.
IT WAS JUST A PROPERTY
THAT HAS SMALL POND ON IT,
HAD A TRAILER ON IT AT THE
END OF THE LONG DRIVEWAY.
WE DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
WAS INSIDE OF THERE.
BUT WE KNEW THAT
SINCE HE DID VISIT IT,
WE BELIEVED THAT TO BE
A POSSIBLE LOCATION
FOR WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO SUZETTE TROUTEN.
(camera shutter click)
THERE WAS A FAIRLY
SIGNIFICANT PERIOD OF TIME
WHERE WE HAD OUR SUSPICIONS
AND WE HAD REAL STRONG
BELIEFS ABOUT WHAT WAS GOING
ON BUT WE COULDN'T PROVE IT.
BUT IN THE INTERIM WE HAD TO
BUILD OUR CASE AND MAKE SURE
THAT HE DIDN'T KILL ANYBODY
WHILE WE WERE WATCHING HIM.
SOME FEEL THE STRONGEST
LEADS TO DATE
REST IN THE VARIOUS
LETTERS RECEIVED BY
SUZETTE'S FAMILY, THE
ONES SUPPOSEDLY WRITTEN
BY THEIR MISSING DAUGHTER.
(camera shutter click)
TO, TO TRACE MAIL
LETTER CORRESPONDENCE
YOU TAKE A LOOK AT THE,
THE POSTMARK, YOU KNOW ON,
ON THE ENVELOPE. THAT'S
GOING TO TELL YOU THE CITY
AND THE STATE
OF ORIGIN.
THERE'S ALSO SOME CODES
IN THERE THAT'LL HELP YOU
IDENTIFY, YOU KNOW, THE
ORIGINATING POST BOX
OR THE ORIGINAL
POST OFFICE.
CURIOUSLY, THE POSTMARKS
ALL CORRESPOND
TO THE DISTANT LOCATIONS
SUZETTE CLAIMS TO BE IN.
AT THE VERY LEAST, SOMEONE
IS DROPPING THEM OFF
AT POST OFFICES A LONG WAY
FROM JOHNSON COUNTY, KANSAS.
(Paul) THE TRICK WAS
FIGURING OUT WHERE
THEY WERE COMING FROM.
IT ISN'T LONG, HOWEVER,
BEFORE DETECTIVES MAKE
A STRIKING BREAKTHROUGH
REGARDING SUZETTE'S
SUSPICIOUS E-MAILS. THEY
PIECE TOGETHER BILLS
IN THE TRASH THAT
PROVIDE DETAILS ABOUT
JOHN ROBINSON'S INTERNET
SERVICE PROVIDER.
POLICE REALIZE THAT
AS OF MARCH 1st,
THE VERY DAY SUZETTE'S
REGULAR COMMUNICATION
DROPPED OFF, ALL NEW E-MAILS
ALLEGEDLY FROM HER ACTUALLY
EMANATED FROM JOHN
ROBINSON'S ACCOUNT AT
HIS RESIDENCE.
(David) WE KNEW THAT
JOHN WAS ACCESSING
SUZETTE'S INTERNET ACCOUNT
FROM HIS RESIDENCE.
JOHN ROBINSON WAS
THE ONE SENDING
THESE FICTITIOUS E-MAILS.
ROBINSON'S ONLINE ACTIVITY
ALSO REVEALS ACCESS
TO INTERNET SITES
RELATED TO BDSM,
A LONG-STANDING
FETISH OF HIS,
WHERE HE OCCASIONALLY USES
THE NICKNAME MIDWEST-MASTER.
(Brad) IT WAS QUITE A SHOCK
TO US OBVIOUSLY TO FIND OUT
ABOUT THESE WEBSITES.
IT'S A MASTER, SLAVE,
BONDAGE AND
DISCIPLINE SEX ACTS.
AND IT INVOLVES PROPS,
AND CONTRACTS AND
SEXUAL ACTIVITY.
POLICE LEARN THAT MISSING
SUZETTE TROUTEN
WAS ALSO INTERESTED IN
THE BDSM LIFESTYLE.
POLICE WONDER IF
HER DISAPPEARANCE
MAY SOMEHOW BE RELATED
TO A CRIMINAL STRAIN
OF THIS ONLINE SUBCULTURE.
(David) THERE WERE
DISCUSSIONS ABOUT SEX SLAVES
AND ABOUT PEOPLE BEING
KIDNAPPED AND TAKEN INTO SEX
SLAVERY AND IN THE BACK OF
OUR MINDS WE'RE WONDERING,
OKAY, IS THAT SOMETHING
WE'RE INTO HERE?
ARE WE INTO, YOU KNOW,
A SEX SLAVE RING?
COULD ANYONE ELSE BE
INVOLVED IN, YOU KNOW,
HARBORING SUZETTE?
IN, IN KIDNAPPING, IN, IN
CHASING HER AWAY OR TAKING,
CARRYING HER AWAY TO BE
A SEX SLAVE SOMEWHERE?
CERTAINLY WITH THE B.D.S.M.
ASPECTS OF IT THAT, THAT
WAS A REAL POSSIBILITY.
THE FACT THAT ROBINSON
HAS CLEARLY ACCESSED
SUZETTE TROUTEN'S E-MAIL
ACCOUNT COULD PROVIDE
POLICE WITH A SEARCH
WARRANT FOR HIS HOME,
BUT NOT FOR HIS STORAGE
LOCKERS OR HIS FARM,
THE MOST LIKELY PLACES TO
HIDE INCRIMINATING EVIDENCE.
(David) WHEN YOU REACH
A POINT TO, YOU KNOW,
YOU STILL DON'T KNOW FOR
SURE IF SUZETTE'S ALIVE,
SURE WHO MAY OR MAY NOT BE
INVOLVED, YOU REACH A POINT
WHERE TO TRY TO IDENTIFY
CO-CONSPIRATORS, YOU MONITOR
TELEPHONE CONVERSATIONS.
WITHIN DAYS, THERE IS A
SUDDEN NEW DEVELOPMENT.
POLICE TRACKING NUMBERS
DIALLED FROM ROBINSON'S CELL
PHONE REALIZE HE IS
CONTACTING WOMEN LIVING
IN DIFFERENT STATES AND
ARRANGING TRAVEL PLANS
TO KANSAS. THROUGH
HIS ONLINE PERSONA,
IT APPEARS JOHN ROBINSON,
A.K.A. MIDWEST-MASTER,
IS ABOUT TO BRING MORE
WOMEN INTO TOWN.
(Paul) HE WOULD CONTACT
THEM TRY TO SEE IF THEY WERE
INTERESTED IN
COMING DOWN HERE.
HE HELD HIMSELF OUT AS
SOME KIND OF A MASTER,
IF YOU WILL, IN BONDAGE AND
DISCIPLINE AND WOULD OFFER
TO TRAIN THESE WOMEN AND
ASK THEM TO BE HIS SLAVE.
HIS ONLINE TACTICS BEAR
A STRONG SIMILARITY
TO THOSE THAT BROUGHT
SUZETTE TROUTEN TO KANSAS
A FEW MONTHS EARLIER.
(Paul) BUT HE WOULD ADD A
FLAVOUR TO THAT BY TELLING
THEM THAT HE WAS A VERY,
VERY RICH EITHER DIVORCED
OR WIDOWED BUSINESSMAN THAT
HAD ALL THESE CONNECTIONS
AND THAT HE WOULD SET
THEM UP WITH A JOB HERE
AND TAKE CARE OF THEM.
IN THE DAYS AHEAD, POLICE
WILL GET THEIR CLOSEST
LOOK YET AT THE
UNDERGROUND WORLD OF BDSM.
AND MEET A WOMAN WHO
BARELY ESCAPED BECOMING
A MISSING PERSON HERSELF.
(♪)
(Narrator)
APRIL 2000.
IN KANSAS, POLICE ARE
INVESTIGATING THE CASE
OF MISSING
SUZETTE TROUTEN,
A 25-YEAR-OLD WOMAN
FROM MICHIGAN.
PRIME SUSPECT IS LOCAL
RESIDENT JOHN ROBINSON,
HEAVILY INVOLVED IN THE
BONDAGE AND S & M SUBCULTURE.
POLICE WATCH AS HE
ACTIVELY SETS UP
SEXUALLY RELATED MEETINGS
WITH NEW ACQUAINTANCES
FROM OUT OF TOWN.
APRIL 24th.
A YOUNG WOMAN NAMED
VICKIE FROM TEXAS
ARRIVES IN OVERLAND PARK,
KANSAS AND CHECKS INTO
A LOCAL MOTEL ROOM
RESERVED BY ROBINSON.
(camera shutter click)
VICKIE WAS ANOTHER
WOMAN THAT, YOU KNOW,
HE WAS - HE HAD MET ONLINE.
VICKIE HAD COME IN TO BE
PART OF THE B.D.S.M.
LIFESTYLE WITH HIM.
SHE HAD, I GUESS WHAT WE
REFER TO AS HER OWN BAG
OF TRICKS. YOU KNOW,
B.D.S.M. INVOLVES DIFFERENT
TOYS, TOOLS -
THINGS LIKE THAT.
SHE HAD BROUGHT SOME
OF THAT ALONG WITH HER.
POLICE WATCH AS JOHN
ROBINSON ARRIVES
AT THE MOTEL AND HEADS
UP TO THE ROOM.
SOON AFTER, VICKIE
APPROACHES THE FRONT DESK
CLERK AND ASKS IF SHE CAN
HAVE A PHOTOCOPY MADE.
THE CLERK, AWARE OF THE
POLICE SURVEILLANCE,
MAKES AN EXTRA COPY OF THE
DOCUMENT AND HANDS IT OVER
TO UNDERCOVER OFFICERS
ON THE PREMISES.
IT TURNS OUT TO BE A
DETAILED SLAVE / MASTER
CONTRACT, POPULAR
IN BDSM CIRCLES.
(♪)
(camera shutter click)
IN THE B.D.S.M.
WORLD OFTEN TIMES
THESE PEOPLE WOULD COME
UP WITH THESE ELABORATE
CONTRACTS ABOUT THE
CONDITIONS OF THE CONTRACT
TO BE SOMEBODY'S SLAVE
AND SOMEBODY'S MASTER,
AND OF COURSE JOHN ROBINSON
BEING THE CONTROL FREAK
THAT HE IS WAS
ALWAYS THE MASTER.
A LOT OF THESE PEOPLE THAT
ARE IN TO BDSM ARE REALLY
INTO THE WHOLE SCENE SETTING
IF YOU WILL OF SOMEBODY
IN CONTROL OR SOMEBODY
BEING DOMINATED I THINK
A LOT OF THE PEOPLE KINDA GOT
OFF JUST ON THE CONTRACTS.
HOPING TO ENSURE VICKIE'S
SAFETY WITHOUT GIVING UP
THEIR COVER, OFFICERS
QUIETLY TAKE UP POSITIONS
IN ADJACENT ROOMS.
(camera shutter click)
(Brad) THE OFFICERS THAT
WERE ON THE SCENE HAD TO
MAKE DECISIONS ABOUT THIS
PERSON THAT HE'S MEETING,
ISN'T OUR MISSING GIRL, BUT
WE ALSO NEED TO FIND THIS
MISSING GIRL AND IS THIS
WOMAN WHO'S MEETING HIM SAFE,
CAN WE ENSURE HER SAFETY
IN THAT ROOM WITH HIM?
OFFICERS HEAR
FREQUENT NOISE,
BUT THEY HAVE TO DISTINGUISH
BETWEEN THE NORMAL VIOLENCE
THAT OFTEN GOES ALONG
WITH BDSM ACTIVITIES
AND A POTENTIAL
REAL THREAT.
(Paul) YOU'D HAVE OFFICERS
IN THE NEXT ROOM LISTENING
AND SOMETIMES THERE'D
BE HITTING AND A LOT
OF HOLLERING GOING ON WE'RE
TRYING TO DISCERN WHETHER
OR NOT THAT'S CONSENSUAL
PLAY KINDA STUFF
OR IF HE'S REALLY
HURTING THESE WOMEN.
AND SO THERE WERE A LOT OF
DIFFICULTIES INVOLVED IN
THAT INVESTIGATION.
AFTER THREE DAYS, VICKIE,
APPARENTLY UNHARMED,
HEADS HOME FOR TEXAS.
OTHER WOMEN SOON
TAKE HER PLACE.
(Paul) HE'D BE GOING TO
HOTELS MEETING WITH WOMEN,
E-MAILING PEOPLE,
SO ON SO FORTH,
AND AS SOON AS HE WOULD GET,
AS SOON AS HIS WIFE WOULD
GET HOME AT ABOUT FIVE IN
THE AFTERNOON ROBINSON WOULD
COME HOME AND HE'D BE
HUSBAND AND A GRANDPA
TO HIS GRANDKIDS AND JUST
A NORMAL ACTING GUY
EXCEPT FOR A 9-5
DURING THE WORK DAYS.
POLICE SURVEILLANCE
IS CONSTANT,
BUT ON ONE BRIEF OCCASION,
ROBINSON SLIPS AWAY WHILE
DRIVING ACROSS TOWN.
(camera shutter click)
WE LOST SIGHT OF HIM,
WE, WE COULDN'T PICK HIM
BACK UP AGAIN AND WE
EVENTUALLY FOUND HIM BACK
AT HIS RESIDENCE.
ONLY LATER, WHILE ROUTINELY
REVIEWING TAPES
BACK AT THE STATION,
ARE THEY ABLE TO
FILL IN THE MISSING GAP.
(Dan) WE WERE ABLE TO TELL
BY VIEWING SOME SURVEILLANCE
FOOTAGE AT A STORAGE LOCKER
THAT DURING THAT TIME FRAME
HE HAD PAID VISIT TO
THAT STORAGE LOCKER.
AND WE JUST HAPPENED TO SEE
HIM WALK IN TO THE STORAGE
LOCKER HOLDING A BAG.
IT JUST LOOKED LIKE A
BLACK SOFT-SIDED BAG,
BRIEFCASE SIZE MAYBE A
LITTLE THICKER THAN THAT.
AND WHEN HE WALKED OUT OF
THE STORAGE LOCKER HE DID
NOT HAVE IT WITH HIM.
WHILE SOME BELIEVE THE BLACK
BAG POSSIBLY CONTAINS
SEX TOYS, OTHERS SPECULATE
IT MAY ALSO CONTAIN
POTENTIAL MURDER WEAPONS.
(Paul) THERE WAS ALMOST
DAILY DEBATE ON WHEN
TO ARREST HIM, BUT YOU HAVE
TO UNDERSTAND, YOU KNOW,
IT'S EASY TO
ARREST SOMEBODY,
BUT WHEN YOU ARREST SOMEBODY
YOU NEED TO BE ABLE TO HAVE
A CASE THAT YOU
CAN PROVE IN COURT.
MAY 19, 2000.
A WOMAN NAMED JEANNA
ARRIVES IN TOWN TO
MEET WITH ROBINSON.
WITHIN HOURS, THERE APPEARS
TO BE A FALLING OUT.
(David) JOHN LEAVES JEANNA
AND JEANNA BEGINS TO BECOME
CONCERNED ABOUT
THE CIRCUMSTANCES
THAT SHE'S PLACED
HERSELF IN.
IN A STRIKING DEVELOPMENT,
JEANNA APPROACHES
THE FRONT DESK
OF THE HOTEL.
AFTER SPEAKING
WITH THE STAFF,
SHE ASKS THEM TO
PHONE THE POLICE.
THE CALL IS PROMPTLY ROUTED
TO OFFICERS IN CHARGE
OF THE SURVEILLANCE.
JEANNA TELLS POLICE SHE IS
WORRIED BECAUSE THE MAN
SHE CAME TO TOWN TO MEET HAD
SEXUALLY ASSAULTED HER
AND USED A FALSE NAME,
SOMETHING SHE DISCOVERED
FROM THE HOTEL STAFF.
THE NAME HE ORIGINALLY
GAVE HER IS JIM TURNER;
THE SAME NAME ROBINSON GAVE
SUZETTE TROUTEN'S FAMILY
TO IDENTIFY THE MYSTERY
MAN SHE HAD APPARENTLY
RUN OFF WITH. AS POLICE
HAVE LONG SUSPECTED,
JIM TURNER AND JOHN ROBINSON
ARE ONE AND THE SAME PERSON.
NOT LONG AFTER POLICE MOVE
JEANNA TO A SAFE LOCATION,
THE WOMAN KNOWN AS VICKIE
ALSO CONTACTS THEM.
SHE REPORTS THAT JOHN
ROBINSON HAS STOLEN
HER SEX TOYS AND REFUSES
TO RETURN THEM.
WITHIN A MATTER OF DAYS, TWO
WOMEN HAVE PROVIDED POLICE
WITH ALL THE PROBABLE CAUSE
THEY NEED TO MOVE IN
AND SEARCH ROBINSON'S
VARIOUS PROPERTIES.
(Paul) THEY WENT TO THE
POLICE INDEPENDENTLY
OF EACH OTHER AND
REPORTED HIM FOR THEFT
AND AGGRAVATED
SEXUAL BATTERY,
WHICH WAS A BIG, BIG
BREAK IN THE CASE FOR US,
JUST AT A TIME WHEN
WE NEEDED IT THE MOST.
JUNE 1, 2000. POLICE
TAKE UP POSITIONS
AROUND JOHN ROBINSON'S
MOBILE HOME COMMUNITY.
SHORTLY AFTER HIS WIFE
LEAVES FOR THE DAY,
THEY DECIDE TO
MAKE THEIR MOVE.
(Brad) HE WAS CONTACTED AT
HIS MOBILE HOME THAT MORNING
AND TWO DETECTIVES WENT
UP AND TALKED TO HIM.
AND, AND THEY ACTUALLY
WENT IN THE TRAILER
AND HE - THEY EVENTUALLY GOT
AROUND TO THE, YOU KNOW,
TELLING HIM THEY NEEDED
TO TALK TO HIM ABOUT SOME
CRIMES AND HE, THEY TOLD HIM
THESE, WHAT THE CRIMES WERE,
WHAT HE WAS GOING
TO BE ARRESTED FOR.
THE CHARGES RELATE TO
JEANNA AND VICKIE
AND INCLUDE AGGRAVATED
SEXUAL BATTERY AND THEFT.
ROBINSON SEEMS EMBARRASSED
AND PLAYS DOWN
THE INCIDENTS, BUT THE
MOOD IN THE ROOM CHANGES
WHEN THE DETECTIVES BRING UP
THE CASES OF THE FOUR
MISSING WOMEN - LISA
STASI, PAULA GODFREY,
CATHERINE CLAMPITT
AND SUZETTE TROUTEN.
(Dan) WHEN THOSE NAMES WERE
MENTIONED YOU COULD TELL
THAT JOHN ROBINSON KNEW
EXACTLY WHAT WAS COMING
HIS WAY. HE LOST THE
COLORATION IN HIS FACE.
HE APPEARED TO
BE SPEECHLESS
AND HE HAD A LOOK OF GREAT
CONCERN ON HIS FACE.
ROBINSON IS HANDCUFFED
AND TAKEN TO THE STATION.
HOPING TO GET A CONFESSION,
POLICE PLACE HIM IN
AN INTERROGATION ROOM
FILLED WITH PHOTOS
RELATED TO THEIR
INVESTIGATION.
(David) THE, THE ROOM WAS
SET UP IN THE MANNER
THAT EVERYWHERE YOU LOOKED,
YOU SAW JOHN ROBINSON'S
LIFE RIGHT THERE, YOU KNOW,
AS WE KNEW IT FROM
OUR CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION.
HE WOULD KNOW
WITHOUT ANY DOUBT,
BEYOND ANY DOUBT AT ALL,
THAT THE GIG WAS UP,
THAT HE'S, YOU
KNOW, HE'S HAD,
THAT THERE WERE
NO SECRETS.
AFTER TAKING IT ALL IN,
ROBINSON ASKS FOR A LAWYER.
WITHOUT A CONFESSION,
POLICE NEED TO TURN UP
CONCRETE EVIDENCE
ON ROBINSON'S PROPERTIES.
THE TRUTH, IT TURNS OUT,
IS FAR WORSE THEN
THEY EVER IMAGINED.
(♪)
(Narrator)
JUNE 1, 2000.
POLICE IN KANSAS HAVE
ARRESTED LOCAL RESIDENT
JOHN ROBINSON.
ALTHOUGH HE DENIES
ANY WRONGDOING,
HE IS THE PRIME SUSPECT
IN THE DISAPPEARANCE
OF SUZETTE TROUTEN
AND THREE WOMEN
FROM THE 1980s.
HOPING TO FINALLY
GET THE ANSWERS
THEY'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR,
POLICE EXECUTE SEARCH
WARRANTS ON HIS PROPERTIES,
STARTING WITH THE MOBILE
HOME HE LIVES IN
WITH HIS WIFE.
(camera shutter click)
HE DID USE SEVERAL
IDENTITIES WHEN HE WAS
SPEAKING TO THESE WOMEN. IN
FACT, WE FOUND PAPERWORK
IN HIS RESIDENCE TO SHOW
THAT HE WAS PORTRAYING
PEOPLE INVOLVED WITH
THE D.E.A., C.I.A.
AND HE HAD PAPERWORK WHERE
HE COULD PHOTOCOPY
AND TYPE UP HIS NAME AND,
AND MAKE PEOPLE BELIEVE
THAT HE WAS ACTUALLY PART
OF THOSE ORGANIZATIONS.
OTHER DETAILS OF
ROBINSON'S SECRET LIFE
TURN UP IN THE STORAGE
LOCKER HE KEEPS
IN AN ADJACENT CITY.
INSIDE, POLICE FIND
THE BLACK DUFFLE BAG
HE OFTEN CARRIED
AROUND WITH HIM.
WHILE IT HOLDS
NOTHING BUT SEX TOYS,
OTHER NEARBY CASES ARE
FAR MORE INCRIMINATING.
(camera shutter click)
WE FOUND IN
THAT STORAGE LOCKER
LITERALLY A TREASURE
TROVE OF EVIDENCE.
SOME OF MISSING SUZETTE
TROUTEN'S PERSONAL EFFECTS
TURN UP,
INCLUDING HER I.D.
POLICE ALSO FIND ENVELOPES
ADDRESSED TO HER FAMILY
AND SHEETS OF PAPER,
BLANK EXCEPT FOR
SUZETTE'S SIGNATURE,
PRE-SIGNED AT THE BOTTOM.
EVEN MORE DISTURBING,
POLICE FIND I.D.
BELONGING TO OTHER WOMEN,
CURRENTLY UNKNOWN
TO THE INVESTIGATION.
ALTHOUGH POLICE NOW HAVE
HARD EVIDENCE CONNECTING
JOHN ROBINSON TO
SUZETTE'S POSSESSIONS,
THEY STILL HAVE NO IDEA
OF HER WHEREABOUTS.
THE FOLLOWING DAY, A LARGE
TEAM OF INVESTIGATORS
MOVES IN ON HIS
RURAL FARM.
(camera shutter click)
WE HAD A SEARCH
WARRANT FOR THE PROPERTY.
WE HAD A REALLY GOOD SIZE
FORCE OF DETECTIVES THERE.
WE'RE MAKING OUR WAY ACROSS
THIS PROPERTY USING SEARCH
PATTERNS LOOKING FOR BODIES.
(Dan) I WAS IN CHARGE
OF FILMING THE SITE,
VIDEOTAPING THE PROCESS.
THE TERRAIN WAS
KIND OF HILLY.
SO IT TOOK US
QUITE AWHILE.
(Brad) WE LOOKED ALL
THROUGH THIS PROPERTY,
WE WERE JUST COMBING
ACROSS THE PROPERTY
AND SERGEANT ROTH HAD
DISCOVERED THESE BARRELS.
(camera shutter click)
SERGEANT ROTH
ROLLED THE FIRST ONE OUT
AND WHEN WE STOOD IT BACK -
I CAN REMEMBER TO THIS DAY -
THERE WAS A, A THIN
LINE OF, OF RED THAT,
THAT RAN DOWN
FROM THE, THE LIP.
(Brad) FLIES FROM NOWHERE
JUST APPEARED AND LANDED
ON THIS RED LIQUID. YOU
KNOW, WE CLEARLY KNEW
THEN THAT WE HAD
SOMETHING VERY IMPORTANT
IN THAT BARREL.
AN OFFICER FROM THE CRIME
LAB IS CALLED OVER
TO REMOVE THE LID.
INSIDE, POLICE FIND
DECOMPOSING HUMAN REMAINS.
(Brad) AND WE ALL JUST KIND
OF STOOD THERE FOR A MINUTE.
YOU KNOW IT WAS
KIND OF A SHOCK.
WE THINK THAT'S HER.
BUT IT'S SOMEONE.
IT'S A DEAD BODY
WE KNOW THAT.
WHETHER IT'S SUZETTE OR
NOT - WE DIDN'T KNOW,
BUT WE CLEARLY KNEW
THEN, THIS IS, WE'RE ON -
THIS IS IT.
MOMENTS LATER, POLICE
FIND ANOTHER BODY INSIDE
A SECOND BARREL.
TWO DAYS LATER,
AT JOHN ROBINSON'S STORAGE
LOCKER IN MISSOURI,
ACROSS
THE STATE LINE,
ANOTHER THREE BODIES
ARE RECOVERED,
ALSO SEALED UP IN BARRELS.
NEWS OF THE GRIM DISCOVERIES
SPREADS QUICKLY
TO THE LOCAL MEDIA.
(camera shutter click)
(Gerald) THERE WAS A LOT OF
GOSSIP AMONG THE MEDIA AND,
AND THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AGENTS.
THIS IS, THIS IS GETTING
BIGGER AND BIGGER EACH,
EACH DAY. BUT WHEN THEY
WENT TO THE SCENE,
AND BASICALLY
FOUND THE BARRELS,
I MEAN YOU TALK ABOUT A
MEDIA FRENZY, IT WAS THERE.
I MEAN, NO ONE EXPECTED
BODIES ROTTING IN BARRELS.
THEN YOU GO ACROSS THE STATE
LINE YOU FIND THREE MORE,
THEN IT'S YOU KNOW THEY
HERE IN KANSAS CITY JOHNSON
COUNTY, THIS IS HAPPENING?
OVER THE NEXT
SEVERAL DAYS
FORENSIC EXPERTS COMPILE
FURTHER EVIDENCE
TYING JOHN ROBINSON
TO THE CRIME SCENES.
(camera shutter click)
I ACTUALLY SPENT FOUR
DAYS AT THE CRIME SCENE
AND MY PRIMARY ROLE
WAS TO PROCESS THE CRIME
SCENE FOR THE DEVELOPMENT
OF LATENT PRINTS.
THERE WERE A TOTAL OF ELEVEN
LATENT PRINT CARDS THAT WERE
LIFTED AT THE SCENE, ALL
THE LATENTS OF VALUE DID
IDENTIFY TO JOHN ROBINSON.
AT THE SAME TIME, DENTAL
RECORDS HELP PUT NAMES
ON THE VICTIMS. ONE
OF THE WOMEN FOUND
ON JOHN ROBINSON'S
FARM IS POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED AS
MISSING SUZETTE TROUTEN.
THE OTHER IS CONFIRMED TO
BE ONE IZABELA LEWICKA,
A 21-YEAR-OLD FROM INDIANA
WHO WAS LAST SEEN IN 1999.
THE THREE BODIES IN MISSOURI
ARE IDENTIFIED AS BEVERLY
BONNER, SHEILA FAITH, AND
SHEILA'S DAUGHTER DEBBIE
FAITH, NONE OF WHOM WERE
EVER REPORTED MISSING
OR ASSOCIATED IN THE
EARLIER INVESTIGATION
INTO JOHN ROBINSON.
(Paul) ONE OF HIS PATTERNS
WAS TO PICK UP WOMEN
AND HOOK UP WITH WOMEN
THAT IN MANY,
MANY WAYS WERE DESPERATE.
HE GOT HIS HOOKS IN THEM BY
BASICALLY PROMISING THEM
THAT HE WAS GONNA
HELP THEM MAKE IT,
HE WAS GONNA GET
'EM A GOOD JOB,
THEM JOB TRAINING,
THAT KIND OF A THING.
AND, UM, THEY WOULD TELL
FRIENDS TYPICALLY OR FAMILY
THAT THEY WERE GETTING
READY TO GO OUT OF TOWN,
THEY'D NEVER BE SEEN AGAIN.
(David) HE WOULD CONVINCE
THEM TO SIGN BLANK LETTERS.
SO THEY DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU KNOW WHAT HE HAD
GOING IN HIS MIND.
THEY DIDN'T REALIZE THAT
THEY WERE YOU KNOW,
HELPING HIM MAKE
THEM DISAPPEAR.
BUT THAT IS WHAT
THEY WERE DOING.
WHILE THE BODIES OF MISSING
WOMEN CATHERINE CLAMPITT,
PAULA GODFREY AND LISA STASI
DON'T TURN UP IN SEARCHES
OF ROBINSON'S PROPERTY,
FURTHER INVESTIGATION
MAKES A STARTLING
DISCOVERY.
JOHN ROBINSON'S OWN BROTHER
ADOPTED LISA STASI'S
DAUGHTER TIFFANY,
ONLY FIVE MONTHS OLD
WHEN SHE WENT MISSING
WITH HER MOTHER.
BY FORGING ADOPTION PAPERS
AND CHARGING HIS BROTHER
THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS FOR
WHAT HE THOUGHT WAS
A LEGITIMATE ADOPTION,
ROBINSON MAY HAVE BEEN
MOTIVATED BY NOTHING
MORE THAN THE CHANCE
OF MAKING A SMALL PROFIT.
(Paul) THERE ARE
PICTURES THAT EVENING
AND JOHN ROBINSON'S SITTING
THERE WITH THE FAMILY
BOUNCING LISA STASI'S
YOUNG BABY ON HIS KNEE,
GRINNING LIKE A CHESHIRE
CAT IN THERE AND WE ALWAYS
THEORIZED THAT THAT WAS
PROBABLY JUST LITERALLY
HOURS AFTER HE HAD
KILLED LISA STASI,
THAT BABY'S MOTHER.
(Paul) PEOPLE LIKE
ROBINSON ARE SOCIOPATHS:
SOMEBODY WHO REALLY LACKS THE
CAPACITY TO FEEL REAL EMOTION.
AND HE LITERALLY WAS
LIVING A DOUBLE LIFE.
YOU KNOW, ON THE ONE
HAND HE WAS A HUSBAND
AND A GRANDFATHER AND ON
THE OTHER HAND HE WAS A,
A SERIAL KILLER.
(Brad) I DON'T KNOW WHAT
MAKES A GUY LIKE THAT TICK.
WHY HE DID THE EVIL
THINGS THAT HE DID?
HE JUST DEVELOPED
INTO THIS PERSON
THAT COULD KILL PEOPLE
WITHOUT REMORSE.
IN OCTOBER OF 2002,
JOHN ROBINSON STANDS
TRIAL IN KANSAS,
CHARGED WITH CAPITAL
MURDER IN THE CASES
OF SUZETTE TROUTEN
AND IZABELA LEWICKA.
HE IS ALSO CHARGED WITH
FIRST-DEGREE MURDER
IN THE CASE OF LISA STASI,
WHOSE BODY WAS NEVER FOUND.
OUTSTANDING CHARGES IN
MISSOURI INVOLVE THE MURDERS
OF BEVERLY BONNER, AND
SHEILA AND DEBBIE FAITH.
WITH ROBINSON DUBBED THE
WORLD'S FIRST CYBER-KILLER,
AND OFTEN REFERRED TO AS
SLAVE MASTER IN THE PRESS,
THE ENTIRE STATE IS GRIPPED
BY THE PROCEEDINGS.
(Gerald) YOU KNOW, JOHNSON
COUNTY AT MOST MAYBE HAVE
LIKE ONE OR TWO
MURDERS A YEAR.
YOU KNOW, SOMETHING LIKE
THIS WHERE BODIES
ARE BEING IN BARRELS.
THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN IN
OUR NECK OF THE WOODS.
FACING A MOUNTAIN
OF EVIDENCE,
ROBINSON IS EVENTUALLY FOUND
GUILTY ON ALL CHARGES
AND SENTENCED TO DEATH.
ALTHOUGH THE BODIES
OF LISA STASI,
CATHERINE CLAMPITT AND PAULA
GODFREY WERE NEVER LOCATED,
THE FACT THAT ROBINSON WILL
PAY THE ULTIMATE PRICE FOR
HIS CRIMES PROVIDES AT LEAST
SOME COMFORT TO THE FAMILIES
OF THE MANY VICTIMS.
(Dan) I FELT RELIEVED.
THAT ALL THE WORK THAT
WE HAD WENT THROUGH,
THAT IT CAME DOWN TO THAT.
RELIEVED FOR THE FAMILIES,
KNOWING THAT THEY COULD GAIN
SOME SORT OF CLOSURE.
TODAY, JOHN ROBINSON REMAINS
ON DEATH ROW IN KANSAS,
AWAITING HIS PUNISHMENT.
SADLY, THE LEGACY OF
HIS LIFE OF VIOLENCE
WILL LIVE ON LONG
AFTER HE IS GONE.
(camera shutter click)
(Stephen) THE NUMBER OF
LIVES THAT, YOU KNOW,
ROBINSON HAS DESTROYED
IS, IS UNBELIEVABLE.
YOU KNOW, OBVIOUSLY THE
VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES,
HE'S IMPACTED HUNDREDS OF
OTHER PEOPLE JUST BY HIS,
HIS THEFTS AND
CRIMES AND LIES.
(Paul) I THINK THE MORAL
OF THE STORY IS HOW
DANGEROUS THE
INTERNET CAN BE.
THE INTERNET BRINGS US
A LOT OF GOOD THINGS,
BUT THERE IS A DEFINITE
DARK SIDE TO THAT,
THAT EXHIBITED ITSELF IN
THIS CASE BY WHAT HAPPENED
TO THESE WOMEN.
AND GUYS LIKE JOHN ROBINSON
THAT SORTA COME OUT OF
NOWHERE AND PROMISE
THE WORLD TO PEOPLE,
THERE'S AN ULTERIOR MOTIVE
AND OFTEN TIMES THERE'S
A REAL DARK SIDE TO
WHAT'S GOING ON,
AND HE WAS AN EXPERT AT
OFFERING HOPE TO THE HOPELESS.
AND LURED 'EM IN JUST LIKE
A SPIDER INTO, YOU KNOW,
LURING A MOTH TO A WEB
AND ONCE THEY GOT HERE,
FOR A LOT OF THEM,
THAT WAS THE END.