- Inside this garage lurks
the mind of a mad scientist.
(maniacal laughter)
He's one part inventor,
one part toy builder.
He's gonna show of some of
his amazing contraptions
that you can make at home.
(crash)
(shouting)
Forget parking a car,
because this garage
is made for do it yourself fun
right now on DIY Sci.
(quirky music)
I'm Steve Spangler and
I love blowing stuff up
with the power of science.
I'm gonna show you how
you can do it yourself.
(crashing)
You can harness the
power of science
in your own home with DIY Sci.
Yeah!
(liquid spraying)
(paper tearing)
Welcome to DIY Sci;
I'm Steve Spangler.
And you know this
guy, he's Bruce Yeany!
He won our DIY Sci contest
for best science video!
(tongue emulating drumroll)
The winner of the DIY Sci
contest is Bruce Yeany!
(adventurous music)
Bruce is a retired
science teacher,
and he's also a
science inventor.
And this is his amazing
science workshop.
As it turns out, we're both
a bunch of garage geeks.
We love puttering
around in the garage
building stuff
for the workbench.
Today Bruce is gonna show us
some of the amazing
DIY Sci gadgets
that he's built in his garage,
like this amazing ping
pong ball launcher.
(crashing)
Looks like you went
to the hardware store.
You got some pipes, some
PVC that I recognize.
There's some other
pieces over here
that are kind of unusual.
- [Bruce] This here
is a vacuum pump.
- So by vacuum pump you
mean this doesn't pump air
into the pipe, it pulls
the air out of the pipe.
And it looks like
you've taken a balloon
like this mylar balloon, and
you've cut the balloon up
and you stretched it
over this end here
and clamped it in place.
So this is sealed.
- We have that end sealed.
- And this end is
sealed as well.
- [Bruce] We have a
ping pong ball in here.
And that's what's going
to be our projectile.
- Yes.
So you're gonna pull
all the air out of here
but the real action comes
when you poke it here.
- Air is gonna rush in.
That's 26 pounds of
pressure pushing in
that ping pong ball through
the tube with no resistance.
And we're gonna see what
happens to this can over here.
- [Steve] How fast will
it come out the end?
- We're looking at maybe
400, 500 miles and hour.
- No kidding.
- All right.
- So, safety glasses on.
(upbeat music)
(machine whirring)
We have a gauge here that's
gonna tell us when to stop.
And that looks about right.
- Okay, so stop.
You're telling me that all
the air is out of that pipe.
And so all you're going to
do for this destructive force
to happen is to simply
poke the little end there.
And that ping pong ball's
gonna go hurling this way.
- That's what's gonna happen.
- [Steve] All right, here we go!
- [Both] Ready?
- Three, two, one.
(crashing)
Wow, look at this!
Oh my gosh, would
you look at this?
You weren't kidding.
That is a ping pong ball.
Not only, it just destroys it
at about 400 miles an hour.
(static and crashing)
- It's moving so fast it
just goes right through it.
(repeated crashing)
(gagging)
- Excuse me.
(crashing)
- Everybody watching
the show is saying
'Okay, but I can't
do that at home.
'I don't have a vacuum pump.'
I get that.
We can do something
else where we could
actually put air into the pipe
and shoot the ping pong
ball down this way.
Again, this is pretty
heavy duty PVC.
- Right, this is
rated at 200 PSI.
- And what you did was
you put a hole here.
You put a tire
valve, is that right?
- [Bruce] Right.
- [Steve] Here.
That's why you're
using this big pipe.
So you could get it in
there, glue it in place.
You've got a gauge
on this as well
so you really can see
how much is inside, and--
- [Bruce] That's our gate valve.
That's when it's sealed.
- [Steve] Everything here is
for plumbing, and you're using
none of it for plumbing, right?
- [Bruce] Well, who knows what
they're actually intended for.
- [Steve] That's exactly right.
- [Bruce] That's a
matter of opinion.
- [Steve] Yeah, safety glasses
on, let's pressurize this.
So we'll seal it up
here, and now you're just
gonna use a bicycle
pump to fill it up.
- [Bruce] Here we go.
(air pumping)
- [Steve] All right,
it's pressurized.
- [Bruce] Okay, ready?
- [Steve] We'll take that off.
- [Bruce] We'll take that off.
- [Steve] Good.
So the ping pong ball
goes into the end.
And let's load it up.
Got it, okay.
Keep it in place because it's
time to pile up the cans.
(upbeat drumbeat)
- [Bruce] Looks good.
All right, here we go.
- [Steve] I'm gonna aim
it here, ready: three.
- [Both] Two, one.
(cans clattering)
- I think that's perfect.
I can't even imagine
what it would be
if you had something larger.
(quirky music)
Now this is what happens when
you super size an air canon.
Bruce, you made this one
out of this amazingly
heavy duty PVC; this is
not the normal stuff.
- Nah, this is the
heavy duty stuff.
This is rated at 220 PSI.
And we're gonna be
putting in 90 PSI.
So we have a pretty
good safety margin.
- [Steve] Okay, but still the
joints have to be perfectly--
- [Bruce] They have
to be perfect, yes.
- [Steve] Mounted and glued
and everything else, and so.
Not a thing to try
at home, this is.
We're gonna leave this
one for us, fair enough?
All right so, I got a plan.
Look at this.
(intense drums)
Let's make apple sauce.
Okay, so.
- [Bruce] Let's do it!
- I'm just gonna put this
here; don't fire anything.
(adventurous music)
Think it should be
about right there.
- [Bruce] It's gonna be perfect.
- All right, ready?
These apples, I think
are the perfect size.
All right, load 'em up.
Excellent.
- [Bruce] That's good?
Right, bring it back up here.
We'll fill it with air.
- All right, here we go.
- 90 PSI.
- 90 PSI; probably a
much better idea to just
buy apple sauce at the
store, but this is DIY Sci.
So this is the way we do it.
Line it up!
- [Bruce] You ready?
- I'm ready!
Three, two, one.
(crashes)
(laughing)
Well, that's the first one!
Now we only have
fifteen more to go!
(repeated crashing)
(laughing)
That's beautiful.
What we need is a
green apple as well.
'Cause you gotta
have good applesauce.
Really, it's a smart
way to make applesauce.
It's not.
So Bruce, we've got three
apples in the chamber.
Try to get some in that bowl.
Three, two, one!
(laughing)
I think there might be
a little bit of wood.
There's gonna be
some fiber in our.
You know what,
here's the problem.
We also need sweetness,
so all good applesauce
has a little bit of sugar.
It's more like powdered sugar.
- [Bruce] If it's
not powdered now,
it will be by the time
it hits that target.
- Okay, here we go.
- Ready?
- [Both] Three, two, one.
(crashing)
(laughing)
(upbeat music)
- That's perfect.
I think the sugar got
out, so that's good.
- [Bruce] It's still
kind of dry though.
- It is dry, it is dry.
So that's why I was thinking
this bottle of water,
this could be great.
- [Bruce] Okay.
(adventurous music)
Okay, that looks good.
Ready?
- Three, two, one!
(laughing)
(crashing)
I don't think there's
a GoPro anymore.
Sorry about that!
(crashing)
Well, you know what they say.
If you want to make applesauce,
you have to break some cameras.
This applesauce is great.
- [Bruce] It is; we
should write a cookbook.
- Probably not.
Coming up.
- Is this thing safe?
- [Steve] Who will win the race
of the homemade
skateboard racers?
The race isn't pretty.
It's the most amazing
string art you'll ever see.
That's not in slow motion!
And you can make it at home.
All still to come on DIY Sci.
(quirky music)
(disappointing riff)
Welcome back to DIY
Sci; I'm Steve Spangler.
I've just proved the obvious.
Drop a piece of string and
gravity pulls it to the table.
But that's not always the case,
especially if you're in
a mad scientist's garage,
like Bruce Yeany's garage.
Bruce, look at this.
(machine whirring)
Wow, you drop the
string and you get art!
You get the coolest,
wait wait, look at this.
That's not in slow motion.
Look, we're not messing
around with this.
Look at this: this
is a loop of string.
- This string is--
- It is moving.
- The string is actually moving
at about 25 miles an hour.
- How cool is that?
And you can angle it
different ways, is that right?
- We can angle it
different ways.
- Look at that.
Oh that's amazing, yes
yes yes look at this!
That is absolutely...
amazing.
All right Bruce, you gotta
show us how to DIY this.
- This is easier to make
than you might think.
- So you've got two craft
motors that you found online.
And this looks like these
are tires from a toy car.
- [Bruce] This
came off a toy car,
and the idea is to get
them close together.
- [Steve] Got it.
- So that it squeezes
the string just a little
bit, and as they're spinning
it's gonna push it out.
- Somehow you've connected a
piece of string into a loop.
And it doesn't look
like you have a knot.
- That's a little
bit of super glue.
- [Steve] Okay, so you
put some glue on there.
- Put some glue on it and
kind of rolled 'em smooth.
So you want it so that
when you pull like this
it doesn't get caught
between the wheels.
- [Bruce] Right.
- Second thing is you
did some fancy work
with a straw here; what is that?
- Well, I just took a straw
and heated it a little bit
and bent it so that
the straw is actually
gonna guide the string in
between the two wheels.
- Got it.
Look at that!
The two tires are squeezing
the rope in between
and shooting it out
but you're saying
gravity is pulling it back
around again, forming this loop.
But you're actually
putting some energy in here
and that's why we're
seeing a wave, right?
- It's actually the same
thing as stretching out a rope
and just flicking it, and you
see the wave go down the rope.
We're doing the same thing.
- But because this
continues to curve around
it makes it the coolest
toy in the world.
Now, there's another version
that I played with here
when you weren't watching,
and I picked this up.
Would you show us
how this works?
- Yeah, see this is
just hanging down.
This is my hanging ribbon, and
there are switches down here.
(machine whirring)
And now once again we have a
moving ribbon in this case.
And if I pull it out once
again, we're gonna see these--
- Look at that.
- Slow moving waves
through the ribbon.
(bubbles)
- And this is what
happens when you supersize
the hanging rope
demonstration, right?
- Right.
- Look at this.
So, two by fours, huge.
It looks like there's a drill
up here hooked to a spindle
that allows this
plastic chain to move.
Plug it in, look at this.
(engine whirring)
You're putting energy into this
and it's becoming this wave.
But the wave looks like
it's moving in slow motion.
It's like the chain
is moving downwards
and the wave is trying
to force itself upwards.
So the wave gets slowed down.
Ah, look at this
on the bottom here.
It's absolutely gorgeous.
The amazing thing is that
we're not running this
in slow motion; this is
exactly how it looks.
Look at it correct
itself, watch this.
It'll spin itself around, and.
- There it is.
- It's gorgeous.
It's the perfect combination
of art and science
that makes this a great
geek garage project.
- That's amazing.
(chain rattling)
Whoa!
(bubbles)
Take a look at this; it's
a classic science toy.
It's called a ramp walker.
Bruce Yeany made this one.
What I love about this is that
it tumbles as it comes down
because not only are
we using gravity,
but we're also able
to change the weight
as it comes down the ramp.
Now, believe it
or not it's easier
to make than you might think.
We can start over here
by making the ramp.
This starts with a
yardstick or a meter stick
and we took some cardboard
and bent it around.
If you just had a ping pong
ball and you set it in the ramp
like this and made
it go back and forth,
well that's not a very fun toy.
So we gotta change
it up a little bit.
It's as easy as splitting
the ping pong ball in half
and putting the weight inside.
So take a look at this: there's
a piece of plastic here.
Some tape, and
then on the inside
it's that same ball bearing.
But what we're really
looking for it to do
is to transfer its
weight and flip over.
Oh that's perfect, look at that.
Nice, so you put a handle on
it like this and now watch.
Here's our little walker.
As the position of
the weight changes,
the little walker works
its way down the ramp.
Potential energy is turned
into kinetic energy.
The position of the weight
changes and that turns
into a fun science toy that's
easy for you to make at home.
Next on DIY Sci.
(shouting)
No, Higgensworth
hasn't lost his mind.
He's making weird sand
art, and you can too!
Find out how right
after this break.
(quirky music)
(yelling)
Welcome back to DIY Sci--
Welcome back to DIY Sci, I'm--
(yelling)
I'm Steve Spangler.
(It's always great to
have Higgens on the show.
Higgens, what are you doing?
- I'm screaming at
these sweet buckets.
- It's because it's one of Bruce
Yeany's coolest inventions.
It's the screaming sand bucket.
Do it again, would you?
(yelling)
Look at the cool patterns
that are developing
on each one of these.
But this is so easy to
make to be able to show
the sound out of your
voice, that vibration.
And vibrating this
little drum here.
Let's show 'em how to make it.
- All right.
- First of all, it's
easy, it's just a bucket
that he cut the bottom out of
and then stretched over the
top here, just a trash bag.
Really, really thin trash bag
and tried to get it as
tight as you can get it.
And the trick here
is really fine sand.
You could use very,
very fine salt
or here is this fine sand.
And the patterns that you get
I think are the most amazing.
As you're starting to see
these little resident frequency
patterns start to be
developed in here as well.
(yelling)
That's not his breath
that's doing that.
That's actually the
vibrations from his voice.
(yelling)
(quirky music)
Try to make it as
smooth as you can.
Try these little
whistles, would ya?
- All right.
(whistling)
- That's perfect, look at that!
Look at that frequency
that you set up there
and that little
pattern that's there.
You can see the
vibration was most
where the sand is missing.
We have nodes and antinodes
that you've seen
before in the waves
and that's actually
where it's sitting
there in that little antinode.
Try another one.
(whistling)
Different pattern.
All right, try this one.
(whistling)
Try this one, oh
there's a slide whistle.
- Whoa, cool.
(whistle changing pitch)
Stop that, don't use that
one ever again, all right?
Go back to this one, this is.
(whistling)
What an amazing way to be
able to see sound patterns
in something as simple as some
plastic stretched over a tub.
And a good friend who
will sit here and do this
for hours on end, keep--
(yelling)
(glass shattering)
Wanna zoom down the hill
on your own street luge?
It's not hard to make and we're
gonna show you how to do it.
Coming up next on DIY Sci.
(quirky music)
Welcome back to DIY
Sci, I'm Steve Spangler.
What good is a great
garage like this
unless you're coming
up with your own
means of transportation?
If you're Bruce Yeany
you know how to do this.
This looks like a skateboard
but you're calling
it a street luge.
- Yeah Steve, this was
actually first developed
in Southern California
where skateboarders
wanted to go a little
bit faster down hills
so they found,
instead of standing up
they made the board longer
and they could lay down on it.
- L U G E, luge, I think of
something in the Olympics
that they would have on
ice, but this is just
using a modified skateboard.
- Right.
We're simply taking
chucks off a skateboard.
We've mounted 'em on
this extended board.
And you've flipped
it over and you put
handles on either side.
- Handles to hold
onto, and then here
we have an extension for our
feet to be up off the ground.
You're not dragging
them on the ground
as you're going downhill.
- [Steve] So truly
you're laying down.
- You're laying
down on the board.
- And where is the
breaking action?
(tires screeching)
- The breaking action is
either using your feet
or aiming for a soft--
- So you're basically saying
you didn't design
a breaking action.
- There is no breaks on this.
- There's no breaks,
you're telling me
you're just inches from the
pavement, going down a hill,
and the only way to stop
is to put your feet out
and you just turn
with your body.
- That's pretty much it, yes.
- It seems really safe.
But good for Higgensworth
because we got two of them
and I think it's
time for a race.
(paper crumpling)
All right Higgens,
this is a race.
- Okay, is thing safe?
- Uh.
- What are you looking
at me for, I don't know.
I didn't invent this.
- I don't know, we'll find out.
(laughing)
- It's safe, Higgens.
- How does this work?
- All right, have you ever
been on one of these before?
- Never.
- Never, okay, well.
Turn it around and the idea
is you're gonna sit on it.
Feet go here, and you're gonna
give yourself a good push.
Fast as you can, and
once you get going
then you're simply
going to lie down.
And if you tilt a little
bit it should steer.
You guys ready?
On your mark, get set.
- [Steve] Look
over there, Higgs!
(Steve laughing)
Higgs, look at me!
(shouting)
Steering is limited!
Steering the luge,
kind of difficult.
Because you're just moving
your body back and forth.
(shouting)
Okay man, we gotta turn!
Okay, we gotta land this thing!
You gotta think of it as a
skateboard but laying down,
which is a weird sensation.
(shouting)
Look at where my
feet are, Higgens.
I won.
- And the winner
is Steve Spangler!
- See you later, Higgs!
(soft music)
This'd be a really
effective way to get to work
if your work was
always downhill.
And you only had
that far to come
and there was nobody
in front of you
and you didn't have to
worry about stopping.
And you could have somebody's
lawn that you could stop in.
Okay, let's go.
(groaning)
I'm getting too old for this.
Glad we picked a place
that wasn't muddy to stop.
Don't go away, there'll be
more DIY Sci after this!
(quirky music)
So what did we learn today?
We learned how to harness air
pressure to propel an apple
hard enough to make
our own applesauce.
We discovered how
to make sand art
just with the
vibrations of our voice.
- Is this thing safe?
- We saw that it just
takes a little ingenuity
(shouting)
to come up with a new means
of ground transportation.
And we learned how much fun
it is to be a garage geek.
Huge thanks to Bruce Yeany
for opening up his
amazing garage.
I'm Steve Spangler.
We'll see you next
time on DIY Sci.
(metallic riff)