Mexico,
May 2014
Again, again!
Little chick.
Little chick, how do you feel now your mum is dead?
Your parents have died.
So, how do you feel?
Eat little chick.
Wait.
Eat.
I've got him.
No, no, no...you'll strangle him, David.
No.
No little chick.
I don't like getting up early.
Why?
Because from Monday to Friday I need to get up...
...to wake up these two children...
...wash them, dress them.
You have no idea how difficult it is
to brush Yami's hair.
to give this boy a wash.
You don't know Alejandro.
Why?
Because you are supposedly looking for a job...
...to be able to feed us.
Do you think it's easy to support you
for a year?
Just me supporting all of you.
My only worry...
...the only responsibility I give you...
...is to look after the children while I'm not here.
Oh sure! One responsibility!
Why do you lie Alejandro?
Don't lie to yourself.
I'm the only one who tidies
the house here!
Who has to tidy the living room?...
...and my bedroom.
While you're supposedly
looking for a job,...
...at least you're able go out and get some distraction.
I have to stay here, shut in.
I can't wait for the day that Mum gets out,...
...because you're old enough
to leave this house.
I wish Mum was out and you left this place...
...and stopped telling me what to do.
I love my brother with all my heart...
...but I feel a kind of hatred for him too.
I don't express my feelings very well.
I'm crazy.
But...
...I hate him because...
...I know the situation we're in but for one day...
...just one day that he rests and says...
..."for the rest of the year, I'm your father.
But today I'm your brother."
But he doesn't.
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE WALL
How many is this?
It was...one, two, three; it's three.
Three potatoes.
Eat properly David.
Well, I'm done.
No, you didn't eat the tomato.
I finished. And you haven't finished yet.
Mum said you shouldn't pee yourself anymore.
That if you did, we had to wash you.
With cold water.
And to David she said
to stop having tantrums in the mornings...
when I change him...
...because that's what he always does.
Mummy said she loves you very much.
She loves you very much
and that if you're good...
...she said that, if you're good,
she'll come and visit you.
Do you want mummy to come?
To come here?
You want that?
Then you have to be good.
Me too.
..si..
...c.
Charles likes music.
Charles likes kuss.
No.
He likes it, huh?
Yami! Yami!
You know I turn into a Lion
when anybody tickles me.
Seriously.
[If you are from outside of Mexico,
what document allows you to work in this country?]
The hardest thing?
To think that...
...I don't know...
...that I'll run out of possibilities...
...to keep fighting, to keep them all afloat.
That's the hardest thing for me.
Ok, did you bring the
papers we asked for?
Well, they are kind of incomplete because...
...I'm not from here, you see.
They're partly done.
Where are you from?
I'm from Honduras.
Ok. So your papers aren't sorted
for you to work here?
No, they haven't been processed yet.
The thing is that I'm from Honduras and...
...that's why I can't get a job here but I need it.
I need to work.
But...why don't you get your papers first?
Didn't he move?
Yes.
He's always moving.
Did you feel pain today?
No, not now.
Only when he moves a lot,
but no. No pain today.
A kick?
He won't move, if you're touching him.
Too bad, when he wants me to carry him I won't.
Hello
Hi son.
How are you Mum?
Ok son, good evening.
How have you been?
Good honey, and you?
Good, thank God.
And the kids?
They're there playing.
David...
And Rocio?
What?
Rocio was watching TV downstairs I think.
Ahh.
On Tuesday?
What?
Everything ok?
Yes, thank God, yes.
And...on Tuesday, right?
On Tuesday, they'll say something, right?
Yes son.
We have to wait.
Be strong, don't fall apart.
You have to keep going.
You know I love you and I'm very grateful.
Yes, don't worry about that.
Sometimes Rocio drives me crazy
but we're getting by.
You know she's a teenager.
She's at that age.
I know.
The phone card is running out. I'll call you tomorrow.
Ok.
Be good honey. Good night.
Do you need anything there?
No honey.
Paper or something?
No son. The girls gave me some food and biscuits.
Ok.
Ok son, good night.
What scares me?
What scares me is...
...the idea that my mum gets
an extremely long sentence...
...and she can't get out again...
...or she dies of sadness in there.
Hello?
Hi Mummy!
I'm ok.
Here they are!
She's asking for her good looking son.
But Ale isn't here.
He's not here.
It's a joke! Here he is.
Take it David.
Hello Mummy.
Jumping, jumping, pum, pum.
What is it? Do you think that's funny?
Do you think that's funny?
Yes, it's funny!
It's not funny!
Yes it's funny!
It's not.
It's not funny! It's very funny!
It's a joke, it's not.
It's not funny or very funny.
It's super funny!
It's mum.This time it's for real. Wait outside.
Hello?
Hi Mummy!
Hi sweetie! How are you honey?
Good.
They gave you the news, right?
What news?
They sentenced me.
No Mummy...how long?
Ten years honey.
No Mummy...don't say that.
Yes sweetie, there's nothing I can do.
Justice isn't for everybody.
Maybe because we're immigrants;
I have to pay for it.
But the true criminals are outside.
Don't tell me it's ten years.
Ten years darling,
it's unfair but what can we do?
No.
Do you know what's the important thing here?
That you know I never did anything wrong.
I feel proud about that and
I want you to feel proud too.
I want you to look forward...
...and no one will destroy you
pshycologicaly or morally.
You have the ability.
You and Alejandro are the older ones, and
you have the ability.
Mummy...
Yes?
...thank you.
Why honey?
For everything you gave us.
No honey, it's my duty.
It's my duty to care for you...
...but now the cirmcustances are keeping us apart.
We won't get the time back...
...but I'll come out stronger from here
to give you the things you need.
I promise I'll make up for the time.
I promise.
With God's will we'll make it; you'll see.
I swear.
Remember when I used to
ring you in Honduras...
...and told you I was going to bring you here?
I kept my promise.
This time too I was going to keep my promise...
...because I was about to leave this place...
...because all the evidence
was in my favour.
But in the end, the law didn't see it that way.
But...
...if we have faith...
...everything will be ok; you'll see.
Yes.
I love you honey.
I thought you weren't going to bring me.
Do you want me to tell the driver to stop
and let you get out?
Huh?
I take responsibilities to make your life easier.
I have to take the role of the father here.
You overdo it.
I have to work. If I don't we won't have food the next day.
They donate  food to the house Alejandro.
I know Rocio, but we can't live off beans all our lives.
You see? Now you get it!
I've been telling you for months...
...that beans and rice isn't the best food.
And now?
This is what we'll do.
We won't tell mum about this...
...because if we tell her she'll worry.
I don't want her to get ill...
...especially in there.
I love you a lot.
I love you very very much.
You can't imagine it.
I love you too.
I want you to promise me...
...that we're going to make this family work
till the day Mum gets out.
I hope that'll be soon.
I want her to find a united family.
Can you promise me that?
Are we going to help each other?
Give me a hug.
Are you sure they'll let this in?
Yeah, maybe.
One year and four months later
If we go at 120km per hour...
My mum has now been in jail
for two years and four months.
Since she was put in jail...
...I haven't been doing very well
in my relationship with myself.
Sometimes I think,
why am I always answering back to my brother?
But sometimes I say to myself,
it's not my fault!
It's obvious. I'm at an age where I think
I'm the queen of the world...
...but I'm not.
I don't know how to explain how I feel...
I'm confused.
Austin...
Look...
Do you want a sweet?
Children...
...you're going to see the surprise I prepared.
Come in.
I haven't opened the door yet.
Wow...is this the new house?
Yes.
What do you think?
This is yours and your brother's bedroom.
This is my bedroom.
This is the kitchen.
This is the living room.
Did you see the huge TV we've got?
Carolina...
...did you see the huge TV?
Wow.
Do you like it?
Yes.
Look!
An email from your dad.
It says...
Hello children, how are you?
I love you very much and...
...I'll be there on Saturday.
I'm in New York at the minute.
See you on Saturday.
I love you. Kisses.
I'm going to take you on holidays very soon, ok?
We love you very much.
We love you very much daddy.
You're the best dad.
You're the best, dad.
And we always miss you in New York.
Ok.
I'm hungry.
Me too.
What if we have...
...hot cakes?...
...fried chicken?
Hot cakes.
or...
...pizza!
Rocio!
Eyoo!
Bring something to wash the vegetables...
...and bring the chopping board to help me here.
Ok.
Anyway, this is Alejandro's. So you know.
I'm leaving.
Eat!
But there's a fly in my soup.
What do you mean,
"there's a fly"?
Look!
We're sorry lady.
Due to this incident her food will be free.
Ale! Your food.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hello?
Hi honey, how are you?
Good Mummy, thanks to God.
And the children?
They're playing there.
Ok. Put me through to Rocio, but let me
tell you something first.
They re-opened my case.
They're processing it.
But is that good or bad news?
I think it's good news. We'll see.
Let's ask God to help.
I could get released or...
...I don't know. We'll have to wait and see.
Look at this.
Should we ask Ale?
No.
Come on David.
Well, if you like this with chocolate.
But.
No David.
This one.
Both.
David says he wants this, and I want that.
One each.
Or we take two each.
Two for you and two for David.
Huh?
One is enough.
But just in case?
No.
I'll get you sweets.
But not this.
You need an oven to cook it.
You need an oven.
Or maybe you don't.
I can't stay here for the next ten years.
It's like getting stuck.
On one hand, hope is good;
but on the other hand, it's bad.
If I have hope that my mum
will be released,
I'll cling to that idea
and won't be able to move forward.
No.
The second option is to go to the United States.
Olga, my mum, and I
have already talked about it.
It's a bit drastic because...
...it means we would separate completely.
The children would go to Honduras with an aunty.
Olga and Austin to Palenque.
My sister Rocio would stay here with a friend.
I think a lot about the children though...
...because they can't understand why.
You can't explain to them what you have to do.
So...
...if we take this option and
the family has to split up...
...the children will ask me, "why?"
And I won't be able to tell them
why I'm taking them away from their mum.
I won't be able to reply.
Do you need help?
Yes.
Have you already taken your trousers off?
Now.
Where are my clothes?
There's no time for you to have a wash.
Are you almost done?
Hurry up! It's getting late.
God! David! You're like a baby.
Honestly! For God's sake.
You can't eat.
Thanks Rocio!
You're welcome.
Go and clean your cup.
Who yelled at you?
Nodody.
Why are you crying then?
For nothing.
And why are you crying?
Nobody cries for nothing
Because you didn't listen to me.
Why?
Ok, but why didn't I listen to you?
I don't know!
Look, my motorbike!
My motorbike!
I'm braking.
My motorbike at high speed...
...at high speed like this.
Hello honey, how are you?
I'm ok.
Ok?
And Alejandro?
He's working. He hasn't arrived yet.
He hasn't arrived?
And how are you all?
So so, but ok.
And what about that boyfriend of yours?
He's not my boyfriend.
He's just a friend, Mummy.
Be very careful.
Don't let that desperation to be with boys...
...make you do something you'll regret.
No Mummy, don't worry.
You're still too young honey.
I know. You've always told me.
Well, I reckon,
you're a very intelligent young woman.
Don't let me down.
Listen I want you to write down the things...
...you need to bring when you come over,
for the pies.
Ok, just a minute. I just need to finish this...
...just a minute.
I don't like it when someone says,
I like you because you're pretty.
I like you because you're hot.
And not because of how I behave, how I am.
I wouldn't like to have the kind of boyfriend that
loves you one minute...
...and hits you the next.
I want someone who's honest with me.
So...
...if that person exists...
...that would be my Prince Charming.
And I'd be willing to have a family with him.
Ale.
Hey, will you give me permission
to go to the cinema with some friends?
No.
Why not?
Because I was talking to Mum
and she said some things...
...that don't make sense.
What things?
Who is that boy you told Mum about?
But why do we need to talk about that?
Are you going to give me permission?
So?
So what?
Who are you going to the cinema with?
I'm telling you.With my friends.
Why don't you believe in me?
I've been here
two and a quarter years...
...putting up with you all
since Mummy's been in jail.
And I go and tell her, "Mum, do you know what?
Rocio got pregnant."
Who do you think I have to give explanations to?
To Mummy Alejandro but,
I'm not gonna let myself be fooled.
I've told you a thousand times!
You won't let yourself be fooled?
So you have a boyfriend.
No Alejandro.
No Rocio,
you don't have permission to go anywhere.
When was this opened?
Today.
Look Ro,...
...if you're all here with me, it's simply because
I don't want to throw in the towel.
Sometimes I want to leave everything behind,
leave you all behind.
But, I start thinking.
Mum says, "think about it, think about it".
Yes, but I need a little bit of space.
I want a fuck load of space too!
You can't imagine how much
I'd like to have time to study now.
To get a degree, be able to earn more money,
so I can fix my fucking papers here.
We want a lot of things,
but we can't have them all like that!
But I also want a little bit of space...
...so I can get out a bit...
...because I've told you a thousand times...
...I get bored here.
Or we go out together, not just by myself!
Even if we don't spend one single cent,
just to get out at least.
Go to the park or something.
Haven't you stopped for a second
to think about Mum?
Don't you think Mummy suffocates there?
Eh?
Imagine, locked up by four walls.
I need that...
I need to know...
...if you'll be there unconditionally
to help me.
Yes Ale.
Because imagine...
...it's more than two years that
Mum has been there.
And who knows how many more years
she'll be there for.
If things carry on the way they are now,
we'll go from bad to worse.
So I need you to assure me and tell me,...
"...Ale, I can help you".
Yes, you can count on me
and I'll support you.
She says this is a test we have to pass...
...a small obstacle to overcome.
And...
...I just hope...
...she will come out soon because...
...I can't continue living like this...
...fighting and fighting with my brothers,
my sister in law, my brother...
...punishments...
...and restrictions.
[How to cross the border through Tijuana ]
Hi.
Hello son, how are you?
Bad.
Why bad honey?
Because I don't know what to do.
Look honey...think about it first.
Look, the children will be split up.
You'll be separated from them.
Nobody is going to look after them like you do.
Give me another couple of months.
Let's keep the hope that I can be released.
I don't know...
...we'll see how things go.
But if this situation doesn't change,...
...I can't stay here.
Without papers everything is fucked.
The money I make isn't enough.
Who's going to take you across?
I don't know. I'd look for a coyote.
Look honey, think about the pros and cons.
It's risky!
It was so difficult for me
to come here from Honduras.
Just imagine from here to the United States!
But here Mummy, without papers,
nobody gives me a good job.
A good salary more than anything.
That's most important.
I know. I know sweety.
But just give me two more months.
If after two months you see
we haven't solved anything...
...let's wait and see what the judge's decision is.
Maybe I'm lucky and I'm let out.
Don't fall apart son, not now!
You've put up with it for more than two years.
Can't you put up with it a bit longer?
Don't be upset! Don't be upset.
Put into practice what I've always told you.
Be optimistic.
And lift up that self-esteem that
you've always had so much of.
Better times will come, son.
Don't fall apart.
Well Mum, I'm going home now
because I just finished work.
I'm a bit tired and hungry.
I'll call you later then, or tomorrow;
because I don't have a phone card.
Ok.
Well son I love you very much, alright?
I love you too.
I love you honey.
You think, why is this happening to me?
You see the people around you and think...
...why me?...
...with so many people in the world.
There are people more miserable than me.
They're in worse situations.
And you feel pity.
You feel sometimes...I don't know.
More than pity,
you feel sorry for those people;...
...because you know what it's like.
And people who've never gone through
such serious problems...
...sometimes they underestimate
what they've got.
You look pretty.
...you're like a happy teddy bear.
Here is your coconut milkshake.
I'll give you shit milkshake...
It doesn't want to go in!
Bloody thing!
I don't like these plates,
they don't want to be clean!
Now.
Bravo!
Hello.
Why did you arrive so late?
I went for a walk with my friends.
Who did you ask for permission?
Noboby. I know I didn't ask for permission
but I get bored here Alejandro.
Is that your excuse for going out
anytime you want?
No, but you know I feel like
a slave here with the children.
Turn down the TV a bit please.
What am I gonna do with you Rocio?
I'm sorry Ale.
I'm sorry, that's all?
I'll say sorry and that's it. He'll forget everything.
I know where you were.
If I wanted I could have gone there
and dragged you back by your hair...
...to make you feel embarrassed...
...and scream at you there.
Would you like me to go there
and scream at you?
...ask you why you went out
without permission?
No.
Imagine, one of these days Mummy calls
and I don't know where you are.
And I say, "I don't know Mummy,
I don't know where she is"
"And Rocio?" I don't know. She went out
without permission.
"Where? Who with?"
"I don't know because she does her own thing."
Can I come in to watch TV?
No Rocio. Go to bed.
They say Mexico has one of the most
transparent judicial systems
It won a prize for it,
but...
I realize it won that for the Mexicans,
but because we're not from Mexico...
...we are like an old rag for them.
They use us, squeeze us and throw us away.
It's not my brother and sister's fault.
It's not our fault.
It's not even my Mum's fault.
My Mum isn't guilty for
having wanted a better life for us.
I can't take a situation like this.
Well my mum's sentence is unfair.
My only hope is that one day...
...they'll discover the truth
and she'll be released sooner,...
...only if that happens.
Hello?
Really?
Ay Mummy! I want to cry right now.
Me too!
But out of happiness.
Take care and be good.
Here they are.
Put them on.
There you go.
Who's that?
Yami.
Hello Mummy.
Hello honey.
Are you happy?
Yes.
Hello.
Hello darling.
Yes, Gaby told me a while ago.
I didn't know anything.
Is the cream...
...wet?
No.
You have a bit there.
Here.
There, on your hand.
Is that her?
Mummy!
It's over now, at last.
Yes.
At last. It's over.
Wait! Wait!
Let's take a photo, come on!
Smile!
You have to smile...
...because this is a happy moment.
Let's go home.
What are we going to eat?
Rice and beans!
No, burgers.
What do you want them with?
Alejandro and Rocio's mother was accused
of extortion and involvement in organized crime.
After 2 years and 4 months in prison
she was released due to lack of evidence.