>ASTEROIDS THE VERMIN OF THE
SKIES, SITTING DUCKS
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE. >KINGSTON,
COME ON.
DO YOU WANT TO SEE
THEM OR NOT.
WE CRUSHED LIKE EGGS. >STOP
EXAGGERATING. >WE'RE ABOUT TO
FLY
THROUGH AN ASTEROID BELT. WHO'S
EXAGGERATING. >YOU'RE JUST
JEALOUS
BECAUSE I FOUND IT FIRST. COME
ON. >YOU'LL SEE. WHEN YOU'RE
HURDLING OUT INTO SPACE
CLINGING TO A LUMP
OF ROCK.
>WE'VE GOT IT.
>IT'S INCREDIBLE.
>INCREDIBLE, IT'S INCREDIBLY
DANGEROUS
THAT'S WHAT IT IS. WHY WE HAVE
TO GO RIGHT THROUGH THE MIDDLE
OF IT IS BEYOND
ME. >FUEL, GEORGE. >IF WE DON'T
CATCH THE OIL CARRIER
NONE OF US WILL SURVIVE. >WHAT
ARE OUR CHANCES?
>OF US HITTING THAT. >OF IT
HITTING US.
>WE'VE MAPPED A COURSE. >WE'VE
ACCOUNTED FOR EVERY LUMP OF ROCK
OF IT. >GEORGE, THEY ARE
MILLIONS OF MILES APART.
IT'S A RISK WE HAVE TO TAKE.
>WOW. IT'S FANTASTIC.
>AND I FOUND IT. I RECKON THEY
MUST HAVE HAD A TELESCOPE DOWN
HERE.
>SO MANY STARS. >YES, SEARCHING
FOR STRANGE CREATURES FROM OUTER
SPACE. >YOU HAVE TO PROMISE NOT
TO TELL, IT'S MY SECRET PLACE.
>AS IF I WOULD. WE'RE NOT EVEN
SUPPOSED TO BE DOWN HERE.
>WHAT ARE YOU SO JUMPY ABOUT?
>ME JUMPY? WHY SHOULD I BE
JUMPY. WE'RE ABOUT
TO BE BLOWN INTO LITTLE SQUISHY
BITS BY A ROGUE ASTEROID.
>KEEP THIS TO OURSELVES, JUST
YOU AND ME.
>IF YOU TELL ANYONE YOU'RE DEAD
MEAT.
>DEAD MEAT. (SCREAMS) >ALIENS.
RUN.
>STAND BY. GEORGE, IF YOU DON'T
STOP WORRYING THERE WON'T BE AN
ASTEROID
THAT GETS YOU, IT WILL BE AN
ULCER. >THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH MY HEALTH.
I AM IN PEAK PHYSICAL
CONDITION. >RUN FOR YOUR LIVES.
THERE'S AN ALIEN DOWN THERE.
>WE SAW IT. >WHAT IS THE
MEANING OF THIS?
HOW DARE YOU BURST IN HERE LIKE
THAT. >YOU'VE GOT TO DO
SOMETHING.
WE WERE WATCHING FOR ASTEROIDS
AND IT ATTACKED US, A HUGE,
UGLY, HORRIBLE,
>ALIEN.
>IT WILL DRIVE HIM CRAZY.
THE PERFECT TORTURE. >JERROD,
MAYBE THIS HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
I THINK
WE SHOULD THEM. >DON'T BE A
WIMP.
LOOK, IF I WAS YOU I WOULD BE
WORRIED WHAT THEY ARE GONNA DO
TO US WHEN THEN FIND OUT.
LIKE A RAT IN A TRAP. TOLD YOU.
ACTION STATIONS. >SOME DUMB
ALIEN IT NOT GONNA GET
THE BETTER OF ME. THEY HAVE TO
BELIEVE US NOW.
>KUMI, IT'S GOING TO GET KUMI.
>COME ON. >ALRIGHT, YOUR LITTLE
GAME IS OVER.
VERY FUNNY. >THE LOOK ON YOUR
FACE. AUGH.
>I KNEW IT. PARTNERS IN CRIME
NOW ARE WE? >HEY WE HAD YOU
GOING FOR AWHILE
>YOU GUYS ARE SO JUVENILE AS IF
ANYONE BELIEVED THAT.
>THE RODENT DID. I'VE NEVER
SEEN HIM MOVE SO FAST.
>IT'S NOT FUNNY. YOU REALLY
FRIGHTENED THEM. THEY ARE ONLY
LITTLE KIDS.
>COME OFF IT. THEY LOVED IT.
>UH OH. LOOKS LIKE WE'VE GOT
VISITORS.
>IT'S GOING TO GET KUMI. THE
CREATURE. >WE CAN PROVE IT.
>IT'S GOT IT. IT ATE THE ZORK.
>NO POWER, NO PROOF.
>THAT SNEAKY LITTLE RATE. HOW
DEVIOUS CAN YOU GET.
>JUVENILES. >YOU HAVE TO
BELIEVE
US IT WAS THERE. >THE ZORK, IT
ATE IT. IT SWALLOWED IT WHOLE.
ONE BITE, GONE. >JUST AFTER IT
ATE KUMI.
>I HAVE HAD ENOUGH OF THIS
RIDICULOUS
FANTASY. I WANT YOU PAIR OUT OF
HERE.
>THIS HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
IF YOU DON'T TELL THEM, I WILL.
>DON'T BE A WIMP. WE'RE JUST
TRYING TO
RELIEVE SOME OF THE BOREDOM IN
THIS DUMP. >WELL THEN PICK ON
SOMEONE YOUR OWN SIZE.
>OK, OK, WE WERE GONNA TELL
THEM ANYWAY.
>ARE YOU HAPPY NOW?
>WE'VE GOT A FRIEND. 1,000
METERS.
>KUMI.
YOU OK? >I'M FINE.
LOOK AT YOUR MATE OVER THERE.
>I WANT DAMAGE REPORTS AS SOON
AS POSSIBLE. >WE'RE LOSING AIR.
IT REACHED THE
HOUSE. >ISOLATE THE THE DAMAGED
AREAS. >CLOSE THE COMPRESSION
DOOR.
>I WANT YOU OUT OF HERE.
SOMEWHERE SAFE. THE REC ROOM.
GO.
>I'M ALRIGHT. >WE HAVE TO GET
OUT OF HERE.
>JERROD, RUN. >I CAN'T RUN. >IF
IT WASN'T FOR THE STUPID
SUIT. >GO.
>GOOD WORK, BOYS.
SATISFIED NOW?
>WHAT D YOU THINK HAS HAPPENED?
>WE'RE FLYING THROUGH AN
ASTEROID BELT. WHAT DO YOU
THINK IT WAS? A PICK ELEPHANT?
>NO NEED TO BE SARCASTIC.
>IT'S THE ONLY LANGUAGE YOU
PAIR UNDERSTAND.
NOW WHAT BRAINS? THINK YOU CAN
INVENT SOMETHING TO GET US OUT
OF HERE?
>WE'RE
STABILIZED AND HOLDING COURSE.
>GOOD.
KEEP THE DAMAGED SECTION
SEALED. TAKE YOUR CREW AND
CHECK THAT SOUND. >I'LL CHECK
THE
TUG. >ARE THEY STILL HERE?
HOW MANY WAYS DO I HAVE TO SAY
IT?
>PERHAPS YOU COULD TRY A NICE
WAY.
I WANT YOU TO GO TO YOUR
QUARTERS. BETTER STILL GO AND
FIND
MICHAEL AND JERROD. THEY WILL
LOOK AFTER YOU. YOU'LL BE SAFE
WITH THEM.
>COME ON. WE'RE WASTING OUR
TIME HERE. LET'S GO
FIND MICHAEL.
>NO. WE DON'T WHAT'S OUT THERE.
>IT'S A CORRIDOR. WHAT DO YOU
THINK IT IS? >USE YOUR HEAD.
IT'S A COMPRESSION DOOR.
>THE ASTEROID MUST HAVE
BREACHED THE HULL.
WE'RE LOSING AIR. >BINGO.
>WHAT, SO NOW WE SUFFOCATE.
>NOT IN HERE. OUT THERE. IF IT
WAS IN HERE WE'D ALL BE SUCKED
OUT INTO
SPACE. >NO PROBLEM THEN. WE
JUST SIT AND WAIT TO BE RESCUED.
>WHERE HAVE I HEARD THAT
BEFORE. THIS HAS GOT TO BE A
COMMUNICATION PANEL
BUT I CAN'T GET IT TO WORK.
>STAND BACK, A LITTLE GENTLE
PERSUASION. >NO!
>GOOD ONE, JERROD. WHY USE YOUR
BRAIN WHEN BRUTE FORCE
WILL DO?
>MICHAEL.
THE REC ROOM MAYBE. >LOOK
FAMILIAR?
THE THING. NICE WORK TOO.
>THOSE CREEPS. IT WAS THEN.
>THEY WERE LAUGHING AT US ALL
THE TIME.
>HOW COULD THEY!
>AND KUMI. SHE'S SUPPOSED TO BE
OUR FRIEND. >RIGHT.
THEY ARE GONNA SUFFER FOR THIS.
REVENGE.
>THERE'S GOT TO BE ANOTHER WAY
OUT. >I WISH THE RODENT WAS
HERE.
>RECKON THEY'D HELP AFTER WHAT
YOU DID. >AIR DUCTS.
THERE MUST BE AN AIR DUCT
AROUND HERE SOMEWHERE. >YOU'RE
WASTING YOUR TIME.
WE'RE SEALED IN. IF IT WASN'T
FOR YOUR STUPID PRACTICAL
JOKE... >HEY LOOK,
WE'RE SORRY. HOW MANY TIMES DO
YOU WANT US TO SAY IT? >THERE.
IT'S THEM. KINGSTON
AND ANNA. >CAN WE SIGNAL THEM?
>WHAT WITH
>WERE IS YOUR MULTIMATE WHEN WE
NEED IT?
>THE ALIEN.
>YEAH RIGHT.
WE CAN FLASH HIS EYES. >DON'T
BE STUPID.
THEY SEE THESE, THEY WON'T COME
ANYWHERE NEAR HERE. >SHE'S
RIGHT.
>MAYBE WE COULD SABOTAGE HIS
PLANS.
>OR WAIT TILL THEY ARE
ASLEEP, THEN POUNCE. SCARE THE
LIFE OUT OF THEM.
JERROD HATES BEING WOKEN UP.
>WE'LL DO SOMETHING REALLY
HORRIBLE TO THEIR FOOD. >WE'LL
HIJACK HER COMPUTER.
>THEY MUST LOOK DOWN SOONER OR
LATER. >WHY? DO YOU ALWAYS GO
AROUND LOOKING AT YOUR FEET.
>HEY, THEY ARE LEAVING. THEY
MUST HAVE SEEN US.
>WE DON'T LET ON WE KNOW ABOUT
THE ALIEN, RIGHT? >RIGHT.
>WE'VE CHECKED THE TUG. THERE'S
NO
DAMAGE. THE AIR LOCKS ARE IN
PLACE. WE'VE ISOLATED THE
BRIDGE. WE'LL CHECK THE REST
>SO, WHAT'S HAPPENING? ARE WE
GONNA DIE SLOWLY OR IS IT GONNA
BE QUICK AND SUDDEN?
SMASHED TO BITS BY A ROGUE
ASTEROID. >THERE'S NOTHING TO
WORRY ABOUT.
WHY AREN'T YOU WITH THE OTHERS?
WHERE ARE JERROD AND MICHAEL?
>DON'T WORRY. WE'LL LOOK
AFTER THEM. >SEE THAT YOU DO
AND STAY AWAY FROM DUFFY.
NO MORE ALIENS. >BETH! WE'VE
LOST
CLIMATE CONTROL ON LEVEL 5.
>COMING. COMING.
>I KNEW IT. WE'RE GONNA FREEZE
TO DEATH. SNAP FROZEN HUMAN
BEINGS.
>KINGSTON. LEVEL 5
THAT'S WHERE WE SAW IT. >THE
THING. >THE ALIEN.
MICHAEL AND JERROD. >THEY'RE
GOING TO MISS US EVENTUALLY.
>MAYBE THEY DON'T WANT TO HELP
AFTER WHAT YOU GUYS DID.
>YOU'RE WASTING YOUR TIME.
>GOT ANY BETTER IDEAS? >WHAT
ARE YOU TRYING TO DO?
>USE MY BRIAN. SOMETHING HE
WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND. I'M TRYING
TO COMMUNICATE
WITH CENTRAL COMPUTER. >AND HOW
DO YOU DO THAT? TALK TO IT IN A
WARM AND
FRIENDLY VOICE? >LOOK, WHY
DON'T YOU MAKE YOURSELF USEFUL
AND KEEP WATCH.
>IF I CAN HACK INTO THE SYSTEM
MAYBE I CAN RAISE SOME SORT OF
ALARM.
IT'S A BIT OF A LONGSHOT.
>WHAT'S THE PANIC? WE JUST HAVE
TO WAIT. >WE COULD BE
IN HERE FOR HOURS AND IN CASE
YOU HADN'T NOTICED, IT IT
GETTING
COLDER IN HERE.
>KINGSTON, WE HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING. >LET'S LEAVE THEM
THERE. >IT'S NOT A JOKE.
>TEACH THEM A LESSON. NO ONE
MESSES WITH KINGSTON LEWIS.
>NO, THEY COULD BE
IN DANGER. >IT'S JUST THAT ONE
LEVEL, LEVEL 5. EVERYTHING ELSE
IS NORMAL.
>MAKE SURE. I DON'T WANT ANY
MORE SURPRISES. >MR. DUFFY.
>YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE IN THE
REC
ROOM. WHAT HAVE I GOT TO DO?
NAIL YOU TO THE FLOOR? >IT'S AN
EMERGENCY.
>THE ALIEN. >I'M GETTING VERY
TIRED OF THIS LITTLE PRACTICAL
JOKE.
>BUT THAT'S WHAT WE'RE TRYING
TO TELL YOU. >NOT ANOTHER
SQUEAK FROM THE PAIR OF YOU.
>IT WAS A JOKE.
>GEORGE.
>KEEP IT ON THE SCREEN. >COME
ON. HE'S NOT GONNA LISTEN.
>HEATING IS OFF, DOORS ARE
SEALED,
POWER IS DOWN, I'D SAY THE
COMPUTER DOESN'T WANT TO KNOW
ABOUT US,
WOULDN'T YOU?
>WE'RE NOT GONNA LAST MORE THAN
A HALF AN HOUR AT THIS RATE.
>OH WHAT I WOULD GIVE NOW
FOR A HOT BOWL OF RECON SLUDGE.
>COME ON.
HUDDLE TOGETHER. WE CAN KEEP
EACH OTHER WARM. >OH GET
SERIOUS. >I AM
SERIOUS. WE HAVE TO CONSERVE
BODY HEAT.
>THIS ISN'T GONNA WORK. >GET
CLOSER. >I THINK I'D RATHER
FREEZE. >YOU PROBABLY WILL.
>THIS IS RIDICULOUS
I FEEL LIKE MY FINGERS ARE
GONNA SNAP OFF. >GOT ANY BETTER
IDEAS?
>YES.
WRAP YOURSELF IN THIS,
INSULATION.
>THIS ISN'T A GOOD TIME TO BE
IN HERE. WHAT IF WE GET HIT BY
ANOTHER ASTEROID?
>WE HAVE TO HELP. THEY. UP
AHEAD.
>LEADS TO THE CENTRAL STAIRS.
SEALED. >WELL. THIS WAY.
>I CAN'T EVEN FEEL MY FEET. >IT
MUST BE 10 BELOW
THERE HAS TO BE A WAY OUT.
THINK.
>FIRE. >WHAT! >WE
LIGHT A FIRE. SIMPLE. >NO. YOU
WANT TO USE UP WHAT OXYGEN
WE'VE GOT LEFT?
>WE EITHER FREEZE OR SUFFOCATE.
PERSONALLY, I HATE THE COLD.
>DON'T BE AN IDIOT. YOU DON'T
EVEN KNOW WHAT THEY ARE MADE
OF. IT COULD BE TOXIC. >NO,
JERROD'S
RIGHT. THE HEAT SENSORS MIGHT
STILL BE WORKING. IT WILL SHOW
UP IN THE CONTROL ROOM.
>WELL WHAT ARE YOU GONNA LIGHT
IT WITH THEN GENIUS? >YOU'RE
NOT THE ONLY SMART
ONE.
POWER PACKS FROM THE ALIEN. WE
ARK THEM TOGETHER.
>MAYBE YOU BOTH HAVE A BRAIN.
>AND I'M GET REALLY SICK OF YOU
PUTTING ME DOWN.
>HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE IF WE
FREEZE?
>SO, WHO'S THE
SMART ONE NOW.
>JERROD.
>I'VE GOT A BAD FEELING ABOUT
THIS. >IT'S OK.
>TROUBLE IS I DON'T KNOW WHERE
THE STAIRS LEADS.
>WE'RE GONNA DIE IF WE DON'T
GET HELP SOON.
>NONE OF US IS GONNA GET OUT OF
HERE. >AND ALL BECAUSE OF SOME
STUPID PRACTICAL
JOKE.
>3 BLOCKS OF ICE.
THAT'S ALL THEY ARE GONNA FIND.
>JERROD?
THIS POWER PACK.
WHAT HAD YOU DONE WITH IT?
>FORGET IT.
>IT'S NOT GONNA WORK WITHOUT
THE REMOTE.
>BUT IT'S GOT A CAMERA IN IT
HASN'T IT?
>KINGSTON'S GO THE REMOTE
CONTROL.
>KINGSTON, WE'RE ALIVE. >ANNA,
HELP. >LEVEL 5.
>WE'VE GOT ANOTHER ONE. IT'S
HEADING STRAIGHT
FOR US. >RETRACT THE SOLAR
CELL. >GEORGE.
THE KIDS. WE CAN'T FIND THEM.
>WE'LL HAVE TO TURN BACK.
>NO WAY. >THIS PLACE HAS BEEN
DEMOLISHED. IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
THIS USED TO BE IN OUR PAIR
REACTOR.
THERE MUST BE ANOTHER WAY.
>THERE.
>NO WAY. I'M NOT GOING OUT ON
THAT. YOU KNOW I'M SCARED OF
HEIGHTS.
ANNA NO. WE GO BACK. WE GET
HELP. >THERE'S NO TIME. THEY
WILL FREEZE.
>THIS WHOLE THING WILL
COLLAPSE, WE'RE DEAD.
>WE'VE GOT NO CHOICE.
IF WE DON'T GET OUT OF HERE
WE'RE GONNA DIE.
MICHAEL.
>THE COMPRESSION DOOR. WE'RE
GONNA HAVE TO RISK IT.
>NO.
>SPLAT. THAT WILL BE THE LAST
SOUND EITHER OF US WILL HEAR.
>JUST KEEP
MOVING AND GENTLY.
WILL YOU QUIT IT WITH THE SOUND
EFFECTS.
KINGSTON, STOP SHAKING. >WHO'S
SHAKING?
>YOU ARE. >AND I WONDER WHY. OH
THEY ARE
GONNA PAY FOR THIS.
>KUMI.
>MICHAEL. GET HER
ON HER FEET. KEEP HER MOVING.
>THIS IS ALL OUR FAULT.
>I'M ALRIGHT.
>SLOW DOWN WILL YOU. YOU'RE
GONNA BREAK YOUR NECK.
>THEY'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
WE'VE GOT TO KEEP MOVING.
>PITY I NEVER PERFECTED
CRYOGENICS.
>NICE THOUGHT. >DON'T WORRY. IT
WILL BE HIS LAST.
>DOESN'T ANY OF THIS LOOK
FAMILIAR? >MAYBE WE'VE GONE TOO
FAR.
>WE'LL BE TOO LATE.
>COME ON THIS WAY.
>KINGSTON, WE'RE LOST AREN'T
WE.
>HERE. IT'S THROUGH HERE. I
KNOW THIS ONE.
THIS WAY. THERE. IT'S GOT TO BE
IT.
>MICHAEL. >JERROD. KUMI.
>JERROD. LISTEN.
>MAYBE WE'RE TOO LATE.
>MICHAEL. >WE'RE HERE.
>IT'S FROZEN SOLID. WE'LL NEVER
GET IT OPEN.
>IF WE COULD UNFREEZE THE
CONTROLS. MICHAEL.
>IT'S FROZEN SOLID. >KUMI, HELP
HIM. >JERROD, THE CONTROLS
THEY ARE FROZEN. >KINGSTON.
GET HELP. >TRY AGAIN.
>THERE'S NO TIME.
>KINGSTON, YOU GUYS HELP US
WEDGE IT OPEN. HEAVE.
>ON HE COUNT OF 3. >CAN'T WE DO
IT ON THE COUNT OF 1? >WE'RE
FREEZING IN HERE.
>COME ON IT'S MOVING. COUNT OF
3.
>HEAVE. >1-2-
>COME ON HEAVE.
(COUGHING)
>KINGSTON. ANNA. >DON'T PANIC.
>ALIENS. >RELAX. THERE'S NO
ALIENS. IT'S JUST US.
>I KNEW IT. >ARE WE GLAD TO SEE
YOU.
>ANOTHER 10 MINUTES. YOU'RE
VERY
LUCKY. >WE'RE SORRY ABOUT THE
CREATURE.
>YEAH, STUPID PRACTICAL JOKE. >
THINK THEY DESERVE TO BE
PUNISHED. >YEAH.
>SLAVES FOREVER.