[ SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE ]
[ PANTING ]
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
WHERE'D HE GO? HE WAS JUST HERE.
THE RICH AND POWERFUL TAKE WHAT THEY WANT.
WE STEAL IT BACK FOR YOU.
SOMETIMES, BAD GUYS MAKE THE BEST GOOD GUYS.
WE PROVIDE...
HARDISON!
YEAH, YEAH. YEAH. ONE SECOND, ELIOT.
-UH, PARKER. PARKER. -WHAT?
GUESS WHAT WE'RE DOING SATURDAY NIGHT.
UM, GOING TO THE --
WRONG.
WE'RE GOING TO FIGHTING ROBOTS AT THE CIVIC CENTER!
-GREAT. -AND CHECK IT.
WE ARE SITTING RIGHT UP NEXT TO THE PLEXIGLASS.
I CAN BREATHE ON IT.
-OOH, THAT'S CLOSE. -REAL CLOSE.
YOU KNOW WHAT? WE'RE SITTING, LIKE, RIGHT ABOVE THE AREA
WITH THE SPINNING SAW BLADES AND THE MALLETS.
SOUNDS, UH, LOUD.
YEAH, IT'S REAL LOUD,
'CAUSE THEY SEND THEM IN, THEY FIGHT TO THE DEATH.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN? YOU KNOW WHAT?
[ Voice breaking ] I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE EVER EXPERIENCED THIS,
BUT HAVE YOU EVER SEEN, LIKE, A ROBOT BLEED OUT OIL?
IT'S SO...EMOTIONAL.
-I MEAN -- -HARDISON!
YEAH, I'M COMING, MAN!
SUCH A -- BUT YOU DOWN, RIGHT? WE GOOD?
-MM-HMM, MM-HMM. -WE GOING? UH-HUH.
ALL RIGHT. GOOD TIMES.
♪ WHAT? GET IT, GET IT
-♪ ROBOTS, WHAT? -♪ WHAT?
♪ WHAT? WHAT?
WHAT? SOPHIE!
NOT EVEN FOR A LITTLE WHILE?
UNH-UNH. I TOLD YOU. I HAVE PLANS.
HEY, AND IT IS A VALID STRATEGY.
IT'S NOT STRATEGY, ALL RIGHT?
BETTING ON EVERY HAND IS NOT STRATEGY. IT'S ANNOYING.
I JUST GOT A PHONE MESSAGE FROM DETECTIVE BONANNO,
SAYING THAT HE -- HE WANTS TO COME OVER.
-HE'S -- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO. -THIS.
-NO, NO, GUYS. -OH, COME ON.
YOUR FATHER HAD A POKER GAME FOR 30 YEARS.
POLICE, CRIMINALS AT THE SAME TABLE.
THIS IS GOOD FOR YOU.
YES, I WANT TO BE LIKE MY FATHER.
GOOD INSIGHT, SOPHIE.
NICE.
YOU KNOW, LIVING INSIDE YOUR OWN HEAD, NATE,
ONLY HAVING CONVERSATIONS WITH YOUR CREW --
-THAT AIN'T RIGHT. -MNH-MNH.
NAME ONE PERSON YOU CAN HAVE A CONVERSATION WITH
WHO ISN'T ON THIS TEAM.
-DON'T SAY MAGGIE. -DON'T SAY MAGGIE.
LOOK, I GOT MY BUDDIES THAT WERE IN THE SERVICE.
HELL, EVEN HARDISON'S GOT HIS LITTLE INTERNET FRIENDS.
THEY'RE ALL ELVES AND GNOMES, BUT AT LEAST --
THEY'RE ORCS. THEY'RE ORCS. YOU JUST DON'T LISTEN.
I HAVE DINNER PLANS.
EVEN PARKER'S MEETING A FRIEND TONIGHT.
MM-HMM. REMEMBER PEGGY FROM THAT JURY JOB IN LOS ANGELES?
TECHNICALLY, SHE'S ALICE'S FRIEND --
-YOU'RE ALICE. -YOU'RE ALICE, ACTUALLY.
SHE MOVED TO BOSTON LAST YEAR,
SO WE'VE BEEN DOING BRUNCH AND OTHER NORMAL-PEOPLE STUFF.
AND WE'RE VERY PROUD OF YOU.
FOR HAVING BRUNCH?
WELL, IT'S NOT HARD. THERE ARE FORKS.
SO, GIRLS' NIGHT OUT, BOYS' NIGHT POKER.
IT'S CHARACTER-BUILDING FOR EVERYONE.
HAVE FUN.
DO NOT LET HIM GO OFF AND SULK.
I'VE GOT TO TALK TO YOU.
UNH-UNH, NO. I CAN'T RIGHT NOW. I'M IN A HURRY.
-NO, IT'LL ONLY TAKE A SECOND. -NO, NO, NO.
-IT'S NOT A GOOD TIME. -WAIT!
-PARKER, IN OR OUT? COME ON. -NO.
YOU KNOW THAT THING YOU DO WHEN YOU FIX WHATEVER I'M DOING WRONG?
-YOU MEAN ADVICE? -MM-HMM.
-I'M GUESSING YOU AND HARDISON? -MM-HMM.
OKAY, SO, HE KNOWS STUFF, RIGHT?
-AND I KNOW STUFF, TOO. [ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
BUT MY STUFF IS COMPLETELY DIFFERENT FROM HIS STUFF.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT, YEAH.
IT'S JUST TYPICAL EARLY RELATIONSHIP JITTERS, ALL RIGHT?
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ] -JUST BE PATIENT,
AND SOON YOU'LL BE -- YOU'LL BE THICK AS THIEVES.
WAIT! YOU HAVEN'T FIXED ME YET.
OH, COME ON. I'M LATE.
CAN'T YOU TALK TO YOUR FRIEND PEGGY?
NO, SHE'S GOT A BLIND DATE.
I'M SUPPOSED TO GO CHECK HIM OUT FIRST
TO MAKE SURE ILUVPAWS72 ISN'T A DISASTER.
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGING ] -WHO?
WELL, THEY MET ONLINE. THEY'RE BOTH CAT LOVERS.
AND SHE DOESN'T KNOW WHAT HE LOOKS LIKE
BECAUSE THEY BOTH USE CATS AS THEIR PROFILE PICTURES.
GOOD NIGHT, PARKER. HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
HEY.
-HI. -HI.
OH. OH, GOSH, I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M DOING THIS.
-IS HE HERE YET? -NO, NOT YET.
-YOU CAN RELAX. -OH, GOD. YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I'M TAKING A PERFECT STRANGER TO A PARTY I'M CATERING.
AND IT'S AT THE VENEZUELAN CONSULATE.
I MEAN, THAT'S A BIG DEAL FOR ME.
-YEAH. [ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
OH. HELLO?
WHAT? NO, NO, NO, NO. NO.
THE AREPAS ARE SUPPOSED TO BE FLASH-FRIED, NOT DEEP-FRIED.
WHAT?
NO.
I'M SORRY. CAN YOU EXCUSE ME JUST FOR ONE SECOND? OKAY.
YOU KNOW WHAT? YOU NEED TO PUT GUSTAVO ON THE PHONE NOW.
YES, SIR. WHAT CAN I GET FOR YOU?
CAN I GET A TEQUILA, TOP-SHELF, VERY COLD,
AND...
HMM -- A COSMOPOLITAN?
NO TAB. I'M NOT STAYING.
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING ]
[ BEEPING ]
[ Ringing ]
-BAM! [ LAUGHS ] [ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
YOU BET OUT ON A PAIR OF 2s?
NEVER TELL ME THE ODDS.
RESPECT THE GAME. RESPECT THE GAME.
RESPECT THE SWAG.
HEY, GIRL. I'M A LITTLE BUSY.
I JUST UPLOADED SOME PHOTOS TO MY SkyDrive.
CAN YOU RUN THAT FACE THING THAT TELLS YOU IF PEOPLE ARE BAD?
YOU MEAN THE ONE THAT TOOK ME
SIX KNOCKDOWN, DRAG-OUT MONTHS TO HACK?
YEAH.
GIRL, I'M TRYING TO PROVE MY MANHOOD WITH MY BOYS.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING? WITH MY BOYS.
PLEASE?
-H-HANG ON. -HARDISON, YOU IN OR OUT?
WHAT?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION IN DISTANCE ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
OH, OH, OKAY.
PARKER, CRAIG MATTINGLY.
HE'S WANTED FOR BURGLARY AND GRAND LARCENY
IN A WHOLE BUNCH OF COUNTRIES.
He is trouble.
AND HE -- HE'S GOT SOME STRIKINGLY GOOD FEATURES --
SQUARED-UP JAW AND EVERYTHING.
P-PARKER, WHAT ARE YOU DOING WITH THIS GUY?
THANKS. YOU'RE THE BEST.
-Wait. Parker, wait. I -- [ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
HEY!
TO A NIGHT OF UNBRIDLED DEBAUCHERY.
I'LL DRINK TO THAT.
TARA, WE'VE BEEN FRIENDS FOR SO LONG.
WHY DO WE NEVER WORK TOGETHER?
WELL, YOU ONLY NEED ONE GRIFTER PER CREW.
IT'S A SILLY RULE.
A YACHT IN SAINT-TROPEZ, YOU AND ME --
-IMAGINE THE DAMAGE WE'D DO. -[ LAUGHS ]
-WELL, THERE IS THAT. [ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
HELLO?
Sophie, I need your help.
IT'S MY FRIEND PEGGY'S BLIND DATE.
I'm sending you a photo.
UNH-UNH, NO. PARKER, LISTEN.
TARA AND I JUST SAT DOWN.
DOES THIS MAN LOOK LIKE "ILUVPAWS72"?
YUM.
AND LOOK WHAT HARDISON FOUND.
[ SIGHS ]
OOH. WANTED IN MULTIPLE JURISDICTIONS.
BAD BOY.
WELL, HE MUST BE TARGETING YOUR FRIEND FOR A REASON.
YEAH. WE HAVE TO HELP HER.
ALL RIGHT. THIS PLACE IS DEAD, ANYWAY.
ZOOM IN ON THE PICTURE -- THE PART WITH THE WALLET.
UH-HUH. STAYING AT THE PALAESTRA.
WE COULD TOSS HIS ROOM, SEE WHAT WE CAN FIND.
ALL RIGHT, PARKER.
-Don't do anything until we -- [ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
PARKER?
PARKER!
[ GROANS ]
HI, I'M PEGGY.
-YOU'RE PEGGY? -MM-HMM.
-TABBYFAN76? -GUILTY AS CHARGED.
ILUVPAWS72 -- CRAIG MATTINGLY. IT'S GREAT TO MEET YOU.
YOU TOO.
-OH. THANK YOU. -MM-HMM.
AHH.
WELL, THIS PLACE IS SWELL,
BUT WE SHOULD REALLY GET TO THAT PARTY OF YOURS.
RIGHT, THE PARTY THAT I, UH -- THAT I'M CATERING,
BECAUSE I'M A CATERER.
-YEAH. -YEAH.
GALA AT THE VENEZUELAN CONSULATE.
WE SHOULD GO.
OH, UH, WHAT'S THE RUSH?
WELL, YOU KNOW, I'M A COUNTRY VETERINARIAN.
IT'S NOT EVERY DAY I GET TO BREAK OUT THE FORMAL WEAR.
RIGHT, OKAY.
UM, WELL, I JUST HAVE TO MAKE A CALL,
BECAUSE I HAVE TO CALL MY CAT.
HE LIKES TO HEAR MY VOICE ON THE MACHINE.
WHEN I GO OUT, HE GETS SAD.
SOMETIMES HE CRIES, AND THE NEIGHBOR CALLS. IT'S CRAZY.
DON'T MOVE. I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
OKAY.
[ SIGHS ]
-SORRY. -IT'S OKAY.
OKAY. IS HE HERE? WHAT'S HE LIKE?
-YEAH. -GREAT.
[ SIGHS ] OH, NO.
YEAH.
YOU KNOW, I REALLY LIKED THIS ONE.
HE SENT ME THE MOST HEARTBREAKING E-MAIL
ABOUT DECLAWING.
-I'M SORRY. -JUST LET HIM DOWN EASY FOR ME.
-TELL HIM I COULDN'T MAKE IT. -OF COURSE.
ALL RIGHT, I HAVE TO GO TO WORK. THANK YOU FOR SAVING ME.
YES. THAT'S WHAT FRIENDS ARE FOR.
HMM.
[ BEEP ]
ALL RIGHT, CRAIG MATTINGLY.
WHAT'S YOUR GAME?
TARA! WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
-UH, SEARCHING THE ROOM? -NO, NO, NO.
YOU CAN'T JUST BARGE IN AND BREAK THE JOINT.
YOU HAVE TO SLOW DOWN, GET ACQUAINTED WITH THE ENVIRONMENT.
WHAT, YOU'RE NOT ONE OF THOSE BOYLAN
TOUCHY-FEELY-VIBE TYPES, ARE YOU?
THE BOYLAN METHOD TEACHES US
TO TREAT A SEARCH LIKE A CRIME SCENE.
YOU KNOW, WE ONLY GET ONE CHANCE TO --
OKAY, YOU KNOW WHAT THEY TEACH US AT QUANTICO?
LIGHTNING STRIKE. YOU NEVER HAVE AS MUCH TIME AS YOU THINK.
[ BEEP ] -OOPS.
-Quantico. -[ Mockingly ] "Quantico."
REALLY? THAT'S THE FIRST PLACE YOU LOOK? THE PILLOWS?
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
STILL LOOKING, SIR.
DO YOU WANT US TO GO BACK TO THE EVENT?
No, no.
[ SNEEZES ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ GUN COCKS ]
DON'T MOVE.
YOUR SAFETY'S ON.
VáMONOS.
[ SIGHS ]
THE SAFETY WAS OFF.
NOT TO A GRIFTER.
[ Mockingly ] NOT TO A GRIFTER.
NO, I LOVE ALL KINDS, EVEN CATFISH.
WHAT KIND OF CATS DO YOU LIKE?
OH, YEAH, I LIKE BIG ONES,
YOU KNOW, LIONS AND TIGERS -- KIND OF A MIX.
-LIKE A LIGER? -YEAH.
YOU KNOW, I MUST HAVE LOST MY INVITATION.
YEAH, I'M THE CATERER, SO I'M ON THE STAFF LIST.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE AN INVITATION, I CAN'T LET YOU IN.
I'M GOING TO NEED YOU TO WAIT HERE, MA'AM.
MA'AM? DON'T CALL ME MA'AM!
OKAY, YOU KNOW, I NEED TO CHECK THIS.
-I HAVE TO -- -NO.
GOOD EVENING. THANK YOU.
OKAY, IN WE GO. VENEZUELA.
OOH, ARRIBA.
[ TANGO MUSIC PLAYS ]
I SHOULD LET YOU GET TO WORK.
YES, THE CATERING.
BUT I HATE TO LEAVE YOU BY YOURSELF.
WELL, DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
[ SMOOCHES ] I MAKE FRIENDS EASILY.
[ SIGHS ]
[ FEEDBACK ] -SOPHIE, TARA? YOU THERE?
RIGHT OUTSIDE. WHAT DO YOU SEE?
HE'S PAYING A LOT OF ATTENTION TO THREE GUYS WITH BRIEFCASES.
ARE THEY HERE TOGETHER OR SEPARATELY?
SEPARATELY. I DON'T THINK THEY KNOW EACH OTHER.
All right, well, we're almost there. Just hold on.
SECRET SERVICE ALIAS.
I'M HERE TO PROTECT HIGH-LEVEL DIGNITARIES.
I'LL BRING YOU IN AS MY DEPUTY.
[ SCOFFS ]
YOU'RE SERIOUS? I DON'T THINK SO.
SUIT YOURSELF.
MM-HMM.
THANK YOU, SPECIAL AGENT.
[ Russian accent ] AGENCY SENT ME.
ALL RIGHT.
RUSSIAN ESCORT? SO THREE YEARS AGO.
THANK YOU, SIR.
HEY, YOU WANT I CALL YURI FROM DOWNSTAIRS?
HE WAS GOLDEN GLOVE BOXER. NOW GO! GO!
WHY SO HARSH?
[ Normal voice ] HE THOUGHT I WAS A PROSTITUTE.
BLOODY CHEEK.
-OOH, DIPLOMATIC I.D. -[ LAUGHS ] NICE.
VERY HANDY FOR GETTING OUT OF PARKING TICKETS.
AH, OOH.
NOW, LET'S FIGURE OUT WHAT MR. MATTINGLY'S GAME IS.
SO MUCH FOR A NIGHT OF UNBRIDLED DEBAUCHERY.
OH, BOO-HOO.
JUST LAST WEDNESDAY, YOU WERE SIPPING CHAMPAGNE
ON A G4 WITH A RACING-CAR DRIVER.
YES, WHO THINKS I'M HEIR TO THE PILLSBURY FORTUNE.
ANY GUESS HOW LONG THAT'LL LAST?
WHATEVER HAPPENED TO THAT NICE CHEF IN LYON
-WITH THE FABULOUS SILVER HAIR? -OH, NO.
HE THINKS I'M A PROFESSIONAL GOLFER...
OR BANKER -- I KEEP FORGETTING.
I GOT SO MANY LIES, I HAVE TO STORE THEM ON MY PHONE.
THE LAMENT OF THE GRIFTER --
WHO REALLY KNOWS US?
TWO THUGS CHASING ME INTO TRAFFIC?
IS THAT THE WAY THE CARTELS DO THEIR BUSINESS THESE DAYS?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
SURE YOU DON'T.
IF I OFFERED TO SELL YOU SOMETHING,
YOU'D NEVER TRY TO STEAL IT FIRST.
WOULD YOU?
I BROUGHT THE MONEY IN THE BRIEFCASE, LIKE YOU ASKED.
NOW CLOSE THE DEAL.
NO DEAL...NOT UNTIL I HEAR ALL THE OFFERS.
MY MISTAKE.
HEY, HEY, HEY, YOUR FINGERS ARE IN THE WATER GLASSES.
RIGHT, NOW YOU NEED TO GO BACK AND GET NEW ONES.
-[ GROANS ] -DON'T ROLL YOUR EYES AT ME.
ALICE?
ALICE! WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
[ COUGHS ]
WAIT, I SAW HIM AT THE BAR.
-IS THAT ILUVPAWS72? -YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M REALLY BAD AT EXPLAINING THINGS,
SO CAN WE JUST SKIP TO THE PART WHERE YOU'RE NOT MAD AT ME?
OH, MY GOD, LOOK AT HIM.
NO, NO, PEGGY, HE'S NOT WHO YOU THINK, OKAY?
HE'S A HOT GUY WHO LIKES CATS.
-AND YOU STOLE HIM FROM ME! -NO.
WAIT. YOU STOLE MY INVITATION, TOO, DIDN'T YOU?
-NO, I WAS JUST TRYING TO HELP. -WELL, YOU DIDN'T HELP!
GOD, I THOUGHT WE WERE FRIENDS.
ALL RIGHT, SO, THE THUGS WHO WERE CHASING HIM
WERE LOOKING FOR SOMETHING.
I THINK HE'S HOLDING A SALE.
THE GUESTS THERE WITH THE SHINY CASES -- THEY'RE THE BUYERS.
THE QUESTION IS, WHAT'S HE SELLING?
YEAH.
PARKER, WHAT'S HIS ANGLE?
[ SIGHS ]
PARKER?
SORRY.
UM, I SAW HIM STALLING THE MEAN-LOOKING GUY,
SO WHATEVER HE'S SELLING, HE DOESN'T HAVE IT ON HIM.
-WELL, WHY WOULD HE DO THAT? -IT'S CALLED A STOP-AND-SHOP.
YOU STEAL SOMETHING, THEN TURN AROUND AND SELL IT ON-SITE --
SAVES YOU THE RISK OF TRANSIT AND STORAGE.
PARKER, WE'RE GONNA FIX THINGS WITH YOU AND PEGGY.
NO, I KNOW, BUT IT'S NOT JUST ABOUT ME.
I USED PEGGY'S INVITE TO GET MATTINGLY INTO THE PARTY,
SO WHATEVER HE'S UP TO, SHE'S GONNA GET BLAMED FOR.
THEN WE'LL JUST HAVE TO STOP HIM.
TARA AND I WILL COVER THE BUYERS.
YOU STICK WITH MATTINGLY.
LET HIM STEAL HIS MYSTERY ITEM.
WITH ANY LUCK, WE'LL TAKE THEM ALL DOWN.
TARGET'S ON THE MOVE.
[ SIGHS ]
THERE YOU ARE!
[ Slurred ] CATFAN72, OR WHATEVER IT IS.
[ LAUGHS ] LOOK, MICHE.
WHOO!
IT'S FROM SUGARCANE.
PEGGY, WHAT ABOUT THE CATERING, HUH?
OH, THEY SAID I'M NOT ALLOWED
TO BE AROUND FIRE RIGHT NOW, SO DRINK!
-MMM. -IT'S 45% ALCOHOL.
IT'S A GOOD THING I CAN HOLD MY L--
-OOH! -[ BOTH LAUGH ]
OH, WHAT'S THROUGH HERE?
UH, MY FRIEND WORKS HERE.
UM, HE BORROWED MY SWEATER, AND HE LEFT IT INSIDE.
OH, I LOVE SWEATERS.
I KNIT ONE FOR MY CAT ONCE WITH LITTLE MICE ALL OVER IT.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
YOU ARE SO CUTE.
YOU'RE TALL.
-OH, OH! -OH! OH!
-OH, LET'S GO. -GREAT.
MOVE OVER, OR HE'S NOT GONNA HEAR YOU.
IF I GET ANY CLOSER, I WILL BE STANDING ON HIM.
NOW SHUSH. I'M STARTING.
I TOLD YOU. MM-HMM. WE BROUGHT ENOUGH.
I KNOW HE EXPECTS BIG OFFERS.
IT'S WORKING.
DON'T YOU TELL ME WHAT TO DO!
Deep tan means he lives in a warm climate.
I'D SAY RICH TEXAN, OIL MAN, MAYBE.
HUH. PRIVATE TAILOR.
YUMMY, TOP-OF-THE-LINE ITALIAN FABRIC.
NOT AFRAID TO SHOW HIS WEALTH. I LIKE THAT IN A MAN.
BIG RING, HUGE WATCH.
WHAT ARE YOU, THE WARDROBE WHISPERER?
It works.
HMM. THERE'S MORE TO IT, SOPH.
IF HE'S SO RICH, WHY ISN'T ANYBODY MINGLING WITH HIM?
I see micro-expressions of fear in the people around him.
They're avoiding him.
I RECOGNIZE HIS TYPE. HE WORKS FOR THE DRUG CARTELS.
CAN YOU READ MY MICRO-EXPRESSION?
[ Laughs ]
BITE ME.
I BROUGHT HALF A MILLION. [ LAUGHS ]
WHAT MORE DOES MATTINGLY WANT?
MICRO-EXPRESSIONS OF ANXIETY,
FOLLOWED BY RELIEF, AND THEN PRIDE.
Rich Texan brought a lot more than half a mill.
RICH TEXAN IS RICH, BUT NOT THAT RICH.
HIS ROLEX IS A FAKE.
I'D SAY HE'S CARRYING $600K.
YES, MM-HMM. I CAN GET THE FULL MILLION.
YOU WANT ME TO MAKE THE CALL?
HUH.
CARTEL HEARD OUR OFFER AND LOOKS UNFAZED. LOOK AT HIM.
I MEAN, YOU ONLY EAT WHEN YOU FEEL SAFE.
I SEE PRIDE AND CONTEMPT.
HE BROUGHT MORE THAN $1 MILLION.
ALL RIGHT.
GUY WITH THE GLASSES -- HE'S AN ODD DUCK, ISN'T HE?
YEAH, I CAN'T GET A READ ON HIM AT ALL.
WHAT'S HIS GAME?
WELL, LET'S GO FIND OUT.
SECRET SERVICE. CAN WE HAVE A WORD WITH YOU?
UMBERTO GARCIA,
PROFESSOR OF LATIN AMERICAN STUDIES AT HARVARD.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
PROFESSOR, THE MAN THAT YOU'RE MEETING WITH TONIGHT
IS HERE TO STEAL SOMETHING, AND WE'RE HERE TO STOP HIM.
CAN -- CAN YOU TELL US WHAT HE'S AFTER?
INFORMATION --
THE EXACT RESERVE LEVELS OF THE OIL FIELDS OF VENEZUELA,
NOT THE LIES THE GOVERNMENT HAS BEEN SPREADING.
THOSE LIES ARE ALL THAT'S KEEPING THE GOVERNMENT IN POWER.
THE OPPOSITION COULD USE THAT INFORMATION
TO TOPPLE THE CURRENT REGIME.
AND THE DRUG CARTELS CAN USE IT
TO KEEP THE GOVERNMENT OFF THEIR BACK.
A TEXAS OIL SPECULATOR CAN USE IT
TO MAKE A FORTUNE BETTING ON THE PRICE OF CRUDE.
YOU'RE A TEACHER.
UH, WHERE DID YOU GET THE MONEY FOR YOUR BID?
I HAVE SOMETHING BETTER THAN MONEY.
[ CHILDREN SINGING IN SPANISH ]
I COME HERE WITH ONLY THE HOPES AND DREAMS
OF THE VENEZUELAN PEOPLE TO TRADE.
-[ LAUGHS ] THAT'S HILARIOUS. -THAT'S LOVELY.
WE'LL TAKE THAT.
[ Yawning ] OH, GEEZ. NO SWEATER, HUH?
NO.
-OH. -OH! HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA JUST CHECK MY E-MAIL REAL QUICK.
MM, OKAY.
WELL, I'M GONNA GO CALL THE KITCHEN,
MAKE SURE THEY'RE NOT GOOFING AROUND.
YEAH, YOU GO GET THEM, PEGGY.
-YEAH. [ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS, DIALS ]
I'M YOUR WORST DAMN NIGHTMARE.
I'M A DIRTY COP!
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ] -SO YOU -- EXCUSE ME.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ] -GOT TO TAKE THIS.
Hardison.
HEY. HEY, HEY, HEY. WHAT'S HAPPENING, BABY?
I just sent you a photo of a room.
IF YOU WERE GONNA HIDE A SUPER-SECRET COMPUTER FILE,
where would you put it?
OKAY. LOOK. YOU SEE THAT FRAME ON THE DESK?
-MM-HMM. -IT'S PROBABLY IN THE FRAME.
MM.
P-PARKER, ARE YOU STILL WITH THAT GUY?
-Thanks. -PARKER? PARKER?
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
IT'S ALL BETTER. [ SIGHS ]
I SHOULD GET ONE OF THESE.
-MM-HMM? -YEAH.
FAMILY PHOTOS CAN GO ON THERE,
-A PICTURE OF MY CAT. -HOW CLEVER.
IT'S PERFECT. I HAVE SO MANY PHOTOS OF HER.
HMM.
[ SLURPING ]
I COULD PUT THOSE ON, EVEN LIKE A LITTLE VIDEO,
WHERE SHE'S, LIKE, CLEANING HERSELF.
-OH. WHOOPS. -HMM? AHH.
-[ CLEARS THROAT ] -[ SIGHS ]
[ SIGHS ]
YOU WANT TO HIT THAT DANCE FLOOR?
MM, YEAH. YEAH.
[ DOOR OPENS ] -I'M CHECKING THE SOUTH TOWER.
HOLA.
[ GRUNTING ]
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DON'T THINK MY FRIEND TOLD THEM ABOUT THE SWEATER.
Cruz, check in. Cruz, report.
Cruz, are you there?
OH, COME ON.
I GOT HIM. SOUTH ELEVATOR.
PEGGY, STAND BACK.
OKAY.
LET'S GO.
YOU DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT CATS.
WHOO! WHOA!
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I COULD SURE USE ANOTHER DRINK.
WHO ARE YOU?
[ SCOFFS ] I'M PEGGY. CATFAN772.
-NO, IT'S TABBYFAN76. -OH, YEAH.
AND THE SHORT CON'S NOT YOUR GAME.
NO, YOU GOT THE COCKTAIL DRESS. YOU PICKED THE LOCK.
THE PICTURE FRAME. YOU'RE A THIEF.
A GREAT ONE.
NOW, RELAX. THIS DOESN'T HAVE TO GET UGLY.
I'M GONNA CUT YOU IN, SAY, FOR...20%?
20%?
[ WHISTLES ] 20%?
[ LAUGHS ]
ARE YOU KIDDING ME? I DID EVERYTHING.
YOU COULDN'T EVEN OPERATE A THUMB DRIVE.
PARKER, REMEMBER WHY WE'RE HERE.
RIGHT.
[ CLEARS THROAT ] REMIND ME.
THE HOPES AND DREAMS OF THE VENEZUELAN PEOPLE.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
OH, LOOK, PEGGY, WHATEVER THE HELL YOUR NAME IS,
I HAVE BEEN ON THIS JOB FOR MONTHS.
MY HACKER BUDDY DID THE ENCRYPTION ON THAT DATA,
AND HE TIPPED ME OFF.
ALL YOU DID WAS --
I DON'T WANT MONEY.
YOU DON'T?
NO.
I WANT YOU TO GIVE THE THUMB DRIVE TO PROFESSOR GARCIA
FOR FREE.
WHY?
BECAUSE IT'S THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
[ LAUGHS ]
WELL, AT LEAST I KNOW YOU'RE NOT A COP.
PARKER, TELL MATTINGLY TO WAIT FIVE MINUTES.
HE'LL GET HIS MONEY.
DON'T MOVE.
OH, LOOK, NO SIGN OF RICH TEXAN --
MUST HAVE GOT COLD FEET --
WHICH MEANS THE ONLY BRIEFCASE FULL OF CASH IS THERE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU START A FIRE IN THE KITCHEN.
I GRAB THE BRIEFCASE. WE USE THE CROWD FOR COVER.
I WAS THINKING SOMETHING A LITTLE LESS...TRAMPLE-Y.
LET'S WORK WITH WHAT WE'VE GOT --
TWO IDENTICAL BRIEFCASES.
YOU WANT TO DO A KICK SWITCH.
YES.
I'LL PEEL ESCOBAR AWAY FROM HIS BODYGUARD,
AND YOU -- WAIT. I...
[ GROANS ] IT'S STILL MY IDEA.
[ SLOW MUSIC PLAYS ]
OOH, WAITER.
I -- WHAT HAVE YOU GOT THERE? I'M STARVING.
-HERE YOU GO. -THANK YOU -- OH! I'M SO SORRY.
I JUST -- I -- I STUMBLED.
BUT THANKS. I GOT IT NOW. THANKS.
TELL MATTINGLY PROFESSOR GARCIA IS READY TO MAKE A DEAL.
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ SIGHS ]
YOU GOT THIS FROM A TEACHER?
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN SOME BAKE SALE.
THUMB DRIVE.
YEAH, YEAH, I'M A MAN OF MY WORD.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL.
THE ESTIMATES ON THAT ARE 30% LOWER THAN THE OFFICIAL NUMBERS.
IT'S A GAME-CHANGER. HEY, HEY.
IT'S GONNA BE REAL HARD TO COUNT THAT MONEY
WITH FIVE BROKEN FINGERS.
YOU GOT ME ALL WRONG.
REALLY?
'CAUSE I'D SAY YOU'RE A SECOND-STORY MAN
WHO DOESN'T CARE ABOUT ANYTHING BESIDES HIS NEXT SCORE.
LOOK, I'M GLAD THIS IS GOING TO THE GOOD GUYS FOR ONCE.
I REALLY AM. BUT THIS IS MY JOB.
AND I HAVE PEOPLE DEPENDING ON ME,
SO LET'S JUST LEAVE IT AT THAT, YEAH?
WELL, I BETTER GO FIND MY FRIEND PEGGY.
WHO?
TABBYFAN76.
SHE REALLY LIKES CATS.
YEAH, A LOT. SHE HAS LIKE SEVEN.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
HEY, LOOK, I NEVER GOT YOUR REAL NAME.
OH. PARKER.
WAIT, NOT THE PARKER?
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ CELLPHONE DIALS ]
WHERE ON EARTH DID YOU LEARN TO TANGO LIKE THAT?
INDIANA.
[ LAUGHS ]
OCTAVIO, I AM MANY THINGS, BUT I AM NOT A LIAR.
-HMM. [ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
WELL, UNFORTUNATELY, I HAVE TO GO.
NOW? WHY?
BUSINESS.
DANCE WITH YOUR BOYFRIEND THE WAY YOU JUST DID WITH ME.
IF HE IGNORES YOU, THEN YOU WILL KNOW HE IS GAY.
ESCOBAR'S ON THE MOVE.
[ SPEAKS SPANISH ]
Sophie, you stay on Escobar.
I'm gonna look for Peggy and make things right.
I HAVE HIM.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
IT'S MATTINGLY... WITHOUT THE BRIEFCASE.
[ GASPS ]
THAT DIRTY DOUBLE-DEALER.
WHERE'D HE GET A SECOND THUMB DRIVE?
YOU COULDN'T EVEN OPERATE A THUMB DRIVE.
I COULD PUT THOSE ON, EVEN LIKE A LITTLE VIDEO,
WHERE SHE'S, LIKE, CLEANING HERSELF.
OH.
HMM?
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
HE'S NOT CLUMSY.
HE'S A DIRTY LIAR.
Yeah.
A DIRTY LIAR WHO'S ABOUT TO OPEN A BRIEFCASE
WITH NOTHING BUT A TAPE RECORDER IN IT.
WAIT, I-I SWITCHED OUT THE BRIEFCASES.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I DON'T KNOW, BUT I'M GONNA FIND OUT.
[ GRUNTING ]
PEGGY?
[ GRUNTING CONTINUES ]
IT'S THE RICH TEXAN.
ESCOBAR MUST HAVE STOLEN HIS BRIEFCASE.
ESCOBAR LOOKED CONFIDENT.
WE FIGURED THAT MEANT HE HAD A MILLION.
IT TURNS OUT IT WAS BECAUSE HE PLANNED TO STEAL THE MONEY
FROM THE HIGHEST BIDDER AND POCKET THE REST.
[ MUMBLING ]
HE MUST HAVE STASHED THE OIL GUY'S MONEY.
ESCOBAR'S ON THE MOVE.
AND AFTER THE SWITCH, HE USED THAT MONEY TO PAY MATTINGLY.
HMM.
WE'RE DONE.
I TOLD YOU I DON'T LIKE PEOPLE WHO WASTE MY TIME,
MR. MATTINGLY.
THIS ISN'T YOUR MONEY, ESCOBAR.
YOU STOLE IT FROM THE OIL GUY.
AND NOW YOU'VE GOT THE THUMB DRIVE,
GIVING YOUR CARTEL CLIENTS LEVERAGE
OF THE VENEZUELAN GOVERNMENT,
SO...YEAH.
WE'RE DONE.
HE'S GOT BOTH BRIEFCASES FULL OF MONEY NOW.
-Parker, what should we -- -HE'S MINE.
HEY. DO YOU THINK ESCOBAR REALIZES THAT WE RIPPED HIM OFF?
THANK YOU.
WOULD YOU DRINK TO LOSING $500K?
[ SIGHS ]
WAIT A MINUTE. WHAT?
WHY WOULD YOU PAY A BRIEFCASE FULL OF CASH FOR SOMETHING
AND THEN THROW IT AWAY?
I'VE ONLY SEEN THIS HAPPEN ONE OTHER TIME BEFORE,
IN ODESSA.
WHAT HAPPENED IN ODESSA?
THERE WAS A BOMB IN ODESSA.
[ ELEVATOR BELL DINGS ]
HEY.
[ GASPS ] HEY, I CAN EXPLAIN.
-TOO LATE. -LET HIM GO.
-PARKER. -[ COUGHS ]
I THOUGHT I HAD YOU ALL WRONG,
THAT YOU HAD PEOPLE DEPENDING ON YOU.
I DO! I'VE GOT TWO EX-WIVES, A BOOKIE, AND A BARKEEPER.
WELL, TO BE FAIR, THE LAST TWO ARE THE SAME GUY, BUT --
WE'VE GOT BIGGER PROBLEMS.
ESCOBAR DOESN'T WORK FOR THE CARTEL ANYMORE.
HE WORKS FOR THE VENEZUELAN GOVERNMENT.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
WHY WOULD THE GOVERNMENT PAY FOR THEIR OWN DATA?
THEY DON'T WANT TO BUY IT.
THEY WANT TO BLOW IT UP,
ALONG WITH EVERYBODY ELSE IN THIS BUILDING.
THEY CAN BLAME THE BOMBINGS ON PROFESSOR GARCIA,
CALL HIM A TERRORIST.
BYE-BYE, OPPOSITION LEADER. BYE-BYE, THUMB DRIVE.
EVERYTHING TIED UP WITH A NICE BOW.
ALL THANKS TO YOU.
WELL, THIS WAS JUST SUPPOSED TO BE A SIMPLE STOP-AND-SHOP.
YEAH, YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD AT RUNNING ONE OF THOSE.
LET'S SEE HOW YOU ARE AT FINDING A BOMB.
OKAY, THIS PLACE IS HUGE.
WHERE WOULD ESCOBAR HIDE IT?
WELL, ESCOBAR IS TOO SMART TO BRING IT HIMSELF.
HE WOULD HAVE HIRED A SUBCONTRACTOR.
IT WOULD HAVE TO BE SOMEONE WITH UNLIMITED ACCESS,
MAYBE A HIGH-LEVEL DIPLOMAT.
YES. OR THE EXACT OPPOSITE.
THANK YOU.
THE FIRST THING ANY WAITER LEARNS
IS HOW TO HOLD A TRAY WITH ONE HAND.
IT'S A LITTLE THIN.
WAIT, NO. I REMEMBER THE WAITER YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
MA'AM? DON'T CALL ME MA'AM!
ALL RIGHT, THAT FOOD CAN'T GO OUT.
-NO, NO. -SO I NEED TO --
ALL RIGHT, SO, WHERE IS THIS GUY?
PEGGY, ONE OF YOUR WAITERS IS NOT WHO HE SAYS HE IS.
YOU MEAN THE WORST WAITER THAT EVER LIVED?
YEAH, I SEE HIM.
HEY, GUYS, CAN YOU CLEAR OUT, PLEASE, JUST FOR A SECOND?
EVERYBODY, CLEAR OUT. THANKS.
NO, NO. NO, NO, NO, DON'T.
SHE HUNG UP.
HEY, SKINNY JEANS. WHERE DO YOU THINK YOU'RE GOING?
I WAS -- I THOUGHT I COULD --
UH-HUH. NO. UH, WHO HIRED YOU?
UH, I'VE GOT MY PAPERWORK OVER THERE IN MY BIKE MESSENGER BAG.
YOU KNOW WHAT? YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE UNTIL I FIGURE OUT WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
THAT KNIFE WAS PART OF A SET!
LOOK, WE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE!
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
WHY CAN'T A SMALL BUSINESS OWNER...
WHO HAPPENS TO LIKE CATS... FIND A NICE GUY?!
-AAH! AAH! -WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
YOU CAN FINISH HIM LATER, OKAY?
FOR NOW, WE JUST NEED TO ASK HIM A QUESTION.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA. OKAY, OKAY. OKAY, OKAY.
IT'S OKAY. OKAY.
OH, GEEZ. CAN SOMEBODY GET THIS GUY SOME ICE?
[ GROANS ]
IT'S IN A SERVING CART? WHICH ONE?
He doesn't know. He was just paid to bring it upstairs.
THE ONE THAT WOULD BLOCK ANY SURVIVORS FROM ESCAPING.
-UH... -OKAY.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
HOW DO WE DO DEFUSE IT?
-YOU'RE ASKING ME? -WELL, YOU WERE IN THE ARMY.
YOU STOLE PAINTINGS.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN YOU KNOW HOW TO DRAW.
ALL RIGHT, PARKER, CLEAR THE ROOM.
BE SUBTLE.
OH.
KA-BOOM!
[ FEEDBACK ]
GOT YOUR ATTENTION! OKAY!
I'M MEG DAWSON. I AM YOUR PARTY PLANNER.
AND THIS IS CHAZ, AND WE ARE HERE TO TELL YOU
THAT THE FIREWORKS ARE ABOUT TO BEGIN!
YES, THAT'S RIGHT, MEG.
THE COLORS OF THE VENEZUELAN FLAG
ARE ABOUT TO LIGHT UP THE SKY,
YELLOW, RED, AND...BLUE WITH STARS.
STARS. STARS.
SO IF YOU COULD ALL JUST FILE OUT IN AN ORDERLY FASHION...
NOW, YEAH.
MáS RáPIDO.
SOPHIE, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
[ Ringing ]
[ DOGS BARKING ] -WHO NEEDS THIS MANY DOGS! AAH!
-WHEW! WHEW! [ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
GET! GET YOUR -- GET YOUR ASS --
WHAT?! I'M BUSY!
LOOK, I JUST SENT YOU A PICTURE.
OH, LET ME GUESS. IT'S A PICTURE OF ANOTHER HANDSOME DUDE.
AAH! AAH!
OKAY, IT'S A BOMB. UM...WHOA.
YES, IT'S A BOMB.
NOW JUST STOP PLAYING WITH THAT DOG AND HELP US!
THAT -- THAT'S A RADICOVA NIGHT TRAIN.
UM, IT'S VERY SOPHISTICATED WORK.
OKAY, YOU SEE -- YOU SEE, THE, UH --
the three wires on the front panel?
YES.
I need you to do this. L-Listen.
CUT THOSE WIRES IN THIS SEQUENCE --
UH, UM, PRIMER, REACTOR, IGNITION TIMER.
BUT -- BUT -- BUT FIRST YOU GOT
TO FIGURE OUT WHICH ONE IS WHICH.
SO GET A NAIL CLIPPER. STRIP THE WIRES.
The live one -- That's the ignition timer.
YES, RIGHT, BUT -- BUT DON'T CUT IT YET.
STRIP. STRIP THE WIRES, OKAY?
IF YOU CUT IT, THE BOMB WILL BLOW.
Are you still with me so far?
Three wires in sequence.
STRIP, DON'T CUT.
[ CROWD GASPS ]
I-I-I don't know if y'all are gonna make it.
[ SIGHS ]
THAT IS THE FIRST THING WE'VE AGREED ON ALL NIGHT.
Look. Look. Um, okay, you see the -- you see the...
WE DID IT.
-YEAH. -YEAH.
OH! [ LAUGHS ]
-OKAY. -OH, I'M SORRY.
IT'S NOT EVERY DAY I GET TO BE THIS CLOSE TO PARKER.
FIVE YEARS AGO, I WAS CASING OUT
THE CHáCARA DO CéU MUSEUM IN RIO,
AND YOU BOOSTED A MATISSE RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF CARNIVAL.
-IT'S... -YEAH.
I'M -- I'M NOT THAT BIG ON PARTIES.
SO THE WORD IS YOU GOT OUT OF THE GAME.
NO, NO, I-I'M STILL IN THE GAME.
I JUST PLAY BY A DIFFERENT SET OF RULES.
I WAS TOLD YOU HAVE SOMETHING FOR ME.
UH...
YOU CAN THANK HIM.
MAY GOD BLESS YOU
AND GRANT THE PEOPLE OF VENEZUELA
THEIR HOPES AND DREAMS.
SO, STEALING, NOT FOR YOURSELF,
BUT FOR OTHER PEOPLE'S HOPES AND DREAMS AND WHATNOT.
SO, I GUESS WHAT YOU'RE SAYING IS
THAT SOMETIMES BAD GUYS... DON'T HAVE TO BE SO BAD.
YEAH.
HEY, BEFORE THE COPS GET HERE, I GOT SOMETHING FOR YOU.
ALICE, YEAH, IT'S OKAY.
YOU WERE JUST LOOKING OUT FOR ME.
-AND NOW I KNOW YOUR SECRET. -YOU DO?
YEAH. YOU'RE A SPY.
MM. THAT'S RIGHT. I AM A SPY.
-WHAT A RELIEF. -WHEW.
AND THAT IS WHY I CANNOT TELL YOU
ANYTHING ELSE ABOUT WHAT I DO.
MNH-MNH. NATIONAL SECURITY.
OH, YEAH, OF COURSE. OF COURSE. I GET IT.
[ LAUGHS ]
OH, I JUST WISH ESCOBAR HADN'T GOTTEN AWAY, RIGHT?
OH, HE WON'T GET FAR.
GOING SOMEWHERE?
YOU CAN'T ARREST US. WE'VE DONE NOTHING WRONG.
I GOT ATTEMPTED MURDER, KIDNAPPING,
GRAND THEFT.
GRAND THEFT OF WHAT?
THAT'S HIM. I WANT MY MONEY, ESCOBAR.
I DON'T EVEN HAVE HIS MONEY. I DON'T EVEN HAVE HIS MONEY.
UGH!
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU KNOW, ALL I WANTED TO DO TONIGHT
WAS MEET A REALLY NICE GUY.
BUT I GUESS I HELPED STOP A BOMBING, SO THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
CHEERS.
MMM. WELL, I'M GONNA GO.
BUT I WILL SEE YOU NEXT WEEK AT BOOK CLUB.
OKAY, "THE CONTORTIONIST'S DAUGHTER."
I AM LOVING IT, AND I WILL SEE YOU THERE.
OKAY, GREAT. [ CHUCKLES ]
ALL RIGHT.
OH, AND YOU KNOW WHAT? MARGE, YOU SHOULD COME, TOO.
AH. OKAY.
MARGE?
I HAD TO COME UP WITH SOMETHING. I KNOW. I KNOW.
LISTEN, PARKER.
I WANTED TO APOLOGIZE ABOUT GIVING YOU
THE COLD SHOULDER ABOUT HARDISON EARLIER.
OH, THAT'S OKAY.
-I THINK I FIGURED IT OUT. -YOU DID?
YEAH. I MEAN, I WAS WORRIED AT FIRST,
'CAUSE HARDISON AND I ARE DIFFERENT, THE STUFF WE LIKE.
BUT I JUST SPENT ALL NIGHT WITH MATTINGLY,
A GUY WHO LIKES ALL THE SAME STUFF I DO.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN MORE FUN WITH HARDISON.
SO I GUESS THE SAME IS BORING.
WHERE IS MATTINGLY, ANYWAY?
OH, HE TOOK THE CAB BEHIND US.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS TARA'S CAB.
YEAH, IT WAS.
THE THINGS WE DO FOR FRIENDS.
[ SINGING IN SPANISH ]