THE JOEY BISHOP SHOW
JOEY? YOU BETTER LEAVE ME
ENOUGH MONEY TO PAY
THESE BILLS. OK MOM. WHAT ARE
THEY? WELL THERE'S A
GAS BILL, AND THIS PHARMACY
BILL SHOULD BE PAID THIS MONTH.
I GAVE YOU MONEY FOR THE
PHARMACY BILL LAST MONTH. I
USED THE MONEY TO BUY STELLA
A DRESS. OH AND HERE SOMETHING
FROM THE
COUNTY OF LOS ANGELES FOR YOU.
WHAT YOU DO? BUY SOMETHING FROM
CITY HALL?
I DIDN'T BUY ANYTHING. MAYBE
YOU GOT A TICKET FOR JAY
WALKING MA?
OH KNOW I NEVER JAY WALK.
JOEY BARNES YOUR HEREBY SUMMOND
FOR JURY DUTY.
OH GOOD.
JURY DUTY?
"JOEY JOEY JOEY"
THE JOEY BISHOP SHOW
HELLO YOUR HONOR. JOEY BARNES.
WE PLAYED GOLF ABOUT TWO WEEKS
AGO.
I DON'T REMEMBER WHILE YOU WERE
PUTTING.
HELLO? HELLO?
ANYTHING I CAN'T STAND IS A
SORE LOSER. CAN YOU BEAT HIM
ANY OTHER WAY?
I TRIED EVERY OTHER WAY.
WHISTLING WHILE HE WAS PUTTING
WAS THE ONLY WAY I COULD BEAT
HIM.
MOM, WHERE'S THAT FIRST LETTER
I GOT FROM LOS ANGELES COUNTY?
IT'S
OUT IN THE KITCHEN, I'LL GET IT.
THAT WILL GET ME OFF OF JURY
DUTY. JOEY I'M DISAPPOINTED IN
YOU.
SERVING ON A JURY IS A CIVIC
DUTY. AND I
BELIEVE IN CIVIC DUTY, I'M A
LOYAL STAUNCH UPSTANDING
CITIZEN AND LIKE ANY
OTHER LOYAL STAUNCH UPSTANDING
CITIZEN I'M NOT GIVING UP MY
VACATION FOR JURY
DUTY. NOW PLEASE GET THE
LETTER. THANK YOU.
JOEY THAT'S THE TENTH
TIME. YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY NORMAN.
KEEP QUIET AND KEEP PUMPING.
JOEY I'M SORRY TO SAY YOUR
HEALTHY, ALRIGHT?
IF I THINK OF ALL THE MONEY I
SPENT SENDING YOU TO MEDICAL
SCHOOL AND YOU CAN'T FIND ONE
THING
WRONG WITH ME? LOO, WHEN I
STARTED MEDICAL SCHOOL, I
DIDN'T KNOW THE IDEA
WAS TO MAKE PEOPLE SICK. NOW
HERE'S GADGET
THAT COST ME ABOUT FORTY BUCKS,
TRY THIS, WHAT EVER IT IS IT'S
AN OPTHAMOSCOPE FOR
EXAMINING THE EYES. LOOK IN THE
EYES. LOOK IN THE EYES, MAYBE
THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG THERE.
ALRIGHT LOOK UP HERE.
HIGHER? NOW WIGGLE YOUR EYES
BACK AND FORTH.
WIGGLE YOUR EYES? I'M WIGGLING.
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE WHAT I
SEE IN HERE. YOUR FOUND
SOMETHING? AND OLD SILENT MOVIE.
LET'S TRY THE STETHOSCOPE.
ALRIGHT TURN AROUND. ARMS DOWN.
WHAT'S THE
MATTER? DON'T DOCTORS BELIEVE
IN WARM STETHOSCOPS? I'LL BLOW
ON IT
TURN AROUND.
YEH, THA'T'S BETTER. BREATHE IN
HARD
BREATHE OUT. YOUR HEALTHY.
I DON'T CARE, I'M NOT GOING TO
SERVE ON ANY JURY DUTY.
JOEY IF YOU CONTINUE LIKE THIS
YOU'RE GOING TO BE A NERVOUS
WRECK. I AM A NERVOUS WRECK.
THAT'S MY OUT.
WHATS YOUR OUT? WELL IF I HAD A
NERVOUS CONDITION, THEY
CERTAINLY WOULDN'T WANT ME TO
SERVE ON JURY
DUTY, WOULD THEY? YEA. WELL
THATS WHAT I'M GOING TO
DEVELOP, I WANT TO DEVELOP
A NERVOUS CONDITION THAT WILL
MAKE THE TWIST LOOK LIKE YOUR
STANDING STILL.
I'VE BEEN WITH THE JURY
COMMISIONERS OFFICE FOR
THIRTY YEARS AND I'VE NEVER
SEEN A MORE PERFECT SPECIMEN.
BARNES
YOUR IN PERFECT HEALTH. YOU UH
YOU MEAN THERE IS ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING WRONG WITH ME THEN, HEY
DOCTOR?
DO THAT AGAIN? DO WHAT AGAIN?
OH, I DON'T DO IT VOLUNTARILY
IT JUST HAPPENS.
YOU GOT SOMETHING IN YOUR EYE?
NO, WHAT GAVE YOU THAT
IMPRESSION?
THE TWITCHING. OH THAT.
WELL THAT'S FUNNY, I DIDN'T
NOTICE THAT TICK IN YOUR EYE
BEFORE? WELL IT'S NOT ALWAYS
THERE, SOMETIMES IT IS AND
SOMETIMES IT AINT. HOW LONG
HAVE YOU HAD IT?
ROUGHLY ABOUT THREE WEEKS.
WELL I DON'T THINK ITS ANYTHING
SERIOUS, BUT
YOU OUGHT TO TAKE A VACATION.
WELL' FUNNY YOU SHOULD MENTION
THAT
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I HAD
PLANNED, THEN I GOT SUMMON FOR
JURY DUTY. OH I SEE, WELL THEN
ALL YOU NEED IS A CERTIFICATE.,
RIGHT? THAT'S ALL I NEED DOC.
THERE'S YOUR CERTIFICATE.
WELL, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
DOCTOR. YOUR ENTIRELY WELCOME.
THIS SAYS EXCEPTABLE FOR JURY
DUTY, THERE MUST BE
SOME MISTAKE? OH THERE NO
MISTAKE.
AND SO YOUR HONOR
IN SUMMING UP THE CASE FOR THE
DEFENDANT, I FEEL THAT IN VIEW
OF THE EVIDENCE AS PRESENTED,
YOU VERY INTELLIGENT LADIES AND
GENTLEMEN OF THE JURY.
WILL DECIDE ON HIS BEHALF. THE
PLAINTIFF HERE MR ROGERS
HAS FAILED TO PROVE THAT MY
CLIENT WAS NEGLIGENT IN THE
ACCIDENT INVOLVING
THERE TWO CARS. SO YOU SHOULD
LITTLE DIFFICULTY IN ARRIVING
AT YOUR VERDICT.
I WANT TO THANK YOU LADIES AND
GENTLEMAN VERY MUCH. YOUR HONOR
THAT CONCLUDES MY CASE
FOR THE DEFENSE. OK LETS GO
JURY WILL REMAIN SEATED UNTIL I
HAVE GIVEN MY INSTRUCTIONS.
SORRY, SORRY
LADIES AND GENTLEMAN OF THE
JURY YOUR DUTY IN THIS
CASE IS TO DECIDE IF THE
DEFENDANT IS LIABLE FOR DAMAGES
INCURRED IN
AN ACCIDENT BETWEEN HIS CAR AND
THE CAR AND THAT OF THE
PLAINTIFF, HAVING HEARD
THE EVIDENCE AS PRESENTED BY
BOTH THE PLAINTIFF AND THE
DEFENDANT
THE DECISION IS ENTIRELY UP TO
YOU, YOU WILL NOW RETIRE UNTIL
YOU'VE A
VERDICT. FOLLOW ME FOLKS
I'M GOING TO MAKE THIS FLIGHT
AFTER ALL
ISN'T THIS A NICE ROOM
NO QUESTION ABOUT IT AT ALL
IT'S AN OPEN AND SHUT CASE.
WOULD YOU MIND
MR BARNES SITTING OVER THERE.
OH I'M SORRY.
WELL, I VOTE FOR THE DEFENDANT.
NOW WAIT A MINUTE THAT IS NOT
RIGHT.
WELL I VOTE FOR THE PLAINTIFF.
MR BARNES I'M THE FOREMAN OF
THIS JURY AND I'M
GOING TO CONDUCT THIS BALLOTING
AS A THE FOREMAN OF A JURY
SHOULD, NOW LADIES AND GENTLEMAN
WE WILL TRY AN OPENING VOTE TO
SEE HOW WE STAND, JUST WRITE
EITHER THE WORD PLAINTIFF
OR DEFENDANT ON A SLIP OF PAPER
AND PASS IT DOWN TO ME.
WELL, IT WOULD BE APPEAR THAT
WE ARE CLOSE TO A DECISION ON
OUR
FIRST BALLOT. I HAVE ELEVEN
VOTES FOR THE DEFENDANT AND ONE
FOR THE PLAINTIFF
I VOTED FOR THE PLAINTIFF SO
LET'S VOTE AGAIN.
MR BARNES, I HAVE SERVED ON
JURIES BEFORE, AND IT IS NOT
CUSTOMARY
TO TAKE A SECOND BALLOT WITHOUT
SOME FURTHER DISCUSSION. I AM AS
IMPORTANT A MEMBER AS YOU ARE
AND I RECOMMEND WE VOTE AGAIN.
VERY WELL, ALRIGHT LADIES AND
GENTLEMAN CAST ANOTHER BALLOT
IF YOU WILL PLEASE.
MR BANES IT CAME OUT JUST THE
SAME, ELEVEN FOR THE DEFENDANT
AND ONE FOR THE PLAINTIFF. OH I
CHANGED MINE TO. WHAT DID YOU
DO THAT FOR?
I VOTED YOUR WAY. WHY? WELL I
THOUGHT
MAYBE SOMETHING WENT WRONG WITH
THE HAND SIGNALS. NOW
AS WE ALL KNOW, WHEN YOU STOP,
YOU PUT YOUR HAND DOWN
WHEN YOU TURN LEFT YOU PUT YOUR
HAND STRAIGHT OUT AND WHEN YOUR
TURN RIGHT YOU PUT IT STRAIGHT
UP, SOMETHING MIGHT HAVE AWRY.
WELL IN THAT CASE PERHAPS IT
MIGHT BE A GOOD IDEA FOR US TO
RECONSTRUCT THE ACCIDENT.
GOOD. WHY DON'T YOU PRESS THAT
BUTTON THERE TO GET THE BAILIFF
TO BRING IN
THAT BLACK BOARD WITH A DIAGRAM
ON IT. THIS WHOLE THING IS
RIDICULOUS, NOW
WHY DON'T WE JUST TAKE A VOTE.
MR BARNES YOU ARE OUT OF ORDER,
AND IF YOU
PERSIST IN TRYING TO RAILROAD
US THROUGH INTO A FAST VOTE, I
SHALL
REPORT YOU TO THE JUDGE. I
THINK YOU WOULD.
YOU WANT SOMETHING? YES WILL
PLEASE BRING IN THE BLACKBOARD
THAT HAS THE DIAGRAM
OF THE ACCIDENT? RIGHT AWAY.
HURRY UP, WILL YOU PLEASE, I
CAN STILL CATCH THAT 11:30
PLANE? ALRIGHT LADIES AND
GENTLEMAN
LET US REVIEW THE FACTS. WE ARE
CONCERNED HERE WITH CAR
A, CAR B AND CAR C. AND WHAT WE
MUST ASCERTAIN, IS WHETHER CAR
B IN JUXTAPOSITION TO CAR A
CREATED A CONDITION IN WHICH IT
IS INDICATED THAT THERE WAS SOME
NEGLIGENCE. MR FOREMAN I'D LIKE
TO SAY SOMETHING. YES MR BRIAN?
I'M A TRUNK DRIVER SEE? DO YOU
KNOW AN GOOD PLACES TO EAT?
AND I'M PROUD TO SAY THAT I'VE
DRIVEN
263,000 ACCIDENT FREE MILES AND
WHATS MORE, I HAVE A GOLD WATCH
TO PROVE IT THAT WAS GIVEN TO
ME IN RECOGNITION OF
MY SAFE AND CAREFUL DRIVING,
AND IN MY EXPERT OPINION I
THINK THAT
CAR A WOULD HAVE MISSED CAR B
IF HE HAD BEEN ON HIS TOES. OH
NO
I DISAGREE, I THINK IT WAS ALL
THE FAULT OF CAR B
NOW YOU SEE, CAR A WAS GOING
STRAIGHT DOWN THIS LANE
BUT CAR B CROSSED OVER THE
DOUBLE LINE. HOW MANY ACCIDENTS
FREE MILES HAVE YOU HAD MADAM?
OH I DON''T DRIVE.
MY HUSBAND WOULD'NT LET ME NEAR
A STEERING WHEEL.
ALL I KNOW IF CAR A AND CAR B
HAD
STAYED HOME I COULD HAVE BEEN
ON VACATION NOW. WHY SPOIL AND
GOOD THING
WERE GETTING FIVE DOLLARS A DAY
AND CARE FARE.
AND MY OLD MAN'S BEEN OUT OF
WORK A YEAR, AND FIVE DOLLARS A
DAY AINT CHOPPED LIVER.
PLEASE LADIES AND GENTLEMAN MAY
WE CONFINE OUR CONVERSATION TO
THE
CASE AT HAND. THE WHOLE THING
IS VERY SIMPLE
CAR A WAS COMING ONE WAY CAR BE
WAS GOING
ANOTHER, THEY MET POW, LETS
VOTE.
MR BARNES THIS CASE CANNOT BE
SETTLED BY A SIMPLE POW
NOW THE DEFENDANT IN CAR A THAT
CAR C
PULLED OUT IN SUCH A WAY THAT
HE FORCED CAR B OVER INTO THE
PATHWAY OF CAR A
MAY I SAY SOMETHING? GO RIGHT
AHEAD. I'M A CITIZEN OF THE
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
AND I'D LIKE TO SAY SOMETHING.
GO AHEAD MR BARNES. MAY I MR
FOREMAN? GO AHEAD MR BARNES, BY
ALL MEANS
THIS WHOLE THING INVOLVES THREE
HUNDRED AND EIGHTY DOLLARS
WORTH OF DAMAGES, IS THAT
CORRECT
MR FOREMAN. CORRECT. NOW THERE
ARE TWELVE OF US HERE, WHY
DON'T WE ALL CHIP IN
THIRTY ONE DOLLARS AND SEVENTY
FIVE CENTS APIECE, PAY FOR THE
DAMAGES AND GET OUT OF HERE?
LIKE I SAID, MY OLD MAN HASN'T
WORKED FOR A YEAR
AND I AINT CHIPPING ON NOTHING.
I';LL PUT UP YOUR END
LET'S HAVE SOME TEA
SHALL WE HAVE
IT SENT IN, OR SHALL WE FLY TO
CHINA FOR IT, THERE'S A FLIGHT
LEAVING FOR HONK KONG
AT TWELVE O'FIVE
WOULD YOU LIKE ANOTHER CUP OF
TEA MR BARNES? NO THANK YOU
STEWARDESS.
OH THIS IS
SO LOVELY, AND YOU ARE ALL SUCH
CHARMING PEOPLE.
I HAVE A SUGGESTION, WHEN THIS
IS ALL
OVER,WHY DON'T WE GET TOGETHER
FROM TIME TO TIME. WHY DON'T WE
HOW ABOUT IF WE CHIP IN AND
HIRE A LIMOUSINE TO GO AND TAKE
ME TO THE
AIRPORT? I'LL LET HIM DO THE
DRIVING. OH YOUR SO FUNNY.
SAY THIS TEA IS THE DELIGHTFUL,
DO YOU SUPPOSE I CAN HAVE A
SECOND CUP? OF COURSE
YOU CAN. I THINK I WILL HAVE
SOME MORE TOO. FINE
YOU KNOW I HAVEN'T HAD IT SO
GOOD IN ALL OF MY TWO HUNDRED
AND SIXTY THOUSAND
ACCIDENT FREE MILES.
NOW TELL ME, TO WHAT YOU
ATTRIBUTE YOUR SAFE
DRIVING RECORD? I ALWAYS GET A
GOOD NIGHT SLEEP, I KEEP MYSELF
PHYSICALLY FIT
AND I STAY ALERT ON THE
HIGHWAYS, I GIVE THE COURTESY
OF THE ROAD TO OTHER DRIVERS
AND I ALWAYS STOP AT RAILROAD
CROSSINGS, BUT MOST IMPORTANT
OF ALL
GOOD BRAKES.
WOULD ANYBODY HAVE ANY
OBJECTIONS IF WE TOOK ANOTHER
VOTE NOW? WELL I THINK
ANOTHER VOTE WOULD BE IN ORDER
NOW MR BARNES, ALRIGHT EVERYONE
CAST YOUR BALLOTS PLEASE
I NOW HAVE SIX VOTES
FOR THE PLAINTIFF SIX VOTES FOR
THE DEFENDANT AND ONE AIRLINE
SCHEDULE. EXCUSE ME MR BARNES,
I'M BEGINNING TO RESENT YOUR
ATTITUDE.
DO YOU HAVE SOME ULTERIOR
MOTIVE FOR TRYING TO RUSH THIS
CASE THROUHG?
AS A MATTER OF FACT I DO HAVE
AN ULTERIOR MOTIVE FOR TRYING
TO RUSH THIS CASE THROUGH
THIS IS MY FIRST VACATION IN
THREE YEARS, I DO NOT INTEND TO
SPEND IT LOCKED IN
A JURY ROOM. MR BARNES DO YOU
MEAN TO SAY YOU WOULD PLACE
YOUR VACATION OVER YOUR DUTIES
AS A JUROR?
COME ON THIS IS NOT A FEDERAL
CASE IT'S A SIMPLE LITTLE
ACCIDENT INVOLVING CAR A
CAR B CAR C PERIOD. ANY CASE
THAT IS
WORTHY OF A JURY, IS WORTHY OF
HONES CONSIDERATION. REALLY
MR BARNES YOU HAVE ME SO UPSET
THAT I AM GOING TO MOVE THAT WE
ADJOURN
FOR THE DAY. I'LL SECOND THE
MOTION,.
WAIT A MINUTE, YOU CAN'T
ADJOURN THIS IS FRIDAY, IF WE
ADJOURN NOW, WE WILL HAVE TO
COME BACK AGAIN MONDAY
THAT IS CORRECT. WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THAT? THE LONGER THE BETTER
WE'RE STILL GETTING FIVE
DOLLARS A DAY AND CAR FARE.
OH I CAN COME BACK. THEN WE'LL
ALL AGREED
LADIES AND GENTLEMAN, WE WILL
ADJOURN TODAY AND RESUME ON
MONDAY.
IS THAT OK WITH YOU MR BARNES?
NO
I HAVE AND EXCELLENT IDEA, WHY
DON'T I GO ON VACATION AND PHONE
MY VOTE IN? SON OF A GUN
I SWEAR THAT YOU REALLY ENJOY
JURY DUTY. REALLY MR BARNES?
REALLY MR FOREMAN.
YOU KNOW I HAD SUCH A
WONDERFUL WEEKEND. WE WENT TO
DISNEYLAND.
OH WHAT DID YOU DO OVER THE
WEEKEND MR BARNES?
I SAW MY GOLF CLUBS. OHH
HOW DID YOU SPEND YOUR WEEKEND?
I'M BACKING OUT OF MY DRIVEWAY
AND
ALONG COMES THIS CLOWN AND
CLOBBERS ME. YOU MEAN YOU HAD
AN ACCIDENT? YEH. I SUPPOSE
YOU'LL HAVE TO GIVE BACK THE
WATCH NOW? i HOPE NOT.
WELL LADIES AND GENTLEMAN I'M
SURE THAT WE'VE HAD A RELAXING
WEEKEND
IN WHICH TO THINK OVER THE
CASE, AND NOW WE CAN RESUME OUR
DELIBERATIONS WITH
A CLEAR MIND. BEFORE WE BEGIN,
DOES ANYONE HAVE ANYTHING HE
WOULD LIKE TO SAY? YEAH, LETS
VOTE AS SOON POSSIBLE. OH NO I
DON'T
THINK WE'RE READY TO VOTE YET.
THERE STILL IS ONE LITTLE THING
THAT CONFUSES ME, NOW THE
DEFENDANT SAID THAT HE WAS
DRIVING NORTH AT A SPEED OF
TWENTY FIVE MILES AN HOUR.
EXCUSE ME LADY, I DISTINCTLY
HEARD THE DEFENDANT SAY HE WAS
GOING FORTY FIVE
MILES AN HOUR. NO DEAR, HE SAID
TWENTY
FIVE MILES AN HOUR. I HEARD HIM
WITH MY OWN EARS, HE WAS GOING
FORTY FIVE MILES AN HOUR. I
DON'T WANT TO SEEM RUDE BUT I'M
INCLINED
TO AGREE WITH TWO HUNDRED AND
SIXTY THREE THOUSAND ACCIDENT
FREE MILES.
BUT IF WOULD SEEM TO ME THAT
THE SPEED OF THE DEFENDANT'S
CAR WOULD BE
AN IMPORTANT ISSUE IN THIS CASE
AND SINCE THERE SEEMS TO BE
SOME DOUBT I WOULD SUGGEST
THAT WE ASK THE JUDGE TO REVIEW
THAT PORTION OF THE TESTIMONY
FOR US
THATS A GOOD IDEA. THE DREYFUS
CASE DIDN'T TAKE THIS
LONG. OH SHUT UP, IT'S FIVE
DOLLARS A DAY AND CAR FARE.
I'LL GIVE YOU
SIX DOLLARS A DAY AND CAR FARE
IF YOU DON'T SHOW UP.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE IN MIND LADY?
IN REVIEWING THE TESTIMONY
REGARDING THE SPEED OF THE
DEFENDANT'S VEHICLE , I SHALL
QUOTE
QUESTION TO THE DEFENDANT, HOW
FAST WERE YOU GOING AT THE TIME
OF THE
IMPACT, I WAS GOING NORTH AT
ABOUT TWENTY FIVE MILES AN HOUR
YOU SEE I TOLD YOU. I GUESS
THAT CLARIFIES THE POINT.
FOR YOU. THANK YOU YOUR HONOR.
OK LETS VOTE. NOW ONE MOMENT
PLEASE
WILL THE JURY PLEASE REMAIN
SEATED
BEFORE YOU RESUME YOUR
DELIBERATIONS
I'D LIKE TO SAY A FEW WORDS TO
THIS JURY.
I'D LIKE TO COMMEND TO EACH AND
EVERYONE OF YOU FOR YOUR
CONSCIENTIOUS APPROACH TO THIS
CASE. FREQUENTLY IN SIMPLE
CIVIL CASES OF THIS NATURE
A JURY WILL ARRIVE AT A HASTY
VERDICT, YOU HAVE NOT DONE IT
YOU HAVE GIVEN WILLINGLY OF YOU
TIME WITHOUT THOUGHT OF
PERSONAL INCONVENIENCE, EACH
AND EVERYONE OF YOU DESERVES A
VOTE OF GRATITUDE FOR YOUR
UNSELFISH DEVOTION TO
DUTY. PEOPLE LIKE YOU HAVE MADE
THE AMERICAN JURY
SYSTEM SOMETHING WE COULD ALL
BE PROUD OF AND THIS COURT
THANKS YOU
YOU MAY NOW RESUME YOUR
DELIBERATIONS
COME ON VACATION BOY, LETS GO
SIX SEVEN EIGHT
NINE TEN ELEVEN.
WELL, THIS IS INTERESTING, NOW
I HAVE
ELEVEN VOTES FOR THE PLAINTIFF
AND ONE VOTE FOR THE DEFENDANT
I VOTED FOR THE DEFENDANT
OH, I'M SURE YOU'LL WANT TO
CHANGE THAT MR LETS
GET IT OVER WITH? I DON'T WANT
TO CHANGE IT MY VOTE
FOR THE DEFENDANT STANDS. BUT
YOU WERE WILLING TO VOTE EITHER
WAY? WHAT HAPPENED?
THERE IS SUCH A THING AS
DEVOTION TO DUTY
WELL I NEVER THOUGHT I WOULD
HEAR THAT COMING OUT YOU. WELL
YOU HEARD WHAT THE JUDGE
SAID, WE PEOPLE SHOULD BE PROUD
OF THE AMERICAN JURY SYSTEM
THAT WE HAVE.
IN THIS COUNTY. BUT YOU WERE SO
ANXIOUS TO GET AWAY ON YOUR
VACATIO?
WITH AN ISSUE LIKE THIS AT
STAKE I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD
THINK ABOUT PERSONAL
INCONVENIENCE
HERE'S THE WAY I SEE IT. MAY I
HAVE YOUR
UNDIVIDED ATTENTION PLEASE.
HERE WE HAVE CAR A CAR B CAR C
CAR B WAS PULLING AWAY FROM THE
CURB, CAUSING CAR C TO
SWERVE, CAUSING CAR A TO GET
OUT OF THE PATH OF C INTO THE
PATH
OF CAR B. AND YOU WERE WRONG,
TWO HUNDRED AND SIXTY THREE
THOUSAND
FREE MILE OF ACCIDENT, IT WAS
NOT FORTY FIVE MILES AN HOUR
MS DISNEYLAND SAID IT WAS
TWENTY FIVE MILES AN HOUR,
THEREFORE I
HAVE DECIDED IN FAVOR OF THE
DEFENDANT, NOW IF THERE ARE ANY
QUESTIONS
I'LL ONLY TOO HAPPY TO EXPLAIN
IT TO YOU.
HAS THE JURY REACHED A VERDICT?
WE HAVE YOUR HONOR, WE FIND IN
FAVOR OF THE DEFENDANT.
AND THE PLAINTIFF IS INSTRUCTED
TO PAY THREE HUNDRED AND EIGHTY
DOLLARS DAMAGES
AND COSTS. HAVING REVIEWED THE
FACTS IN THIS CASE MYSELF
I FEEL THAT YOU HAVE ARRIVED AT
A VERY FAIR VERDICT
I SUPPOSE WE HAVE TO GIVE
CREDIT TO MR BARNES HERE, HE'S
THE ONE WHO
CONVINCED US ALL THAT WE SHOULD
DECIDE IN FAVOR OF THE
DEFENDANT. WELL I MUST
CONGRATULATE AL OF YOU, YOU'RE
THE KIND OF CITIZENS WE CAN ALL
TAKE PRIDE IN
AND I MUST SAY THAT YOU ARRIVED
AT YOUR DECISION WHEN YOU DID,
BECAUSE I'M LEAVING ON MY
VACATION THIS AFTERNOON. THIS
COURT WILL STAY IN RECESS
FOR TWO WEEKS.
WELCOME TO THE HOLLOW PINE LODGE
THANK YOU. HOW MANY ARE THERE
IN YOUR PARTY SIR? I'M ALL ALONE
OH THATS ALRIGHT. UNDER WHAT
NAME WAS THE RESERVATION SET IN
IT WAS MADE UNDER THE NAMES
JOEY BARNES LAST THURSDAY.
THAT'S CORRECT
LAST THURSDAY TODAY IS MONDAY,
YOU SHOULD HAVE BEEN HERE LAST
THURSDAY
I WOULD HAVE BEEN HERE LAST
THURSDAY BUT I STARTED JURY
DUTY LAST FRIDAY
AND I SPENT FOUR DAYS ON JURY
DUTY, SO HERE I AM MONDAY.
NOW LETS BE VERY VERY SENSIBLE
ABOUT THIS ENTIRE THING I WAS
MERELY TO MY DUTY
AS A CITIZEN. WELL SIR I'M
DOING MY DUTY AS A DESK CLERK
WE ARE ALL FILLED UP. I WOULD
LIKE TO SPEAK TO THE MANAGER
PLEASE. WELL IF YOU INSIST
BUT IT WON'T DO YOU ANY GOOD,
ALRIGHT, MR ROGERS
MR ROGERS DESK PLEASE
WELL, MR BARNES REMEMBER ME?
THE PLAINTIFF? CAR B?
MR ROGERS THIS GENTLEMAN WANTS
A ROOM, OH, WE HAVE A LOVELY
ROOM
FOR MR BARNES IF YOU WOULD JUST
REGISTER
THANK YOU
THREE HUNDRED AND EIGHTY
DOLLARS A WEEK
THREE HUNDRED AN EIGHTY DOLLARS
A WEEK FOR A ROOM?
WITHOUT BATH