THE JOEY BISHOP SHOW
HAPPY ANNIVERSARY DEAR. HAPPY
ANNIVERSARY FRANK.
BETTY WOULD YOU EXCUSE
FRANK AND I FOR JUST A MINUTE;
I WOULD LIKE TO TALK TO HIM
ALONE. WHY SURE JOEY.
THANK YOU. HAPPY ANNIVERSARY
DEAR. HAPPY ANNIVERSARY
SWEETHEART.
WHOO.. WHOO...
FRANK? UMM FRANK?
IF YOU WEREN'T OUT OF WORK AND
YOU HAD A FEW BUCKS IN YOUR
POCKET; WHERE WOULD YOU LIKE TO
TAKE MY
SISTER ON YOUR ANNIVERSARY?
HOME; I GUESS I'D TAKE HER
TO THE COCANUT GROVE. AND HOW
MUCH DO YOU THINK AND EVENING
LIKE THAT WOULD COST YOU?
OH WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE I
DON'T HAVE THE MONEY. I MEAN IF
YOU HAD THE MONEY; HOW MUCH DO
YOU THINK IF WOULD COST?
THE LAST TIME I WAS THERE, IT
COST ABOUT THIRTY DOLLARS.
HERE YOU ARE FRANK
BE MY GUEST MY ANNIVERSARY GIFT
TO YOU AN BETTY; HAVE A NICE
TIME.
BUT JOEY I DON'T KNOW HOW TO
THANK YOU? YOU DON'T HAVE TO
THANK ME AT ALL, HERE ARE CARE
KEYS
YOU CAN USE MY CAR. NOW WHY
DON'T YOU GO TELL BETTY THAT
YOUR GOING TO THE
COCONUT GROVE I'LL CALL IN THE
MEANTIME AND MAKE RESERVATIONS
FOR YOU. YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO
THAT, I ALREADY MADE THE
RESERVATIONS.
JOEY JOEY JOEY
THE JOEY BISHOP SHOW
STARRING JOEY BISHOP
THAT WAS ANOTHER GREAT MEAL
MOTHER BARNES, NOBODY CAN COOK
LIKE YOUR MOTHER.
EH JOEY? NO YOU TOWN ARE
PERFECT COMBINIATION MOM'S THE
WORLDS GREATEST COOK
AND FRANK YOUR THE WORLD'S
GREATEST EATER. FRANK YOUR ALL
WELCOME. WELL THANK YOU MOTHER.
I'LL REMEMBER THAT ESPECIALLY
NOW THAT I'M OUT OF WORK. JOEY
CAN I HAVE THE SPORTS PAGE? I'M
READING THE SPORTS PAGE FRANK,
HOW ABOUT THE
HERE HOW ABOUT THE WANT ADS?
I'M SURE
THAT SOMEWHERE THERE MUST A
GOOD JOB FOR FRANK?
THERE ARE GOOD JOBS FOR FRANK,
HE JUST DOESN'T WANT TO START
FROM THE BOTTOM
HE WANTS TO BE A BIG SHOT IN
SOME FLY BY NIGHT ORGANIZATION.
ALRIGHT FOR YOU TO TALK, YOU
GOT IT MADE, BUT WHAT AM I
SUPPOSED TO DO?
OH FRANK YOU MUSTN'T BE
DISCOURAGED ABOUT TODAY,
ANYBODY CAN GET FIRED
RIGHT JOEY? TEN TIMES IN SIX
MONTHS? WHY DON'T YOU FIND
YOURSELF A JOB
AT A REPUTABLE FIRM AND WORK
YOUR WAY UP LIKE I DID? IN THE
MAIL ROOM?
WELL I ADMIT I STARTED IN THE
MAIL ROOM FRANK BUT LOOK WHAT
I'M DOING NOW?
THAT WAS THE ONLY WAY I COULD
GET INTO PUBLIC RELATIONS;
BESIDES ITS A JOB WITH A FUTURE.
HEY, THAT'S A GOOD IDEA; IF
JOEY WANTS FRANK TO START AT
THE BOTTOM
LIKE HE DID, MAYBE JOEY CAN GET
FRANK A JOB AT HIS PLACE/
MY PLACE? WHY, WHAT A MARVELOUS
IDEA.
THE TWO OF YOU WORKING TOGETHER.
I WOULDN'T MIND WORKING WITH
YOU JOEY.
YOUR RACKETS SOUNDS OK TO ME,
YOU MEET IMPORTANT PEOPLE AND
STARTS AND
BUSINESS TYCOONS, YOU GOT AN
EXPENSE ACCOUNT, I THINK I HAVE
A FLAIR FOR THAT
KIND OF THING. YOU DON'T JUST
JUMP INTO IT, PUBLIC RELATIONS
IS NOT ALL ITS CRACKED UP
TO BE. AND MY BOSS MR WILLOWBY,
HE'S A REAL SLAVE DRIVER.
I WOULDN'T HAVE MY WORST ENEMY
WORK THERE.
I'M NOT YOUR WORST ENEMY, I'M
YOUR BROTHER INLAW. THAT'S WHAT
I MEAN, I MEAN
HE'S A TOUGH MAN TO WORK FOR,
WE DON'T HAVE COFFEE BREAKS YOU
KNOW
WE HAVE ASPIRIN BREAKS. IF YOU
CAN TAKE IT I CAN TAKE IT.
WELL, THERE ARE NO OPENINGS.
I THINK I'M GOING TO BED. WHAT
DO YOU MEAN THERE ARE NO
OPENINGS, YOU GOING TO BED YOU
CAN'T HELP ME GET A JOB, GET A ?
START AT THE BOTTOM, WORK YOU
WAY UP, YOU TELL ME WHEN IT
COMES TO HELPING ME
HE'S JUST ALOT OF ADVICE. FRANK
YOU WOULD BE PERFECT PUBLIC
RELATIONS.
IF YOU THINK FRANK WOULD BE
PERFECT IN PUBLIC RELATIONS, I
WILL TRY AND GET HIM A JOB IN
PUBLIC
RELATIONS. OH THANK YOU JOEY.
TOMORROW I WILL PUT AN AD IN
THE PAPER. JOEY!
FRANK WANTS TO WORK WITH YOU.
COULDN'T YOU JUST ASK MR
WILLOWBY ABOUT FRANK?
CASUAL LIKE? NO, NAH, NEVERMIND.
WHY SHOULD HE ASK ANYBODY ABOUT
ME OR TRY TO HELP ME, I'M JUST A
POOR STRUGGLING OUT OF WORK
GUY, WHOSE
MARRIED TO HIS SISTER.
IT WOULDN'T DO ANY HARM.
MR WILLOWBY WOULD DO ANYTHING
FOR YOU,IF YOU'D
JUST ASK. ALIGHT ALRIGHT I'LL
ASK, FIRST THING TOMORROW MR
WILLOWBY.
DOES THAT MAKE EVERYBODY HAPPY?
OH JOEY THAT'S WONDERFUL.
I ALWAYS SAID, BLOOD IS THICKER
THAN WATER.
I'M NOT PROMISING ANYTHING. AND
IF I DO GET YOU THE JOB FRANK
AND MIND YOU I'M SAYING IF?
IT'S HARD WORK.
I DON'T MIND. THE HOURS ARE
LONG. I DON'T MIND. YO MAY HAVE
TO
GIVE UP YOUR SATURDAYS AND
SUNDAYS. JOEY YOU CAN DO IT I
CAN DO IT.
YOU'LL HAVE TO START FROM THE
BOTTOM AND WORK YOUR WAY UP, IS
THAT UNDERSTOOD? SURE.
OK, HOW MANY WEEKS DO YOU THINK
I WILL HAVE TO STAY AT THE
BOTTOM?
ONLY AN LITTLE FAVOR I'M
ASKING. AFTER ALL I HAVE DONE
FAVORS FOR ME WILLOWBY IN THE
FAST. WELL YOUR CERTAINLY
ENTITLED TO ASK. IT'S NOT LIKE
MY BROTHER INLAW WANTS TO START
OUT AS THE VICE PRESIDENT
WITH THE FIRM. HE'S WILLING TO
TAKE ANY JOB START AT THE
BOTTOM. WHATS SO
DIFFICULT, ITS A SIMPLE THING
YOU JUST WALK IN AND SAY, DO
YOU HAVE AN OPENING FOR MY
BROTHER INLAW?
YOU KNOW YOUR ABSOLUTELY RIGHT,
I'M STANDING OUT HERE MAKING A
WHOLE BIG THING ABOUT NOTHING.
I'LL JUST WALK RIGHT IN AN ASK.
AFTER ALL WHAT CAN HE DO DO TO?
BARBARA DID YOU HAVE TO SAY
THAT?
MR WILLOWBY, MR BARNES WOULD
LIKE TO SEE YOU.
THANKS ALOT
PAL.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO SEE ME
ABOUT. IT'S A RATHER A SMALL
FAVOR, HE'S
WILLING TO START FROM THE
BOTTOM AND WORK HIS WAY TO THE
TOP, HE'LL TAKE ANY KIND OF JOB
AT ALL TO GET STARTED. WHAT ARE
YOU TALKING ABOUT? YOU WOULD'NT
WANT TO HIRE MY BROTHER INLAW
WOULD YOU? HIRE OUR BROTHER
INLAW? THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT I
POMISED MY
FAMILY I'D ASK, SO I ASKED...
NOTHING PERSONAL BARNES, IT'S
JUST THAT I WOULD NEVER
HIRE A RELATIVE EVER. THAT'S
SOMETHING I LEARNED YEARS AGO
WHEN I FIRST
BROKE INTO THIS BUSINESS. YOU
HIRE A RELATIVE, WHAT HAPPENS
IF THEY ARE INCOMPETENT? HOW DO
YOU GET
OF THEM? LET'S DROP THE SUBJECT
BARNES, I'VE GOT AN ASSIGNMENT
FOR YOU TONIGHT.
TONIGHT? WE'VE GOT A NEW
ACCOUNT, BUDDY MORGAN THE
COMEDIAN, HE'S FLYING IN
FOR SOME TV APPEARANCES AND I
WANT HIM TO HAVE THE RED CARPET
TREATMENT.
BUT SIR,... I'VE NEVER MET
MORGAN PERSONALLY, I SHOULD
REALLY PICK HIM UP AT THE
AIRPORT MYSELF, BUT
I'VE GOT THAT BIG MEETING
TONIGHT, SO BARNES CALL FOR HIM
TAKE HIM TO THE HOTEL
YOU MAY HAVE FORGOTTEN MR
WILLOWBY, I'M HANDLING THE PHIL
FOSTER OPENING TONIGHT, OH YES
WELL SOMEONE ELSE WILL HAVE TO
MEET MORGAN'S PLANE. ROBERTS?
ROBERTS IS IN
CHICAGO AND LAWSONS ON VACTION
AND MURPHY'S WIFE IS EXPECTING
AGAIN.
I THINK WE ARE STUCK MR
WILLOWBY, I'M AFRAID THERE IS
NO ONE TO MEET BUDDY MORGAN AT
THE AIPORT.
WELL DO YOU THINK YOUR BROTHER
INLAW CAN HANDLE IT? WELL, NOW
HUH
MR WILLOWBY, YOU KNOW YOUR
POLICY ABOUT HIRING RELATIVES?
I MEANT MY RELATIVES NOT
EMPLOYEES RELATIVES.
BESIDES HE'S NOT A BLOOD
RELATIVE HE'S A BROTHER INLAW.
WILL IN KNOW SOMEBODY....
JUST DOENS'T SEEM RIGHT TO SEND
A STRANGER OUT TO THE AIRPORT
TO MEET BUDDY MORGAN. WELL
WE'RE IN A
SPOT BARNES. I'LL GIVE HIM A
WEEKS TRIAL. BUT SIR HE KNOWS
NOTHING AT ALL ABOUT PUBLIC
RELATIONS
WORK, NOTHING. I'S A SIMPLE
ASSIGNMENT, HE MEETS HIM AT THE
AIRPORT, TAKES HIM TO THE
HOTEL. ANY DOPE CAN DO IT.
HIS NAME IS FRANK . I'M SO
NERVOUS ABOUT IT,
IT SOUNDS LIKE A VERY SIMPLE
ASSIGNMENT. I MEET HIM AT THE
AIRPORT I TAKE HIM TO HIS HOTEL.
ANY DOPE CAN DO IT.
FRANK, BUDDY MORGAN IS A VERY
IMPORTANT CLIENT. PLEASE DON'T
FOUL UP.
JOEY, HOW AM I GOING TO FOUL
UP, IT'S ALL RIGHT DOWN HERE ON
THE
PAPER? BUDDY MORGAN HUH? I GOT
A JOKE
FOR THIS GUY THAT WILL KILL HIM
JOEY, IT'S ABOUT AN OCTOPUS
WALKING DOWN THE STREET
FRANK THE QUICKEST WAY TO
OFFEND A COMEDIAN IS TO TELL
HIM JOKES. AND CHANCES ARE HE'S
HEARD IT A HUNDRED TIMES
BEFORE. NOW JUST WHAT YOU ARE
SUPPOSED TO DO, MEET HIM AT THE
AIRPORT TAKE HIM
TO THE HOTEL, NO JOKES PERIOD.
ALRIGHT
WHAT ARE SO WORRIED ABOUT?
GET YOUR BROTHER INLAW OUT OF
HERE, HE'S FIRED GIVE HIM HIS
PAY
FOR THE WEEK AND GET HIM OUT OF
HERE, IF YOUR BROTHER INLAW SO
MUCH AS SETS A FOOT INSIDE THIS
OFFICE, I'LL KILL HIM, AND NO
JURY IN THE WORLD WOULD CONVICT
ME, CAUSE THAT NUMSKULL
MAY HAVE COST UP THE BUDDY
MORGAN ACCOUNT. ALL HE HAD TO
DO WAS GO TO THE AIRPORT.
OH HE WENT TO AIRPORT, AND HOW
I WISH HE HADN'T
ON THE WAY IN FROM THE AIRPORT,
YOUR BROTHER
INLAW, TOLD BUDDY MORGAN IS
LIMITING, HE
SHOULD BECOME MORE VERSATILE,
HE SHOULD DO DRAMA.
BUDDY MORGAN? HE WENT FOR IT
HOOK LINE AND SINKER, NOW
INSTEAD OF HIS COMEDY
SPECIAL, HE WANTS TO DO
SHAKEPERE. SHAKESPERE? HAMLET!!
CAN YOU PICTURE BUDDY MORGAN
STANDING IN FRONT OF AND
AUDIENCE
SAYING "TO BE OR NOT TO BE" AND
BEING SERIOUS ABOUT IT?
YOU KNEW MY POLICY ABOUT NOT
HIRING RELATIVES AND YOU
TALKED ME INTO IT, NOW GET RID
OF HIM!
I'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
JOEY, YOUR BROTHER INLAW LEFT
TODAY WITHOUT FILLING
OUT THIS WITHOLDING FORM, WOULD
YOU TAKE IT HOME AND HAVE HIM
FILL IT OUT? THAT WON'T BE
NECESSARY BARBARA
MY BROTHER INLAW HAS ALREADY
BEEN FIRED. AFTER ONE DAY?
YES, AFTER ONE DAY, THAT'S EVEN
A NEW TRACK RECORD FOR MY
BROTHER IN LAW.
YOU WANT ME TO CALL HIM AND
BREAK THE BAD NEWS? THAT WON'T
BE NECESSARY, I WANT TO GO HOME
AN TELL HIM
RIGHT TO HIS FACE. WON'T HE
TAKE IT HARD? I HOPE SO
HE WASN'T HAPPY JUST SERVICING
BUDDY MORGAN
NO. I SAID GO TO THE AIRPORT
PICK HIM UP AND TAKE HIM TO THE
HOTEL, NO JOKES PERIOD.
IS THAT SIMPLE ENOUGH, NO NOT
MY BROTHER INLAW, NO
HE HAD TO TAKE WONDERFUL
COMEDIAN AND TELL HIM TO BECOME
A BIG BIG STAR.
A BIG COMEDIAN LIKE BUDDY
MORGAN, HE DON'T WANT TO BE A
COMEDIAN ANYMORE, HE WANTS TO
BE DRAMATIC
ACTOR. CAN YOU IMAGINE BUDDY
MORGAN DOING SHAKESPERE?
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THE ELEVATOR?
JOEY, YOUR JUST IN TIME FOR A
SUPRISE. YOUR TYPE
OF BIG SUPRISE TO..... HEY
EVERYBODY JOEY'S HOME. HI JOEY
HAVE A CANAPE THERE DELICIOUS,
POUR JOEY SOME CHAMPAGNE. THE
CAVIAR IS THE END.
WHAT'S WITH THE CAVIAR AND
CHAMPAGNE? WE'RE CELEBRATING
FRANKS JOB.
I TELL YA JOEY, THIS PUBLIC
RELATIONS
THIS IS THE STUFF, YOU SHOULD
HAVE BEEN WITH ME LAST NIGHT AT
THAT AIRPORT.
I WISH I HAD BEEN FRANK. FIRST
JOB I EVER HAD IN MY LIFE
OH I DON'T KNOW, THERE ARE MANY
BETTER JOBS....OH BETTER JOBS...
I WOULDN'T LEAVE WILLOWBY IN A
MILLION YEARS. OH JOEY YOU KNOW
HOW FUSSY
FRANK IS, I'VE NEVER SEEN HIM
SO ENTHUSIASTIC, HE'S JUST
CRAZY ABOUT HIS NEW JOB.
WHY WOULDNT I BE, THIS JOB HAS
GOT EVERYTHING, IT'S GOT
GLAMOUR IT'S GOT
EXCITEMENT AND FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN MHY LIFE I FEEL A REAL
SENSE OF
SECURITY. YOU KNOW, AND
WILLOWBY OH WILLIOWBY, I FEEL A
CERTAIN
REPOUR WITH THIS WILLOWBY.
JOEY, JOEY IS
HAS HE SAID ANYTHING ABOUT ME?
AS A MATTER OF FACT HE DID
MENTION YOUR NAME A COUPLE OF
TIMES TODAY. WHAT I TELL YA HE
LIKES ME.
HAVE SOME MORE CHAMPAGNE, NOW
THAT YOU ARE WORKING YOU CAN
AFFORD IT. LARRY
REMEMBER YOU HAVE A SURGERY
CLASS TOMORROW? OH MOM, IM NOT
DRINKING I'M POURING.
OH, FRANK I ALMOST FORGOT THE
SURPRISE.
HEY JOEY THE SURPRISE KID, WAIT
TILL I SHOW YOU THE SURPRISE.
COME ON OVER HERE, I'LL LAY
THIS ON YA, IT'S JUST A
SMALL TOKEN OF MY APPRECIATION
JOEY, THERE YOU ARE. OPEN IT
DEAR. OH LET ME OPEN IT FOR
YOU. HOW ABOUT THAT
WHITE ON WHITE, ITS JUST LIKE I
WEAR. BELIEVE ME FRANK I CAN'T
ACCEPT
IT. COME ON JOEY
DIDN'T COST ALL THAT MUCH. JOEY
YOU DON'T LOOK WELL
DON'T DRINK ANYMORE CHAMPAGNE.
WELL HE HASN'T HAD ANY.
WELL PICK THAT UP, HOW ABOUT A
TOAST FOLKS,
JOEY, WHOSE RESPONSIBLE FOR
EVERYTHING THAT HAS HAPPEN TO ME
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SAY THAT
FRANK. OH DON'T BE MODEST.
COME ON JOEY, DRINK WITH US,
OTHEWISE ITS
BAD LUCK. SO WILLOWBY WAS
TALKING
ABOUT ME, WAS HE? WHAT DID HE
SAY?
I DON'T REMEMBER THE WORDS, HE
WAS JUST RAVING ABOUT YOU.
OH, BY I OWE IT ALL TO YOU JOEY.
"FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW,
FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW,
FOR HE'S
A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW"
WHICH NOBODY CAN DENY".
EASY JOEY, EASY
YOU'LL WEAR OUT THE RUG. I JUST
DIDN'T HAVE THE HEART TO TELL
HIM. I DON'T GET IT, WHY YOU SO
UPSET? IS IT YOUR FAULT FRANK
WAS CANNED? NO IT WASN'T MY
FAULT, I JUST
COULDN'T BRING MYSELF AROUND TO
TELLING HIM, I WALKED IN SAW
WHAT WAS HAPPENING, THEY WERE
CELEBRATING WITH THE
CAVIAR AND THE CHAMPAGNE AND
THEY GAVE A SHIRT AS A GIFT.
THEN THEY SANG FOR HE'S A JOLLY
GOOD FELLOW. HE EVEN WENT HOME
EARLY SO TO GET UP
BRIGHT AND EARLY TOMORROW FOR
WORK. THAT'S SOMETHING HE'S
NEVER DONE IN HIS LIFE.
I JUST DIDNT HAVE THE HEART TO
TELL HIM. YEAH, I KNOW WHAT YOU
MEAN.
LOOK IF HE'S GOING INTO WORK
TOMORROW, YOU BETTER TELL HIM
SOON
MAYBE I CAN SEND HIM AND
ANONYMOUS LIGHT LETTER, "DEAR
FRIEND DON'T
COME TO WORK TOMORROW, SIGNED A
FRIEND". ITS' NO USE
I'M GOING TO GO TELL HIM RIGHT
TO HIS FACE. AT ONE THIRTY IN
THE MORNING.
YEAH, YOUR RIGHT. IF YOU WANT
MAYBE I CAN STICK A PINK SLIP IN
TO ONE OF HIS EMPTY MILK
BOTTLES RING THE BELL AND RUN.
NO MATTER HOW YOU TELL HIM
JOEY, YOUR GOING TO HURT HIS
PRIDE.
HE WALKS INTO WILLOWBY'S OFFICE
WILLOWBY WILL THROW HIM THROUGH
THE DOOR AND THAT WILL HURT
MORE THAN HIS PRIDE.
ONE THINK LEFT TO DO JOEY, YOU
GOT TO HAVE A HEART TO HEART
TALK WITH WILLOWBY ABOUT
FRANK. I WOULD RATHER HAVE A
HEART TO HEART TALK WITH
DRACULA. ITS NO USE
WILLOWBY WILL NEVER GIVE FRANK
ANOTHER CHANCE, WHAT CHANCE
HE'S ALREADY GIVING HIM IS
WEEKS SALARY
ALL HE HAS TO DO IS KEEP HIM
UNTIL THE END OF THE WEEK. NOW
WHAT GOOD WOULD THAT DO?
WELL YOU KNOW FRANK WITH HIS
TRACK RECORD, HE WILL QUIT THIS
JOB ON HIS OWN.
AND HE WILL NEVER KNOW HE WAS
FIRED AND YOUR OFF THE HOOK.
YOU KNOW IT'S NOT A BAD IDEA,
JUST ASK WILLOWBY
TO LET FRANK FINISH OUT THE
WEEK, THEN I TELL MR WILLOWBY,
IN THE MEANTIME I I WILL HAVE
FOUND FRANK
ANOTHER JOB. SON OF A GUN
SOMETIMES I THINK YOUR A
GENIUS. SURE ALL KID BROTHERS
ARE.
THANKS FOR THE HELP. ANYTIME.
OH HEY JOEY
YOU KNOW THAT FRANK GAVE YOU? I
ALREADY PUT IT IN YOUR DRAWER.
CONSIDER IT?
POSITIVELY NOT. JUST THREE MORE
DAYS SIR, HE'LL BE GONE.
ALONG WITH MOST OF MY CLIENTS,
NOT A CHANCE BARNES.
I WON'T HAVE THAT NUMSKILL
AROUND.
LOOK AT THIS WAY, YOU HAVE
ALREADY PAID THE NUMSKULL FOR A
WEEKS WORK. DON'T RUB IT IN.
JUST THREE MORE DAYS SIR, AND
BY THAT TIME I'LL HAVE FOUND
HIM SOMETHING ELSE. THE MAN'S
DANGEROUS BARNES. I WILL WATCH
HIM LIKE A HAWK SIR, I PROMISE
HE WON'T GO ANYWHERE WITHOUT
ME. I'LL EVEN GO WITH HIM WHEN
HE WASHES HIS HANDS. NO ITS' TOO
RISKY. I'LL KEEP HIM HIDDEN
SIR, NOBODY WILL BE ABLE TO
FIND HIM, HE WILL BE DOWNSTAIRS
IN THE BASEMENT.
WELL ALRIGHT, ALRIGHT.
SINCE I HAVE ALREADY PAID HIM,
I DON'T KNOW WHY I'M SO SOFT
BUT HE GOES FRIDAY. YES SIR, HE
GO ES FRIDAY, I WILL ESCORT HIM
OUT MYSELF PERSONALLY
RIGHT TO THE STREET. I'M
WARNING YOU BARNES, IF HE AS SO
MUCH AS CAST A
SHADOW. THERE'LL BE NO SHADOW
SIR. MS SIMPSON SOME
DICATATION. "YES SIR"
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
OH MS SIMPSON
WE'VE GOT ALOT OF WORK TO CLEAN
UP, YES SIR. AND I WANT YOU TO
REMIND ME LATER THAT
I HAVE A FIVE THIRTY
APPOINTMENT AT HIS HOTEL.
HELLO
BETTY? JOEY, IS FRANK AROUND?
YOU BET I AM READY FOR A DAYS
WORK
AND EAGER TO GO. EH, HOW DO YOU
LIKE IT?
THE CHARGED ME A FEW EXTRA
BUCKS FOR THE MONOGRAM
BUT WHAT THE HECK, WHAT'S A FEW
BUCKS WHEN YOUR IN THE BUSINESS
FOR THE FUTURE
IS PJ IN? IT'S JP.
WELL I GOT TO SEE HIM, I'VE GOT
SOME IDEAS FOR BUDDY MORGAN
THAT ARE BLOCKBUSTER
I'LL SEE YOU LATER. WAIT JUST A
MINUTE FRANK, YOU CAN'T GO IN
THERE
WHY NOT? HE'S NOT IN THAT'S WHY
NOT. "BLASTED OPERATOR
YOU GAVE ME THE WRONG NUMBER"
WHAT WAS THAT A RECORDING? OH HE
MUST HAVE COME UP THE BACK
STAIRWAYS. ALL I KNOW HE IS
VERY BUSY TODAY.
WELL THAT'S ALRIGHT, I'LL WAIT
FOR HIM, WHEN HE HEARS THESE
IDEAS, HE WILL FLIP.
YOU DON'T KNOW THE HALF OF IT.
STAY RIGHT HERE. WHERE WE GOING
ANOTHER ASSIGNMENT?
YEH, WERE GOING TO CHANGE
TYPEWRITER RIBBONS. TYPEWRITER
RIBBONS? THAT'S RIGHT
REMEMBER WE AGREED YOUR GOING
TO START AT THE BOTTOM, WELL
THAT'S WHERE THE TYPWRITERS ARE
IN THE BASEMENT
OK FRANK?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND,IS THAT ALL
MR WILLOWBY COULD FIND FOR YOU
TO DO? WILLOWBY? WHO GOT INTO
SEE WILLOWBY? IT WAS JOEY
WHO WAS GIVING OUT ALL THE
ORDERS. I TELL YOU BETTY HE'S
JEALOUS OF ME.
JOEY JEALOUS? I DON'T BELIEVE
IT. WELL THEN WHY
ELSE IS HE GIVING ME MENIAL
LABOR ALL THE TIME? I'LL TELL
YOU
WHY HE'S DOING IT? I'LL TELL
YOU WHY. IT'S BECAUSE I'VE GOT
SOME GREAT
IDEAS FOR BUDDY MORGAN. SOME
IDEAS THAT WILL SET WILLOWBY ON
HIS EARS
JOEY THINKS I'M TOO BRIGHT FOR
HIM, HE'S AFRAID OF HIS OWN JOB?
DOESN'T SOUND LIKE JOEY? I'M
TELLING YOU BETTY, I DON'T
HAVE TO PUT UP WITH THIS. WELL
GEE FRANK REMEMBER YOU DID SAY
YOU WERE
WILLING TO START AT THE BOTTOM?
I DON'T MIND THE BOTTOM, BUT
THIS IS TWENTY THOUSAND LEAGUES
UNDER THE SEA. BE PATIENT
HONEY, AFTER ALL YOU
JUST BREAKING IN. WELL I'M
THROUGHT BREAKING IN, FROM NOW
ON I'M BREAKING OUT
I'M TAKING MATTERS INTO MY OWN
HANDS, THESE IDEAS
ARE TO GOOD TO SIT IN A
BRIEFCASE. WELL FRANK WHAT ARE
YOU GOING TO DO?
IF I CAN'T GET IN TO SEE
WILLOWBY, I'M GOING OVER HIS
HEAD, , I'M GOING STRAIGHT TO
BUDDY MORGAN
I'M GOING TO HIS HOTEL.
WHAT MORE CAN I SAY, EVERYBODY
KNOWS YOU AS BUDDY MORGAN THE
COMEDIENNE
LEAVE HAMLET TO SHAKESPEAREAN
ACTORS
THE WORLD NEEDS THE SORT OF
LAUGHTER YOU CAN GIVE IT, NOW
YOU'VE GOT TO FORGET ABOUT DOING
DRAMA? WELL MAYBE YOU RIGHT JP,
WITH ALL THE TROUBLE
THAT'S GOING ON TODAY, THE
WORLD COULD USE MORE LAUGHTER.
NOW YOUR TAKING
A SENSIBLE ATTITUDE. WHY JUST
LOOK AT THAT ROUTINE WE HAVE
WRITTEN FOR YOUR TV
SPECTACULAR. HI JOEY
HOW'D THINGS GO TODAY? OH THAT
BAD HUH
WORSE, ONLY A FEW DAYS LEFT AND
FRANK STILL HASN'T QUIT
HIS JOB. AND I'VE DONE
EVERYTHING TO MAKE HIM QUIT. I
HAD HIM CHANGING TYPEWRITERS
RIBBONS. I EVEN HAD HIM
SHARPENING PENCILS. I THINK I'M
GOING TO GIVE HIM ONE MORE
PENCIL HE WOULD RUN ME THROUGH.
WORST PART ABOUT IT IS HE'S
BEGINNING TO HATE ME.
COME'ON FRANK DOESN'T HATE YOU.
WELL IF HE DOESN'T HATE ME
KNOW, HELL CERTAINLY HATE ME
TOMORROW
BECAUSE TOMORROW I'VE GOT HIM
WASHING WINDOWS.
OH JOEY, I'M SO GLAD I FOUND
YOU HOME. WHATS YOUR TROUBLE?
THERE'S SOMETHING I THINK YOU
SHOULD KNOW?
FRANK CAME HOME VERY UPSET,
FIRST HE ACCUSED YOU OF
BEING JEALOUS THEN HE SAID
ABOUT TAKING MATTERS INTO HIS
OWN HANDS.
HE SAID HE WAS OVER RIGHT OVER
MR WILLOWBY'S HEAD. THE NEXT
THING I KNOW, HE'S OFF TO BUDDY
MORGAN'S
HOTEL. BUDDY MORGAN'S HOTEL! OH
NO!
OHHOHO HO, THAT'S JUST GREAT.
AS LONG AS YOU CAN DO COMEDY
LIKE THAT,STICK TO IT BOY. NOW
HOW ABOUT A LITTLE DINNER
I KNOW A TERRIFIC SEA FOOD
HOUSE RIGHT DOWN THE STREET.
GREAT I CAN USE A GOOD LOBSTER
RIGHT NOW.
OH GOOD, I WOULD LIKE TO WASH
UP FIRST. OH SURE,IT'S RIGHT IN
THERE
OH THANKS, I WON'T BE A MINUTE.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
COME IN ITS OPEN. MR MORGAN, I'M
JOEY BARNES FROM THE WILLOWBY
PUBLIC RELATIONS OFFICE, WAS
THERE A MAN SAYING HE'S FROM
THE WILLOWBY OFFICE? YES
AS A MATTER OF FACT... NOBODY
WHAT HE SAID YOU HAVE TO FORGET
IT, THIS MAN'S AN ABSOLUTE
MANIAC.
MANIAC? THAT'S RIGHT SIR, BUT
HE SAID HE WAS...I DON'T CARE
WHAT HE SAID, HE'S A PHONEY. A
PHONEY?
WHY WOULD HE SAY HE IS WILLOWBY
IF HE'S NOT?, HE WOULD DO
ANYTHING JUST TO GET UP HERE
SIR?
NOW JUST FORGET EVERYTHING HE
HAS TOLD YOU, HE KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT PUBLIC RELATIONS. TWO
WEEKS AS A MATTER OF FACT
HE WAS SELLING SWIMMING POOLS
AND BIRDSEED. YOU MEAN THIS
MATERIAL
HE GAVE ME ISN'T FROM WILLOWBY?
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE FIRST THING
ABOUT MATERIAL. THANKS FOR
TELLING ME. JUST TAKE MY WORD
FOR IT.
ENTIRELY WELCOME, AND IF HE
EVER GETS UP HERE AGAIN, JUST
THROW HIM OUT OF HERE
BODILY. WAIT A MINUTE, HE HASNT
LEFT
HE'S STILL HERE. HE'S IN THERE
WASHING UP, HE AS TAKING ME OUT
FOR
DINNER. HE WAS GOING TO STICK
YOU FOR DINNER TO, JUST LET ME
HANDLE THIS
MR MORGAN. I'M TERRIBLY SORRY,
JUST LET ME HANDLE THIS AND
EVERYTHING WILL BE ALRIGHT
WITH YOUR PERMISSION SIR.
COME OUT OF THERE YOU NITWIT I
KNOW
YOUR IN THERE. COME ON COME ON
OUT OF THERE!
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY ABOUT THIS
WHOLE THING, BELIEVE ME IT WILL
NEVER HAPPEN AGAIN
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S COME OVER
HIM
I'M GOING TO COUNT TO THREE,
THIS IS NO TIME TO PLAY HIDE
AND SEEK, AND WHEN I COUNT TO
THREE
IF YOUR NOT OUT OF THERE I'M
COMING IN AND THROWING YOU OUT
BODILY
IS THAT CLEAR? COME OUT!
APPRECIATE IT IF NO ONE
EVERY HEARS OF THIS, IF THE
REAL MR WILLOWBY, IT COULD COST
ME MY JOB.
MR WILLOWBY.