JOEY BISHOP SHOW
(PHONE RINGING)
JP WILLOUGHBY? WELL YES
MRS BARNES.
WHAT IS IT NOW MOM? A TERRIBLE
THING HAPPENED
FRANK PACKED HIS SUITCASE AND
LEFT BETTY.
AH DON'T WORRY MOM, HE'S DONE
IT BEFORE, I'LL FIND YOUR SON
IN LAW AND STRAIGHTEN THIS
WHOLE THING OUT.
NOW WHAT HOTEL DID HE GO TO? HE
DIDN'T GO TO ANY HOTEL, HE
MOVED IN WITH
US. JOEY JOEY JOEY
THE JOEY BISHOP SHOW
STARRING JOEY BISHOP
HERE.
JOEY, I'M SO GLAD YOUR HOME,
TALK TO THEM DO SOMETHING.
ALRIGHT MOM, RELAX, I'LL DO
WHAT CAN, REMEMBER I'M NO
MARRIAGE COUNSELOR.
WONDERFUL.
ALRIGHT YOU TWO, WHAT'S THIS
ONE ALL ABOUT? WHERE DOES SHE
GET OFF TELLING ME
THE BREAD WINNER, WHERE WE'RE
GOING TO SPEND OUR VACATION.
SHE KNOWS
I LIKE THE SEASHORE. NOW ISN'T
THAT SIMPLE, SO YOU GO TO THE
SEASHORE?
BUT I LIKE THE DESERT. NOW
FRANK ISN'T THAT SIMPLE?
SO YOU GO TO THE DESERT. I'M
NOT GOING TO THE DESERT. I WENT
FISHING WITH YOU LAST TIME.
ALRIGHT HOLD IT DOWN.
BETTY, FRANK LET'S ACT LIKE
ADULTS, YOU LIKE THE SEASHORE
YOU LIKE THE DESERT?
COMPROMISE, FIND YOURSELF A WET
SAND DUNE.
JOEY. OH COME ON YOU'VE BEEN
MARRIED FOR 7 ROUNDS
YEARS. DON'T YOU REALIZE WHAT
YOU'VE GOT? A SELFISH HUSBAND.
STUBBORN WIFE. I MEAN BESIDES
THAT. YOU DON'T APPRECIATE
MARRIAGE.
MARRIAGE IS A, MARRIAGE IS A
BEAUTIFUL THING.
IT'S UH, IT'S TWO PEOPLE UH,
SHARING EACH OTHERS LIVES, THE
JOYS AS WELL AS THE PROBLEMS.
WELL ONE PROBLEM
THAT I DON'T WANT IS A HEAT
RASH FROM THE DESERT. WELL MY
SINUSES
ALWAYS ACTS UP AT THE SEASHORE.
SO YOU GET A HEAT RASH, SO YOU
GET A SINUS
AT LEAST YOU HAVE EACH OTHER.
SOMEONE TO LOVE, SOMEONE TO
FIGHT
WITH AND MAKE UP WITH, SOMEONE
TO SCRATCH YOUR BACK.
IT'S EASY ENOUGH FOR YOU TO
TALK, YOUR A BACHELOR.
YOU THINK ITS FUN BEING A
BACHELOR? YOU THINK I LIKE
COMING HOME AT NIGHT WITH NO
ONE TO MEET ME AT THE DOOR NO
ONE TO KISS ME SHAKE MY HAND
AND TALK TO ME
ABOUT THE TROUBLES OF THE DAY?
JOEY, I ...MOM...
YOU KNOW WHAT ITS LIKE TO GO
UPSTAIRS TO MY LONELY ROOM AND
STARE AT FOUR WALLS?
YOU REALIZE HOW OFTEN I LIE UP
THERE AND DREAM
ABOUT GETTING MARRIED SOME DAY?
NOW, YOU TWO HAVE
SOMETHING BEAUTIFUL GOING FOR
YA, HANG IN THERE.
IF YOU WILL ALL EXCUSE ME I
I THINK I WILL GO TO MY LONELY
ROOM.
BETTY?
YOU WANT TO GO TO THE DESERT,
WE'LL GO TO THE DESERT.
OH FRANK.
OHHH, OH I FEEL JUST
TERRIBLE. OH BUT MOM IT WAS
ONLY A LITTLE ARGUMENT.
OH I DON'T MEAN THE ARGUMENT, I
MEAN JOEY
I DIDN'T REALIZE THAT HE WAS SO
ANXIOUS TO GET MARRIED.
WHAT'S HE WANT TO GET MARRIED
FOR? HE'S GOT US.
THAT DOESN'T HELP WHEN HE GOES
UP TO HIS LONELY ROOM AND
STARES AT THE
FOUR WALLS. YOU SHOULD HAVE
HEARD HIM, IT WOULD HAVE TORN
YOUR
HEART OUT. I NEVER REALIZED
JOEY WAS SO UNHAPPY
ABOUT NOT BEING MARRIED. I
NEVER REALIZED EITHER, I FEEL
SO GUILTY
HE'S BEEN SLAVING ALL HIS LIFE
TO SUPPORT US
HE JUST NEVER HAD TIME TO MEET
THE RIGHT GIRL. WELL THEN IT'S
UP TO US TO HELP HIM
FIND SOMEBODY. HEY I KNOW A
CUTE NURSE AT THE UNIVERSITY
HOSPITAL
JOAN ROGERS, SHE'S CRAZY ABOUT
ME, BUT SHE'S TOO OLD FOR ME.
THERES THIS GIRL IN MY
DRAMATIC CLASS, PEGGY IRWIN,
SHE'S REALLY BEAUTIFUL, SHE
EVEN PLAYED
JULIETY ONCE. I KNOW WHO'D BE
NICE FOR JOEY
EMILY JOHNSONS DAUGHTER
ANNABELLE, SHE'S GOT HER OWN
FUR COAT
AND SHE'S ALREADY HAD HER
APPENDIX OUT
YES, BUT WITH A NURSE IN
THE...GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY,
GOOD MORNING JOEY, OH JOEY I'LL
GET
YOUR BREAKFAST. NEVERMIND MOM,
I'M LATE. I'LL CALL YOU LATER.
LOOK, JUNE ROGERS IS A PRETTY
GIRL AND SHE'S GOT A GOOD JOB,
SO WHAT IF SHE STILL HAS HER
APPENDIX
I'LL GIVE JOEY FAMILY RATES.
EMILY JOHNSON COMES FROM A
FINE....FORGOT MY BRIEFCASE.
NOW IF HE'D HAD A
WIFE SHE'D BE THERE TO HAND HIM
HIS BRIEFCASE. WELL I STILL
THINK PEGGY IRWIN WOULD BE
PERFECT. I MEAN IF SHE'S PRETTY
ENOUGH FOR ROMEO, SHE'S PRETTY
ENOUGHT FOR
JOEY. YES BUT...
FORGOT MY CAR KEYS.
PEGGY IRWIN....
OH UH, I'VE GOT EVERYTHING, SO
PICK IT UP FROM WHERE YOU LEFT
OFF.
POOR LAMB, THERE
HE GOES OFF TO WORK WORK WORK,
HE
CERTAINLY ENTITLED TO FAMILY OF
HIS OWN
HOW ABOUT THAT
HE DIDN'T BALL ME OUT, HE GAVE
ME TICKETS. MR WILLOUGHBY GAVE
ME TWO TICKETS
FOR THE JACK BENNY CONCERT
FRIDAY NIGHT AT THE GREEK
THEATER. BARBARA WOULD YOU LIKE
TO GO?
OH I WOULD LOVE TO. GOOD HERE
ARE THE TICKETS, I CAN''T MAKE
IT.
WELL I JUST
REMEMBERED, I CAN''T MAKE IT
EITHER. JUST GIVE THEM TO
SOMEBODY, MR WILLOUGHBY DOESN'T
WANT THEM TO GO TO
WASTE. WELL I CAN'T JUST GIVE
THEM TO ANYBODY, AFTER ALL
I HAVE TO FIND A NICE ROMANTIC
COUPLE, THE GREEK THEATER, THE
OPEN AIR
UNDER THE STARS. OH ARE YOU
LUCKY YOU'RE JUST IN TIME GIVE
THEM TO HER.
WHAT WAS THAT
ALL ABOUT? JOEY ASKED ME IF I'D
LIKE TO GO TO THE JACK BENNY
CONCERT.
FRIDAY NIGHT, WHEN I SAID YES,
THINKING HE WANTED TO TAKE ME,
HE GAVE ME BOTH
TICKETS, MAYBE HE THOUGHT YOU
WOULD GO BY YOURSELF AND HOLD
HANDS WITH THE OTHER TICKET.
MIND IF I STEAL A CIGARETTE? HE
HAD NO
INTENTION OF TAKING ME, HE
DOESN'T EVEN KNOW I'M ALIVE.
HONEY
IF HE DOESN'T KNOW YOUR ALIVE
THEN HE NEEDS GLASSES., EITHER
THAT OR HE'S GOT LOW BLOOD
PRESSURE.
LOOK,
FOR THREE YEARS YOU'VE BEEN IN
LOVE WITH AND HE DOESN'T EVEN
KNOW YOU EXIST, FORGET
HIM, THE MEN I'VE INTRODUCED
YOU TO, YOUR NOT EVER
INTERESTED.
NOW A NICE GUY LIKE HERMAN, A
BUTCHER. MARGE, HERMAN'S JUST
NOT MY
TYPE, LOVE CAN COME LATER,
FIRST THERES LAMB CHOPS.
AND WITH A BUTCHER, YOU NEVER
STARVE. AND STANLEY
HE OWNS A BOWLING ALLEY, FOR
THE REST OF OUR LIVES WE COULD
HAVE GONE BOWLING FOR NOTHING.
MY HUSBAND WAS SO DISAPPOINTED.
MARGE IT'S NOT THAT
I DON'T APPRECIATE IT, IT JUST
THAT I HAPPEN TO BE IN LOVE
WITH JOEY.
TAKE AN ASPIRIN, IT WILL GO
AWAY.
HE'S NOT INTERESTED IN YOU
FORGET HIM, BARBARA
HAS JOEY EVER KISSED YA? NO,
HAS HE EVER PUT HIS ARMS AROUND
YA? NO. HAS HE EVER TOLD YA
HE LOVED YA NO, A CASANOVA HE'S
NOT, IN FACT THE ONLY
RESEMBLANCE
BETWEEN HIM AND CASANOVA IS
THAT THEY ARE BOTH DEAD. OH
MARGE THAT'S
THE WAY IT IS. WELL, LOOK WHY
DON'T YOU AND HARRY TAKE THESE
TICKETS AND GO TO THE
JACK BENNY CONCERT? HOW ABOUT
THAT, THESE ARE THE SAME TICKETS
I GAVE TO MR WILLOUGHBY.
AND SHE'S ON HER WAY OVER NOW?
GOOD
EMILY, YES JOEY'S HOME FROM
WORK AND HE'S ALREADY HAD
HIS DINNER. OH LET'S HOPE IT
WORKS OUT
I'VE GOT MINE CROSSED TO.
(DOORBELL) DOORBELL, MUST BE
ANNABELLE, BYE EMILY. OH I'LL
TAKE CARE OF IT DEAR.
WHY ANNABELLE JOHNSON, COME
RIGHT IN
GOOD EVENING MRS BARNES, MOTHER
SENT ME OVER WITH THAT KNITTING
PATTERN YOU WANTED
WELL, HOW SWEET OF EMILY.
AS LONG AS YOUR HERE, COME ON
IN, BY THE WAY
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU'VE MET MY
SON JOEY, JOEY THIS IS
ANNABELLE JOHNSON, HOW DO YOU
DO? HELLO JOEY
NOW YOU TWO SIT RIGHT HERE AND
GET ACQUAINTED, AND I'LL GET
SOME TEA
AND BROWNIES. MY YOU TWO MUST
HAVE LOTS IN COMMON
SHE'S NOT MARRIED EITHER.
I THINK I OWE YOU AND APOLOGY,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT MY MOTHER HAS
BEEN
IN MIND, BUT IT MAY EMBARRASS
YOU. MOTHERS ARE LIKE THAT
I HOPE I WON'T EMBARRASS YOU
WITH WHAT MY MOTHER SAID,SHE
SAID
THERE SHOULDN'T BE A LONG
COURTSHIP, THAT THERE WOULD BE
NO LARGE WEDDING AND SHE
THOUGHT THE BEST THING WAS
FOR US TO ELOPE. I THINK I LEFT
THE HEADLIGHTS BURNING IN MY
CAR.
HOW'S HE MAKING OUT? I DON'T
KNOW
HE JUST WENT OUT TO TURN THE
LIGHTS OFF IN HIS CAR.
JOEY. WOULD YOU MIND TELLING ME
WHAT THIS IS
ALL ABOUT? WELL I WAS JUST
MAKING IT COZY FOR YOU AND
ANNABELLE, SHE'D MAKE YOU A
NICE WIFE. WIFE?
WHO WANT'S TO GET MARRIED? WE
KNOW. WE DO?
WOULD YOU MIND EXPLAINING IT TO
US. JUST YESTERDAY, YOU SAID YOU
DIDN'T WANT TO GO UP TO YOUR
LONELY ROOM AND STARE AT FOUR
WALLS
AND THAT YOU OFTEN LIE IN BED
DREAMING OF
ABOUT GETTING MARRIED SOMEDAY.
MOM I ONLY SAID THAT FOR FRANK
AND BETTY'S BENEFIT. JOEY STOP
BEING NOBLE
THE FAMILY IS NOT GOING TO
STAND IN OUR WAY ANYMORE. MOM
WHEN I CAN AFFORD
TO GET MARRIED, I WILL GET
MARRIED TWO CAN LIVE AS CHEAPLY
AS ONE.
THE SIX OF US HAVE BEEN DOING
IT FOR YEARS.
NOW YOU GO BACK INTO THAT
LIVING ROOM AND
BE FRIENDLY.
IT'S A GOOD THING I REMEMBERED
THE HEADLIGHTS OTHERWISE MY
BATTERY
WOULD HAVE BEEN DEAD IN THE
MORNING. I SPOKE TO MY MOTHER ,
SHE DOESN'T BELIEVE IN
ELOPEMENTS
IT SEEMS THAT NO ONE IN MY
FAMILY HAS EVER ELOPED, MY
MOTHER SAYS THERE SHOULD BE A
LONG
LONG COURTSHIP AND THEN A LONG
LONG ENGAGEMENT AND THEN A LONG
LONG MARRIAGE.
HI JOEY. THANKS FOR THE USE OF
THE
CAR. HERE ARE THE KEYS.
JOEY, I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
PEGGY IRWIN FROM
MY DRAMATIC CLASS. YOUR'RE JUST
IN TIME WITH YOUR ENTRY, WE'RE
STILL AT THE STARTING GATE. I
HOPE WERE NOT INTERRUPTING
ANYTHING?
NO NO, NOT AT ALL, ANNABELLE
WERE JUST TALKING IN THE
CATEGORY IS ELOPEMENTS
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HOME SO
EARLY?
I BROUGHT PEGGY IRWIIN HOME TO
PICK UP A SCRIPT. WHAT A SHAME
IT HAPPENED THE SAME NIGHT
ANNABELLE JOHNSON BROUGHT ME A
KNITTING PATTERN.
HEY EVERYBODY. I BROUGHT JOAN
ROGERS HOME WITH
ME, I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND JOEY,
FINE, WHY SHOULD I MINE?
MOM, I THINK YOU OUGHT TO SELL
THE COUCH AND PUT IN BLEACHERS.
I TOLD YOU HE HAD A GREAT SENSE
OF HUMOR, JUNE THIS IS MY
BROTHER JOEY, JOEY THIS IS JUNE
ROGERS. HOW DO YOU DO?
WELCOME TO THE CLUB.
WHY DON'T WE ALL MAKE OURSELVES
COMFORTABLE....HELLO EVERYBODY.
JOEY, I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET A
VERY DEAR FRIEND OF OURS
MS DINSDALE. HOW DO YOU DO MS
DINSDALE?
AH, WOULD I STEAR YOU WRONG?
WELL NOW THAT WERE ALL SEATED
HERE IN THE DUGOUT.
HOW ABOUT A FEW WORDS FROM THE
COACH
I THINK MY FAMILY'S FLIPPED
YOU SHOULD HAVE SEEN THAT GANG
OF CUPIDS, ONLY THEY WEREN'T
USING BOWS AND ARROWS
THERE WERE USING SLEDGE
HAMMERS, BARBARA I TELL YOU
LAST NIGHT MY LIVING ROOM
LOOKED LIKE A HAREM. JOEY DID
YOU EVER STOPPED TO THINK THAT
MAYBE IT'S TIME YOU HAD A
STEADY GIRL? WHOSE SIDE ARE YOU
ON?
NOW LISTEN JOEY, WHAT'S WRONG
WITH HAVING A STEADY GIRL?
BARBARA, YOU JUST GAVE ME A
GREAT IDEA, A STEADY GIRL. YEAH
MY FAMILY THOUGHT I HAD A
STEADY GIRL THEY WOULD LAY OFF
WITH THAT TALENT HUNT. OH SURE
THEY WOULD.
WELL ALL I HAVE TO FIND A
STEADY GIRL THAT'S NOT THE
LEAST BIT INTERESTED IN ME WHO
WILL PRETEND TO BE MY STEADY GIL
BELLA THE BOOKKEEPER, NO MY
FAMILY WOULDN'T BELIEVE THAT
I DON'T EVEN BELIEVE IT.
LOOK HOW YOU CAN'T SEE THE
TREES FOR THE FOREST. BARBARA
YOU'D BE
PERFECT. GEE JOEY, I DON'T
KNOW.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO IS PRETEND
THAT YOU ARE MY STEADY GIRL,
I'LL TELL MY FAMILY THAT WE'D
BEEN OUT, THAT WE'D BEEN TO COCE
THE CRESHENDO, THE BALLET, THE
THEATER, THE OPERA, AND YOU
WOULDN'T HAVE TO
GO TO ANY OF THOSE PLACES, YOU
COULD JUST STAY HOME IF YOU'D
LIKE. THANKS ALOT.
AND THEN ON SATURDAY, I'LL TAKE
YOU TO MEET THE FAMILY AND
WE'LL KISS IN FRONT OF THEM
WE'LL
ACT LIKE LOVEBIRDS, WE'LL HAVE
A MILLION LAUGHS. SHOULD BE A
SCREAM.
BARBARA YOU ARE A REAL PAL. I
DON'T BELIEVE IT CASANOVA
HAS COME TO LIFE, DON'T FORGET
SATURDAY NIGHT. ITS' A DATE.
CONGRATULATIONS. HE FINELY
ASKED YOU FOR A DATE. YEAH,
HE'S TAKING ME HOME TO
MEET HIS FAMILY. THAT'S
WONDERFUL, THE FIRST TIME
OUT AND HE WANTS YOU TO MEET
HIS FAMILY HUH? IT WAS SEVEN
YEARS BEFORE
I GOT TO MEET HARRY'S FAMILY,
AND WHEN THEY APPROVED, THEN I
GOT TO MEET
THE IMMEDIATE FAMILY. HE WANTS
US TO ACT LIKE LOVEBIRDS, TO
KISS
IN FRONT OF HIS WHOLE FAMILY.
LIKE I ALWAYS SAID IT'S THE
QUIET ONES
YOU GOT TO LOOK OUT FOR. FIRST
TIME HARRY KISSED ME WAS IN
FRONT OF MY FAMILY
TOO, IT WAS AT OUR WEDDING.
WELL I'M NOT GOING TO TO DO IT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
YOUR NOT GOING TO DO IT? DO YOU
KNOW WHY HE WANTS ME TO MEET
HIS FAMILY?
I'LL TELL YOU WHY? IT'S NOT
BECAUSE HE'S IN LOVE WITH ME,
HE WANTS TO CONVINCE HIS FAMILY
THAT HE'S GOT A
GIRL, ME. SO THEY'LL STOP
TYRING TO TRY TO FIND A WIFE FOR
HIM. HE'S USING ME AS A DECOY.
DIDN'T I TELL YOU IT'S THE
QUIET ONE'S
YOU GOTTA LOOK OUT FOR? I
WOULDN'T GO OUT WITH HIM IF HE
WERE THE LAST MAN
ON EARTH, I'D RATHER GO OUT
WITH HERMAN OR STANLEY.
IF HE THINKS I'M FOLLOWING
THROUGH WITH THIS LITTLE PLAN
OF HIS, HE'S GOT ANOTHER THING
COMING. WAIT A MINUTE...
WAIT A MINUTE. OF COURSE YOUR
GOING TO GO THROUGH WITH HIS
PLAN, BUT YOU ARE GOING TO TAKE
HIS LITTLE PLAN AND MAKE IT
BACKFIRE. BACKFIRE?
YOU KNOW THE OLD SAYING, THE
BEST LAID PLANS OF MICE AND MEN
OFTEN GO
ASTRAY? WELL THIS ONE'S GOING
INTO ORBIT, BECAUSE WE'RE
DEALING WITH
A RAT.
I WONDER IF THEY ARE REALLY
SERIOUS? THEY MUST BE THEY'D
BEEN OUT
TOGETHER FIVE NIGHTS IN A ROW.
MOM THEY LOOK PRETTY GOOD, NO
NO, THOSE ARE FOR
LATER WHEN JOEY'S GIRL COMES,
OH IM SO EXCITED
DUM, DUM, DUM DUM
JOEY? ISN'T THAT THE WEDDING
MARCH? WELL IT
CERTAINLY ISN'T TIPPY TIPPY
TIN. I'M SO THRILLED,
AND THE WAY YOU PULLED THE WOOL
OVER OUR EYES. YES..
HERE WE WERE ALL TRYING TO GET
YOU A DATE, AND ALL THE TIME
YOUR GOING STEADY.
YOU GOTTA WATCH OUT FOR THOSE
QUIET ONES YES SIR, STILL
WATERS RUN DEEP.
THAT'S RIGHT, A STITCH IN TIME
SAVES NINE
WHAT IS SHE LIKE? WELL
SHE'S A NICE PLAIN SIMPLE SWEET
LITTLE GIRL.
WELL CAN'T YOU TELL US WHAT SHE
LOOKS LIKE? SHE'LL FIT IN
PERFECTLY WITH
THIS FAMILY NOW, YOU CAN ALL
STOP WITH YOUR TALENT SEARCH.
WELL CAN'T YOU DESCRIBE HER?
WELL I COULD, BUT YOU WOULDN'T
BELIEVE IT. NO COME ON, TELL US
ALRIGHT, SHE'S GOT UH, HAIR
LIKE LANA TURNER,
AND EYES LIKE ELIZABETH TAYLOR
AND LIPS LIKE BRIDGET
BARDOT AND A FIGURE JUST LIKE
MOMS.
REALLY? OH JOEY
WHAT ARE YOU ALL EXCITED ABOUT?
YOU'LL SEE HER IN FEW MINUTES.
YOU KNOW AT FRANK AND BETTY'S
WEDDING, I WAS ONLY
AN USHER, YEH AND I WAS ONLY
BRIDESMAID, AT YOUR WEDDING
LARRY AND I
WANT TO BE SOMETHING A LITTLE
MORE IMPORTANT. ALRIGHT AT MY
WEDDING YOU WILL BE MORE
IMPORTANT
AT MY WEDDING, LARRY YOU WILL
BE THE MAID OF HONOR AND STELLA
YOU WILL BE THERE BEST MAN
JOEY, WHEN DO YOU PLAN TO BE
MARRIED?
WELL IF I HAD MY WAY, I WOULD
GET MARRIED TOMORROW. LIKE I
SAID, BARBARA IS A NICE PLAIN
SIMPLE LITTLE GIRL, SHE
BELIEVES IN LONG LONG
LONG ENGAGEMENTS. (DOORBELL)
I THINK I'M GOING TO FAINT. NOW
MOM, JUST RELAX WILL YA?
JUST RELAX. LARRY
STELLA, COME ON.
HIYA, SWEETHEART
BABY.
WHERE IS THE CAR WERE GOING TO
A MOVE NOW COME ON, THERE
PLAYING A GREAT DOUBLE FEATURE,
PLAYING
NOW LETS GO. NOW COME ON WE
DON'T WANT TO MISS THE MOVIES,
LETS ALL GO
IT MUST BE YOUR GIRL AT THE
DOOR, GO AND ANSWER IT.
BOY THAT'S THE KIND OF FAMILY
THIS IS, WHEN YOU WANT TO GO TO
A MOVE, I ALWAYS GO
AND WHEN I WANT TO GO TO A
MOVIE NOBODY WANTS TO GO, NOW
COME ON LETS ALL GO TO A MOVE.
MOM HE'S BASHFUL
JOEY, STOP BEING BASHFUL AND GO
AND ANSWER THE DOOR.
ARE THOSE KIDS DRIVING YOU
CRAZY? WHAT KIDS?! THE KIDS
THAT RING
BELLS AND RUN AWAY. YOU KNOW
WHAT I'D DO WHEN I WAS A KID?
FIRST THEY RING THE BELL, WHEN
YOU OPEN THE DOOR
THERE NOT THERE, WHEN YOU CLOSE
THE DOOR THEY RING THE DOOR
AGAIN, BOY ONCE YOU ANSWER THAT
DOOR YOU ARE HOOKED
BEST THING TO TO IS IGNORE THEM
RELAX, DO WHAT I DO, REMAIN
CALM UNDER FIRE
GRAB A FEW MAGAZINES AND READ.
WELL I'M
CERTAINLY NOT GOING TO LET THAT
BELL RING ALL NIGHT,NOT WITH
YOUR GIRL
COMING. LARRY GO AND CHASE
THOSE KIDS AWAY.
NO, NO. NEVER FROM THE INSIDE,
ALWAYS FROM THE OUTSIDE,THAT'S
HOW YOU CATCH THOSE KIDS,
WATCH THE WAY I DO IT.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
YOU MUST BE JOEY'S MOTHER?
YOUR JOEY'S GIRL?
YEA, BY THE WAY WHERE IS JOEY
BABY
JOEY BABY, WHERE ARE YOU? JOEY
HE JUST STEPPED OUT FOR A
MINUTE, CAN I HELP YOU
WITH OUR WRAP?
I DON'T BELIEVE IT, WHO EVER
THEY WERE, SHE'S
GONE. I TOLD YOU I'D GET RID OF
THOSE KIDS? YOU CERTAINLY DID.
JOEY, SHE'S EVERYTHING YOU SAID
SHE WAS
AND THEN SOME. JOEY BABY, ARN'T
YOU GLAD TO SEE ME?
THEY ARE GOING TO BE
MARRIED. I THINK WE BETTER SLIP
OUT THE BACK WAY AND GO TO A
MOVIE. I'D RATHER
STAY HERE AND WATCH THIS. I
HOPE YOU DON'T
THINK I'M TOO AGGRESSIVE, BUT
JOEY'S THE BASHFUL TYPE, HE'S
JUST LIKE MY FIRST HUSBAND. YOU
WERE MARRIED BEFORE? THREE
TIMES.
JOEY BABY
YOU'LL BE NUMBER FOUR
HOW ABOUT A LITTLE DRINK? HEY
YEA
ME TOO. STELLA LET'S HAVE SOME
MUSIC.
I FELL LIKE DANCING. LETS GO TO
A BALLROOM IF
FEEL LIKE DANCING. OH JOEY THAT
WOULD BE A WASTE OF MONEY, IF
WE'RE GETTING MARRIED
WE'LL NEED EVERY CENT. SHE AN
ANGEL MOM
WHY DON'T WE DANCE RIGHT HERE?
BUT THERE'S NO ROOM.
WHY THERE'S PLENTY OF ROOM.
SHE'S VERY GOOD ISNT' SHE?
WHY DON'T WE JUST TALK?
WHEN DO YOU TWO PLAN TO BE
MARRIED?
OH WELL, I ALWAYS WANTED TO BE
A JUNE BRIDE, BUT
I GUESS THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE THIS
YEAR, MY DADDY DOESN'T GET OUT
FOR ANOTHER SIX MONTHS
LETS DANCE
OH THAT MUST BE THOSE KIDS
AGAIN?
HI, I'M BARBARA'S MOTHER, JUST
CALL ME MARGE