(BOOM!)
>IS THIS YOUR WORLD? >NOT
EXACTLY. >THEN WHY ARE WE HERE?
WE HAVE TO
GET BACK TO THE PALACE AND SAVE
AYA?
>THAT'S WHAT WE'RE DOING. >HOW?
>I'LL GO AND FIND CARL.
>WHAT'S GOING ON? >SUN, SHOW ME
THE MAP.
>THIS IS YOUR IDEA, ISN'T IT,
CARL?
SOME SICK STUNT FOR YOUR SHOW.
>NO, IT'S NOT, MOM.
REMEMBER HOW WEIRD I ACTED WHEN
YOU PICKED ME UP
OUTSIDE THE HOTEL? THAT'S
BECAUSE IT WASN'T ME.
>AND THERE WERE TWO OF ME RIGHT
IN THIS HOUSE. WE LOOKED
EXACTLY THE SAME.
EXCEPT I DRESS BETTER. >IT'S
IMPOSSIBLE! >NO, IT ISN'T.
QUANTUM PHYSICS SAYS THERE
COULD BE MILLIONS OF
PARALLEL WORLDS. >AND EACH ONE
HAS A MORGAN FAMILY.
JUST LIKE US. >NO, NOT EXACTLY.
EACH WORLD IS DIFFERENT, SO EACH
MORGAN FAMILY WOULD BE
DIFFERENT. >IN THEIR WORLD, YOU
AND I AREN'T DIVORCED.
WONDER WHAT CHANGED THINGS.
>AND JOSH SAID HIS FATHER
HAD AN INJURY AND HAD TO STOP
PLAYING FOOTBALL. >SO HE NEVER
GOT
TO DO ALL THIS. >YOU AND MOM
SPLIT UP NOT LONG
AFTER YOU WON THAT PREMIERE
ISSUE. >BECAUSE ALL THE FAME
WENT TO MY HEAD.
MUST HAVE BEEN PRETTY HARD TO
LIVE WITH.
>YOU WERE IMPOSSIBLE TO LIVE
WITH.
>YEAH WELL, I'M SORRY FOR THAT.
>WISH YOU'D SAID THAT THEN.
(PHONE RINGS)
(PHONE RINGS) >VICKY MORGAN.
IT'S --
YOU.
>WE TOLD YOU. (HORN HONKS)
>THANKS FOR COMING.
>HOW COULD I REFUSE? YOU'RE
FAMILY. KIND OF.
>CARL? >I'M THE OTHER ONE.
YOU MUST BE THE DRAGON LORD.
WELCOME TO MY WORLD. WHAT DID
YOU ASK ME TO BRING THE TRAILER
FOR?
>TO MOVE THE BOAT, SO WE CAN
GET TO THE PALACE IN SUN'S
WORLD BEFORE SUNSET.
DO YOU HAVE ANY MAPS OF THIS
AREA? >MMM!
>NOW THE PALACE IS ON A LAKE
ABOUT 20 KILOMETERS NORTHEAST
FROM HERE. >I'D SAY --
MUST BE NEAR (?) LAKES. >LET'S
GET THE BOAT ON THE TRAILER.
(CRACKLING)
>HOW ARE YOU DOING THAT? >SORRY?
>HOW ARE YOU MAKING THOSE
SPARKS? >POWER RUNS FROM
THE TRANSFORMER DOWN THROUGH
THE CABLE AND INTO THE METAL.
WHEN I TOUCH THE METAL WITH THE
PROBE, THE CIRCUIT'S COMPLETED.
UNDERSTAND?
>YES.
(CRACKLING)
>HEY! WHAT'RE YOU DOING?
(CLANG)
(BOOM!)
>I MUST FOLLOW THAT CAR. YOU
WILL TAKE ME IN THIS.
>NO WAY. >DO YOU WANT TO END UP
LIKE THAT? >NO!
OKAY, OKAY.
>WE'RE GOING TO BE SLAVES.
THEY'RE GONNA CHAIN US UP AND
MAKE US EAT TOAD. NEVER GONNA
SEE OUR CHILDREN AGAIN. >CARL,
SHUT UP!
>HAVE THEY HURT YOU, DRAGON
LORD? >WHY WOULD I HURT HER?
AT SUNSET SHE WILL BECOME MY
WIFE. >I WON'T MARRY YOU!
>THEN YOUR BROTHER WILL SUFFER
WHEN WE CATCH HIM.
>THINGS HAVE BEEN MUCH BETTER
BETWEEN MOM AND DAD
SINCE HE OPENED UP THE SHOP.
>DOES CARL EVER REGRET GIVING
UP FOOTBALL?
>A BIT. HIS TEAM WON THE
PREMIERSHIP AFTER HE RETIRED.
HE ALWAYS WONDERED WHETHER HE
COULD HAVE BEEN INSIDE.
>HERE. GIVE HIM THIS FROM ME.
>YOUR PREMIERSHIP PHOTO! >'82.
>(LAUGHING) HE'LL BE RIPPED!
>CARL, CAN YOU HURRY UP A BIT?
IT'S GETTING LATE. >DON'T
PANIC. WE'RE NEARLY THERE.
>WHEN WE ARRIVE IN SUN'S WORLD,
WE'LL HAVE TO BE ON OUR TOES.
SHARAK WILL HAVE HIS MEN
EVERYWHERE.
>HE WON'T BE EXPECTING US TO
LAND INSIDE THE PALACE.
>WE HOPE SO. >ARE YOU SURE YOU
GUYS CAN DO THIS?
>NO, BUT WE DON'T HAVE ANY
OTHER CHOICE. (PHONE RINGS)
>CRAZY CARL. >CARL, WHERE ARE
YOU?
WE'RE GOING TO AIR IN AN HOUR.
>WHAT? >I REMINDED YOU ABOUT IT
THIS MORNING.
>I'LL BE THERE.
>8 5 4 2.
OKAY, MATE. BACK IN THE CAR.
>WHY ARE WE STOPPING? >I CAN'T
GO THROUGH.
I DON'T KNOW THE CODE. >IDIOT!
>DON'T GIVE UP HOPE. SUN IS
STILL FREE.
AND JOSH WILL BE BACK WITH
KATHY. I KNOW HE WILL.
>IT'S TIME TO GET READY. PUT ON
YOUR WEDDING DRESS. >NEVER.
>YOU CAN'T FORCE HER TO DO
THIS.
>I'VE GOT YOUR BROTHER. >IF YOU
HAVE HURT HIM -- >HE'S SAFE --
FOR NOW.
NOW GET READY.
>NOT UNTIL I SEE MY BROTHER.
>AFTER YOU PUT ON THE DRESS.
>WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO,
DRAGON LORD?
>I DON'T KNOW.
>FIND THE BOY. >WHY IS HE
IMPORTANT? YOU CAN JUST FORCE
HER
TO MARRY YOU. >AYA'S PEOPLE
MUST SEE HER MARRY ME WILLINGLY,
OR THEY WILL NEVER ACCEPT ME AS
THEIR DRAGON LORD.
IF I HAVE HER BROTHER, SHE WILL
DO EXACTLY AS I SAY. >HE WILL
COME HERE
TO RESCUE HIS SISTER.
>THEN HIDE MEN OUTSIDE THE
PALACE WALLS. IF HE TRIES TO
GET IN,
CATCH HIM!
>THANKS FOR EVERYTHING, CARL.
>GOOD LUCK!
>SUN, WATCH THE FRONT. JOSH,
YOU WATCH THE BACK. I'LL RESET
THE CONTROLS
AS SOON AS WE GET THERE. IF
THERE'S ANY KIND OF TROUBLE,
YELL AND (?) >WAIT.
I'M COMING TOO. YOU COULD USE
SOME MUSCLE. >ASHKA!!
>GET GOING! GO!
(BOOM!)
>I'M TAKING THE BOAT. GET OUT.
DO IT!!
LEAVE THE BAG. >NO!!
>QUICK!
KEEP HER WRISTS APART. >LET ME
GO!! >COME ON!
>THEY'RE GETTING AWAY!
(BOOM!)
>YEAH, HI NIKKI, IT'S CARL.
UM -- I HAD A BIT OF AN
ACCIDENT.
(CRACKLING) (BOOM!)
YOU OKAY?
WHERE'S ASHKA? >WE DON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT HER ANY MORE.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
>BIT GROGGY. WHY DID YOU COME
BACK?
>WE HAVE TO MOVE THE BOAT. WE
LANDED OUTSIDE THE PALACE
WALLS. >CARL!
CARL! ARE YOU THERE? >YES, THIS
IS CARL.
UM -- BAD NEWS, MATE.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO GET
SOMEBODY ELSE TO DO TONIGHT'S
SHOW.
GOTTA GO SOMEWHERE. IF I TOLD
YOU, YOU'D REALLY THINK THAT I
WAS CRAZY.
SO WHERE DOES THE BOAT HAVE TO
GO? >THAT WAY.
ABOUT 300 METERS.
>VERY NICE. KEEP IT NICE AND
HIGH, THAT'S THE WAY. VERY NICE.
HEY!
WE'RE IN THE MIDDLE OF A
TRAINING SESSION. YOU CAN'T
BRING THAT IN HERE. >UH --
WE ARE RUSSIAN CIRCUS
PERFORMERS.
WE ARE HERE TO USE WONDERFUL
AUSTRALIAN FACILITIES AND TO
TRAIN FOR NEW SHOW.
THIS IS EQUIPMENT FOR ACT.
>CIRCUS PERFORMERS?
I HAVEN'T HEARD ANYTHING ABOUT
THIS. >NOW LOOK, PAL.
WE WON'T BE LONG. >HEY, YOU'RE
CRAZY CARL! I LOVE YOUR SHOW!
>GOOD. SO IF IT'S ALL RIGHT
THAT WE PARK HERE,
WE'LL GIVE YOU A DEMONSTRATION.
>YEAH, NO WORRIES, CARL!
(BLOWS WHISTLE) OKAY EVERYBODY,
GATHER ROUND, WE HAVE A REAL
TREAT FOR YOU.
RUSSIAN CIRCUS PERFORMERS. HEY
CARL.
CAN YOU GIVE US A FEW
AUTOGRAPHS, MATE? OH, COME ON,
THE KIDS WOULD LOVE IT.
>OKAY. LINE UP.
ONE AT A TIME. HEY, WAIT FOR ME!
>THANKS, CARL! YOU'VE DONE
ENOUGH ALREADY.
(KIDS SCREAM)
(BOOM!)
>AREN'T THOSE RUSSIANS AMAZING?
NEXT?
(BOOM!)
>NO ONE'S SEEN US.
>LET'S GO AND FIX THE ORACLE.
>THERE'S AN ENTRANCE
TO THE SECRET PASSAGES OVER
HERE.
>SO I MAY HAVE TO POSTPONE THE
WEDDING.
UNTIL THE BOY IS CAUGHT. >YOU
MUST NOT!
IF YOU DELAY, YOU WILL HAVE BAD
LUCK.
>SHARAK, SEE WHAT I HAVE CAUGHT.
>WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE? >I
DIDN'T WANT TO MISS YOUR
WEDDING.
>SUN WAS WITH HER, BUT HE
ESCAPED. >HE'LL BE BACK. DOUBLE
THE GUARD!
WAIT. I'LL TAKE THAT.
AS A WEDDING PRESENT, YOU CAN
TEACH ME HOW TO USE YOUR MAGIC
SUIT.
BRING HER.
>IF HE LEARNS HOW TO USE THE
POWER SUIT,
HE'S UNSTOPPABLE. >THE ORACLE'S
MORE POWERFUL THAN THE SUIT.
>THE ONLY PROBLEM IS, THE
SUIT'S WORKING. THE ORACLE
ISN'T.
>COME ON.
>DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA WHERE
SHARAK MIGHT
BE KEEPING AYA? >PERHAPS SHE'S
BACK IN A CAGE.
>CAN'T DO IT. THIS TECHNOLOGY'S
WAY OUT OF MY LEAGUE.
>WE'LL HAVE TO FIND MEK. >SUN,
COME BACK! WE'LL HELP!
SUN!
THERE HE IS!
(BOOM!) >SHARAK!
BE CAREFUL! THIS IS NOT A TOY!
THIS SUIT IS MAGIC. ONLY A
SPELLBINDER
CAN CONTROL ITS POWER. LET ME
HAVE IT BACK AND I PROMISE TO
PROTECT YOU.
>HA! >I DON'T NEED YOUR
PROTECTION.
I'M GOING TO BE THE DRAGON
LORD. (CLANG)
(BOOM!) (SUN SHRIEKS)
>HA HA! HA HA!
WE'VE GOT THE LITTLE MONKEY!
>PUT ME DOWN! >HA HA!
>WELCOME BACK, SUN.
YOU'RE JUST IN TIME FOR YOUR
SISTER'S WEDDING. >I WANT TO
SEE AYA. TAKE ME TO HER!
>OF COURSE. BRING HER!
>COME! COME ON!
>WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
>LET'S FOLLOW THEM AND SEE
WHERE THEY'VE GOT AYA.
>SOMEONE'S COMING!
(DOOR CRASHES OPEN) >SUN!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT? >HE'LL
REMAIN THAT WAY AS LONG AS YOU
DO AS YOU'RE TOLD.
PICK UP THAT DRESS. COME WITH
ME.
IT'S TIME TO GET MARRIED.
>YOU. AND YOU. COME TOO.
YOU CAN ATTEND THE DRAGON LORD
AT THE CEREMONY.
>JASMINE! WHAT'S SHE DOING HERE?
>VICKY, DON'T DO ANYTHING
STUPID.
>TAKE THEM!
(CLANG) >NO, LORD SHARAK. HE
DIDN'T MEAN ANY HARM.
>PUT ASHKA IN WITH THE OTHERS.
WE'LL DECIDE WHAT TO DO WITH
THEM
AFTER THE WEDDING. >INSIDE! GO
ON!
>YOU'LL REGRET THIS, SHARAK.
>YOU BROUGHT HIM HERE! YOU'RE
RESPONSIBLE FOR
WHAT HAS HAPPENED. 400 YEARS
OF CIVILIZATION GONE.
>STOP YOUR WHINING. >YOU
HAVEN'T GOT YOUR POWER SUIT
NOW, ASHKA.
WHERE'S MY CHILDREN? >I DON'T
KNOW AND I DON'T CARE!
>TAKE THEM TO (?) >GO.
>BE BRAVE, SUN.
>GO! >GO.
>WHO DO WE TRY AND SPRING FIRST?
>MEK. HE'LL NEED TIME TO FIX
THE ORACLE. >HOW ARE WE GOING
TO GET PAST THAT GORILLA? >GOT
ANY BANANAS? >NO.
BUT I'VE GOT THESE. WE COULD
TRY BRIBING HIM TO LET MEK GO.
>NAH, HE'D JUST TAKE THEM AND
LOCK US UP.
I'VE GOT A BETTER IDEA.
>DAD! CAN YOU HEAR ME?
DAD! >HEY!
>JOSH! WHAT -- >SHHH. >WAS THAT
KATHY?
>JOSH, NOW! >KATHY!
(GROANS)
>WHERE DID YOU LEARN TO DO THAT?
>LET'S GET HIM INSIDE.
>WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU TWO?
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN? >WITH YOU
AND MOM.
>WHAT? >WE WENT TO ANOTHER
PARALLEL WORLD. IT'S LIKE OUR
WORLD, BUT NOT QUITE.
WE MET OURSELVES. >AND GUESS
WHAT, DAD. YOU'RE A BIG
FOOTBALL HERO. YOU'VE EVEN GOT
YOUR OWN TV SHOW. >ME? TV?
>YEAH. YOU'RE A STAR, BUT MOM'S
DIVORCED YOU AND WE DON'T LIVE
WITH YOU ANY MORE.
>WELL, IN THAT CASE, I'M
PROBABLY HAPPIER SELLING
SPORTING GOODS.
>DID YOU GET THE INTERFACE?
>YES, BUT I CAN'T FIX THE
ORACLE. MEK, IT'S UP TO YOU.
>HANG ON JUST A MINUTE. >SORRY,
DAD. THERE'S NO TIME.
>I'LL HELP YOU. >NO, YOU DON'T.
GO, JOSH.
>YOU AND I HAVE TO RESCUE AYA.
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN MAKE THE ORACLE WORK.
YOU'LL NEED A DISGUISE.
PUT HIS CLOTHES ON. >AYE,
CAPTAIN.
NO, YOU GET THEM, KATHY. I
DON'T TRUST HER.
>CARL,
SHARAK'S GOT A LOT OF MEN. YOU
NEED ALL THE HELP YOU CAN GET.
>DON'T LISTEN TO HER, DAD.
>I'M SHARAK'S PRISONER TOO,
KATHY.
WE'RE ON THE SAME SIDE NOW. >NO
WAY!
(CLICK)
(CLICK) (WHAM!)
>I CAN'T BELIEVE I JUST DID
THAT.
>YOU DIDN'T HAVE ANY CHOICE,
DAD. >GRAB YOUR SCARF
AND LET'S GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
>GET OUT. CAN'T YOU SEE THE
DRAGON LORD IS DRESSING?
>(INDISTINCT) >OH, CARL!
OH, KATHY! OH!
I'D ALMOST GIVEN UP HOPE.
>LISTEN, THERE'S SUPPOSED TO BE
A GUARD ON DUTY OUTSIDE.
I BETTER GET OUT THERE. YOU
DON'T NEED ME ANYWAY. KATHY'S
IN CHARGE. >WHERE'S JOSH?
>HE AND MEK ARE FIXING THE
ORACLE. AYA, WE HAVE TO GET YOU
THERE.
>IF SHARAK FINDS I AM GONE, HE
WILL HURT SUN.
>WHAT IF YOU ARE STILL HERE. I
CAN PRETEND TO BE YOU.
>NO, YOU CAN'T. SHARAK EXPECTS
YOU TO BE WITH AYA. HE'LL GET
SUSPICIOUS
IF YOU'RE NOT THERE.
I'LL HAVE TO TAKE AYA'S PLACE.
>KATHY, NO!
>MOM, SHARAK WILL BE HERE ANY
MINUTE. >DON'T ARGUE.
ANYWAY, IT WOULDN'T WORK.
YOU'RE TOO SHORT.
SHARAK WOULD KNOW AS SOON AS HE
SAW YOU.
>WHAT ELSE CAN WE DO?
>ALL CLEAR.
>WHAT DO YOU TWO WANT?
>WE NEED YOUR HELP.
>AND IF I GIVE IT? >THEN I
PROMISE YOU SAFE PASSAGE FROM
THIS WORLD.
>WHAT DO YOU NEED ME TO DO?
>WE WANT YOU TO MARRY SHARAK.