[narrator]
From the myths of the north,
Germanic tribes headed south,
Reaching as far as
the borders of the Roman Empire.
Barbarians,
the Romans called them.
[somber music]
[narrator] But in 375 AD,
the most feared of all warriors,
descended upon Europe,
murdering and pillaging.
The Huns
triggered a great migration.
Hundreds of thousands
of Goths, Vandals and Franks,
went in search
of a new homeland.
They sapped Rome.
Some tribes disappeared,
almost without trace.
Others left behind
valuable treasures.
The Germanic Barbarians
were to become
the founders of Europe.
[opening theme music]
[narrator] 375 AD, the Huns
were devastating Europe.
Hoards of Germanic peoples
fled through the Roman Empire
spreading fear and terror.
[somber music continues]
[casual music]
[narrator] Graves are
often the only traces of the
great tribal migrations.
The mortal remains
of many Germans
found their last resting place
in the anthropologists
storeroom, in Budapest.
The skull of a Visigoth.
What could he have
experienced and suffered?
What might he have looked like?
For anthropologists,
a skull is not just a skull.
A recent scientific process
makes it possible
for Anges Gustar
to restore
the faces of dead people.
Ancient deeds
have handed down the names
and deeds of the great kings,
while the fate
of ordinary people
remains largely unknown.
Yet we can find out
something about them today.
Anthropologists, archaeologists
and historians are all involved.
[suspenseful music]
[narrator] We are
going back with him,
into his past.
[pulsating]
[narrator] He was one of
one hundred thousand Visigoths.
A people
who made their mark in history
and completely changed
the ancient world.
To the Romans,
he was sometimes an enemy,
sometimes a friend.
However, they always
called him a Barbarian.
Although,
like them, he was a Christian.
As a warrior,
he took part
in the Visigoths journey
across the whole of Europe.
He moved
through Greece and the Balkans.
He besieged and conquered Rome
with King Alaric.
He traveled over
seven thousand kilometers
with the Visigoths.
Only
in the south of France, in 418,
did he find a permanent home.
After wandering
for over forty years.
[casual music]
[narrator] He survived
flight and exile,
dangers and hardship,
wars and battles.
The historian, Jordanis,
reported
on the fate of the Visigoths.
from the knowledge of the old,
from songs and stories.
[rippling]
[narrator] As a child,
our Visigoth escaped the Huns
with his family, just in time.
Until then,
they had lived peacefully
near the Roman Empire.
It was the year, 376 AD.
Men, women and children
gathered with their belongings
at the Danube, on the border
of the Roman Empire.
It took weeks,
to ferry everyone across
to safety
on hastily built rafts.
There was always fear!
They knew
the greedy looting Huns
were on their way.
[yelling]
[anxious music]
[narrator] The Visigoths
tried desperately
to escape from them.
[yelling continues]
[narrator] Terrifying stories
were told of the Huns weapons
and their incredible range.
[screaming]
[narrator] Terrible stories
were told of their appearance.
They were said to be ugly,
cruel two-legged animals.
[splashing]
[screaming]
[narrator] The only
way out for the Visigoths
was to flee across the Danube.
The Visigoths asked
the Emperor Wallins for refuge
and vowed to submit to his rule,
to live according to his laws,
and to become Christians.
The emperor has said
to have taken them in
prone misericordia out of mercy.
In fact,
the Roman Emperor was too weak
to defend itself
on the Huns on its own,
it desperately needed
the Goth warriors.
[haunting music]
[narrator] The Huns had come
from deep in the Asian steppes.
In 375, they subjugated
the Allen's and the Ostrogoths,
and drove
the Visigoths ahead of them.
Their army was created
to make the world tremble!
They turn up
where they are least expected
and attack the people
with robbery and cunning.
[chanting]
[narrator] For the people
of the ancient world,
The Huns were the
most feared of all the warriors.
Never before
had people experienced
such brutal fighting.
They are extremely fast.
They sit on their agile horses,
as if they are one with them.
In the fury of battle,
they aim with calm hands.
Their arrows
bring certain death.
[clanking]
[narrator] Not one
of them touches a plow,
or cultivates a field.
They know no occupation
other than hunting,
and they
roam about like robbers.
[yelling]
[neighing]
[ominous music]
[narrator] The Huns were
mounted nomadic warriors.
They stole
everything they needed.
Grain, livestock,
gold, even people.
While many smaller groups
wondered about
looting indiscriminately,
the Huns were far more
than a collection
of wild undisciplined hordes.
They subordinated
themselves completely
to their leaders,
and were capable
of far reaching
strategic campaigns.
A danger
for the whole of Europe.
[ominous music continues]
[narrator]
A sword, a few coins,
burial objects from Austria.
One was fatal.
The three-winged tip
of a Hun arrow.
It found its mark
in a Germanic spine.
The Hungarian archaeologist,
Peter Tomka,
excavated
a significant Hun treasure.
The pan and harmer find.
Insignificant pieces
of gold leaf were part of it.
He was able
to use them to reconstruct
one of the
fearsome composite bows.
The Huns magic weapon.
Feared for its range
and penetrating power.
[whooshing noise]
[narrator] Peter Tomka
was able to reconstruct
the bridles of the Huns horses
from other fragments of gold.
The Huns
lead them with snaffle bits,
and were the first
to put proper saddles
on their horses,
to give the riders support.
The Huns were agile riders,
and feared archers
at the same time.
At full gallop,
they were still able
to shoot up to
thirty arrows per minute.
[dramatic music]
[narrator]
Another significant find
is this heavy
sacrificial cauldron
from the Huns Empire,
north of the Danube.
Under their king, Atelier,
they became
an ancient super-power.
He aimed to rule the world.
His legendary residence
is presumed to be between
the Danube and the Trays.
According
to ancient descriptions,
his palace,
with its Roman bathhouse
and surrounded by palace aids,
could have looked like this.
The power of the mounted nomads
became a threat to Rome.
The Danube in Budapest,
was once
a border of the Roman Empire.
After the Huns had driven
the Goths north of the Danube,
this part of Hungary
became their empire.
The Huns are
horribly deformed monsters.
Instead of a face,
they have a repulsive lump
with pinholes, rather than eyes.
That is how
their enemies described them,
giving no more
than a distorted image.
But what did Atelier's warriors
who aroused
so much fear, really look like?
The anthropologist, Agnes Kustar
knows how to reconstruct faces.
Now we are
able to see a Hun's face
being restored
1500 years after his death.
It's not an imaginary face
emerging under her hands,
she's using
a scientific process.
After weeks of work,
the skull
turns into a real face.
That of a Hun, with the
characteristic small eyes,
flat nose and broad cheekbones.
[narrator] The horse riding
people of Mongolia today,
have the same facial features.
It's assumed that
the Huns once came from there.
What frightened both the
Germans and the Romans?
Was there strange appearance
coupled with their
merciless fighting style?
The Ostrogoths
were among the first people
to be attacked
by the Huns in 375.
[dramatic music]
[narrator] Their legendary
king, Ermanaric, was feared
because of his
valiant war deeds.
He ruled over a huge empire,
but the Huns
had already attacked
and subjugated
the neighboring tribes.
Ermanaric knew
that his Ostrogoth
would also lose their freedom.
As Amiyanos Markalenos puts it,
he himself neither
wanted to experience that,
nor to be responsible for it.
In the face
of the terrible dangers
which threatened, and fearing
to make crucial decisions,
he put an end to his life.
[galloping]
[narrator] He died,
because he could not bare
the veracity of the Huns.
But his death gave them
power over his people.
The Visigoths, however,
refused to submit to the Huns.
They would rather
conquer a kingdom
out of their own efforts,
than to be subject
to others out of sluggishness.
In the year 376,
the Visigoths
crossed the Danube.
It was
the beginning of the greatest
of the tribal migrations.
A hundred thousand
men, women and children,
including ten thousand warriors,
were fleeing from the Huns.
[dramatic music]
[narrator] The exiles were
accepted into the Roman Empire.
Legend has it,
that the emperor joyfully
consented to taking them in
as people seeking help.
They did have to submit to Rome,
but were allowed
to keep all their weapons.
For the empire
depended on the Visigoths army.
The Visigoths wanted
to become part of the empire,
and to participate
in the wealth and achievements
of Roman civilization.
For this,
they were willing to defend
the empire's borders.
The Visigoths
were the first German's
to settle
in the empire as allies of Rome,
as a state, within a state.
They were settled
south of the Danube.
A valiant outpost
of the empire, against the Huns.
What the
fleeing tribe left behind,
on the far side of the Danube,
is preserved in Bucharest today.
The capital of Romania,
was once the land of the Goths.
The national museum
houses one of the largest
and most significant findings
from the age of migration,
the treasure of Petrosa.
A royal treasure with more than
forty kilograms
of gold and precious stones,
which the Goths buried
after fear of the Huns.
As it has already been
stolen from the museum once,
it is now housed
in a high security wing.
It was found by peasants
in the
Eastern Carpathians in 1837.
Illegal trade, blackmail,
robbery and even deaths
are all part
of the treasure's history.
And of course,
people say today that
there is a curse
on the barbarians gold!
It is the pride of the
Romanian National Museum.
This is why,
as a special privilege,
the archaeologist, Radu Harhoiu,
is showing us the full splendor
of this unique find.
[narrator] The Barbarians,
Mothers of God,
made of pure gold.
The priceless treasures were
status symbols for the living.
For the dead kings of the Goths,
they were an appropriate gift
for the other world.
Red [indistinct]
stud saddle mountings buckles,
and magnificent fibula
or clasps.
The world famous Eagle Fibula,
from the Petrosa Treasure,
the Goths made the
royal bird of prey their symbol.
For archaeologists,
the eagle motif
is often the only trace
of the Goths
wanderings throughout Europe.
[mysterious music]
[narrator] In 395 however,
they had
to leave their settlement,
south of the Danube.
On their forty year wanderings,
they traveled through Greece,
the whole of the Balkans,
and on towards Italy.
Robbed of their homeland
by Huns and Romans,
and having
escaped enemy weapons,
they sought
a new abode in foreign parts.
Almost
one hundred thousand Visigoths
had been traveling
in the Roman Empire since 376.
They had made Alaric their king.
He would go down in history
as the conqueror of Rome.
He led the refugees,
more than ten different peoples
who had herded together,
including Asiatic tribes.
Not descent,
but courage and valor
decided who would be of goth.
Human restlessness
drove them on.
Through impossible
unknown terrain.
They were looking for a land,
that could
feed such a multitude.
Those words
applied to the Visigoths
more than any other
ancient people.
They would be
on the move for forty years.
A true philodendron,
migrants, wandering endlessly.
As a child,
he had fled across the Danube.
As a man, he became a warrior,
like all the Goths.
The nomadic life
became second nature
to the Visigoths.
And new generations
grew up, knowing nothing
but the tribulations
of life on the move.
[dramatic music]
[narrator] They tried
again and again to win asylum
in the Roman Empire
by force of arms.
For decades, it was in vain.
At the same time
as the Visigoths,
other Germanic peoples
were also fleeing.
The Huns,
had also driven out the Vandals,
who crossed the Rhine in 406,
and pillaged their way to Spain.
When they
had finished looting the south,
they began
to implement a daring plan.
They made their way
from Gibraltar to Carthage.
Tarifa,
on the strait of Gibraltar.
From here, Genseric ,
the King of the Vandals,
dared to cross to Africa
with his people in 429 AD.
Over the Mediterranean
came an invasion
as huge as it was dangerous.
They landed
near Tangier, in Morocco.
Africa was enticing!
A country full
of legendary treasures
and blessed
with abundant resources.
The Vandals
are like the wrath of God.
They set fire to cities
and steal all of the provisions.
The starving people
are forced to eat human flesh.
Mothers even eat their children.
So rouge their adversary,
Isidore of Seville.
He was a Roman Catholic.
The Vandals however,
were Arian Christians.
Wanton heretics in his eyes.
That's why Isidore
made the Vandals
the villains
of the great migration.
[dramatic music]
[neighing]
[narrator] So today,
vandalism has come to mean
blind destructive rage.
This is wrong.
Like all the other
Germanic peoples,
the Vandals
were only fighting for survival.
Genseric had them all counted
for their trip
across the Mediterranean.
Eighty thousand people took part
in the great Vandal journey,
including other tribes,
such as Alans and Suebi.
From Tangier, they still had
a seven year
long march ahead of them.
On the way, they took
what was there for the taking.
And conquered Roman towns.
The Roman provincial town
of Duguay, in Tunisia,
one of many through
which the Vandals passed.
Not a trace of vandalism,
the town fell victim
to the normal ravages of time.
In the shadow of the capital,
they would have
learned the local language.
Opposite,
the hot springs of Duguay,
with steam baths
and massage rooms.
When they had captured Africa,
they took hot baths every day,
and lived in magnificent villas.
For the Vandals,
Africa was Arcadia,
paradise on earth.
Underneath the town,
are the achievements
of Roman civilization.
Running water, sewage,
and floor heating
for cold nights.
The Christian Vandals put an end
to the Romans
bloody gladiatorial combats.
But they would have
gone to the theater
to both comedies and tragedies.
Besides,
why would the Vandals
have destroyed
what they wanted to occupy,
in the style
of the Romans who they admired?
The Bardo Museum
in Tunisia is replete
with evidence
of ancient culture.
Nowhere,
are so many and such artistic
mosaic floors
preserved as in Tunisia.
The archaeologist,
Ieshia Benabed,
is fascinated
by the idea that here,
Vandals walked
on many of the mosaics,
chatted to the Romans in Latin,
listened to Greek music and
celebrated bacchanalian feasts.
Hundreds on mosaic floors
from the Vandal period
tell stories
of the life of the Barbarians
under the African sun.
Dancers and music,
everything that delights the eye
and the ear, were customary.
They were no less devoted
to the joys of the wine cup,
than to those of love.
[haunting music]
[narrator] The blue-eyed
blond people from the north,
had once been desired as slaves.
Now, they became
the masters of the country.
They did not just dispose,
but also
purchased villas and land
from their owners.
It is known
from surviving documents,
that they respected Roman law.
[haunting music continues]
[narrator] In the workshop
of the Bardo Museum in Tunis,
twenty artisans
are working under Ieshia Benabed
restoring
mosaics for the museum.
Year after year,
new ones are excavated.
They can hardly
keep up with the work.
[speaking foreign language]
[clanking]
[narrator] In the workshop
of the Bardo Museum,
Ieshia Benabed is training
young women
in the traditional craft.
They are using original mosaics
from the
Vandal period as models.
During excavations, Iesia
found out the local experts
laid the mosaics
in the Vandals villas
with motifs of Roman myths,
legions,
and scenes from everyday life
on the Mediterranean.
[haunting music continues]
[narrator] The Vandals enjoyed
the pleasures
of a richly laid table.
They ate the best that
the sea and the land produced.
Thus writes the
early historian, Procopius.
They adapted very quickly
to conditions
on the Mediterranean,
and lived as the
new masters of the country,
in the style of the Romans
they so admired.
The African provinces were named
the Granaries of Rome.
For centuries,
the fertile land provided
the people of Rome with grain,
dried dates, wine and oil.
In Africa,
the Vandals sought and found
the promised land.
Their Garden of Eden
as they knew it from the Bible.
However,
their goal was Carthage.
[splashing]
[narrator] Just the journey
from Gibraltar, took six years.
Two thousand kilometers
through Roman territory,
heading east.
They had reached
the second and third generations
in their search for a new home.
Not many of those
who had first fled from the Huns
in their homeland in the
cold rainy north, were left.
[galloping]
[narrator]
The Vandals had left Spain,
and crossed the Mediterranean
to take possession
of the Roman provinces
in Africa for themselves.
The emperor,
too weak to fight them,
made peace with the Vandals
and generously handed over
a part of Africa
to their king, Genseric.
Genseric was forty years old.
A general who was
as brilliant as he was brutal.
A clever
strategist and diplomat.
Their king,
Genseric, was a deep thinker.
Silent, furious in anger,
acquisitive, far-sighted,
and extremely cunning.
That is how
the Gothic historian,
Jordanis, described him.
Genseric led
his people for fifty years,
and made the Vandals
a power, feared by Rome.
[majestic music]
[narrator] They met no
significant resistance in Africa
as there was no longer
a Roman army to block their way.
So, Genseric led his Vandals
without
major losses, to Carthage.
This is how archaeologists
imagined how Carthage looked.
It was one of the largest
port cities of antiquity.
To protect it
against the Vandals,
a wall
was built around the metropolis,
but to no avail.
Genseric took the city
by surprise, during peacetime.
[narrator] However,
according to Ieshia Benabed,
Carthage did not suffer
under the Vandals rule.
In fact, the ancient
metropolis in the Bay of Tunis
became
dangerous competition for Rome.
[casual music]
[narrator] The Carthage
basin has been here
for thousands of years.
The legendary prize
of the Roman war
and merchant fleet was here.
It fell
into the hands of the Vandals.
They were not
originally seafarers,
but took
to the sea very quickly.
From here,
the Vandals soon controlled
distant parts
of the Mediterranean
with their fleet.
They conquered
the Balearic Islands,
Sardinia, Corsica and Sicily.
They sailed
up the Tiber, sacked Rome,
and expanded
their kingdom in Africa.
Archaeologists have excavated
the villa area of Carthage,
and partially reconstructed it.
This is where
the richest of the rich lived.
The Vandal kings joined them,
in order to live the life
of luxury like the Romans.
[narrator] To this day,
Ieshia Benabed
and her colleagues, have not
found any traces of destruction
by the Vandals anywhere
in the whole of Tunisia.
Once they settle down, she says,
they had only one interest,
to assimilate, to integrate
into society,
and live like civilized Romans.
[casual music]
[narrator] So the Vandals rule
is not a blot
on Tunisia's history.
On the contrary, it was a period
of independence from Rome.
Thus,
like many countries in Europe,
Tunisia also has
a Germanic history.
[haunting music continues]
[narrator] Archaeologists
found important evidence
of the Vandals role
deep in the south of Tunisia
in [indistinct] which is
Arabic for the arcades.
A baptismal font
from the Vandal period
lies buried under rubble.
The Vandals
are regarded as suppressors
of the Roman Catholics here.
The archaeologist,
Fahti Bejaoui, has excavated
the Basilica
of the Vandal king, Thrasamund.
He was more tolerant
in religious matters
than his opponents
would have it, he says.
[narrator] The Vandals
were Arian Christians,
but the local people
were Roman Catholic Christians.
The Vandals later gave up
persecuting the Catholics
in order to win them over.
The Basilica in [indistinct]
is evidence of this.
Here, both Arians
and Catholics went to church,
were married,
and had their children baptized.
The Basilica was built in 521,
in the 26th year
of the rule
of the Vandal King, Thrasamund.
Anno, Bicesimovi,
Domni, Treasamundi.
It is the only known
inscription of the Vandals.
After the Vandals failed
to keep their promises to Rome,
the emperor sent
General Belisarius with troops
in 533. He defeated
the Vandals convincingly.
After
one hundred and four years,
their empire
in Africa ended forever.
Over one hundred years before,
the Visigoths
had journeyed through Greece
and the Balkans,
fleeing from the Huns.
In the year 408,
they appeared in Italy.
[screeching]
[narrator] In 40 of wandering,
about two generations,
they had traveled more than
three thousand kilometers.
Alaric, was their king.
At the foot of the Italian Alps,
they were hoping
for more than asylum.
For the emperor
needed Germans as legionaries.
Sometimes fighting,
sometimes negotiating.
They had moved from the
Byzantine to the Roman world.
Refuges between the fronts
of the divided empire.
All the Visigoths, eighty to
one hundred thousand of them,
were on their way to Rome.
Including twenty thousand
experienced warriors!
A sizable army.
[dramatic music]
[narrator] The army had lost
many battles against the Romans,
but not the war.
Emperor Humorous was inclined
to underestimate them.
He lived to regret it.
Ubbi, Benni, Ebbi, Partia.
Where I live well,
that is my country.
And where
could the Visigoths live better,
than in the land
of their dreams, Italy.
It was 409 AD.
King Alaric sent an emissary
to Emperor Humorous,
to ask whether his people
could stay peacefully in Italy.
And offering him
the services of the Goths.
Rome, the eternal city.
The Visigoths
admired the achievements
of remnant civilization,
the prosperity,
and the legal system.
They did not
want to destroy all that.
The Germans wanted
participation and integration.
They wanted
to become like the Romans.
Alaric told the emperor
that the Visigoths were willing
to defend
the frontiers of the empire,
and wanted to live
in such harmony with the Romans,
that they could be
taken for one people.
But if the emperor
were to refuse the request,
the stronger of the two
would drive away the weaker,
and the victor
would rule in peace.
[galloping]
[narrator] The emperor briskly
rejected Alaric's request.
With their military strength
greater than ever,
the Visigoths were confident.
Their army
was extremely well equipped.
Many of them had served
as officers and generals
in the Roman army.
[roaring]
[narrator] Spangenhelm,
or helmet of the kind
worn by the Germanic leaders.
The Visigoths were all
professional soldiers
willing to serve Rome for gold,
grain and land to settle.
And to use their weapons
against the empire's enemies.
[banging]
[narrator] But although
the emperor in Italy no longer
had any
legions worth mentioning,
he refused
the Visigoths request.
He did not want them in Italy!
He felt safe
behind the walls of the cities.
[sizzling]
[narrator] That could mean
only one thing, war.
[galloping]
[narrator] In the year 410,
the battle for Rome began.
For eight hundred years,
Rome's enemies
had entered the city
only as prisoners or slaves
of the most
powerful engine empire.
Never as conquerors!
[ominous music]
[narrator] The senate and
the people of Rome felt safe.
Two hundred years earlier,
Marcus Aurelius had
the foresight to have new walls
built around Rome
to stop the Barbarians.
The walls
are still standing today.
For the Visigoths,
the city proved impregnable.
As they were approaching,
Emperor Humorous had the
gates closed to Alaric's hordes.
Apparently, 10,000 Romans
were ready to defend the city.
The thicker the grass,
the easier it is to mow,
Alaric is believed to have said.
[ominous music continues]
[narrator] In August 410,
the Visigoths besieged
the eternal city.
It was the third time,
this time they were serious.
They cut off the water supply,
and blocked
the grain shipments to Rome.
Rome was thirsty and starving.
Epidemic spread.
Sixty thousand Germanic slaves
were waiting
for their liberators.
They had plenty of accounts
to settle with the Romans.
Turmoil reigned.
To prevent things getting worse,
a noble lady
apparently had a gate opened
for the Visigoths.
[clanking]
[screaming]
[narrator] For three days,
an eternity for the Romans.
The Visigoths
pillaged, killed and raped.
At Alaric's behest,
the Visigoths sacked Rome.
However,
they did not set fire to it,
as wild peoples usually do.
And did not allow any
sacred places to be desecrated.
Roma capta.
On the
twenty-fourth of August, 410,
Rome was captured.
After eight hundred years,
the most
powerful city in the world,
was once again
in the hands of strangers
of Barbarians.
[serious flute music]
[narrator] While his warriors
were marauding in Rome,
Alaric proved himself
to be a Christian.
The Pantheon, the former temple
of all the Gods, was now
a Roman Catholic church.
For a thousand years,
it was the largest in the world.
Alaric placed all the priests
under his personal protection.
No one
was allowed to touch them.
And he forbid
the looting of church treasures,
for the Visigoths
were Christians.
Although they were Arians,
they respected
the Roman Catholic Church,
and the bishop of Rome.
Many Romans preferred
the Christian Barbarians
to their fellow citizens,
who still offered
bloody sacrifices
to the heathen Gods.
[creaking]
[narrator] Although
the Visigoths did not believe
that Jesus
was one substance with God,
they did believe
in God the Father,
read the same Christian Bible,
and say
the same Christian prayers.
[heavenly music]
[narrator] Alaric never
wanted to roll over the empire.
All he wanted
was a place for his people
in the Roman Empire.
But,
the emperor refused him that.
An error
with fateful consequences!
The city of Rome
has been conquered,
that previously
conquered the whole world,
lamented Humorous,
a father of the Church.
Rome had lost
much of its power.
The Roman Empire
had long been an invalid,
barely able to survive,
without the Germanic peoples.
So, the Goths merely toppled,
what was already falling.
Only after eight more
years of wandering and war,
were they able to settle
in the Roman provinces
in the south of France, in 418.
They finally became
what they always wanted to be,
legionaries,
in the service of Rome.
As hospices,
or guest workers for a period,
they received latifundia,
or estates from the Roman state.
But like all guest workers,
they would remain.
The Visigoth immigrants
must have lived in harmony
with the local people.
Today,
historians are sure of that.
[heavenly music continues]
[narrator] But very few of those
who had fled over theDanube
from the Huns
as children were still alive.
From the knowledge of the old,
from songs and stories,
the historian Jordanis,
wrote the saga of the Goths.
It tells of their ancestors,
who had once left Scandinavia,
and traveled to the Black Sea
and the Danube
as far as the south of France.
Of all the Germanic peoples
on the [indistinct]
the Visigoths
had the longest journey
to find a permanent home.
[haunting flute music]
[narrator]
The Visigoths were the first
of the
wondering Germanic tribes,
to find their own
realm in the Roman Empire.
The Visigoth kingdom
in the south of France.
However, they did not
destroy the Roman Empire,
they established
themselves in it.
But danger still threatened them
from the Huns.
[serious music]
[narrator] In 451,
the Huns attacked Gaul,
looting and murdering.
Germanic tribes followed them.
Ostrogoth's, Illyrians,
Maculmany, Bagandians
and Frankish groups.
A huge
military column changed Rome.
At the head of the Huns,
was the most
terrible of all warriors,
Attila, the leader
of so many victories
and ruler of so many peoples.
The scourge of God.
History has
demonized the king of the Huns,
and made him
into an anti-Christ.
It is true,
that Attila could only increase
his kingdom at the expense
of the western Roman Empire.
That is why he invaded Gaul.
The Catismoriacus,
or the Catalaunian Plains,
here, near Troyes,
in the heart of France,
two gigantic armies
opposed one another
in a decisive battle.
The battlefield was a plain,
with a gradual incline.
General Aetius and his Romans
formed the left flank,
while King Theodoric
and his Visigoths
formed the right flank.
It was four hundred
and fifty one, AD.
The historian Jordanis recorded
what happened on that day.
A turning point
in Europe's destiny.
[trickling]
[narrator] The battle
with the Huns, lasted all day.
The stream
was swollen with blood.
Nightfall
put a stop to the battle.
However,
the result was uncertain.
Only the next morning,
when they saw the piles
of corpses on the field,
and saw
that the Huns no longer
dared to leave their camp,
did the Romans and Visigoths
believe that the battle was won.
[serious music]
[narrator] But the Visigoths
were missing their king,
Theodoric.
They searched for him
desperately, among the dead.
This part of the earth
became the battlefield
of countless peoples.
How great,
must the hatred have been
to make them all resort
to arms against one another?
Not only Huns and Romans
lay among the dead
on the Catalaunian Plains.
Ostrogoths
had fought against Visigoths,
Franks from the lower Rhine,
against Franks
from the upper Rhine.
Germans against Germans.
For them, loyalty and allegiance
counted more than descent.
The relationship
between their tribes,
did not prevent
the Germans from fighting
one another to the death.
[haunting music continues]
[narrator] And then
the Visigoths found their brave
and noble king,
Theodoric, among the corpses,
pierced
by the spear of an Ostrogoth
from a related tribe,
who had followed Aetius flags.
It was forced fratricide,
Jordanis wrote
in his saga of the Goths.
In the battle however,
it was
the courageous Visigoth army
that attacked
Aetius and the Huns,
and forced them to flee.
Was it the Barbarians,
the Visigoths of all people,
who saved
the Roman Empire from the Huns?
That's one way of looking at it!
After they had terrorized
Europe
for eight years,
the myth of the invincible Huns
was shattered!
[dramatic music]
[narrator]
They had finally been defeated
by the alliance of the Romans,
Visigoths and Franks.
Their rule in Europe
had come to an end!
Their king,
Aetius, died in 453 AD.
The Huns moved back
to the steps of Asia.
Just as they
appeared from nowhere,
they vanished again,
into nothing.
In 463 AD,
everything was open again.
Would Rome
regain its power and strength?
Would the Germanic Barbarians
destroy the Roman Empire
and the ancient civilization?
Or would they
become the heirs of the empire?
[ending theme music]