(thrilling music)
(seagull calling)
(gentle music)
- It's like torching every relationship
that's ever meant a damn to you.
I left that dear, sweet
baby in his dirty diaper.
And after all that, I still
ain't put that bottle down.
(prisoners chattering)
(bell ringing)
- This is a safe place.
This is a haven from the world outside.
There's no judgment here.
Today is a very, very special day for him
because today he earns his 90-day chip.
Thomas.
(prisoners chattering)
(banging)
- My name is Thomas Lewis,
and I'm an alcoholic.
- [Together] Hi, Thomas.
- Now I can speak to a
classroom full of 200 students,
but every time I come up here
it's like I'm sweatin' bullets.
It means 13 months ago I
was finalizing my divorce.
A short amount of time,
things look so different,
I feel...
Clear.
(prisoners chattering)
(bell ringing)
I'm grateful my ex-wife
is finally allowing me
to see my daughter unsupervised,
which means I don't have
to look over my shoulder
at the social worker looking
at me like I'm a criminal.
- You'll be back.
- Brittany, that's my daughter's name.
Things go well then she gets
to spend the night with me.
Because of you, I'm planning on
having ice cream with my daughter.
(group applauding)
(upbeat pop music)
(sniffing)
(children shouting)
- Dad!
- Hey, I know you!
- Oh, I missed you.
- I missed you.
Look at you.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Hey, sweetie, go ahead, go play.
You know what?
I'll let you know when it's time to go.
Wow.
These kids got so much energy.
They're hype, they're making me hyper.
You remember having this
much energy as a kid?
- No, I don't know anybody that has
as much energy as she does.
- 90-day chip, just like I promised you.
- I'm surprised you went through
with everything this time.
- Oh.
- I didn't mean that.
- No, no, no, it's fine.
Hey, Brittany!
Let's go, let's go!
(hands clapping)
I got a surprise for you at home.
- Bye, guys.
Ooh, a surprise?
Is it a phone?
- Well, how are you gonna find out
unless you get in the car?
- Yes!
(laughing)
Bye, Mom!
- Bye.
Have fun, honey.
Be sure you have her in bed by nine, okay?
- Yeah.
- And look, Thomas, I
didn't mean anything.
- No, no, look, it's fine.
Thanks again.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- All right.
(birds chirping)
(sighs)
(midtempo hip hop music)
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ First things first,
you da girl, get it ♪
♪ And I tell her till the
end, Imma fuck with her ♪
♪ And she tell me all she
want is me to roll with her ♪
♪ Imma take her to the top ♪
(clears throat)
♪ I never give up ♪
- Wish me luck.
♪ You're the only girl I
like, only girl I like ♪
♪ You know you is my type,
know you is my type ♪
♪ You know your pussy fine,
know your pussy fine ♪
♪ You know that pussy fine ♪
♪ First things first,
you da girl, get it ♪
♪ And I tell her till the
end, Imma fuck with her ♪
♪ And she tell me all she
want is me to roll with her ♪
♪ Imma take her to the
top and I won't give up ♪
♪ Never give up ♪
- Hmm, and where did you say
this high school was again?
- Fairbanks, Alaska.
- Oh.
- My dad was in the military.
- Oh, okay.
'Cause I've just never seen a
transcript like this before.
- Is that gonna be a problem?
- No, no, it shouldn't.
Here's your schedule
and map of the campus.
And welcome.
- Cool, thanks.
- [Lady] Hey, there, how can I help you?
- My name is Professor Thomas Lewis.
For those of you in the back,
that is...
(sharpie scratching)
Professor
Thomas
Lewis.
Now in broad strokes we will be
covering various ancient
mythologies from around the world.
But before I get started,
I'd like to introduce you to my assistant.
Your TA, Leslie.
Please stand and tell the class
a little bit about yourself.
- Of course.
Hi, everybody, that's me.
I have known Thomas for quite a while.
I've taken this course before so I
have a pretty good idea at what I'm doing.
If you guys have any questions,
you guys need help with anything,
please feel free to ask me.
I'm here to help.
- Now, if you're looking
for her work hours,
they're in the syllabus right under mine.
Well, speaking of syllabus,
who in here doesn't have one?
Raise your hand.
Can you help me with, uh.
- Yeah, of course.
- In the back and I'll
take care of the front.
All right.
(mellow music)
Now that everybody has their syllabus,
let's get into this mythology.
Right, isn't it about a hero's journey?
Let's find this hero's journey.
All right.
- You guys need help with something?
- Yeah.
- [Leslie] So I don't really
know what this is saying,
but I can go ahead and ask the
professor if he can help us.
Professor Lewis, can you come over here
and help us for a second please?
- Sure.
- Kay, they need help
with this one, if you can.
- Okay, well, you know what?
Disregard that, just go
to chapter one, all right?
- You are so smart.
- Oh, no, no.
You're the smart one.
(laughing)
- I really appreciate it.
You know, I'm happy to
be back in your class.
- Oh, I'm happy to have you, yes.
- [Leslie] So I'll
catch up with you later?
- Okay.
- Okay, cool.
(hip hop music)
♪ Gimme space, let me breathe ♪
♪ '02, give me three ♪
♪ Know I'm never trying to please ♪
(books crash)
(horn honking)
(tires screeching)
- Jerk!
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
- In his defense, he
did kinda honk his horn.
- I can't hear nothing with
these on so maybe he did.
- You're in one of my classes, aren't ya?
- Yeah.
- How are you liking it so far?
- I mean, for the first day it was cool.
- It was cool?
Okay, well, that's good.
I see you're job hunting, huh?
- Yeah.
I need a job.
- Well, I don't wanna impose,
but do you mind if I make a suggestion?
- Go ahead.
- Well, a couple blocks from
here is a diner called Sal's.
I used to go there a couple of days
out of the week after class.
Best steak and eggs I've ever had.
Owner's name is Julio, great guy.
Could always use some help.
That's, well, of course if you don't mind
getting your hands dirty.
- No, I don't mind at all.
- Good.
Tell him Thomas Lewis sent you.
- All right, cool, thanks.
- All right.
And, uh.
I think you should look
both ways when you cross.
It's a good thing.
- All right.
- I'll see you in class.
- Yeah.
(crickets chirping)
Hi.
Hi!
That's me!
Leslie!
I already took this class.
So I already know everything.
Yeah, I know it all.
I already know Professor Lewis.
Hmm.
(pills rattling)
(suspenseful music)
I'll get the ones in the back.
- A frequent theme in all mythologies
is the correlation between love and loss.
Heart-wrenching passion...
and death.
Hello, Ms. Jacobs.
Please, have a seat.
- Sorry.
- Your hair looks nice by the way.
- Thank you.
- Love and death is a constant trope
used in all mythologies.
A character is allowed to
find their one true love,
allowed to be with them for
a certain period of time.
And then, for one reason or
another, tragedy strikes,
and the two are torn apart.
If you look at the Greek story, allegory
of Orpheus and Eurydice,
or Isis and Osiris,
or even in the modern biblical parable
of Sodom and Gomorrah.
In it, Lot worked
tirelessly to save the city,
but even in the end,
it is his own wife that is
turned into a pillar of salt.
- Hey, Professor Lewis.
Hey.
- Hey, Tracy.
What can I do for you?
- I just wanted to say thanks again.
Besides saving my life last week
you recommending Sal's was a good thing.
I got the job, I started yesterday.
- Good, congratulations.
- Thank you.
- I guess I'm gonna have to go down there
and order a steak and
eggs special from you.
- Oh my God, I would love that.
I usually work
Wednesday nights--
- Hey, Tom, I had a few
questions about the papers
I was given yesterday...
Oh, I am so sorry.
I didn't realize you
guys were, I apologize.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
Go ahead and finish.
- No, it's cool.
We were finished.
- Well, congratulations again.
I'll see you next class.
- Okay.
- It's a cute little color though.
Um, yeah, so apparently I'm
gonna be here late tonight
between discussing a
paper with the students
and now I'm reading--
- Yes, yes, I know another long night,
but I really need you to
take care of this for me.
- All right, no problem.
- Thank you, Leslie.
- Got it.
(thrilling music)
(pills rattling)
(crickets chirping)
(heels clacking)
(thrilling music)
(suspenseful music)
(whistling)
(dramatic music)
(box crashes)
(groaning)
(hand slapping)
(screaming)
Help!
(choking)
(dramatic music)
(body crashes)
- I'm sure you all heard about
what happened to Leslie already.
Needless to say that today's
class will be canceled.
(knocking)
Please, come in.
These detectives would like
to have a word with you.
- Thank you, Mr. Lewis.
This is my card in case any
of you have heard anything
or have any details
regarding Leslie's murder.
We also have a photo of
the potential suspect
that was captured on the security camera.
- I'll make sure to make some
copies and hand them out.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Mr. Lewis.
(sighs)
(knocking)
Hold on.
Come in.
- Hi, hope I'm not interrupting anything.
- No, no, no, please.
Come in, have a seat.
How can I help you?
- Actually, I was coming
to check up on you.
- Very kind of you.
I'm still trying to process
all of this, you know.
Leslie was a great person.
She didn't deserve what happened to her.
Well, listen, if it makes
you feel any better,
I'd like to offer you a
steak and eggs dinner on me.
I mean, at this point I
kinda owe you my life.
You gotta let me repay the debt somehow.
- Maybe another time.
Right now, I don't have
much of an appetite.
- Okay.
Well, I have another favor.
Leslie was giving me rides home from work.
She was so sweet to help me out for that.
I should have known something was wrong
when she didn't respond to my texts.
- I'm sorry, I had no idea
that you two had gotten that close.
- Yeah, I went to her to
ask her for help on a paper
and, from there, she
let me open up to her.
And she offered to help me.
- That sounds like Leslie.
Always going the extra mile.
I'm sorry, yes.
- You know what, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have asked.
- No.
- It was inappropriate.
- No, no, no, it's fine.
What time do you need me to pick you up?
- Well, I get off at nine,
but if you come in at 8:30
I can have that steak and
eggs plate ready for you.
- Sounds like I'll be there at 8:30.
- Great.
(hip hop music)
♪ They know I keep it 100 ♪
- Oh, right on time, just how I like it.
Go ahead and sit anywhere.
- Okay, thanks.
- I've got your steak cooking right now.
What sides would you like?
- Toast and hash.
- Okay.
You want something a
little stronger than water?
I've got a little personal
stash in the back.
- No, water's fine.
- You sure?
It'd be our little secret.
- I don't drink.
- Never or not anymore?
- Anymore.
- Interesting.
I'll be right back.
- I'm not doing this.
What the hell are you doing here?
Get up.
Get up and go.
All right, all right. (clears throat)
- Oh, food's here.
I had them prepare your steak medium well,
and your hash browns will be right out.
- Looks perfect.
- (sighs) Oh, good.
What a long, weird, twisted day, right?
- So, how's work coming along?
- It's as pleasant as
working any night shift
in a diner could be.
I'm like Cinderella around here.
It's very glamorous.
(chuckles)
- So what did you do before this?
- Before the diner?
- No, before L.A.
I'm sorry, I saw on your resume
that you worked a few places out of town.
- I was in the military,
stationed in Germany,
and then I did two years in Iraq.
- Wow.
Thank you for your services.
- Yeah, I guess.
Listen, you better eat
up before that gets cold.
- Yeah.
(knife scratches)
- Mmm.
You were right, that is good.
- Oh.
(moans softly)
- You're blushing, that's cute.
I'm gonna check on your hash
browns and let you finish,
and I have a few things to do around here
and then we can go, okay?
♪ You know I keep it 100 ♪
♪ 100, 100, 100, 100 ♪
- This is me right here.
Hey, thanks again, professor.
It's like you're always saving me.
- Call me Tom.
Don't worry about it, I
was a college student once.
- So, Tom.
Are you full?
- I'm stuffed.
Might as well try and get to a bed ASAP.
- Sounds like fun.
- No, I didn't mean it like that.
- You're blushing, again.
- Tracy, you're a beautiful girl.
- I'm 26.
I'm far from a girl, okay?
- I'm sorry, you're a beautiful woman,
but I'm practically twice your age.
- And?
- And, not to mention,
you're also my student.
- It's not illegal for us to
enjoy each other's time, Tom.
- No.
No, it's not.
But it is unethical.
If anyone was to find out
then I could lose my job.
Look, I wanna be straight with you.
I'm just coming off of what
was over a yearlong sabbatical
so I can't afford to be
a part of any scandal.
- I can keep a secret.
Listen, I...
think that you should reconsider, okay?
- Let's just go back and, oop.
I really can't do this,
I just got back and.
Wait, I.
Stop, stop, all right?
I, this can't happen.
- Well, I can feel that
you're not gay so what is it?
You married or divorced?
- Divorced.
- Well, clearly you're not
over it, but that's okay.
If you need help getting over it
you know where to find me.
You still love her?
(sighs)
Right.
(hip hop music)
- [Tom] Megan, come on!
I just need to talk to you for a second.
- Thomas, is that you?
Thomas, what the hell are you doing here?
- Look, I'm sorry, I've been
calling Megan on the phone.
She's not picking up.
- Honey, it is after midnight.
- Yes, I know, I just need
to talk to her for a second.
- Mom, Mom, Mom, I got it.
- What, what?
- No, I have it.
I got this one.
- Are you sure, honey?
- Yes, thank you.
Thomas, what the hell are you doing here?
- When'd your mother move in?
- What do you want, Thomas?
You know Brittany's asleep upstairs,
not to mention the fact I have two houses
to show in the morning.
- Look, I just need to
talk to you for a second.
Can I come in?
(groans)
(Thomas sighs)
(sighs)
- What do you want, Thomas?
(gentle music)
- I miss you.
I just want to know if we're
working towards something,
towards fixing us?
- Fixing us?
Is that what you've been
worried about, Thomas?
Fixing us?
- Look, I know I wasn't there
for you when you needed me.
- Look, Thomas.
I used to beg you to worry about fixing us
before we were broken.
But you don't even remember that
because you were too blacked out drunk.
- You know why I drank.
- Of course I know why you drank.
- I never blamed you for what
happened and I never will.
You're a good father.
But what I will blame you
for is what happened after
'cause that bottle became
your shoulder to cry on
instead of me.
Where was my shoulder, Thomas?
Where was my shoulder?
- Megan, I.
- You know what?
You really even shouldn't even be worried
about fixing us right now.
What you need to worry about fixing
is that little girl
that's sleeping upstairs.
Repairing her memory of seeing her father
coming in in the middle
of the day all the time
blacked out drunk.
Okay, you fix that, Thomas!
Fix that, okay?
Fix that!
(Thomas sighs)
- Tell Diane that I'm
sorry for waking her.
- Thomas.
- It's fine.
- Hey.
The hardest thing in the world
is to reject the man you love.
- Mom, I can't.
(crying)
- Oh, honey.
Oh, don't cry.
Don't cry, I know, baby.
It's gonna be all right.
It's gonna be all right, I promise, okay?
(lips smacking)
You'll be all right.
(heels clacking)
- Knock, knock.
- Tracy.
Ms. Jacobs.
- Professor Lewis.
- I didn't see you in class today.
- I couldn't show my face in there
after what happened the other night.
(suspenseful music)
- You know what?
Why don't we just forget it?
- No, I was inappropriate,
and you were being a perfect gentleman.
I can't forget it.
- Look, we all do things
we shouldn't have done.
Sometimes we make mistakes we regret.
- I didn't say I regretted anything.
I mean, you're cute, you're
smart, you're single.
An opportunity presented
itself and I took it.
- Ms. Jacobs.
- Listen, I'm just saying,
my offer still stands.
You forgot what it feels
like to be desired.
(clears throat)
- This has gone far beyond appropriate.
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
- (sighs) No.
I'm not stupid.
I know you want me.
- It doesn't matter what I want.
- It's the only thing that matters.
(door slams)
♪ Girl, you're when I woke up ♪
♪ And all this time I've
been trying to find you ♪
♪ There's no woman that compares to you ♪
♪ No one that does the
things you do, baby ♪
♪ Girl, you're beautiful, beautiful ♪
♪ In case you didn't know, now you know ♪
♪ Girl, you're so beautiful, beautiful ♪
♪ Girl, you're beautiful, beautiful ♪
♪ In case you didn't know, now you know ♪
♪ Girl, you're so beautiful, beautiful ♪
- Hey.
Sorry I took so long.
Oh.
Ooh, I spilled something.
You have napkins in here?
- We have napkins right.
- What is this?
- Let me get that.
- Is this her, your ex-wife?
She's pretty.
- Yeah.
That's her.
- Oh my gosh, is this your daughter?
She's adorable, she's your twin.
- Let me, let me.
- Tom, I thought you said
you only had one kid.
(gentle music)
- I do.
You know, Megan named him after me.
I was excited to have a Junior.
He was a great kid.
Then one summer, Megan, my ex-wife,
she had to go out and show some houses and
she left me with the kids.
I remember Brittany,
she was taking a nap and
I put Junior in the crib.
I can't remember, you know.
Did I put him on the side,
did I put him on his back.
It go.
It goes and plays over
and over in my head,
but I...
I can't remember.
But I remember the phone
rang, it was my publisher.
He was all excited about my new book.
Projected sales and all kind of nonsense.
Things like that.
And I remember I had
a few glasses of wine,
and I'm thinking like, man.
(laughs)
I don't know. (clears throat)
Maybe it was an hour,
but when I looked back,
it was like an eternity.
'Cause when I went back in that room.
He was blue.
Sudden infant death syndrome, SIDS,
that's what they call it.
Happens in one in every
1000 infants and my...
Junior, he had to be one.
You know, two things.
Two things that'll haunt
me for the rest of my life
and that's...
Seeing my son blue in that crib.
And then having to tell his mother
and look her in the eyes
and tell her, her son,
our boy, he's gone.
He's gone.
You know, she never
accused me, not one time,
not one time, never said
one accusatory remark,
but she didn't have to, no.
I did that all by myself.
You know, I couldn't face
her, I couldn't face her.
I couldn't face my daughter, Brittany.
All I could do was drink.
I had to drink.
Malt liquor, drink that.
Vodka, drink that.
Tequila, I don't want
no shots, drink that.
That's all I knew that would allow me
to look at myself in the mirror every day.
And Megan she, ah.
She tried, she tried.
But all I knew was to push
her away, push everyone away.
Megan, she had to realize she
had to take care of herself
and Brittany, and three DUIs later,
and a little stint in jail,
she gave me the divorce papers.
1:36 PM on a Thursday she gave 'em to me.
I signed them, didn't even look at it.
I sighed away my rights to my daughter
because I knew
they were better without me.
And I was better without
them because, you know what?
At least I had the bottle.
It took me six months
to get up enough courage
to go to AA and...
Another three months to stop drinking.
- So this is what you want?
To never drink again?
- It's a blessing.
♪ Girl, when you're emotional ♪
- Yeah, bruh, so you
say she's your student?
Bruh, have you lost your mind?
- Man, you know what?
I knew you were gonna say that.
That's why I didn't wanna tell you.
- You're damn right I was gonna say that.
Because you have lost it!
- I didn't pursue her, she pursued me.
- (baby voice) Look, I didn't
pursue her, she pursued me.
I don't care who pursued who, man!
Wait, wait, how old is she, man?
Please don't tell me she 18.
- She not 18.
- Well, how old is she?
- Look, there's something
about this woman.
It's like she's exactly
what I need right now.
- Oh, she exactly what you
need right now, but is she 18?
- She's 26.
- What you need is a swift
kick in your ass right now.
That's what you need, man.
What if the faculty finds
out that you're sleeping
with one of your students?
Then what happens?
Maybe I get reprimanded,
a suspension, maybe worse.
(sighs)
- It's worth risking all that, huh?
- Hey, come on, man, look.
You're not just my AA sponsor, all right,
you're my best friend.
So you know everything about me.
This the first woman that
I've been with since Megan.
Look, look, I'm talking raw,
animalistic distraction.
(chuckles)
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait a minute.
- That's what we talking,
what we talking about.
- About...
- [Together] Raw.
Animalistic.
Distraction.
- There you go.
- All right, all right,
all right, all right.
Okay, I understand that,
brah, and I get it, all right?
But I just. (groans)
Just be careful, man, all right?
Hey, you know what they say, man.
The easiest time to start a new addiction
is when you're getting over a old one.
Food for thought.
- Food for thought.
From my AA sponsor who brings me back
to my old watering hole.
- Drink your water.
Okay, all right. (laughing)
- Totally not a big deal.
- You sure we gonna make
our reservation?
- Yes, I'm sure, I just need
five minutes, 10 minutes tops.
I just gotta freshen up.
- You know you're perfect
as you are, right?
- Thank you.
Give me five minutes, go sit down.
- Hey, is this a picture of you?
- Yeah!
- Why is it I never noticed it before?
- [Tracy] You come in here and
you go straight to the bed.
You don't notice anything in here.
(laughing)
- When'd you take this picture?
- It was taken the nights my parents died.
- What?
- Not a big deal, I was five years old.
I barely remember anything.
All I know is there was a fire,
I made it out, they didn't.
Some jerk photographer took
my picture and there it is.
- You have any siblings?
- Nope, just me.
- So what happened to you
after your parents died?
- I moved from foster home to foster home
until I turned 18 and I
decided to go in the military.
- Why is it that I'm just
finding out about this?
- Because I was trying to avoid
these awkward conversations
and now that you know everything,
can I finish getting dressed?
- [Tom] Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Thanks.
(sighs)
- You know I could just imagine that--
- Please, do you knock?
- What's that?
Come on, come on, let me see.
I'll open it for you.
Clozapine.
What's that for?
- Oh my goodness.
- All right, what's going on?
Come on, talk to me.
- Well, if you must know,
they're antidepressants.
I suffer from post-traumatic
stress disorder
from being in the military,
and a doctor prescribes them for me.
- Okay.
Well, I guess I'm learning
all kind of new stuff
about you tonight.
- It's not that bad really.
I just hate taking them
because I start feeling weird
and foggy, almost like
I'm not my natural self.
- Come here.
It's all right.
(gentle music)
You're an amazing woman.
And I'm in awe of you right now.
- Really?
- Absolutely.
After all that you've been through,
pulling yourself up by the bootstraps.
Look, if those pills, they
make you feel like that
then I'm sorry, it's a shame
because I enjoy getting
to know the natural you.
- You do?
- Of course, I do.
- I think we should stay in tonight.
- You do?
- Yeah.
I have a surprise for you I've been
wanting to give you anyway so.
I'm gonna go get ready for the surprise.
You get in the bed and I'll
get your surprise ready.
- Surprises.
I like surprises.
♪ Can't live without you, yeah ♪
♪ I'll never run out on you, yeah, yeah ♪
- You like?
- Oh yeah, I like.
- Lay down.
- And what are you gonna do with those?
- These...
are part of my surprise.
Are you nervous?
- I don't know, should I be?
- No.
Maybe a little.
- So.
- You ready for the surprise?
- I hope it has nothing
to do with a feather
because it's unmanly how ticklish I am.
- (whispers) It's not feathers.
Okay, close your eyes.
(dramatic music)
Open your mouth.
- Hmm, what?
- Open your mouth.
Open it.
(coughs)
- What are you doing?
- I'm being your serpent in the tree.
You know you want it.
And I won't tell anyone,
especially your ex.
- No, stop.
- Why, because of some AA pledge?
They don't know anything.
They just tell you to suppress your urges.
Life is about giving in.
You can be free here.
I want you to be your true self.
So have a drink with me.
I won't tell anyone.
(slow tempo hip hop music)
(suspenseful music)
(pill rattles)
(pills rattle)
(birds chirping)
- Hey.
What you doin' out here?
I was looking all over for you.
- Did you get my note?
- No, I didn't get your note but
I saw you through the window.
- This is amazing.
I come out here.
I like to feel the wind.
This is my safe place.
Clear out all the noise in my head.
- Well, your safe place is
not that good for my migraine.
- You got a hangover?
- Yeah, I guess you could call it that.
I need some asprin or something.
What time you got?
- 12:42.
- Ah.
I gotta get outta here.
- What's wrong?
- I'm late.
- Late for what?
- Well.
I need to pick up my daughter
and take her to swimming lessons.
And, well, it's gonna take
me at least 30 minutes
to go home, change up,
I need to take a shower.
- All right, well, let me get dressed.
I'll go with you.
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no, nah.
I'm good, I'm good.
Look, I couldn't find my
phone, where'd you put it?
- It's on the side of the bed.
Why is it that you don't want
me to be around your daughter?
It's like you don't want me
to meet her or something.
Why?
- Come on, really?
Because.
- Because?
Because is not an answer.
Because why?
- It's a little too early for
all of that, don't you think?
I mean, I got a 10-year-old
daughter who's already
wondering why her daddy's
not there tucking her in.
Now she's gonna wonder why
I'm 30 minutes late or more
just to take her to swimming lessons.
Last thing I need to do is
add another adult in the mix
so she has more questions to ask, okay?
- No, it's not okay.
- It's gonna have to be, 'cause
you're not gonna meet her.
Come on, give me a kiss, I gotta go.
Come on.
Come here.
(lips smacking)
All right.
Talk to you later, all right?
I need to get outta here.
(knocking)
- Thomas, you're late.
Brittany, your dad's here!
I missed an appointment because of you.
- Megan, I'm sorry, I got caught up.
- Dad, you're late.
You made Mom miss an
appointment with a new client.
- You sound just like your mother.
Don't let it happen again.
And are you still gonna take me swimming?
- Well?
- Brittany, go get the swimsuit
your grandmother gave you, okay?
- Yes!
- Megan, I just wanna
thank you again for this.
I know you ain't have to do this.
- What's going on with you, you okay?
- Well, I'm worse than
some, better than most.
- And what is this?
- What?
- You're more dressed down than normal.
- Come on, Dad, let's go.
Come on!
- [Megan] You guys have fun.
(phone ringing)
- [Brittany] Bye, Mom!
- Bye, honey!
- Well, I'll have her call you
before she goes to sleep tonight.
- Okay.
(lips smacking)
(engine revving)
- [Tom] Let's go, my
little fish, let's go.
(engine revving)
(TV chatter)
- [Man] He's given a
whole lot of speeches.
And we have seen that the speeches
and the reality don't match up.
- [Woman] So the basketball tournament
is this weekend at three,
and Kim's gonna come with us.
- [Man] I cannot wait.
(phone buzzing)
(phone beeping)
- [Woman] Oh, please, Scott
is never gonna settle down
with a model.
(TV chatter)
(clears throat)
- [Tracy] Okay, Tom, maybe
I overreacted a little
bit this morning.
Just call me back, okay?
Silence is not how we solve problems, Tom.
Call me back.
(suspenseful music)
Who the hell do you think you are?
How dare you ignore me?
I can destroy you.
(sighs)
(TV chatter)
(crickets chirping)
(knocking)
(soft jazz music)
I'll just invite myself in.
- Look, I don't wanna argue
with you again, all right?
- Me either, crazy.
That's not what I'm here for.
I came to give you a gift.
- What's this?
- It was my father's.
It was the only thing
that survived the fire.
(suspenseful music)
- Listen, I can't take this.
- Listen, I really, really
overreacted the other day.
You don't deserve that.
So I wanted you to have
this so you could know
how much you mean to me.
It's an apology gift.
- Look, Tracy, I accept your
apology but I cannot take this.
Are you just gonna forget about
all the 100 calls you made?
And then the
(phone ringing)
30-something voice
messages you left me, huh?
Hold on.
Hey, baby, what's goin' on, Brittany?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, slow down.
No, right, look, I can't understand you.
No, what, Diane, what's going on?
Oh, oh, okay, oh my god.
All right, all right, okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm on my way right now.
Okay, I'm leaving, bye.
- What's going on?
- Megan was in an accident,
she's in the hospital.
- [Tracy] Is Brittany okay?
- Yeah, she was with her grandmother.
I have to go.
- We can go to the hospital together.
- No, no, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, no, no, no.
You can't come with me, all right?
We've been over this.
- I'll go with you.
- No, you, no, no.
I gotta go to the
hospital, you gotta leave.
- Well, we're not finished here.
I'll just wait here until you get back.
- I don't have time for this, all right?
Look, I gotta go, lock
up the door behind you!
(sucks teeth)
- Thomas, Thomas!
- [Brittany] Dad!
- Oh, come here.
- Mommy's hurt.
Really bad.
- I know, baby, I know.
- Ah, sorry, she just came outta surgery.
She had some broken bones,
internal bleeding and.
Oh, honey, I know.
- All right, baby.
- They caught all that
in time but right now
they're just worried about
the swelling in the brain
so they had to put her in
a medically-induced coma.
- Wait, wait, ho.
Coma?
- Yeah.
They don't know how long it's gonna take,
like days, weeks, I don't know.
We just gotta, we just
gotta hope and pray.
- Hey, hey, Daddy's right here.
All right, hey, hey, it's okay.
Stay with Nana.
- It's gonna be fine.
Oh, honey, don't cry.
Please don't cry, you're
gonna make Nana cry.
(monitor beeping)
(crying)
- Okay.
(siren wailing)
(monitor beeping)
- Thank you.
(snoring softly)
(sighs)
Thomas.
Good morning.
(grunts)
- I must have dosed off.
- Here, honey.
- Good morning.
- What time is it?
I need to get Brittany to school.
- Already taken care of, my love.
- Thank you.
- Ain't nothin' but a thing.
We all family here, honey.
- And thanks for this.
- Why don't you just go on home?
I'll call you if anything changes.
- Ngh-ngh.
I can't get any rest with
her in here, not like this.
- Well, you're not gonna do her no good
if you end up in the bed
right beside her, honey.
Please, listen to me,
go home, take a shower.
Lay your head on the pillow
and get some winks of sleep
and then come back here
nice and refreshed.
You're gonna do yourself
and Megan a favor.
- Maybe you're right.
- You know I'm right.
- Okay. (clears throat)
Diane.
You know I must have
apologized to your daughter
over 1000 times for what
I did to our marriage.
But, um.
I know after our divorce
you had to step up.
I never got to say thank you.
I'm sorry.
- Matthew 18: 21 and 22.
- I'm not familiar.
- Then came Peter to him and said Lord,
how oft shall my brother sin against me
before I forgive him?
Till seven times?
Jesus sayeth unto him,
I do not say unto thee
till seven times, but
until 70 times seven.
I know you were sorry
as soon as it happened,
and I forgave you way back then,
but it's way past time
you forgive yourself.
Please.
Oh.
- I gotta go, I'll be back.
- I know.
(monitor beeping)
(dramatic music)
- Tracy, Tracy, Tracy.
What are you doing here?
- How was the hospital?
How's Brittany?
- What have you been doing?
- This.
I moved this chair here
so I could be right here
when you got in.
- Fine, get up, come on.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Come on, really?
Moving all my stuff around,
rearranging my stuff.
I mean, what?
You've been here for the last
few days while I've been away?
- I just wanted to make
sure you were okay.
How's your ex-wife, did she die?
- What'd you say?
Why would you say
something like that?
- (sighs) Oh, Tom.
Because I care.
I care, Tom.
I was worried about you.
I was really worried about Brittany.
- Hey, stop, no really, just stop.
- What?
- Look, I.
I just can't entertain this anymore.
- What are you saying, Tom?
- I'm saying that we're done.
This is it.
We're through, Tracy, all right?
I don't have the energy or the willingness
to even entertain your antics anymore.
- No.
- Yes.
No!
No.
No, no.
- Look, the only priority I
have right now is to my family.
All right, not to anyone
else, and that includes you.
- Was your family a priority
when you killed your son?
(dramatic music)
I didn't mean that.
I didn't mean that, I'm sorry.
I was outta line.
- Just stop.
I was outta line, I didn't mean that.
- Don't touch me.
- I'm sorry.
- Look, get out.
I didn't mean to say that.
- Look, get out!
- We can talk about it, Tom.
- No, get.
- Let's talk about this.
- Look, get out, let's go.
- We can talk about this!
- I said get out.
I want you out!
- You're hurting me!
- Look, out!
I want you out of here right--
- No, no!
Tom!
- Get out!
- [Tracy] Tom!
- And stay the hell away from me!
- [Tracy] We need to talk about this!
Tom!
Please!
Please.
(thudding)
(gentle music)
♪ Do, do, do, do, do, do, do ♪
♪ Where did I go wrong ♪
♪ It seems that I've
done everything wrong ♪
♪ The pieces ♪
♪ How do I put 'em back together ♪
♪ It's like I'm lost forever right now ♪
- Baby.
♪ Been waitin' ♪
- Baby, I hope you could hear me.
♪ Any better right now ♪
- I need you to wake up.
I need you to wake up.
(sniffling)
I can't imagine being in
this world without you.
♪ I'm feeling so empty right now ♪
- Brittany needs you.
I need you.
♪ I need you right now ♪
- I love you.
I love you so much.
- I love you too.
- Megan.
She's awake.
Baby.
- Oh, thank God.
- She's awake.
- Thank God.
- Nurse, nurse, she's awake!
- [Diane] Thank God, thank God.
- Oh, I just never wanna let you go.
- I love you, Mom.
- I love you too, baby.
- Mom, can I get some candy?
(dramatic music)
- [Megan] Sure, you want
Grandma or Daddy to go with you?
- [Brittany] No, I know where it is.
- You sure you don't want
Dad to just come help you
push the buttons?
- [Brittany] Dad, I got it.
- Come here, baby, I'll
give you some change.
I got $5.
Machine's right around the
corner, and she'll be fine.
- Thanks, Grandma.
- [Megan] Hurry back, sweet pea.
- Okay, Mom.
- You're so grown.
- You sure you weren't speeding?
- No, Thomas, I don't speed.
I usually have the baby so no.
- Wow.
And you don't remember anything else.
- No.
(candy rattles)
(dramatic music)
- Hey, Brittany.
- This one guy cutting me off and
I swerved and tried to hit the
brakes and they didn't work.
Next thing I know, I'm slamming
into a concrete barrier.
Then nothing.
- What's taking her so
long to get some candy?
There you go.
You're finally back.
Let's see what you got.
(suspenseful music)
- Where'd you get this?
- Tracy gave it to me.
- Tracy?
- Dad.
Why did she say she's my stepmom?
- Baby, I need you to
stay with your grandma.
- Okay.
- Sorry.
- [Hatch] Just the man we're looking for.
- What's this about?
- You need to come with me.
- Get your hands offa me!
- You don't remember
us from the university?
'Cause we remember you.
- What's this about?
- You need to come with u--
- Get your hands off of me!
I got a ex-wife who just got out of a coma
a couple hours ago,
I'm not going anywhere.
- Fine.
You want to explain to her
why we got an anonymous tip
stating that a certain
professor who's currently
under a murder investigation
might have also cut his
ex-wife's brake lines?
- What?
- You're coming with us.
- Tracy Jacobs, all
right, I keep saying it.
Tracy Jacobs.
Maybe you're not spelling it right.
- We ran her name and all the
other information you gave us
and nothing came up.
- What about her apartment?
- We sent a unit to the address,
but the landlord told our officers
that nobody lives there by that name.
- That's impossible.
Look, I've been there, I slept there.
- And you're saying this
fantasy woman of yours
is your ticked off girlfriend?
- Was.
- Was your girlfriend and student.
- Look, look, you asked me
who I thought it might be,
all right, I'm telling you.
No person comes up to a child and says,
"I'm gonna be your stepmom."
Are you serious?
- That's right.
You felt threatened because she
gave your daughter a bracelet.
- That's right.
Look, I know how crazy it sounds.
- It sounds like a load of crap.
If you ask me, you're the
one with everything to lose.
Ex-wife, ex-girlfriend,
cushy teaching job.
- Fine, y'all don't wanna
listen to me, all right.
I'm telling you there's
something off about this woman.
If my ex-wife brake lines were cut
then that's who you should be looking at.
(monitor beeping)
(dramatic music)
(coughing)
- What is this?
What is this?
(screaming)
Take this.
- [Nurse] It's okay.
- [Tom] Megan, I would never do that.
- So this woman has been
around our daughter?
- No, all right?
I never brought her around Brittany.
She must have followed me
to a visit or something.
- Do you love her?
- Just because I slept with
her doesn't mean I love her.
I love you.
- Then get me outta here.
Mom, I want to go home.
- I know, baby, I know.
- Get me outta here, now!
- I know, honey.
we're gonna just--
- No, get me outta here!
- Please, just wait a second, all right?
- All right.
Diane.
- Yeah?
- Can you pick up Brittany from school
and keep her with you tonight?
- Absolutely.
All right, I'll leave now.
All right, baby, I love you.
- I love you too, Mom.
- All right.
Call you later!
- Okay!
- [Brittany] Do you think
Mom's gonna be okay?
- Mm-hmm.
I do believe she's gonna be okay, honey.
You're gonna come to my place,
and we're gonna have some
smores and hot chocolate,
and stay up late and carry on.
- Hey, Brittany!
- Oh, can I go play with him please?
- Yeah, baby, you want me to hold that?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Come on.
- Have fun!
(children chattering)
- You're it!
(Brittany laughs)
- Brittany?
Brittany?
Brittany!
Did you see Brittany, honey?
Did you see a little girl, you
were just playing with her.
- I don't, she was here but I don't.
She's not here anymore.
- She's not here.
Brittany!
- Brittany!
- [Boy] Brittany!
- [Diane] Oh my God, where did she go?
- Brittany!
- Yes, is this 911?
Yeah, my granddaughter's missing.
- I was on the playground the whole time.
- Ms. Shibley, what happened to you?
- As I said before, she was
playing with these little kids,
those little kids, and I
turn around for two seconds
to use my phone, then I
turn back and she was gone.
She was just gone!
I don't understand!
- Do you know any of these
kid that she's playing with?
- No, but they seemed to know her.
- Did you call her parents?
- I did.
They're coming home from the hospital.
- Thank you for your time.
If we need any more information,
we'll give you a call.
- Okay. (crying)
- Thank you.
(sobbing)
- And you have no idea
of where our daughter is?
- We're doing the best we can, sir.
- The best you can?
The best you can, let me tell
you what the best you can
would have been.
You out there looking for that woman
instead of sitting down questioning me!
- Thomas.
- No, no, no.
This is BS.
Find my daughter!
- I apologize.
- No, you're family's going
through a very tough time.
We understand.
(suspenseful music)
- Brittany!
Brittany!
(crashing)
(foot smashing)
(lock rattling)
Brittany!
Brittany, where are you?
Brittany.
(whimpering)
Come on, baby, baby, come here.
It's okay, it's okay,
all right, all right.
Come on, come here, come here.
Come on, I got you.
I got you.
(siren wailing)
Here you go, all right, all right.
Are you hurt?
Are you hurt, baby, huh?
- My arm.
- Your, okay, okay, okay.
All right, okay, all right.
Daddy's here.
She's okay, baby, yeah.
She's just a bit shaken up.
- Oh, thank God.
Thank God you found her.
- I'm bringing her home now.
Listen, sorry about this.
- Hurry, please.
(dramatic music)
- I'll see you soon.
- [Megan] Hurry.
(dramatic music)
(fist smashing)
(Megan groaning)
(wheelchair rattles)
(thrilling music)
(groaning)
(objects crashing)
(women grunting)
(elbow smashing)
(table crashes)
(women grunting)
(foot smashes)
(groaning)
(whimpering)
(vase smashes)
(grunting)
(wheelchair rattles)
(head smashing)
(body thudding)
- Hi, young lady, I'm Detective Daily.
- Oh, come on, come on.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Mr. Lewis, it would be best if we could
take Brittany to the station
tonight and get her statement.
Now, I realize this is a
traumatic experience for her but--
- I've had enough of you guys.
The only place I'm taking my daughter
is to be home with her mother.
Now, if she's feeling up to it tomorrow
then I'll bring her by the police station.
She'll give you a statement then.
- Understood.
- Thank you.
All right, baby.
We're going home, all right?
All right.
(tape crackling)
- You think I wanted to be this person?
You think I wanted to be like this, again?
Do you?
Answer me!
(hand slapping)
(thrilling music)
- How's it goin'?
(dramatic music)
Brittany!
Wait, wait, don't go in there.
Don't go in there.
- Why, why?
- I know women like you.
Controlling, manipulative,
just like my mom.
We fixed her too.
But you're a bit more stubborn, see.
You didn't die in the car.
But that's okay.
(muffled screams)
- I have an emergency.
I need you to send the
police to my address.
I think there's an
officer down, all right?
Here, you give them
your address, all right?
Go in the car, lock the door.
Lock the door, sweetie!
- You're gonna drown.
(thrilling music)
(muffled screams)
- Megan.
- You're daughter is gonna call me Mom.
(muffled screams)
- Megan!
Megan.
- Stop!
- Tracy.
- Don't come any closer,
I swear to God I'll--
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Come on, Tracy.
Just please let her go.
There's still enough time,
the police aren't here.
All right?
It doesn't have to be like this.
Just let her go, okay?
You don't deserve this and
neither does she, okay?
If you let her go, me and
you, we can get outta here.
- You and me, we can leave together?
- That's right, just let her go.
Come on, let's go.
- You think I'm stupid.
You and me and Brittany,
we can never be happy
as long as she's still in the picture.
She has to die.
- No!
(siren wailing)
No, no!
(water splashing)
- [Officer] Freeze!
Get on the ground, now!
Put your hands up!
(whistling)
- [Tom] So you're saying
that there were new findings?
- Yes, sir.
For one, the woman who attacked you two,
her name isn't Tracy
Jacobs, it's Laura Santiago.
She got herself picked up out
of Texas for jumping bail.
Apparently she's been locked up
down there since she was only 12.
- We had given them a
call to let them know
she was arrested.
They were more than happy to
come down and take her back.
She'd only been out for six
months when she met you.
- What did she do to get
arrested in the first place?
- The story that she told
you wasn't too far off.
Her parents did die in a fire,
but it was she and her brother who set it.
- Her brother?
(whistling)
- She wasn't an only child.
Remember the apartment was
under an Alfred Santiago?
That's Laura's older brother.
It took a lotta red tape to
get their juvenile records
because they were sealed
by the arresting state.
Once we got the judge to unseal them,
it cleared everything up.
Laura and Alfred had both been convicted
of killing their parents,
but there wasn't enough information
to make a murder conviction stick.
The State had offered them a plea deal.
Plead guilty and they
would only have to go
to a mental institution
until their 25th birthdays.
- And after they were arrested,
they were both diagnosed with
histrionic personality
disorder, schizophrenia,
and a list of other mental disorders.
- So she was never in foster care?
- No, just state facilities.
- [Megan] So where is this brother now?
- [Daily] We're still
looking for him, Ma'am.
But don't worry, he won't get far.
- [Hanks] He has nowhere to go
and no family on the outside.
- [Daily] Please, trust us.
You have nothing to worry about.
(somber piano music)